♪
(no audio)
MATT: Welcome back, guys.
I hope you enjoyed your--
your holiday.
Hope you enjoyed
your new year
and are ready to tackle all the
chaos this year has coming.
Both fists forward.
So, missed you guys.
Last we left off
was a little crazy,
but before we get
to that circumstance,
let's go ahead and start
with our announcements.
Yay!
(cheers)
First and foremost, our
first episode of the year
is sponsored by us
happy to be back.
We have no
sponsor tonight.
(cheers)
MARISHA: Happiness!
MATT: So sponsored instead
by viewers like you.
So...
Thank you.
But, yeah, so other
announcements we have.
Me and Marisha will be running
from this episode tonight
to pack and leave at a super
early, pre-dawn flight.
Pretty much, or at
dawn flight, to MAGFest.
We'll be there getting
in later tomorrow,
and be there this weekend.
So, those of you who are going
to MAGFest, we'll see you there.
We have--
LAURA: Is that what it is,
just a lot of magazines?
MATT: Just a lot of magazines.
-TALIESIN: People, US Weekly.
-MARISHA: Oprah.
MATT: We pretty much got
in there only because
of the article
in Game Informer.
That's the only
reason we were invited.
No, MAGFest is great.
We have a Critical Role
panel tomorrow evening
that me and Marisha
will be doing,
and other fun stuff
Saturday and Sunday.
So, look for us
in the schedule
and we'll look forward
to seeing you guys
at the actual event.
Travis, you wanted to
mention something real quick?
TRAVIS: Yes! I wanted to
give a quick shout out
to Kathy Creshe, Creshaw,
I don't know
how to say it.
TALIESIN: That was a good shout out.
TRAVIS: From Pennsylvania.
SAM: Big fan of the show?
TRAVIS: We love you,
from us, to you.
-LAURA: We read your email.
-TRAVIS: It was wonderful.
TRAVIS: Sam!
SAM: Uh, yeah, tonight's sponsor
is Critical Role, as you said,
we have lots of stuff.
Lots of merchandise
available in the store.
The logo shirt, mugs,
patches, nail wraps,
hats, key chains, and
necklaces are available
and if you didn't see it
over the Christmas break,
we have the
Gilmore shirts and the
"How do you want
to do this?" shirts
and you guys know this,
we have a big Spanish
speaking fan base,
and I wanted to
give them some love,
so I thought I'd do our
ad tonight in Spanish.
Two notes, two notes,
I don't speak Spanish,
and second note
is my neighbor's son
translated this for me.
So, he's in Spanish Two.
Should be pretty basic.
TRAVIS: Not, "He's Spanish too."
SAM: No, he's-- he's a
sophomore in high school.
Hola, me llamo Sam Riegel.
Aquí está mi perro. Se llama Travis Willingham.
Una broma. ¿Te gustan las camisas t-shirt?
Espero que sí porque tenemos dos camisas
t-shirt para vender en nuestra tienda.
Una es color morado.
Es para Gilmore's Glorious Goods.
(laughter)
La otra no es morado, es gris.
Tiene el slogan de Matthew Mercer,
which is...
¿Como quieres hacer esto?
(laughter)
No cuestan muchos pesos.
Tu vas a ir internet y comprar ahora.
¡Gracias por favor!
(applause, cheers)
-TRAVIS: Muy bien!
-MARISHA: Yay for Spanish Two!
TALIESIN: High school Spanish is
the official language
of Los Angeles, well done.
TRAVIS: A future translator
will then, like, show up?
-SAM: I don't know.
-TALIESIN: It'll be insulted.
Actually, yeah, it'll
actually Google translate
and will be like,
I refuse to even touch this.
SAM: It's for our
Spanish language viewers.
-There are many.
-TRAVIS: That was great.
MATT: This is true.
Thank you so much.
Anyone else?
Oh, I want to announce
real fast too.
We received quite a
bit of Critmas gifts
after we had filmed the
Critmas episode last month.
So, as we're slowly retrieving
them from the mailbox,
me, Marisha,
Taliesin, and possibly
anybody that's available
at the time, Liam,
Laura will be
doing a Periscope opening
of the rest of those gifts
in the next couple
of weeks or so.
Be announcing it
ahead of time,
so pay attention to
that, but it is coming.
So, don't worry.
We'll be getting
to your presents
and thanking you for all your
awesome unnecessary generosity.
You're so wonderful
and we'll let you
know once it's happening.
Anybody else have any other
announcements they want to make?
-TRAVIS: Hands up!
-SAM: Uh?
TRAVIS: Hands up!
MATT: Alright, great.
That being the case.
-MARISHA: I don't know--
-LIAM: I don't know what this--
MATT: Let's go ahead
and dive in.
To the first 2017
episode of Critical Role.
TALIESIN: ♪ Do you believe
in life after-- ♪♪
(growling, screaming)
♪
(electricity crackling)
MATT: Hello, everyone,
and welcome back.
So, getting us up to speed
with the current circumstance
that we left off at
the end of last episode.
Vox Machina,
the main adventurers,
spending the better
part of this past year
under the shadow of
the Chroma Conclave,
a group of ancient
chromatic dragons
that have
banded together,
seemingly under the banner
of Thordak, The Cinder King,
a great red dragon
that had been sealed
in the fire elemental plane
for a number of years.
Newly released and
carrying with him
what was called
a soul anchor.
A magical artifact made from
the heart of a fire primordial
that had begun to
cause him to mutate
and swell and become something
beyond what he was.
Also driving him
apparently insane.
As he dominated the
countryside of Tal'Dorei,
along with the
rest of the Conclave,
you gather artifacts
of great power
called the Vestiges
of Divergence
under the guidance
of two sphinx allies.
You travel between
various planes
and gathering
these artifacts
gathered allies and prepared for
this climactic confrontation
in your home city of Emon,
now partially brought
to ruin and flame.
You assembled an army.
You snuck beneath the city.
You arrived within the center
of the Cloudtop district
nearly under the nose of
Thordak's defending hordes,
and through a climactic
seeming sacrifice
by your friends
Kashaw and Zahra,
were allowed to pass
directly into the Cloudtop
heading off Thordak
before he could emerge
from his subterranean lair
and lay waste to the armies
as they pushed inward
towards his lair.
♪
TRAVIS: When you say it like that.
MATT: There you all did battle
with the great colossal
Thordak, The Cinder King.
A well prepared
fight rolled out
and while there
was much danger,
you all persevered and managed
to, using the vestiges,
destroy the soul anchor
once it was revealed within the
body of the great red dragon.
His form rescinding
and withering back
to its regular,
seemingly withering size.
You-- it attempted to
flee back into its lair,
but the rather rapid and
temporarily winged rogue,
Vax'ildan gave chase and
dealt a finishing blow
to the great red beast
midway through its cavern
towards its lair.
There you were joined
briefly by your sister
and an ally you had made through
this circumstance, Raishan,
one green dragon.
The member of the Conclave
that seemingly had made
a tenuous alliance with you
as her goal also was
to destroy Thordak.
Aiding you in the battle,
Raishan followed suit
and upon the corpse of
Thordak laying cut, bleeding
and dead in the
center of this cavern,
she wished to take her end
of the deal you had made.
To be left alone with
the corpse for a moment
to acquire some
secret knowledge
that apparently she was seeking
from the dead dragon.
Upon releasing the
energy from the scroll
which she had utilized
the incantation from,
you decided that vengeance
being your oath as a paladin
and the history that
you have with Keyleth
and Keyleth's people
that died under the guise
of Raishan's initial
plotting with Thordak
to not let this creature
stand and attacked it.
Both you and your sister, just
as Keyleth began to arrive.
The rest of the party
slowly staggering behind.
Raishan sneered and went
further back into the cavern.
You all gave chase into this
dark, volcanic tunnel system
which then opened up into
a large, red flaming cavern
filled with
lava pools and rivers,
and apparently a
handful of red eggs,
it looked like scattered
throughout this room.
Thick dark red
crimson scales
with crystalline formations
pouring out of the sides.
Very similar to Thordak's
primordial dragon form.
Upon finding not Raishan,
but just this empty space,
you looked up
to see a series
of arcane
summoned meteors
suddenly given form,
rocketing from the
ceiling of the cavern
and slamming into the floor
dealing some of you
a pretty dangerous blow
and sending you scattering
across the floor a bit.
Vex being thrown
across the way.
You all managed to survive as
at the end of the last battle,
I'd forgotten that
you had made your save
and you actually, your
bludgeon damage was halved,
so Vex is conscious,
though still hurting.
-SAM: ♪ Whoo ♪
-LIAM: ♪ Whoo ♪♪
MATT: As the dust settles
and you all take stock of
what had just transpired,
you see the snout of
the green dragon pull up
into what appears
to be a series
of dark volcanic
exhaust tunnels
that seem to be like
a hive network of--
of honeycomb type tunnels
that just spiral off
all through the ceiling,
and that's where we left off
in the last sequence here.
SAM: Geez, Louise.
MATT: Which, previously, behind
if I'm--if I'm correct,
and I believe I am, and
if not, internet, it's fine,
we'll--we'll do
the narrative.
We have the three
of you in the room.
We have Percy, Scanlan,
Pike and Gilmore
rushing up behind
as fast as they can.
Grog and Kima
had stayed behind
to finish up one of
the more recent battles
and Jarret is
just not going in.
He is not in a
place to follow suit.
"You got this, you got this.
Do not worry, it's okay."
LIAM: Before we ran into
the bigger chamber,
Gilmore and Jarret had caught up
with us if I remember correctly.
MATT: No, they did not.
LAURA: Oh, they hadn't
gotten to us.
LIAM: I remember
that they did.
MATT: No, they would have gotten
into the chamber with you.
Only the three of you
made it into the chamber.
LIAM: That's what I mean.
MATT: They got into the tunnel,
but they hadn't
got up to your guys.
The speed in which
you guys all got there
was basically just Raishan
and the three of you,
then the
attack happened.
Raishan rushed in,
you rush after her.
Everyone else has kinda
been left in the dust.
They're not too
far behind you,
but things be as they may.
We begin tonight's episode
at this next
round of combat.
Continuing
where we last did.
LAURA: Oh, God, oh God!
-MARISHA: Jesus Christ.
-TRAVIS: Oh God, oh God, oh God.
-MATT: So--
-SAM: Why from there?
You're fine.
-TALIESIN: No, stop, don't.
-MARISHA: Yeah, police.
MATT: So, at the top of
this combat round,
technically, Percy, you
have the initiative on this.
You are continuing to push
through this-- this hallway.
You haven't quite even,
at a double dash,
you can hear explosions
in the distance
and then you guys watch as
suddenly smoke, silt and ash
come flying through
the tunnel from within
immediately followed by the
sound of these large, heavy,
banging explosions.
Some sort of heavy impact,
a series of impacts seem to have
detonated deep within the tunnel
and immediately set everyone
in the vicinity on edge
knowing that something
is still transpiring
in a very dangerous way
deeper within this tunnel.
TALIESIN: I am throwing on my mask and
I am running into the room.
I'm actually gonna
be spider crawling.
I'm gonna be on the-- on
the walls so that I'm-- yeah.
I don't want to be in the line
of anything that happens.
MARISHA: That's awesome.
LIAM: Spider Percy's
my favorite Percy.
MATT: It's just the feet, Percy.
MARISHA: ♪ Spider Percy,
Spider Percy ♪♪
MATT: You can if you want,
if you really want to.
SAM: He's like
walking like this?
-MATT: Yeah.
-TALIESIN:Running.
SAM: Cool!
TALIESIN: This ain't Dr. Strange,
this is--
LIAM: He's doing this and
nothing's happening.
TALIESIN: Out of fluid, you know.
LIAM: If anyone can make it,
it's you.
TALIESIN: I know, I got to make-- I got
to make Spider-- Spider Percy.
MATT: So, anyway,
that ends your turn.
You--you run past
on the side of the wall,
as the ash begins to settle
around you as you run past,
kind of preparing your weapons
for a coming confrontation,
you glance out to your right
and see there the smoldering
wreckage of red scales
and dragon blood that was once
Thordak, the cinder king.
You see that and
down it's about--
You keep running.
You can see a gentle glimmer in
the distance of a battlefield,
but you're not
quite there yet.
TALIESIN: Okay.
MATT: Okay, the top
of the round.
The three of you finding
yourselves in this circumstance.
We go to the lair actions.
So, these lair actions are--
LAURA: Oh God.
MATT: Of Thordak's lair, as this
is not Raishan's lair,
but even though
Thordak is dead,
the lair itself
has its own natural,
naturally
occurring dangers.
-TRAVIS: Damn it!
-MATT: So.
SAM: What?
That don't make
no sense, man.
Thordak's dead.
His lair dies with him.
MATT: Over time!
Maybe, you don't know.
TRAVIS: His home security
system still pays for it.
-LAURA: Yeah.
-MATT: Exactly, yeah.
It's-- it's on a recurring
subscription plan.
So, there will be--
TALIESIN: How do I pee?
MATT: The lava that you had
just landed across.
So, Vex'ahlia, as you are
knocked from the explosions
of the meteors from
landing on your back,
and just barely getting
back up to your feet,
your vision comes back as
you see the stream of lava
that's just
barely pouring past.
Very slowly begins to...
LAURA: I back up, I back up.
MATT: As it opens and sprays
here at 20 foot radius.
LAURA: I climb back up
and I bump an egg.
MATT: I'm going to bring
out my templates.
TALIESIN: No.
LAURA: This is gonna
kill me, isn't it?
MATT: This will explode
and all three of you--
I need you all three to make
dexterity saving throws.
-MARISHA: Oh, boy.
-TALIESIN: Yay.
MARISHA: This is great.
LAURA: Cool.
This is-- is this--
TALIESIN: First roll of 2017.
-LAURA: Oh, wait, I'm hasted.
-MARISHA: Twenty total.
-SAM: Twenty total's good.
-MARISHA: Yeah!
-LAURA: Seven.
-LIAM: Twenty-seven.
MATT: Okay, that's fine.
So, as it is a hotter, more
dangerous vicinity here,
the damage is higher, but you
all managed to make your saves,
so you're only
taking half damage
as you all avoid from
the spray of magma
that just bursts out and
splashes in your area.
LIAM: Evasion keeps me
at zero, yeah?
MATT: Yes, because you have
your rogue evasionness,
and it's
three ones, alright.
-LAURA: Yay.
-TALIESIN: Yay.
MATT: So, that'll be 18 points of
fire damage reduced to nine.
(indistinguishable dialogue)
MARISHA: I mean, I'm not, you know.
-LAURA: Still terrified.
-MARISHA: Taking it for granted.
(talking over each other)
Yeah, yeah,
something like that.
Or five, it's debatable.
Depends on the
health of the people.
MATT: Next up in the initiative
order is Raishan.
LAURA: Oh, good.
MATT: So, as the splash happens,
you glance up and you
can see what looks to be
a series of maybe a dozen or
so of these volcanic lava tubes
that kind of are these--
these caverns roughly the
size of a very low live,
kind of pushed in
cat-like Raishan.
You see the head and the tail
kind of hanging out the side
as Raishan begins
to mutter some sort
of an incantation
under her breath.
You hear the echo...
(whispering incantation)
Between the room as it kind
of quivers for a second.
And her form
just vanishes.
TRAVIS: Damn it.
LIAM: But we saw where she was
before she went into--
MATT: You did.
SAM: Fight over, that's it.
That's great.
LAURA: Oh my God, she--
she ran away.
SAM: Alright, let's mop
up here and go home.
TRAVIS: Punk ass, Raishan.
MARISHA: The air ate her.
MATT: I guarantee you that's
probably not the case.
No.
TRAVIS: You're saying
there's a chance.
MATT: Yes.
Alrighty.
MARISHA: Dude.
TALIESIN: Just shunned her
into invisibility.
MATT: Great.
That brings us next
to Keyleth's turn.
LAURA: Keyleth, just kill her.
Find her and kill
her so we can get--
MARISHA: Whereabouts
was she last?
MATT: Last you saw was up
in this cavernous area
roughly in this
portion of the ceiling.
MARISHA: But we can assume she probably
went invisible and then moved.
LIAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: I could do Faerie Fire on her,
but I mean, I don't
know where she is
and it's a 20 foot cube.
It'd probably be a waste.
So, instead, I'm going
to cast Call Lightning
at fourth level,
and go fire elemental.
MATT: Okay.
-SAM: How's that work?
-LAURA: It's an ongoing--
Lightning is an ongoing--
MARISHA: Yeah, it's a concentration.
Yeah, I can make it--
SAM: So it just exists there?
-Ready to strike?
-TALIESIN: Like a ghostbuster.
SAM: Cool.
MATT: So, as you watch
Keyleth's eyes flare
with this bright electric
kind of blue yellow light,
as the ash and bit of dust
that has been kind of
plummeting from the ceiling
from the impact of
the meteor swarms
and the movement of some
now not seeable dragon
amongst the ceiling caverns.
It gathers into
this swirling storm
that begins to build
and form across the top
domed portion
of this cavern.
As it does, you watch bolts
of electricity...
Arc through the storm
as Keyleth's form
then whooshes into a burst
swirl of flaming energy.
Her physical body now becoming
a swirling fire elemental.
You wish to move or you're
gonna stay where you are?
MARISHA: I'm going to take a few
steps back and-- question.
Can I look up
and see if, like,
the clouds are kind of shaping
around like a, you know,
roughly
dragon shaped body?
That make sense?
TALIESIN: She's looking for
disturbances of the force.
MATT: Sure.
MARISHA: You gave me that
"this is bullshit" look.
TALIESIN: Roll a 29.
MARISHA: Oh, that's not bad.
With perception,
perception.
Sorry, I'm so nervous, 26.
MATT: Twenty-six.
Glancing about between
the dust that's falling,
the movement of the storm
that you've gathered
at the roof of the ceiling,
you don't see anything
that identifies
the location
of a dragon now.
MARISHA: Yeah, so it's fine.
So, I'll take a
few steps back.
MATT: So you're
about right there?
MARISHA: Yeah, oh, oh.
TALIESIN: Wow, it's
weirdly mirrored.
Okay, that
took me a second.
-MARISHA: It's totally mirrored.
-TALIESIN: Yeah!
LAURA: Oh!
-TALIESIN: Yeah, I know, cool.
-LIAM: Your screen is flipped.
-LAURA: That's crazy.
-MARISHA: It's fine.
It's not a problem.
TALIESIN: We have the
same view you do.
LAURA: It's actually, no,
I think it's better,
because we're looking at
it from his perspective.
TALIESIN: So, we can say
like, "move us down,"
and they'll be
towards him now.
Yeah.
-MARISHA: I'm sorry, so move me--
-MATT: Further in?
MARISHA: Yeah, down-- down.
SAM: Towards the lava
or away from the lava?
MARISHA: Right there,
down one more.
-Other way.
-TALIESIN: South.
-LAURA: Oh my God.
-MARISHA: South.
Yeah, that's good,
that's-- that's good.
-TALIESIN: There.
-MATT: Good, alright.
LAURA: Where's our pointer?
MATT: Where's your
laser pointers guys?
TALIESIN: Where are our pointers?
We need new pointers.
LAURA: It's been
three weeks, Matt.
MATT: It has been, I know.
SAM: We've forgotten how to play.
MATT: That's okay.
Alright, so--
MARISHA: It's like inverted controls.
TALIESIN: I'm taking Diva.
MATT: Now, is that your turn?
MARISHA: Yes.
MATT: Alright, finishing
Keyleth's turn.
That brings us to Gilmore
who's rushing up past--
LAURA: Come on, Gilmore.
MATT: Keeping up his pace
as much as he can.
"Oh, boy.
I know you guys take
me to the nicest places."
And he's just
jogging as best he can.
Rushing into the ash cloud
as another one pushes through.
Some of the wind
tending to push
and causing swirling little
dust devils of ash and cinder.
That's gonna
end his turn.
Vex, you're up.
LAURA: Oh.
-MATT: So you glance up.
-LAURA: I glance up.
MATT: You see all this happening,
what are you gonna do?
LAURA: I'm gonna get on my broom.
TALIESIN: Get on up.
LAURA: And I'm gonna
take a health potion.
-MATT: Okay.
-LAURA: So...
MATT: Regular health potion?
LAURA: I have a Greater.
-MATT: Okay.
-LAURA: I have one Greater.
So, that's a what?
4d8?
MATT: A Greater is 4d4 plus four.
Remember you guys
are pretty low
on any powerful
potions at this point.
You used most
of them, so, yeah.
LAURA: Yeah, yeah, I had
a Greater left.
It's jack shit.
Ten, ten whole points.
MATT: There you go,
ten points of healing.
On your broom.
LAURA: I'm gonna go back
towards the entrance.
Post up to the entrance,
like off the ground
as far as I can get.
MATT: That's about as
far as you can get.
You want to stay hovering or
just like there on the ground?
LAURA: Hovering!
Stay off the ground
and can I--
MATT: Are you going up
ten feet or 20 feet
or are you staying
just above the ground
so you're not
standing on it?
LAURA: I'm gonna go up ten feet.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: And if I can be a little bit
further away from Keyleth,
that'd be clutch.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: I mean, I don't know
if it'd be clutch,
but it would be helpful.
Can I look up,
and see if
I can see like,
dust coming down
from any of the holes,
to see if Raishan is moving around
in the holes
on the ceiling--
MATT: Roll a perception check.
LIAM: There's a storm cloud.
LAURA: I know, I know.
Is this
pertaining to dragons
so I would
get advantage?
MATT: Sure.
-LAURA: That's the same thing.
-LIAM: Two 13's.
LAURA: So, perception,
so that's 26.
MATT: Okay, so glancing
about, unfortunately,
the gathering of the
Call Lightning cloud
combined with the other
dark ash-filled interior,
you don't see anything
that signifies
the location
of a dragon.
You do glance over
and you notice
that where you
landed previously,
one of the eggs was pretty
much just destroyed by this--
'cause it was the area
of the meteor swarm
where you guys were hit.
So, all gathered here,
so this egg right here
by where you were,
is currently just crushed
inward and filled with rock.
-MARISHA: And--
-LAURA: Really?
Is there anything
oozing out of it?
MARISHA: Yeah, what's--
LAURA: I should have
looked at it before.
MATT: It's hard to see,
it's far away,
but it looks like the
egg has been destroyed.
-LAURA: Destroyed?
-SAM: Destroyed?
LAURA: She doesn't care
about the eggs.
SAM: Or she didn't destroy it.
LIAM: Not the Mama!
LAURA: Okay, so I've got--
I'm so sorry.
MARISHA: That's true.
TRAVIS: So, it's covered with rocks.
LAURA: I don't know
where my notes are
to see what my
spells were from before.
I didn't have it set up
cause I'm a horrible person.
MARISHA: But that was
from the lair action.
SAM: Yeah, that wasn't her.
LAURA: Okay, this is--
this is the last one.
Oh, I didn't do like
any spells before.
So, I'm gonna cast--
I'm gonna cast
Cure Wounds on myself.
MATT: Okay.
What level?
MARISHA: Yeah, but does she
care or even not care?
TALIESIN: We'll find out.
LAURA: I'm gonna cast
it at third level.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: So, that's 1d8-- 2d8 plus
my spell casting modifier.
-MATT: So, a 3d8 technically.
-LAURA: 3d8?
MATT: Cause if you're
casting at third level,
it's 3d8 plus your spell modifier.
LAURA: Okay.
TRAVIS: That's good,
that's good, that's good.
MARISHA: This is turning into
a Jerry Springer episode.
Is she or is
she not the mom?
LAURA: No, my modifier, which is my wisdom.
Ten plus--
Jesus Christ,
I'm sorry!
Ten plus--
TALIESIN: Three weeks, man.
LAURA: Thirteen points heal.
MARISHA: It's like riding a bike,
riding a bike.
LIAM: Three weeks to
stew, everybody.
MATT: Alright, there you go.
At the end of your turn--
Actually she's gonna do--
TALIESIN: It's like riding a
bike with pen and paper.
MATT: Okay.
You feel this strange,
sudden warm tingling sensation
separate from the healing spell
just in your vicinity.
Almost like a warm breeze
just kind of passes through you.
That's it.
-SAM: Oh, boy.
-MATT: End of your turn.
-SAM: What does that mean?
-LAURA: I don't know.
SAM: You've been
cursed forever.
-TRAVIS: It's a bloody fart.
-TALIESIN: Farting dragon.
Invisible
farting dragon.
LAURA: What if that
was a baby dragon?
LIAM: I'm gonna take to the air.
I'm going to-- do I
still feel hasted yet?
MATT: You-- yes, you do.
LIAM: I'm going to
fly past my sister
and slap the one Greater healing
potion I have into her palm.
LAURA: Oh, thank you.
LIAM: Oh, Superior,
excuse me.
LAURA: What?!
LIAM: And then
I'm going to
curve around over Keyleth
and stab the egg there with
the Dragon Slayer blade.
-SAM: Oh, boy.
-MATT: This one?
-LIAM: Yes.
-MATT: Okay.
SAM: Stabbing eggs?
TALIESIN: That should give you a
Dragon Slayer bonus also.
MATT: Go ahead and
roll for attack.
TRAVIS: Isn't that poaching?
LIAM: That is 29.
MATT: That hits.
SAM: Go home Travis, you're drunk.
TRAVIS: I'm working on it.
LAURA: The babies will
help us though.
What if the
babies are cute?
-Can we raise them?
-TALIESIN: No.
MARISHA: You want to try and
Daenerys this shit?
TALIESIN: We can raise them
by setting them on fire.
MARISHA: We each get one, you guys.
LIAM: Twenty-six.
MATT: Twenty-six
points of damage.
Alright, you take the
blade as you rush up
and then hack through it.
The blade only
gets a few inches
into the tough outer
exterior of this egg
and you have to push
and carve through
and you do carve a--
a sliver through the egg's shell
and a little bit of
deep, brownish-maroon liquid
begins to spill out
of it, but that's--
it's not a heavy amount
of damage to the egg.
LIAM: I'm gonna take Whisper
and take that further.
MATT: Go ahead and roll for a
secondary attack.
-LIAM: That is 28 to hit.
-MATT: 28, that hits.
I'll mark the eggs that
are damaged and destroyed.
This one is...
LIAM: That's a total of 15.
MATT: Oh, that's not
working too well.
Good to know. Total of what?
-LIAM: Fifteen.
-MATT: Fifteen, okay.
With that much damage, the egg
begins to crack even further.
More of the liquid
begins to spill.
The blade pulls through
and you can see,
as you tear a chunk
of the actual shell
of this egg off
and it falls,
you have punctured some
sort of thick amniotic sac.
That's what the fluid
that's spilling out of it,
but you haven't
seemingly touched
any sort of flesh
or creature within,
but the egg is currently has
a section that is exposed.
LIAM: And I have--if
I'm still hasted,
I have a lot of
movement left,
so I'm going
to fly and hover
about 15 feet above
the egg towards you,
towards your DM tape
on the side there.
-MATT: Over here?
-LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: Fifteen feet
in the air.
♪
I have 120 feet of
movement total hasted.
LAURA: So, we were lining up?
We're seriously lining up?
LIAM: No, I'm all the
way over there.
-LAURA: No, you're in a line.
-LIAM: That's not where I want to be.
I want to be--
MATT: I know, I'm-- I'm calculating
how much movement you have.
LIAM: I'm arguing with
her, not you.
MATT: Ah, no worries.
LIAM: Cause that's what we do
cause we love each other.
MATT: You can get
right there.
LIAM: Okay.
Fifteen feet
in the air.
MATT: Fifteen feet
in the air?
LIAM: That's not the egg that
I'm talking about though.
LAURA: Look, I'm talking about--
LIAM: I'm talking about
the egg closer to Matt.
LAURA: Yes, there it is.
-LIAM: There.
-LAURA: That one!
LIAM: This is where
I want to go.
LAURA: That's where
you are, dude.
LIAM: That's over there?
LAURA: Yeah, it's reverse.
LIAM: It's the--it's the
flip screen is--
I don't want
to go there.
I want to go across
from everybody.
It's the flip.
SAM: Guys, just don't
look at the TV.
Look at the screen.
MATT: Over this way?
TRAVIS: Closer, Matt?
LIAM: I'm gonna kill you all.
MATT: Bare with this, new tech.
New year, we're
making this work.
LIAM: There, there.
The egg that's there.
TALIESIN: I have a brilliant solution
for this for next time.
MATT: So, from there-- yeah.
You wouldn't be
able to make it there.
LIAM: Literally, in game.
SAM: Invert controls.
TRAVIS: It's like a jet fighter.
-MARISHA: Battleship.
-TALIESIN: We can Battleship it.
Next time, next time, we'll
just have a row of letters
and a row of numbers.
-Says move me up to L7.
-LAURA: I can't use inverted controls.
SAM: I only use inverted.
LAURA: Really?
TALIESIN: Isn't that a great idea?
MATT: Destroyed.
TALIESIN: That was amazing.
MATT: This egg has one
crack in the side there.
Okay.
LAURA: Did you just mark
on your cool eggs?
TRAVIS: He's using dry erase.
MATT: Wet erase and, you know. It's fun.
TALIESIN: It's either that
or lick them.
SAM: How many more times are we
gonna play
with dragon eggs in a year?
TRAVIS: Did you have us on
tiny plastic eggs?
MATT: Yeah, so I ordered
way too many.
I put a bunch in my cart
to make sure that I--
I didn't know
which one to get
and then forgot about it,
came back and was like,
"Oh shit, I got
to order that."
Ended up buying
like three bags full.
TALIESIN: What am I gonna do
with all these eggs?
MATT: We'll have egg
plastic giveaways.
That ends
your turn, Vax?
Alright.
At the end of
your turn, Vax,
you feel the effect of
the haste potion dissipate
and your body, all of a sudden,
goes from this hyperactive,
very familiar mode
to extremely lethargic
and you find yourself having
to fight to catch your breath.
So, you can't take
any actions next turn.
-Can't do anything.
-LAURA: Oh, it's the potion.
MATT: It's the potion,
it's not the boots.
LIAM: The boots, right.
MATT: Kima is trying to keep
up pace with you, Grog.
You're still in
your large form.
How long's that last for?
TRAVIS: Let me check.
Enlarge: 10 minutes.
MATT: Yeah, alright, so you're
like bounding through.
Kima's falling behind.
As you guys both enter,
and continue past
you hear the explosions in the
distance and all of a sudden,
the rolling of smoke
and ash rushes past you.
The smell
doesn't bother you
cause you've had the smell
of burning beard hair
most of this
close to your nose.
What was once your
great bush beard
is a little tighter
to your face now.
TRAVIS: What?
You've taken a few dragon fire breaths
to the face.
The fact that
you have any hair
is by the grace of your
ancestral history.
That Dwarven
belt you have.
TRAVIS: I know, that's why it's so precious.
MATT: But are you just going full sprint
to catch up
with everybody?
-TRAVIS: Yeah.
-MATT: Alright.
TRAVIS: I'll just roll it.
I still have
Pike with me, right?
MATT: Pike is coming
with you, yeah.
'Cause you picked her up.
so you're just
running with Pike.
Kima's just
like, "Damn it!"
Left in the ash.
You, while you were behind,
you, with your full speed,
being faster than everybody
else in this group,
you almost catch up entirely
to Percy and Gilmore
and pretty much on their
initiative count going forward,
or at least of the arrival
count in the next round.
That finishes your go.
Let's see.
♪
You were after Vax, right?
TRAVIS: Yes, no, no, I was
right before Vax.
MATT: Right, so I got a little out
of order, sorry, my apologies.
Alright, so anyway, it wouldn't
have made a difference.
So Kima goes for a run. Pike.
Is Pike doing
anything on your back?
LAURA: Yes.
Pike's gonna heal you.
-TRAVIS: Who?
-LAURA: You.
-TRAVIS: Me?
-SAM: Ran away.
-LAURA: Yeah, she's--
-LIAM: Oh, wait, she's with him.
-LAURA: Yeah.
-MATT: He's carrying her.
LIAM: Nice.
TRAVIS: I got a little backpack.
MARISHA: I was just gonna say,
is she Yoda-ing you?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MARISHA: Is it like a Yoda
situation, that's awesome.
TRAVIS: The force.
That was terrible.
MATT: That was pretty
awful, actually.
(talking over each other)
SAM: Hi, I'm Yoda.
TRAVIS: I think that's
his brother, Carl.
LAURA: She's gonna cast Cure Wounds
at third level on him.
TALIESIN: That Seagulls
song is so great.
LAURA: So, that's three d8's.
MARISHA: One of the best things
they've done in a while.
TALIESIN: One of the best things
they've done in a long while.
LAURA: Ooh, that's pretty good.
Sixteen plus her page, her modifier.
What is-- oh, that's--
TRAVIS: Wisdom?
LAURA: That's my page.
LIAM: Clerics are--
MATT: Wisdom, wisdom.
Five, so add five to that.
LAURA: Plus five, 18.
-Twenty-one.
-MATT: There you go.
TRAVIS: Thanks, Pike.
LAURA: "Oh, you're
welcome, Grog."
-LIAM: You know.
-LAURA: Well, you know.
MATT: Scanlan.
SAM: I will run...
my 25 feet,
and then pop a potion.
Just a normal potion of healing
'cause that's all I got.
MATT: So, that's a 1d--
2d4 plus two.
SAM: Okay.
Ooh.
2d4 plus two?
MATT: Yep.
SAM: Five.
MATT: You heal
five hit points.
SAM: Great, I'm up to 70.
MATT: Are you-- are you doing
anything else on your turn?
Are you dashing?
SAM: Can I use my action to dash?
MATT: Yes, your action to
move again, essentially.
SAM: Okay.
I will do such a thing
cause I don't even know.
I'm just following
people and--
MATT: Yeah, you're a little bit behind
and you're pretty much--
Grog has caught up to you,
and you guys are just behind
Gilmore and Percy at this point.
SAM: Okay, I'm in
front of Grog still?
-MATT: Yeah.
-TRAVIS: Damn.
(laughing)
MATT: Well, he was
running while you--
(breathing heavily)
SAM: Objects in the mirror
are gigantic.
MATT: Okay, at the end
of your turn--
SAM: I die.
♪
MATT: Vax.
You, as you fly over with
your wings in the air,
looking down at the egg.
You feel this sudden
warm wind pass through you.
LAURA: What is that?
MARISHA: Fuck, is that her?
MATT: You don't quite--
it seems sourceless,
but it just seems to
fill you and leave.
LAURA: Does it feel good when it
happens or does it feel like--
MATT: It's just different.
It's already a hot, like
you're all sweating in here,
so the fact that
you feel something,
like, warm briefly comparatively
to the temperature around you
is what catches
your attention.
It doesn't hurt
or damage you,
but it just
seems strange.
TALIESIN: I don't like any of this.
MARISHA: I don't like any of it.
SAM: It's menopause.
(laughing)
LAURA: It's natural.
LIAM: You ruined the surprise.
TRAVIS: I cast Menopause on you.
LIAM: I'll pretend like
I suffer it myself.
-MATT: Okay, good.
-TRAVIS: You bastard.
MATT: Percival, we're up at the
top of the initiative.
TALIESIN: I'm running my
way in there.
MATT: Alright.
So...
Alrighty.
Percival, at a full run.
If you go full run,
you'll manage to get
just barely inside
the cavern about there.
TALIESIN: Okay.
MATT: Right there.
-TALIESIN: That'll do.
-MATT: So, that'll be your turn.
There's still a bonus action
if you have any use for it, so.
TALIESIN: I don't really have--
Mostly I just want to
use my bonus action
to take in everything and
look around and have a--
have a good, good
serious look.
In fact, I'll even
take a perception roll
if I can have one.
-MATT: Go for it.
-TALIESIN: Okay.
SAM: Just a good
sit and think.
TALIESIN: Let's get-- okay,
no never mind.
That's pretty good.
Wow, it has been a while.
-Twenty-five.
-MATT: Twenty-five.
Glancing around,
you see a fire elemental
that briefly startles you
as you kind of whip
around in that direction,
but you recognize--
MARISHA: And like, it's got
antlers, and I'm like...
(grunts)
TALIESIN: I love Hannibal
too, it's great.
Okay.
Eggs, dust.
MATT: Yeah, you see eggs.
One is destroyed
and just leaking out
and like a series
of boulders
and what looks like
some sort of a large,
concave impression on the top.
There are eggs scattered
throughout the area.
There's a giant
storm cloud gathering
in the roof of the cavern,
and there is the
large pool of lava
with the small
pool over there.
You see occasional glimmers
of what look like
coin in the distance.
TALIESIN: Can you put me,
like, on the wall
just cause I don't
think I'd be--
I was still spider crawling
so even
on top of the little
wall thing, if you want.
MATT: Sure, I'll
put you there.
Sure, why not, Percy?
-TALIESIN: Thank you.
-MATT: You're welcome.
TALIESIN: That makes me happy.
LIAM: How high is it to these
holes in the ceiling from--
MATT: I'd say it's
about 60, 70 feet up?
-LAURA: Okay.
-TALIESIN: Cool, cool.
MATT: Yeah, the whole cavern's
kind of domed like this.
Alrighty, then,
that's Percy's turn.
Another lair action's
going to transpire.
SAM: Oh.
This one's a good one.
This one heals everybody.
MATT: Yeah.
There is a fissure
that erupts
over in this
side of the room.
The ground kind of
cracks open and this--
You've seen
it happen once.
A plume of poisonous gas
fills this space here.
LAURA: It's okay, we're
immune to poison.
MATT: Let's see.
I need-- I need you, Vex,
to make a constitution
saving throw.
LAURA: Even I'm immune to poison?
Oh, no.
MARISHA: Really?
Even with Hero's Feast?
-SAM: Oh, no.
-MARISHA: Oh, shit.
LAURA: I got plus two
for the ring.
So, 11.
SAM: Eleven.
MATT: Okay, good, I'll
keep that in mind.
TALIESIN: That's a number.
MATT: Okay.
It is now...
TRAVIS: What does that mean?
What does it mean?
LAURA: Slowly my skin starts
to melt off my body.
MATT: Yeah, you just-- the cloud
kind of fills the area
and you start
coughing, that's it.
It hasn't gone your turn yet,
so, it is now Raishan's turn.
Legendary actions
are restored.
TALIESIN: I hate all of this.
Oh, good, I was worried
about her legendary actions.
♪
MARISHA: Are you being facetious?
TALIESIN: I don't know
what that means.
LAURA: Who's turn is
it right now?
-It's Raishan's?
-MATT: It's Raishan's turn.
Deciding what to do.
Okay.
TALIESIN: I don't know the
meaning of the word.
MATT: Um...
SAM: This is fun.
Just good, clean fun.
MATT: Percival.
SAM: Oh.
MATT: As you're running
along the wall,
and you glance in the vicinity,
you see the cloud of poison
kind of burst from the ground
and you're just
out of the range of it.
I'm sorry, it's just within
your range from where the--
TALIESIN: I'm wearing my mask.
MATT: Yeah, you have
your mask on.
TALIESIN: I don't know if it actually
helps, but there we are.
TRAVIS: You look fabulous.
MATT:So, as you're standing
kind of amongst this--
this fume, you see this
within this, this cloud,
a kind of strange burst of very,
very faint light in your area
and you feel, even
in this heated room,
a sudden surge of heat within
your kind of torso region
and then it fades.
LAURA: What does it mean?!
It's freaking me
the fuck out.
TRAVIS: She's blazing us, ya'll.
She's lighting us up.
LAURA: What if it's like--
TRAVIS: Doesn't Hunter's Mark feel
like something sometimes?
LAURA: Oh my God,
that's right.
What if she's like marking
us for death or something?
MATT: You now can faintly
hear what sounds like...
There are footsteps moving
through the tunnels,
but you're unable
in the current chaos
and the obscured vision
to see where it's happening
but there is movement happening
above you throughout the cavern.
TALIESIN: My save versus magic
would not help
with this at all.
Cabal's Ruin would
not help with this.
Okay, just check.
MATT: Okay.
That ends Raishan's turn.
That's gonna bring
us to Keyleth.
MARISHA: Okay.
Really unsure of what's going
on, so I'm just going to...
TRAVIS: Laser pointer right here.
LAURA: Laser pointer.
MARISHA: Thank you.
I'm gonna go to that egg right
here that Vax was wailing on.
-MATT: Yep.
-MARISHA: And try and finish it off.
MATT: Okay, you move up and as
you get to the edge of it,
you can see now the light
that your body's giving off.
So, the fire elemental
is glinting off of piles
of gold and platinum that are
kind of gathered around the egg.
About a third of it is
still submerged in volcanic rock
and has been placed
here for quite some time.
LAURA: Don't let me die,
I need to loot.
MATT: You can see the crack in
the exterior of the egg
and the kind of thick
purplish amniotic fluid
that is slowly dribbling
down like a--
like a slow moving molasses
or sap from the wound
left behind by Vax.
MARISHA: I'm gonna do
two slam attacks.
-MATT: Go for it.
-MARISHA: Multi attack.
Uh, wait.
Those were
both nine's.
Which is--
so 15 total.
-To hit?
-MATT: Fifteen to hit?
It does hit, yes.
MARISHA: Okay, and that is--
MATT: Only because he pre-damaged
it to that point.
You're basically attacking
through the shell of the egg.
Removed a portion of
its armor, so otherwise--
TALIESIN: You're punching a
dragon fetus right now.
MARISHA: I am totally
punching a dragon--
TALIESIN: That's like
so eggs benedict.
MARISHA: Plus six,
so that's a ten.
Fourteen,
eighteen damage.
MATT: Okay.
So, you plunge your
flaming fist into the fluid.
You hear it immediately sizzle
as your fist goes into it.
You punch something
dense on the inside.
(groaning)
LAURA: Oh, you punched
a baby dragon.
LIAM: Good.
LAURA: "Good."
-MARISHA: Okay, that's my turn.
-LAURA: In the head.
MATT: You did both of
those slam attacks?
MARISHA: Those were both--
those my attacks.
MATT: You rolled a 15 and a--
MARISHA: I rolled two nine's
and I have a plus six.
-MATT: Oh!
-MARISHA: I rolled both of 'em twice.
MATT: Oh, oh, so you
rolled 15 both times.
-MARISHA: Yes.
-MATT: Got you.
Then how much damage
did you total?
-MARISHA: Eighteen.
-MATT: Eighteen from both attacks?
-MARISHA: Yes.
-MATT: Okay, cool.
Alright, so,
with both slams,
the first fist goes in and
slams and hits something.
The second time you
reach in and slamming,
you grab it and pull out,
as you kind of yank out of
the egg just a little bit,
you see what looks
like the snout of a very
tiny Thordak essentially.
But whereas the red dragon
you saw Thordak,
that was like
partially volcanic,
crystalline with
the burning eyes,
this creature
is seemingly made
from pure primordial
fire and rock.
This is a whole
new form of dragon.
MARISHA: He made them clones.
LAURA: What if he made--
what if it's one
for every member
of the Conclave?
MARISHA: How many are there?
LAURA: There's five eggs,
but one is crushed
and that would be Raishan and
there would be nothing in it.
SAM: What?
MARISHA: Wait, are we sure
there was nothing in it?
LAURA: I don't know.
MARISHA: Do you want to go check and see
if there was something in it?
TRAVIS: Covered in rock,
we can't see.
MARISHA: Are there five--
there are five eggs?
SAM: Or he was making their
own basketball team.
MATT: There are five eggs
that you can see currently.
LIAM: And they're all red,
they're all red.
MATT: They're all red, yes.
LAURA: Okay, well,
they're all red.
Maybe they're
all Thordak's.
MARISHA: They're little clones?
TALIESIN: If they're clones, maybe it's
literally five new
breeds of dragon.
LAURA: Oh my God.
TRAVIS: Only one way
to find out.
MARISHA: Yeah, only one
way to find out.
-Let's bust open another one.
-LAURA: Is it still alive?
TALIESIN: What do you call the
little chocolate eggs?
LAURA: Is it alive?
MARISHA: Is it alive or did
I kind of kill it by--
MATT: You kind of killed it.
It's currently
limp in your grasp.
SAM: Hey, you killed a dragon.
LAURA: Good job.
MARISHA: "I did it!
I got one!"
MATT: Keyleth, the
dragon snapper.
TALIESIN: This is the like the Westworld
version of killing a dragon.
SAM: How do you want to do this?
Sunny side up.
(laughing)
TALIESIN: Benedict.
MATT: Perfect.
You still have
some movement, Keyleth,
if you want
to move still.
MARISHA: I do, don't I.
I want to start
heading towards Vax.
MATT: Towards Vax
this way, okay.
What's your movement
in fire elemental form?
-MARISHA: Fifty feet.
-MATT: Fifty feet?
You get about there, however,
unaffected by fire and--
MARISHA: And I'm, like, hovering.
MATT: You're comfortable in this.
-MARISHA: It's like a spa.
-MATT: Kinda yeah.
-It's tingly.
-MARISHA: It's like a hot spring.
MATT: It's perfect.
Alright, that
ends your turn.
Gilmore, just at a full run
gets up to the side here,
and is kind of flanking.
He enters the space,
pushes up against the wall
and just kind of
surveys the territory.
He looks spooked but
also kind of in that,
"Well, we're here"
type mentality.
Looks about the room and
goes, "Everyone all right?
Please tell me
everyone's all right."
(coughing)
(whimpering)
"Great."
That ends Gilmore's
turn as he just arrives.
Grog.
(roars)
You just come sprinting in.
TRAVIS: Can I smack Shaun's
ass as I go by?
Going, "Come on, Shaun."
-MATT: Sure.
-LIAM: Shaun breaks in half.
MATT: You aren't stealthy,
and as you run by,
Shaun sees you about
to swing and goes like,
"Fine."
Whack!
Might have
dislocated his hip.
He's like...
(strained laugh)
"I'll charge you later."
LAURA: That's gonna be a bruise
on the ass for sure.
MATT: You get about there
and you are--
Pike is technically
on your space,
kind of clutching
to your shoulders.
We'll say back here.
Little Yoda backpack.
TRAVIS: Do I get any
additional movement
or am I just here now?
MATT: You are a little
bit behind everybody.
You've just now caught up to
everybody, and that's--
Just your full double run
and you just arrived
at the edge of the map.
TRAVIS: "I'm here.
Let the piñatas begin."
SAM: "Okay, what's a piñata?"
TRAVIS: "I don't know, I thought
it was a celebration.
-Is it not?"
-MARISHA: You should ask Sam.
SAM: Hola, me llamo Sam Riegel.
MARISHA: Yeah, there you go.
TALIESIN: ¿Donde está la biblioteca?
MATT: Alright, that'll
bring us to Vex's turn.
LAURA: Oh, okay, alright.
MATT: At the top of your turn,
the poison has
filled your lungs
and while you
suffer no damage,
you are incapacitated.
You are just in
a coughing fit,
almost falling
off of your broom.
Like sliding off
to the side and just...
(coughing)
And you just
can't do anything.
-LAURA: I can't do anything?
-MATT: Nope.
LAURA: It was a whole
fucking turn?
-MATT: Yep.
-LAURA: Gone.
MARISHA: So, both the
twins have no turns.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: The poison has
completely filled you
to the point
where you're seizing.
You feel the muscles
tightening up, and--
LAURA: It's not hurting me--
MATT: It's not hurting you, but
you're unable to do anything.
TRAVIS: Sulfurous gas.
It wrecks your shit.
LIAM: Welcome to Hot Pepper Gaming.
LAURA: That's good,
because you know what?
I didn't have
anything planned
and it would have been a
cluster fuck like last time,
so fuck it.
MATT: Vax.
You currently
are just kinda like...
(gasping)
Taking a breath, your vision
kind of blurs for a moment
and you can see the double
vision trying to align.
It comes in to focus
and you see Keyleth's
fire elemental form
kind of gliding across.
You see the edge of your
sister currently shadowed
against this cloud of toxic, sulfurous gas
that is spewed up
from the ground.
You can hear her
coughing in the distance.
You see a bunch
of your allies
now beginning
to just show up
on the outside of the
room's kind of lit interior,
and it takes you
the full round
to kind of
catch your breath.
LIAM: No movement either, yeah?
MATT: Let me double
check actually.
I'm pretty sure...
Let me see here.
♪
Can't move or take actions
until next turn, so no.
Alright, so that ends
the end of Vax's turn.
Let's see, at the
end of your turn.
There is going to be...
LIAM: This is fucking--
(indistinct whispering)
SAM: Did I--did I get a turn?
No, I did mine already.
MATT: Yeah, we're gonna
get to yours.
LIAM: I'm still in the same position
15 feet up that I was.
MATT: You are, yes.
Yeah, your wings
are just like...
Grog, you see this
kind of faint glimmer
of energy around you
and you instinctually
kind of like...
(grunts)
(growls)
But no temperature change.
Nothing seems to happen.
TRAVIS: Do I smell anything?
MATT: You smell sweaty gnome on metal armor.
-LAURA: "Sorry."
-TRAVIS: "Honestly, really?
I mean, come on."
LIAM: "I'm just a little
nervous is all."
TRAVIS: "Did you eat mustard pretzels
before this, my god?"
LIAM: "Maybe."
LAURA: "You know how
they make me calm."
TRAVIS: Calm?
SAM: Double Ashley is
the best Ashley.
MATT: Kima's running, desperately
trying to catch up.
But she's not quite
in the battlefield yet.
It's Pike's go.
LIAM: Pike, Pike,
it's your turn.
LAURA: Okay, okay.
LIAM: Yeah, let's buff everybody.
LAURA: Yeah, so she's gonna cast--
what she should do mass--
MARISHA: Is there anything
that could help
with the stuff that has
been magically cast on us?
TALIESIN: We don't actually
know what's been done.
LAURA: Oh, on everybody
and it's 30 feet.
How far--
Can she move up and get--
How many people can
she get in a 30 foot cone?
MATT: A 30 foot cone?
LAURA: A 30 foot radius.
MATT: From where she is,
it's six squares.
LIAM: But she can
move forward.
MATT: She can move 25 squares
right now.
She's been
on Grog's back.
She can kind of
like leap off and--
LIAM: But she could get closer
to--to Vex, right?
LAURA: Vex and Percy and Grog?
LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: She's right here,
she can move this way
or this way or
wherever you want.
LAURA: Let's-- okay.
MARISHA: Here, guys.
TRAVIS: Here's a pointer.
MARISHA: Laser pointer.
LIAM: If she gets near Vex,
then she can get Grog,
Gilmore, Percy.
LAURA: Maybe like in that area?
-LIAM: Yeah, yeah.
-LAURA: Or like, no.
-LIAM: Closer to Percy.
-LAURA: Yeah!
MATT: This-- she'll just be on the
outskirts of getting Percy
and can get all
the rest of you guys.
LIAM: Keyleth as well?
TALIESIN: She doesn't
really need it.
LIAM: Why not?
MATT: She can just
catch Keyleth.
LAURA: Yeah, sweet,
that's great.
Then she casts Beacon
of Hope from there.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: What did that do,
oh, that was--
LAURA: That gives you advantage
on wisdom saving throws,
death saving throws,
regains max number of
hit points for healing.
MATT: Or it would, possibly.
SAM: Oh, shit.
There's interferon.
LIAM: Gilmore stabs Vax.
LAURA: I'm hitting him
with the laser.
SAM: Don't blind our DM.
TALIESIN: I can't see the die, I'm gonna
assume it was an natural 20.
MATT: I'd roll again.
There we go, that's
we're looking for.
Okay.
It's a natural 20,
so yeah.
There is a burst of
greenish blue arcane energy
that just kind of...
around Pike as she
tries to cast the spell.
The spell fizzles.
MARISHA: She got counter spelled.
LAURA: Oh!
I hate her!
TRAVIS: We're in a
no magic zone.
LAURA: No, it's just--
SAM: No magic works here.
Don't even try.
LAURA: Alright.
TRAVIS: Just ruins everything
I was gonna do.
LAURA: Great.
TALIESIN: It's okay, she burned
a counterspell.
LAURA: Great.
MATT: Scanlan, your turn.
SAM: I move as far as I can.
-MATT: You...
-SAM: Did I make it in?
MATT: Running up, you're like
just on the outskirts.
You get caught up right about
there in the center of the room.
That's as far
as you can get.
SAM: Alright.
Can I yell out?
MATT: Yes.
SAM: "Where's Raishan?"
LAURA: (coughing)
LIAM: "Ceiling."
TRAVIS: "I just got here."
LIAM: "She's in the
fucking ceiling, man."
SAM: "She's in the ceiling?"
LIAM: "Yeah."
LAURA: (coughing)
LIAM: I'm sorry: Alien.
Ceiling!
MARISHA: They're in the walls.
The goddamn walls.
MATT: It would have taken you
moving action to get there.
You have a bonus
if you want to take it.
SAM: Bonus?
Bonus, I will-- shit.
TALIESIN: You'll shit?
-SAM: Bonus.
-LIAM: True to form.
SAM: No, I'll heal
myself again.
I'll do a second level.
MATT: Healing Word?
-SAM: Healing Word.
-MATT: Go for it.
SAM: So that's 2d4 plus--
MATT: 2d4 plus six, yeah.
MARISHA: Oh, yay.
SAM: Twelve, okay.
MARISHA: That's better,
that's good.
Good job.
-SAM: Gerd jerb.
-TALIESIN: Gerd jerb.
SAM: Great, I'll take it.
Back up to something.
MATT: Perfect.
Let's see here.
That ends Scanlan's turn.
Percy, you're up.
TALIESIN: Alright, I'm gonna use Animus
and I'm gonna take
some potshots at that
egg that's on
the other side of Grog.
-MATT: Over here?
-TALIESIN: Yeah.
Is that one of the
dead one or is that the--
MATT: That was the one that
Keyleth just punched.
TALIESIN: That you just
punched through?
MARISHA: Uh-huh.
TALIESIN: Okay, in that case,
I'm gonna keep--
MATT: You see no other eggs
where you currently are.
MATT: Except the one
that's right over here.
You could technically fire at
the one that's across the way.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna actually start
walking along the wall.
This way as
far as I can go.
LIAM: Oh, he's sticking
to it, yeah.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MARISHA: That's cool.
LAURA: Hey, look, an egg.
TALIESIN: And I know, like, I'm too
close to shoot at that egg,
but I can shoot at--
MARISHA: It's like an
Easter egg hunt.
LAURA: But you're above it.
Aren't you high
on the wall?
TALIESIN: Technically, I am
far away enough from it that I shouldn't--
MATT: Do you want to go
further on here
or on this alcove here?
TALIESIN: Further like--
like this direction.
I want to
head this way.
MATT: Okay, so you're moving
across the wall.
You end at about
there at full movement.
TALIESIN: Okay, and I'm too
close to the egg
to get a clean shot
at it right now, right?
-MATT: Well, I mean--
-TALIESIN: I've got some height, so.
MATT: Yeah, you could--
TALIESIN: I'm using a
one-handed, so.
I'm gonna
fire with Animus.
I'm gonna take three pot shots at it
with Sharpshooter.
Shot number one.
Yay, that could
have been terrible.
-26.
-MATT: 26 hits.
TALIESIN: Should I just roll
all three and then do damage?
-MATT: Sure.
-TALIESIN: Okay.
26, um, 14.
MATT: Fourteen does not hit.
-TALIESIN: That's fine.
-MARISHA: Oh, man.
♪
TALIESIN: And 16.
MATT: Sixteen does not hit.
TALIESIN: Okay, I'm firing really
terribly, but that's okay.
LIAM: Hanging off a wall.
TALIESIN: Hanging off a wall,
this is new.
Let me get my dice.
That's alright.
Twenty-three points of damage
plus four psychic damage.
MATT: Okay.
Alright, so,
first shot.
It pierces through and actually
cracks part of the egg.
You can see it's almost
like a spider spiral
where the egg
interior cracks inward.
It pierces and a
little bit of dark liquid
begins to pool out of it.
That's as much as you make
as the next two shots
seem to ricochet
off of its hard shell.
TALIESIN: Alright, that's my--
Yeah, I'm just gonna
use my bonus to reload
and take some more shots.
TRAVIS: ♪ Dancing on the ceiling ♪
♪ Oh, what a feeling ♪♪
SAM: Best music video.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: It's like a piñata.
¿No sé?
MATT: Okay.
Suddenly, the entire
lair begins to shake.
-TRAVIS: Shit.
-TALIESIN: Goddammit.
MATT: Like this tremor
begins to emanate
from the ceiling
portion of this.
Pieces of rock begin to...
Fall from the ceiling.
I need...
The guys who
are flying, so,
Keyleth, Vax and Vex,
don't worry about this.
Everyone else, I need you to
make a dexterity saving throw.
SAM: Even me, I'm
barely in the room?
MATT: It's a big radius.
SAM: I got one foot out.
What is it dex--?
MATT: Dexterity.
TALIESIN: That's better.
TRAVIS: Ten.
SAM: Seventeen.
TALIESIN: Fifteen.
-MATT: Okay.
-LAURA: Five.
MATT: Five, okay.
-Pike...
-LAURA: Oh, I'm sorry.
TRAVIS: Grog both lose your footing
and plummet backward.
Gilmore rolls a
natural 20, he's fine.
-LAURA: Hey!
-MARISHA: Hey!
MATT: "Oh ho.
Great dodger,
since I was 12."
Yeah, Percy, you mange
to just barely hold on
without losing your the--
TALIESIN: Thankfully my
spider sense tingled.
-MATT: Oh!
-MARISHA: Oh!
MATT: I almost want you to
just go home for that.
TALIESIN: Now I'm gonna fall.
TRAVIS: A whole bunch
of cheese here.
MATT: Yep.
Okay.
That ends the lair action.
LAURA: Next turn with disadvantage.
(laughing)
MATT: It is now Raishan's turn.
LAURA: Oh, that was
a lair action?
-MATT: Yeah.
-LAURA: Oh, Jesus.
TRAVIS: We should just call
that Raishan's turn.
MATT: Nah.
You watch as through
the cloud of lightning
that's kind of swirling,
a small dragon-like form
just pierces through
momentarily.
It's still see-through.
You can see the rest
of the swirling storm around it,
but it's enough of that
Predator-like appearance,
where it just
shapes and shimmies,
or shimmers
through the vicinity.
It shimmies through.
As it does, you watch
this claw kind of lift up
as this low
echoing voice...
(whispering in foreign language)
LAURA: This is all of
us with the light.
All of us
with the heat.
TALIESIN: Okay, what is this?
LAURA: It's gonna do something,
I know it.
TALIESIN: We're-- we're all--
MATT: Okay, 30 foot cubes.
TALIESIN: We're all just gonna turn inside
out and that'll be the end.
TRAVIS: We'll all turn
into chickens.
TALIESIN: It's gonna be like
John Carpenter's The Thing.
TRAVIS: And then the eggs will
turn into big chickens.
LIAM: First, we'll all
mash together.
TALIESIN: And then get separated
out into equal piles.
LAURA: Oh, geez.
MATT: Yeah, 30 foot cube.
I can only get-- she can
only get Vex, Pike and Grog,
but I need the
three of you to make
a constitution
saving throw.
TRAVIS: Constitution?
MATT: Yes.
LAURA: Damn it!
TALIESIN: ♪ Constitution ♪
♪ Come on ♪♪
-LIAM: Yeah.
-LAURA: So, that's good.
I don't get
any bonus though.
Twenty-one?
TALIESIN: Nice.
LIAM: Oh, thank God.
-TRAVIS: Twenty-seven.
-MATT: Okay, and Pike?
LAURA: Oh, oh.
You roll for Pike.
LIAM: Okay.
She gets the meteor.
I hope it's good.
-It's a one.
-LAURA: Oh, no!
MATT: Well, Vex and
Pike both failed.
LAURA: Oh, that's as high as I get
without a natural 20, man!
MATT: It's a spell DC of 22, I'm sorry.
SAM: Whoa.
MATT: You and Pike both suffer 57
points of necrotic damage.
LAURA: Fucking shit!
TRAVIS: Oh, fuck.
MATT: Grog, you take
half as much.
So, it'd be 28.
Twenty-eight points
necrotic damage.
Suddenly, you feel the
very air itself go gray.
The color is taken
from your vision
and your life force
is drawn out of you
through Abi-Dalzim's
Horrid Wilting.
-SAM: Horde wilting?
-MATT: Horrid wilting.
The air is drawn
from your lungs.
You feel your skin crack and
tighten against your skeleton.
MARISHA: Adele Dazeem's--
MATT: Adele Dazeem's
Horrid Wilting.
(laughing)
TRAVIS: Amazing, yes.
Change it, don't
ever say it right.
MATT: That's what it is now going forward.
LAURA: Man!
SAM: Are you alive?
LAURA: No, I'm-- I'm unconscious,
so is Pike.
-Both of us.
-MATT: Oh, shit.
Well, Pike is
not unconscious.
(gasps)
LAURA: Pike came back.
MATT: Wait, did her armor
get used last battle?
-I don't think it did.
-LAURA: It didn't?
TRAVIS: It got used once,
where was it?
TALIESIN: Previously, in
a previous battle.
-LAURA: Against?
-TALIESIN: Fire giant.
LAURA: Oh, yeah.
TALIESIN: How do I remember this?
That's horrifying.
MATT: The fire giant of--
TALIESIN: At the battle at the--
-LIAM: In the fire fort.
-MATT: To the fort, yes.
LAURA: Oh, at Fort Daxio.
-LIAM: Yep, yep, yep.
-MATT: You are correct.
LAURA: Okay, so Pike's alive.
-MATT: With how many hit points?
MARISHA: Jesus, that was an eighth
level necromancy spell.
LAURA: No, no, no, she got
five hit points.
MATT: So, Pike is at
LAURA: And are there any eggs
within 15 feet of her?
MATT: Nope.
LAURA: Is there a Raishan
within 15 feet of her?
-MATT: Nope.
-LAURA: Well, then, fuck it.
MATT: But Vex plummets out of the
poison cloud off of her broom,
slams into the
ground and clatters,
spinning and falling
to the ground not moving.
LAURA: Thanks for knocking
over the little cube too.
I like that added.
TALIESIN: Backhanding it, no less.
-TRAVIS: Damn.
-MATT: Alrighty.
TRAVIS: Are there lasting effects
from Adele Nazeem's wilting?
Like are we halved
or anything?
-MATT: From what you know, no.
-LAURA: "From what you know."
TRAVIS: It just sucks right
now is all I know.
Everything just sucks.
SAM: Jesus!
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: So, that-- that is gonna
end Raishan's turn.
The form is still somewhat
visible, though, transparent.
It took her full movement
to even get to that point.
MARISHA: And where is she,
she still on the ceiling?
MATT: To give you a position, right now...
♪
It's right there.
SAM: Forty, fifty feet up?
MATT: Though transparent.
It's 50 feet up.
TRAVIS: Fuck.
TALIESIN: Oh, don't do that then.
LAURA: Oh, I just remembered.
TALIESIN: You left the gas on.
TRAVIS: And she's 40, 40 up?
MATT: Fifty feet up.
SAM: Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
MATT: So, Keyleth, what
are you doing?
MARISHA: Okay.
I can still see her a little bit.
SAM: This is a dragon fight, guys.
MATT: Yeah, you can barely make
out the-- the outline.
MARISHA: Okay, so since
she's in my cloud,
I'm going to kind of like,
do one of those sideways
arcing lightning strikes.
Just...
and arc everything
right towards that bitch.
MATT: Great, go for it.
MARISHA: She just takes
damage, right?
MATT: For Call Lightning, no,
you have to roll--
No, sorry, a creature has to
make a dexterity saving throw.
So, what's your DC?
-MARISHA: Twenty.
-MATT: Twenty?
LAURA: How many lightnings
are heading towards her?
MATT: Nineteen.
Total of ten plus nine.
-MARISHA: Yes!
-TRAVIS: Wow!
MATT: That's 4d10.
MARISHA: Yes, it is!
-SAM: Whoa.
-MATT: Lightning damage.
MARISHA: Yep, yep!
4d10.
-Okay, I rolled that.
-TALIESIN: You rolled well.
MARISHA: I rolled okay.
I actually rolled--
did roll real well.
You're right,
I rolled well.
Nine, nine, 18.
Plus eight,
that is 26 damage.
MATT: Nice.
You watch as the form tries to
pull itself back into the cloud,
the cloud lights up
with this crackling
reddish pink
electrical energy
that then turns to
a bright burning red
as it arcs past
and slams into her.
You watch the energy arc
across the body of
Raishan, the dragon.
(snarling)
TALIESIN: Does she have to make
a concentration save?
-MATT: She does.
-TALIESIN: To remain invisible?
MATT: Yeah, she's fine.
TRAVIS: "Yeah, she's fine."
Fifty-seven.
MARISHA: I still have
movement, right?
MATT: You do, yes.
Your full movement,
you haven't moved yet.
You just pulled it
down in that one moment.
MARISHA: I am going to head towards
the egg that got cracked open
that's in the center there.
MATT: Over there?
-MARISHA: Yeah.
-MATT: Okay.
You can go all
the way over to it.
MARISHA: Can I do a bonus action
to like, examine?
MATT: I mean, you can make a
perception check and look at it.
If you want to
rummage through it,
that'll probably
take your action.
MARISHA: Okay, I'll do just a
perception check right now.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: Twenty-three.
MATT: Okay, as
soon as you rush up
and get a glance at it,
you can see that a lot of the
dark, purplish maroon fluid
that filled most of the egg
is just coating the
outside of the egg's shell
and there are a series of
rocks and pieces of rubble
from the initial
meteor swam impact
that has just
sundered this egg.
It's about half the
height of the others,
it's just all that's been
kinda collapsed inward.
This egg is ruined.
TALIESIN: So, we have two ruined
eggs at this point.
MARISHA: And no sign of a--
SAM: And one almost ruined.
MARISHA: And no sign of
a dragon baby?
MATT: Nothing you can see.
MARISHA: Alright.
TALIESIN: Might be just deep
in there and flattened.
MARISHA: Flattened, yeah,
that's my turn.
TALIESIN: Could have just
been a bad egg.
MATT: Ending Keyleth's turn,
that brings us to Gilmore.
Gilmore watching
this happen,
watching Vex go down.
Let's see what he does here.
(indistinct muttering)
MARISHA: Oh, that's funny.
TALIESIN: Like five of
them in here.
Do something about this.
MATT: Okay, as Raishan's form
is up there he goes,
(sighs)
"Not today, not ever!"
And releases
his hand like this
and you watch as a burst
of strangely shifting
rippling arcane energy
similar to the same ripple
that is shrouding Raishan
seems to kind of scatter
up in that direction.
He's going to attempt to...
MARISHA: Come on.
MATT: With his successful
dispel magic, Raishan--
the form becomes
completely visible now.
The invisibility
has worn off.
And is now standing
completely visible.
As this happens, Raishan...
(snarls)
"I will enjoy eating
the flesh from your bones."
SAM: Oh.
Did she say "balls"?
LAURA: Yeah, definitely.
MATT: Definitely said balls. No.
MARISHA: Dragon delicacy.
MATT: Gilmore is then going to...
Gilmore goes from
excitement to "Shit."
TRAVIS: Not my balls!
MATT: He's going to-- knowing the
tactics that are being used,
he's gonna try to spread out
form the rest of the group.
Over here towards the
destroyed egg across the wall.
That's going to
end Gilmore's turn.
This brings us to Grog.
TRAVIS: Uh, can I get up, please?
-MATT: You can.
-TALIESIN: Get on up.
LAURA: Get on up!
TRAVIS: Can I see Vex
sprawled out?
MATT: You do, yes.
TRAVIS: Yeah, can I run to Vex?
MATT: Sure.
TRAVIS: (humming)
I have one really-- what's
the really big potion?
-Is it the Superior?
-LIAM: Superior.
TRAVIS: I have one of those.
Can I shove it in her gullet?
MATT: You can, it'll take
your action to do it.
LAURA: Oh.
You don't have
to Grog, it's okay.
I mean--
TRAVIS: Okay, I want you
to reroll a character.
Here we go.
I'm going to take
my axe and--
Yeah, I shove
it in her mouth.
MATT: Superior, that
is 8d4 plus 8.
TRAVIS: Oh, I got to roll it?
-MATT: Yeah.
-TRAVIS: Oh, gee-- oh man.
LAURA: Wait, 8d4.
(indistinct)
Whoa, 17.
-TRAVIS: Twenty-four.
-LIAM: Plus eight.
-TRAVIS: Thirty-two.
-LAURA: Thirty-two?
That was insane, Grog!
MATT: So with that, your eyes
come into focus, Vex,
as you feel the clatter
of glass against your teeth,
the vial being
pulled from your mouth.
You kind of
cough for a second.
Come into conscious as Grog,
in his giant form,
cradling you like a tiny baby
in his one giant mitt.
Just kind of smiles.
TALIESIN: It's like a
Terry Gilliam movie.
LAURA: "Thanks."
(snarls)
(laughing)
Go rage!
MATT: Alright, don't forget you do
have a point of exhaustion,
as you've gone-- unless
you've continued your rage
this whole time,
which you can, so never mind.
TRAVIS: Yeah, just
rolling through.
MATT: You got that now.
You're just
like a freak.
TRAVIS: I might have
chipped a tooth...
LAURA: All good.
All good, all good.
TRAVIS: Like Mentos and Coke.
MATT: You're like drink it, drink it.
Alright, great,
that ends Grog's turn.
Vex, you are conscious,
prone, but conscious.
LAURA: God, okay.
Fuck.
Can I shoot from my
laying down position?
MATT: You can, I'd say your attacks
would have disadvantage.
LAURA: Okay, then I'm gonna get
up on my knee and shoot up.
Cause I just wake up and see
her right above me, don't I?
MATT: Yep, you do.
LAURA: Alright, then
I'm gonna try to--
Oh wait, I already
used Brambleshot,
or at least,
I tried to today.
MATT: You did, yeah.
LAURA: So, I'm gonna shoot her.
MATT: Do it!
LAURA: Can I Hunter's Mark
her first, though?
MATT: You certainly can.
LAURA: Hey!
I don't get
sneak attack.
Nobody's near her, right?
MATT: That was--
that was great.
Gilmore rolled a 19 on the dispel.
LAURA: Nineteen?
MATT: Yeah, that was
really good.
LAURA: Oh, that's
what I rolled.
-MATT: Oh, did you?
-LAURA: As well.
MATT: Nice, look at that, you
and Gilmore just synchronizing.
-MATT: And 19's your total?
-LAURA: Yeah.
-MATT: Misses.
-LAURA: Fuckin' A.
That one,
I hope, 28.
MATT: Hits.
LAURA: Okay, so 28
on the second one.
Oh God, what's
happening?
MARISHA: I don't know.
LAURA: Sixteen plus three
points of lightning.
TALIESIN: I'm not gonna
play that game, man.
Not playing.
I'm not playing
this game no more.
It's not the time.
MATT: Did you include your
damage for it being a dragon?
LAURA: Yes.
MATT: Alright.
So now you can
see Raishan emerging
from one of the
volcanic caves.
The storm's
swirling around her,
as she begins to
pull back into it,
you fire two arrows.
One gets lost, the other one--
(snarling)
Into the side
of her throat.
LAURA: Can I move--
can I move...
MATT: You move three squares.
LAURA: Can I get on my broom?
MATT: You get onto
your broom, yeah.
LAURA: Like move a
one square away.
-MATT: One square?
-LAURA: Yeah.
Away from Grog
and Pike, yeah.
Like that makes
any difference, but--
-MATT: Okay, perfect.
-TALIESIN: It's a start.
LAURA: Thanks, Grog.
TRAVIS: (snarls)
MATT: Ends Vex's turn,
Vax, you're up.
LIAM: Okay, just to clarify,
so looking at the minis.
The back side's
to me, but really,
her face is poking
out of a hole, right?
MATT: Like the front half is.
LIAM: Front half of
her and she's--
and she's at the roof
which is 70 feet up,
so maybe her head is
down, like, five feet out,
ten feet out,
something like that?
MATT: Roughly, yeah.
LIAM: Alright, I want to,
and I'm--I'm back, right?
-After...
-MATT: You have now--
Yeah, you've regained
your composure.
However your other
potion has now worn off.
-You are no longer--
-LAURA: Invulnerable?
-LIAM: I want to fly--
-LAURA: Oh!
-LIAM: Go ahead.
-LAURA: My hasted had worn off, right?
I just assumed
it had, okay.
LIAM: So, if I'm 15 feet up
and she's, maybe, 65 down,
I'm within range for
sharpshooter already.
MATT: Technically, yeah.
LIAM: So, and-- and
last question.
When you do-- for
duel wielding, action--
bonus action, but you told
me once you can reverse that
and do bonus
action and action.
I think.
MATT: The bonus attack is part
of your attack action,
so it's actually
after your--
LIAM: Never mind then.
I'm gonna fly
straight at her face,
and I'm gonna shove the Dragon
Slayer sword into her mouth
and I want to try to sever her
fucking tongue out of her mouth.
-SAM: Oh!
-LAURA: Whoa!
LIAM: Terrible.
Whisper, I'm gonna do the same
thing with the bonus action.
That is 26.
MATT: Twenty-six to
hit, that hits.
♪
LIAM: Ten plus four,
psychic damage 14.
MATT: Fourteen points of damage.
Okay, so you go
for the tongue
and you get the
blade up to the mouth.
Suddenly, her looking down
and having a very,
very wide view of the entire
battlefield is very advantageous
from her perspective.
She sees you out of the
corner of her eye,
she turns to try
and snap at you,
and the jaws come down
and catch the blade.
So, it doesn't
go for the tongue,
but you use that momentum to
glide it up the actual tooth
and jam it into the gum.
You manage to slam up there
and the blood spurts
out from the wound and--
(snarls)
Rears back and so now
you're kind of flying up
by her face now.
LIAM: I should have like
10 or 15 movement left
with 60 for wings, yeah?
If I was 15 feet up and she
was a little less than 70?
MATT: Fifteen feet up, yes, but
you're also coming at an angle,
which, you lose
distance on that.
LIAM: So am I at zero?
MATT: You're pretty
much at zero, yeah.
LAURA: Ooh, like right
in front of her face.
-TRAVIS: Just stay there like Tinkerbell.
LIAM: Okay. All done.
MATT: That ends your turn.
TRAVIS: You are grounded.
MATT: At the end of your turn,
she's going to use
another legendary action.
To do a tail
attack against you.
She pulls part of
her torso out for a moment,
and her tail whips
out in your direction
to try and slam into you.
That is a 19 plus,
what is it, 32.
LIAM: Don't think that
hits actually.
So I'll use
Uncanny Dodge.
MATT: That's gonna be 24 points
of bludgeoning damage
reduced to 12,
so there you go.
Alright, that brings
us to Kima's turn.
Kima finally arrives.
-MARISHA: Kima!
-SAM: Hey!
TRAVIS: Slow poke!
MATT: "Seriously?"
That's her turn.
TRAVIS: That Holy Avenger's
real heavy.
MATT: So that brings us to Pike.
Actually, no at the
end of Kima's turn,
let's see here.
Raishan's gonna use
another legendary action
to attempt another
tail attack against you,
since you're
within range.
-That is a...
-LIAM: 10,000.
MATT: Twenty-one to hit.
-LIAM: Shit, it just hits.
-MATT: Just hits?
Okay.
Seventeen points of
bludgeoning damage.
Yeah, go and halve that.
She's used all of her legendary actions
for this round.
Okay.
TRAVIS: All legendary-- did you hear that?
MATT: Pike.
-TRAVIS: Pike's up.
-LAURA: Okay.
I think we
should do...
But okay, if she
does Flame Strike
can she focus it
on the ceiling?
Or does it have
to be on the ground?
MATT: No, it can-- I'd say--
let me pull it up
real fast here.
It roars down from the
Heavens in all locations,
so it doesn't come
out of the floor,
it comes out of the
ceiling, so yeah.
LAURA: Okay.
So, it's her
level five spell.
-LIAM: Okay, aim it at--
-LAURA: At Raishan?
At Raishan's butt,
not at Vax.
MATT: Raishan currently,
only visible,
is about maybe
10 feet or so of--
actually pulling
out the tail attack,
I'd say about 15 feet.
So if she's careful, yeah,
she could probably hit
Raishan and not hit Vax.
-LAURA: Pike is always careful.
-TRAVIS: So careful.
LAURA: She's the carefulest.
MATT: Fair enough.
LAURA: Okay.
So, wow, that's
a really big--
Sixty feet, damn.
TRAVIS: That's good shit.
LAURA: So, that's 4d6
plus 4d6 radiant.
MATT: It's gonna be close.
Yeah, roughly about
55 feet up on the ceiling.
With that 60 foot range,
she can just hit Raishan
with the column, so yeah.
-LAURA: Okay.
-MATT: So that is 8d6 damage.
LAURA: Okay, wow.
MATT: Go ahead
and roll that.
Raishan makes a save--
LAURA: I roll five and
you roll three.
MATT: So a dexterity
saving throw.
LAURA: Oh, just kidding.
MATT: Twenty-seven, I'm
pretty sure that saves.
LAURA: No, I want
to roll some.
I roll, I'll roll three.
You roll five.
♪
-LIAM: Eighteen.
-LAURA: Thirteen.
MATT: And also makes a
concentration check from your attack earlier.
LAURA: Thirty-five.
-SAM: No.
-LAURA: No.
-SAM: Thirty-one.
-LAURA: Thirty-one.
-MATT: Thirty-one?
-LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: So half
that to 15.
Fifteen points
of damage.
MARISHA: Benefit of the doubt.
MATT: Alright, cool, got it.
LAURA: Why half?
TALIESIN: She made her
saving throw.
TRAVIS: At 27.
MATT: Sorry.
So, you just barely
move out of the way
as you watch a familiar
gathering of radiant energy
up in the ceiling.
You see the glimmer
in the corner
of Raishan's
slick eyeballs
recessed within the
green armor-plated face.
of the dragon as
all of a sudden--
A great column of fire
and radiant energy
blasts Raishan in
the side of the face.
LAURA: And she's gonna back
up towards the opening
towards the
entrance a bit.
-Yeah, like right there.
-MATT: Right there?
That's as far as
she can get right there.
Cool.
SAM: Does she have
a bonus action?
LAURA: She's got a
bonus action.
-SAM: Heal herself?
-MARISHA: Is it Healing Word?
LAURA: Oh, yeah,
she can, right?
'Cause she can use
a level two or less.
So, yeah,
she'll do a level--
she doesn't have
any level two's left.
She'll do a level one
Healing Word on herself.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Oh, God, she's
at five hit points.
-SAM: Yeah, I know.
-TALIESIN: Not anymore.
LAURA: She's--she's
Pike though.
This is what
she would have done.
-TALIESIN: She's now at--
-LAURA: I think.
TALIESIN: What does the
level one Healing Word do?
SAM: It's 1d4 plus five
or something like that.
MARISHA: It does an
additional d4.
LAURA: Oh.
MARISHA: Right?
No, sorry,
just one d4.
LAURA: One d4 plus five,
so yeah, seven.
TALIESIN: So, she's at
12 hit points now.
-SAM: Double dig!
-LAURA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: That's better.
-MARISHA: Double dig!
-TALIESIN: That's--
SAM: What's that look, Matt?
TRAVIS: Seven points of
healing, so yeah.
MATT: Cool, does that
end your turn?
-TRAVIS: Yep.
-LIAM: Yep.
MATT: Good, Scanlan, you're up.
SAM: Okay.
I don't know, man,
this looks rough in here.
I don't want
to be in here.
(laughing)
I'll move forward
and to the left a bit.
MATT: That's about as
far as you can go.
SAM: Sorry, to my right.
To the right,
four to the right.
Oh, man.
It's a rough fight.
But we're winning,
right, now, guys?
We're winning, we don't
need any help, do we?
LAURA: (gasps)
LIAM: Did you forget?
LAURA: I totally forgot!
MARISHA: How could you forget?
It's like all
I've thought about.
TRAVIS: I will cuddle you,
I will cuddle.
LAURA: I even wrote--
TALIESIN: He's not gonna do it
until Ashley's dead.
LAURA: I wrote a limerick.
MARISHA: Ashley is almost--
-SAM: You wrote a limerick?
-LAURA: For you.
SAM: For me? To do what?
LAURA: Wait, wait,
I forgot I did it.
"Have you heard tale
of Scanlan, the bold?
He won't tell us his age,
but he's old.
With his blade,
he's a slayer,
with the ladies,
a player,
but if he picks up the
flute, he's pure gold."
MARISHA: Hey!
(applause, laughing)
SAM: Alright, so I'm gonna
do Lightning Bolt.
LAURA: Goddammit!
(laughter)
SAM: I will-- I assume that
Scanlan feels strange
with a brass flute
touching his lips,
because he's never
played one before.
MATT: This is true.
SAM: But does it still come out just
as beautiful and pure as always?
MATT: Roll a performance check.
SAM: Okay.
LAURA: I'm so nervous,
I'm about to cry.
-SAM: Thirty.
-MARISHA: Oh!
MATT: In the midst of this chaos,
the rumbling of the room,
the sound of the lightning
and thunder in the clouds,
the falling of rock and
soot from the ceiling
is drowned out by
what sounds like
the most beautiful
clear flute.
It just trills...
(whistling)
SAM: ♪ Call the dragon ♪
(all humming)
♪ Call the dragon ♪♪
MATT: You finish the song
as you watch the brass glow.
It begins to
kinda give this--
this weird shine around
it that begins to emanate
this kind of
additional warmth
and light from it
and then it dulls
and the brass
goes to a very tarnished
dark metal material.
TALIESIN: It's Amazon Prime.
It's gonna take three days
but it's gonna be here.
SAM: I've played better.
MATT: You watch the flute ping
in the hallway behind him.
-So that's your action.
-SAM: Okay.
As a bonus, I will--
Boy, everyone's
dying, right?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
SAM: Pike's near me, so I'll turn
and give her a
level two Healing Word.
-MATT: Okay.
-SAM: As well.
And I will sing to her:
♪ I've got Mythcarver
in my pocket ♪
♪ Got that sunshine
on my feet ♪
♪ When I dance and
prance around you ♪
♪ You just stop ♪
♪ Hoo! ♪
MARISHA: ♪ Hoo! ♪
SAM: ♪ And I dance
so very handsome ♪
♪ And I sing phenomenally ♪
♪ There's just something
bout that gnome ♪
♪ That makes me smile ♪
♪ Woo! ♪
MARISHA: ♪ Woo! ♪♪
MATT: Alrighty.
MATT: Pike takes her inspiration die.
SAM: Uh, no, not inspiration,
healing, healing.
So, wait, I got
to roll or she rolls?
MATT: You roll for her.
SAM: Okay, ooh.
Oh, boy.
(groaning)
(laughter)
-SAM: Eight.
-MATT: She heals eight points.
SAM: She's up to 20!
-TALIESIN: She can almost drink.
-MARISHA: She can drink next year.
MATT: Alrighty, ending Scanlan's turn,
brings us to the top.
Percival, your turn.
TALIESIN: Okay, I'm going to...
Yeah, this is fine.
SAM: ♪ Can't stop ♪♪
TALIESIN: I'm going to--
this is fine.
I'm going to take
some shots with Animus
at that awful bastard at the
top of the cave.
First shot, and I'm not making
it a sharpshooter shot,
I'm just shooting.
That's good too.
Oh, that's not bad, 24.
MATT: 24 hits.
TALIESIN: Alright.
LAURA: Look at all those pots
of gold in the corners.
TALIESIN: That's 13 points plus five
points of psychic damage.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: And another shot.
TRAVIS: Shot.
TALIESIN: And that's, uh, that's--
Oh, that's not bad.
That's two points of
psychic damage to me.
MATT: Oh, buddy!
-SAM: He's already unhinged.
-TALIESIN: So that's 54.
So, that was like
thankfully, just an ow!
I'm just putting it away.
I'm just gonna
try and pull--
pull out the big gun and take
one last shot while I'm--
while I'm--
well, actually, no,
that knocks out my
attacks, doesn't it?
Cause it's a
psychic damage.
MATT: Well, I was gonna say,
the psychic damage doesn't
negate your attacks.
TALIESIN: I don't have time
to switch guns.
No, cause the psychic damage
knocks that out if I recall.
MATT: No, psychic damage
doesn't affect the way--
TALIESIN: So, do I have
time to just try
and get one more
potshot out or am I--
MATT: Was Bad News prepared?
TALIESIN: It was fine, it
was working fine.
-MATT: It was fine.
-TALIESIN: Yeah.
Nothing's broke,
well, now...
MATT: Now it is, yeah.
TALIESIN: Now that's broken, okay.
So, and now Bad News,
here we go.
LIAM: Come on, Golden Snitch!
Do it!
TALIESIN: Natural 20!
-LAURA: Yes!
-TRAVIS: On cue!
(cheering)
TALIESIN: Thank you, baby.
Okay.
MATT: So, that'll hit.
TALIESIN: Yeah, let's--
let's take--
Let's take--
SAM: Weird critical
things here?
TALIESIN: I don't do any
weird critical thing
other than doing
a lot of damage.
MATT: Correct.
TALIESIN: Although, where's my--
I do have, okay, so--
That does a
lot of damage.
(talking over each other)
-MARISHA: Amazing.
-TALIESIN: Double dice.
TRAVIS: Come on,
you deranged--
LIAM: Find one thing
and do it well.
TALIESIN: Not bad, okay, that's--
31 points of damage.
-MATT: Alright.
-TALIESIN: That'll do.
MATT: Very nice.
TALIESIN: Yeah, it's 4d12,
plus six, so.
And now I'm gonna hide
behind that dragon egg.
MATT: Alright, so you move behind
the dragon egg right there.
TALIESIN: Yep.
Oh, and that means I get
a grit point back ah-ha!
I can actually do
a thing, that's good.
Okay, alrighty.
SAM: So, things are turning around
ever since that limerick.
LIAM: Watch this, I'm gonna
get turned
into pulled pork right now.
MATT: Well, it's the
lair actions now.
So in this one...
TALIESIN: The Earth itself
turns against us.
(rumbles)
MATT: From beneath
your feet, Grog,
you feel and you look down
just as the rock splits
and a spray of--
a tiny geyser of molten rock
just sprays outward.
You try and move out
of the way in time,
but sprays across you,
Pike, Scanlan and Vex.
So I need you guys all to make
dexterity saving throws.
LAURA: You want to
make it for me?
SAM: Natural 20, 25.
MATT: Whoo! That'll do.
TALIESIN: There's nothing
natural about 25.
Purely artificial, you've
had work done on that 20.
-SAM: This is LA.
-TALIESIN: This is LA.
MARISHA: Lot of LA things
right back to back.
-It's overwhelming.
-TALIESIN: Man.
TRAVIS: 21.
-MATT: 21? Succeeds.
-LAURA: Twenty.
MATT: Succeeds, Pike?
LIAM: Eleven for Pike.
MATT: Pike does
not succeed.
SAM: 20, 25.
MATT: Succeed, alright, so, you
guys who all succeeded,
you take 12 points
of fire damage.
Half of you
are resistant.
-SAM: So six.
-MATT: Just six.
Pike takes 12 points
of fire damage
because she's resistant even
though she failed her save.
-LAURA: Okay.
-MARISHA: Oh, that's good.
That's good.
LAURA: So she's still up.
-SAM: She's still alive!
-TALIESIN: She's still alive.
SAM: Because of me, let's just
go on record and say that.
TALIESIN: I'll go with that.
LIAM: Can you say
it in Spanish?
SAM: No, I cannot.
-TALIESIN: Pike.
-SAM: Yo no soy Marinado.
Alright, that brings us
back to Raishan's turn.
LAURA: Oh God, oh God.
MATT: Gets her legendary
actions back.
TRAVIS: It's cool,
you can just go.
MATT: Given the current
circumstance...
TALIESIN: No.
No.
MATT: Raishan is going
to unleash...
TRAVIS: Handshake?
MATT: She's going to unleash a full
round of attacks against you
as you are right up in her face
and stabbed her in the gums
and avoided the entirety
of her meteor swarm
and you also
attacked her.
TALIESIN: In defense, she had
some corn stuck in her--
LAURA: Yeah, he really
was helping.
It'd been there for like--
MATT: And she appreciates that,
but the rest of the
stuff is still a problem.
TALIESIN: I'm trying not
to say anything.
MATT: That is 22 to
hit with a bite.
LIAM: That just hits,
Uncanny Dodge.
SAM: Maybe you should remind
her that we have a deal.
We're supposed to
be working together.
MATT: 22, well,
yeah, so they all hit.
SAM: What happened to
our deal, Raishan?
LIAM: The first one is Uncanny
and then the rest are--
MATT: Correct, so the
bite attack is halved.
Which is good.
That'll be 22 points
of piercing damage
and you got the warm
tingle earlier, right?
You also suffer
ten points
of poison damage.
SAM: Ten points of poison?
LAURA: Even though he's
immune to poison?
MATT: He's not immune to poison.
-LAURA: He's not?
-MATT: No.
LIAM: Not from that-- so that
our Hero's Feast does nothing.
LAURA: It was Dispel, she dispelled
our Heroes' Feast.
That's what that
fucking shit was.
-TRAVIS: Oh!
-LIAM: Is that the total--
MATT: That was the bite attack.
So that whole
attack is halved.
The poison damage and the
piercing you took is halved.
The claw attack...
SAM: There was a shimmering and
you didn't feel anything.
MATT: 26 points of piercing damage.
LIAM: Vax is falling.
(gasps)
SAM: Oh, no.
MATT: And the tail bats
you on the way down.
You guys watch as the
darkened wings of Vax go limp
and he just plummets.
MARISHA: Oh, boy.
SAM: That's gonna be--
MATT: Roll a d20.
LAURA: Oh, God.
LIAM: Is this a death save?
MATT: No, this is a trajectory.
MARISHA: Oh my God, please
don't land in the lava.
MATT: You smack right
into the edge,
but not into
the magma river.
You hear the cracking sound
of bones breaking upon impact
and the wings
themselves broken.
Feathers falling and burning
within the molten rock.
The wings slowly
fold in and curl
like a spider
dying and vanish.
LIAM: That sucks.
SAM: Forever?
LAURA: No, not forever!
TALIESIN: He just went unconscious.
MATT: And with that...
TALIESIN: Something's gotta
be done about that.
TRAVIS: You are Anakin
on the riverbed.
MARISHA: Totally.
TALIESIN: Magma is practically like your
arch nemesis to be fair.
LIAM: I don't-- I don't know.
MATT: Raishan is going to move.
(pieces crash)
(shouts)
MATT: Kima, no!
-MARISHA: Poor Kima!
-SAM: Bye.
I just got here!
(indistinct talking)
MATT: Alrighty.
And as she emerges now, after
knocking you out of the air,
wings fully out, Raishan...
(snarling)
"You're next."
And then swoops over
and is now floating
over the lava pool
over that way.
And appears to be
preparing for something.
LIAM: Have I got any automatic
fails in a death save?
MATT: Yes, you did fail a death saving
throw from hitting the ground.
-LIAM: Hitting the ground?
-MATT: Yes.
SAM: As she does that, I yell out,
"Could you be more specific?
Who is next, who?
Oh, we didn't see who you
were looking at over here.
No?
Alright, guess
we'll find out."
TRAVIS: I was so preoccupied,
I missed it.
MATT: That ends Raishan's turn.
Keyleth, you're up.
MARISHA: Okay, so Keyleth,
pretty pissed off
from seeing her boyfriend
spiked from the sky.
I'm going to
kinda get a few,
well, no, I guess
I can stay here.
Kind of above the lava
create a swirling
angry lava vortex
of lightning and fire
and I'm gonna hit her
again with lightning.
MATT: Okay.
Make her save.
Save 12 plus nine that
is 21, which does save.
MARISHA: Yeah, she saved.
MATT: So takes half damage,
so 14 then halved.
MARISHA: Okay, not too bad.
Twelve, 14 plus
seven, 21 total.
Half damage.
MATT: Okay, so ten points
of lightning damage.
MARISHA: Not great.
MATT: Okay, did you want to move or
you gonna stay where you are?
MARISHA: Um...
TALIESIN: You can't heal as a
bonus action, can you?
MARISHA: No, I can't do anything.
Does-- does Vax look like he's
about to fall in the lava?
MATT: Vax is approximately
one foot
from the edge
of the river.
SAM: One third my size.
TRAVIS: Is it flat or is it...
MATT: It's slightly domed in.
MARISHA: Do you have flame
resistance right now?
Yeah, you said
you're flame resistant.
TALIESIN: On the armor.
MARISHA: Okay, so I'm gonna
use my movement then.
I'm gonna be very careful
to make sure I touch the armor,
the Raven Queen armor
and I'm going to see if
I can just fire elemental
like roll him away
from the edge a little bit.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: The armor is set
to flame resistance.
MATT: Yes, it is.
TRAVIS: I thought you were
saying you were gonna like
roll him in the lava.
MARISHA: It's been nice.
(talking over each other)
MATT: I will say-- I will say the
touch of a fire elemental
ignites whatever
it touches.
It's kind of the
essence of the element.
MARISHA: But he has
fire resistance.
MATT: Right, which means
he'll take half damage
from any fire
that you deal.
However, being the fact
that you are in
control of your form
you're not
trying to hurt something,
I would say that you could
carefully push him aside
and I'll allow you
a death saving throw
as opposed to just
taking straight damage.
LIAM: Okay.
MATT: I'm making a--
LIAM: I'm rolling an advantage.
MATT: An advantage because
of your armor, yeah.
LIAM: Twelve, succeed.
So, we're good,
we're good.
MARISHA: We're cool,
SAM: Here, let me help you.
Oh God, I killed him.
LIAM: I feel like in another dimension
this didn't go so well.
MATT: So you kind of
roll him over...
MARISHA: That would be the
most Keyleth thing to do.
I love you so-- oh God,
I killed the thing I love.
SAM: Oh my God, George, I hugged
the puppy really hard.
LIAM: No, no, no!
MARISHA: I'm sorry, George.
MATT: You barely move him,
you only get him five feet
from being so careful.
You could have moved him
further, but he would have--
been ignited in the process.
TRAVIS: Oh my God.
TALIESIN: I got that
extension so bad.
MATT: Does that end your turn?
MARISHA: I'm gonna then take a few
steps back away from him now.
MATT: Okay, back this way,
back where you were?
MARISHA: Yeah, yes.
TRAVIS: You would have turned
into a vestige.
TALIESIN: I don't got to
pretend I'm (indistinct).
MATT: Okay, that ends your turn?
-MARISHA: Yeah.
-MATT: Okay.
At the end of your turn.
Raishan is still overhead
and casts a spell.
-LIAM: Duvet, Duvall?
-TRAVIS: Duvet.
MATT: Alrighty.
You watch as Raishan
over on the edge...
her front claws
begin to form
this strange
geometric sigil
in the middle of the air
and each corner of it
is a different color.
Green, orange, yellow,
red, purple, blue.
And suddenly
this giant burst--
SAM: Can I try to
counterspell her?
MATT: What's the
range on that?
SAM: 60 feet,
am I just there?
MARISHA: Come on, Scanlan.
LAURA: Oh God, Scanlan.
TRAVIS: What is she casting?
MATT: She's within range!
-LAURA: Oh, God!
-TALIESIN: Please, please!
Please kill it!
MATT: d20 add six.
SAM: Eighteen.
MATT: You rolled an 18?
SAM: No, I rolled a 12.
MATT: You rolled a 12,
that's an 18 total?
It is a...
Hold on a second.
TALIESIN: God, I can't breathe.
MATT: I'm pretty sure...
SAM: I get a plus two for--
MATT: Right, oh, I know.
The sigil-- as the
burst of colored light
begins to spray forward,
you watch as it just...
(cheering)
LAURA: Scanlan! MVP!
LIAM: Vax wakes up for
two seconds, says,
"You da man!" and
then lies back down.
(laughter)
MATT: Shit.
I never get to
use Prismatic Spray.
TRAVIS: That was a day
ruiner, right?
Day ruiner.
(talking over each other)
There's no chance that was
like a healing spray, was it?
LIAM: Probably not.
TRAVIS: Like the gesture
of surrender?
LIAM: It was kind of
like rainbows.
TALIESIN: It's the angriest Captain
Planet-- it's just the worst--
MARISHA: Like the most fucked
up Care Bear stare.
MATT: Alright, so, as the
spell dissipates...
Raishan angrily...
SAM: ♪ You got eggs and
you gonna lose 'em ♪
♪ You got eggs ♪♪
LAURA: Oh God.
MATT: Alright, so that ends--
that ends Keyleth's turn.
That brings us to Gilmore.
Now, Gilmore over here is--
what else does he have
left in the tank here?
He's gonna do a level
four Lightning Bolt.
TALIESIN: Chromatic spray.
SAM: Chromatic spray could have
been many things though.
TALIESIN: Yes, but they're all bad.
-It's a wheel of death.
-SAM: And they're all bad.
One of them's
like 70 points of...
-MARISHA: Yeah.
-TALIESIN: Of just-- just goop.
MARISHA: Each color
is like bad.
MATT: Gilmore is going to...
TALIESIN: It's a great way of dealing
with people who are--
who are attuned
to deal with you.
(indistinct talking)
TALIESIN: You were looking
at that for a while.
SAM: Yeah, I was, it was good.
-It looks good.
-TALIESIN: It's really good.
-It's very you too.
-SAM: Rainbow colored.
MATT: Sorry.
LAURA: Check out those
Gilmore t-shirts.
MATT: I know, sorry, I'm
checking to make sure
he can do this cause this
is what he's trying to do.
LIAM: Gilmore's wearing
one right now.
SAM: Hey, Laura, are those
key chains laser etched?
LAURA: Why, they are!
It's so funny
you should ask.
SAM: Wow, what about the--
LAURA: So precise.
SAM: Did I say the key chain
or the necklace?
What about the necklace?
MATT: So, Gilmore--
Gilmore runs up.
And just vanishes
from his place
and instantly blinks
up over into this area
using his misty step
as his bonus action.
And looks upward.
"How do you like it?"
Raises his hand
and pulls this way.
You watch as this
necromantic energy
begins to gather
around his hands.
A familiar spell
to you, Keyleth.
As you watch the
diseased blackened veins
up the side of Raishan's
body begin to spread
and grow momentarily
and kind of begin to--
to dig their way
into her throat.
She begins
to pull backward,
unfamiliar with this
sudden internal pain.
Rolls a natural
20 for her save.
But regardless,
that's still--
LAURA: I like how he genuinely
looked kind of disappointed
though that
he rolled a 20.
TRAVIS: I think he's just--
LAURA: It made me--
it made me feel great.
LIAM: He's a really good actor.
SAM: See, we're not even
gonna need the flute guy.
LAURA: I hope he shows up.
I hope he's not like...
TALIESIN: No, a month from
now he's gonna show up.
TRAVIS: Attacking like
his carry-on?
SAM: He's at TSA right now.
"I have nothing
else metal on me.
I don't-- oh, I'm bronze."
MATT: Seventeen points of necrotic
damage to Raishan with the save.
That's Gilmore's
turn there.
That brings us to...
Grog.
-TRAVIS: Me?
-MATT: Yes.
TALIESIN: Your dragon-based humor
is way too tight right now.
TRAVIS: Can I run
over with Shaun?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Can I attach the Chain
of Returning to the axe?
MATT: Yes.
TRAVIS: Then, can I swing
it really hard and go,
"Yeah, catchphrase!"
and throw it up.
(laughter)
MATT: Yes, you can.
TRAVIS: Good, reckless, please.
MATT: Yes, you may.
-SAM: Laura.
-TRAVIS: That's a natural 20.
-MARISHA: Whoo!
-MATT: Oh, shit!
Alright.
TRAVIS: Oh, and with the
brutal critical,
I get two additional...
MATT: Yeah, two additional
d12's to that,
so roll the die first.
Plus don't forget you
double the necrotic die.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I do double it?
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: Yes!
TRAVIS: That's a six,
so that's 12.
I'm enlarged. Where's the triangle,
who took the triangle?
LAURA: I don't-- here you go.
TALIESIN: You got like
valley girl on that.
"Who took the triangle?"
TRAVIS: That's 29 and then
two additional d12.
MATT: Correct.
TRAVIS: Nine, 38.
Ten, 48.
MATT: 48?
Okay.
LAURA: Did you double
those extras?
Do you double
those dice as well?
-TRAVIS: No.
-LAURA: Okay.
TRAVIS: Brutal critical, you get
two additional damage
die on my roll.
MATT: Okay, so, as you rush up,
"Catchphrase!"
and throw the
axe sideways.
It arcs upward and
Raishan is currently
kind of reeling
from the dispel
and angrily yelling
into the room in draconic.
Gets partway into a phrase,
just finishing...
(roaring)
The axe just jams into the
side of her collarbone
and front torso area and...
The axe is still kind of wedged
there, are you gonna pull back?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'll
pull it back.
MATT: So go ahead
and roll your...
TALIESIN: I don't know why you're
looking over here for that.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I got it. 23.
MATT: So, yanking the axe, dislodges
itself and you catch it.
You see it's covered
in Raishan blood.
As you pull the axe back, you
watch as something just, like,
a flash of arcane
energy around her,
and some sort of spell,
uncast by her,
just seemingly
automatically just
kind of surrounds her
and her flying
begins to speed up.
LAURA: She got hasted?
-MARISHA: But how?
-LAURA: How?
TRAVIS: I didn't know
I was this powerful.
What the fuck happened?
LAURA: How did she get hasted?
LIAM: Well, we'll find out.
LAURA: What if the brass
dragon's helping her?
TALIESIN: Or what if the eggs
are helping her?
MATT: Yeah, you have
maybe 15 more feet.
TALIESIN: I don't know, I just like
putting things out there.
TRAVIS: Rolling towards that end
of the map as far as I go.
MATT: This end, sure.
LAURA: That end of the map.
TRAVIS: Can I go that way?
Yeah, that's cool.
-Cool.
-MATT: Great.
LAURA: Oh God.
MATT: That puts you at
the end of your turn.
She's gonna use
legendary action.
At this point in her kind of,
sped up form, she begins to...
(chanting)
And there's a slight
ripple again in the air
similar to what Gilmore
did towards Raishan
early part of the battle.
Let me see the...
TALIESIN: We're making some bad groupings
there, by the way, people.
MATT: Yeah.
You feel a kind
of a strange warmth
and tingling sensation
within your body, Scanlan.
SAM: Oh, what, me?
But I didn't
do anything.
TALIESIN: You relieve
yourself gently.
LAURA: Did you just pee?
TALIESIN: I cast Tinkle.
SAM: I don't get to save or
anything, it just happens?
MATT: It's not a save, it's
against an effect on you
and she rolls to--
just like how you roll
to overcome her
spell's counter spell,
she gets to roll
to overcome
whatever effect is on
you with dispel magic.
SAM: Okay.
MATT: So, that's gonna be the last
of her legendary actions.
LAURA: She just dispelled all of us.
Can we bust out
a feast right now?
-Just like sit down.
-TALIESIN: We can make eggs benedict.
We have the makings
for eggs benedict.
SAM: Does that dispel my fire
resistance as well?
MATT: No, it only affected
the Heroes' Feast.
SAM: Okay.
You'll have to
explain that sometime.
MATT: Vex, you're up.
LAURA: So, giving a potion to
somebody is a full action?
MATT: Yes.
Cause you have to basically
get there, open it,
grab them and help
them swallow it
to have the
effect take place.
It's a pretty
involved action.
SAM: That means we don't have
advantage on death saves either.
Right, wait.
-LAURA: Did we ever?
-SAM: Yeah, we did.
LAURA: Oh, that's from
Beacon of Hope.
That's gone anyway.
SAM: Is that gone, okay?
TALIESIN: Yeah, that got eaten.
LAURA: Okay, then I'm gonna
fly down to my brother.
And I'm gonna
cast Cure Wounds
on him at fourth level,
so that's 4d8.
SAM: 4d8?
♪
LAURA: Oh, 19 plus
eight, wow, 27.
-SAM: Wow.
-LIAM: Thank you.
LAURA: You don't got
no wings anymore.
-LIAM: She dead?
-LAURA: No.
LIAM: Oh, shit.
LAURA: Get away
from the lava.
And then, I'm gonna
fly away from the lava.
-Up.
-MATT: This way?
-TRAVIS: Towards Matt.
-LAURA: Yeah, towards Matt.
Up and towards Matt.
-MATT: Up and towards me.
-LAURA: Kind of away from Pike.
Actually,
let's go, oh God.
MATT: This way?
LAURA: Yes, yes, what
you just did.
That way.
MATT: That's about as far
as you can go right there.
Okay.
LAURA: And I get a bonus.
I can do something
with a bonus.
I'm gonna
re-Hunter's Mark her.
-MATT: Yeah, cause you--
-LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: Alright, so
Hunter's Mark reapplied.
LAURA: Oh, wait!
I can take a potion
for myself as a bonus.
-MATT: Yes.
-LAURA: I'm gonna do that.
MATT: Alright, go for it.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
-Get it.
-LAURA: Okay.
MATT: Just a regular potion?
-LAURA: Just a Superior.
-MATT: Oh, right.
LAURA: That my brother gave me.
MATT: That is an
8d4 plus eight.
LAURA: It's a four.
TRAVIS: Easter egg.
LAURA: Seventeen plus eight.
TRAVIS: You have one
more dice to roll.
-LAURA: I do?
-TRAVIS: Yep.
LAURA: Ooh.
So, 21 plus
eight, so 29.
MATT: Nice.
SAM: You healed
yourself that much?
Jesus, that's
a big potion.
LAURA: Yeah that was,
I rolled really well.
TALIESIN: I may make one
for the table.
LAURA: I didn't trust that
I would roll that well.
MATT: That ends your turn, Vex?
-LAURA: Yes.
-MATT: Vax, you're up.
LIAM: Okay, so half my movement just
to get to standing, right?
MATT: Correct.
LIAM: Okay, I'm gonna throw
Whisper, Flame tongue.
Raishan should be
within 60 feet, yeah?
-MATT: Uh, yeah.
-LIAM: Okay.
-Seventeen for the first.
-MATT: Fails.
-LIAM: Second is 22.
-MATT: Twenty-two just hits.
TRAVIS: That's it, that's
Raishan at 22.
-LIAM: Ten.
-TALIESIN: 22?
-MARISHA: She's 22.
-MATT: How much damage?
-LIAM: Ten.
-MATT: Ten points damage.
LIAM: And I'm going to use my
remaining 15 of movement
to go diagonally
away from Raishan.
MATT: Diagonally away this way?
LIAM: Away from-- diagonal.
-MATT: Here?
-LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: Okay, that's as far
as you can get there.
Okay.
That ends your turn.
That brings us to Kima.
Let's see.
Kima rushes in with
Holy Avenger,
and looks over at the distant
dragon and goes, "Oh, shit.
Who's hurting?"
LAURA: Everyone.
SAM: I'm fine.
LAURA (as PIKE): "I am, I don't want
to say anything though,
but I kind of am.
I feel kind of shitty.
I--I feel like shit."
-LIAM: "Um..."
-LAURA: "Um..."
SAM: "I'm kind of bleeding
from my ears, but, whatever."
MATT: Kima as an action
is gonna cast a...
LAURA: "I can deal with it.
It's no big deal."
MATT: I'm gonna say third
level Cure Wounds.
LIAM: Matt, my wings
are toast, right?
MATT: Yeah.
That's 17 points
of healing to Pike.
LAURA: Okay, thank you.
MATT: I think Kima's just
gonna go at a full run.
(indistinct talking)
Right, that ends Kima's turn.
There is a
flash of light
in the tunnel
behind you guys.
As a sudden burst
of kind of...
a whitish orangish energy
that briefly halos Kima,
Scanlan, and Pike's forms.
As you watch,
a brass talon...
(cheering)
A brass talon, that since it was
used as the top of our tree,
I forgot to bring its base,
but he'll be acting there.
TALIESIN: It was a beautiful tree.
-LAURA: Hey, look, he's standing!
-MARISHA: He's standing.
TALIESIN: You've been drinking,
brass dragon.
LAURA: Oh, J'Mon,
you looking good.
-LIAM: J'Mon!
-LAURA: J'Mon!
TALIESIN: Have you been
working out?
You look like you've
been working out.
MATT: He watches as they arrive
and kind of bully
their way past the entrance.
"I was wondering
when you'd call."
SAM: Glad you came!
TRAVIS: Nothing cool,
nothing cool with that!
TALIESIN: Swipe right, swipe right!
TRAVIS: Sure is glad
you're here!
SAM: We're happy
to see you?
TRAVIS: No court speak here.
SAM: How-- how
was the flight?
MATT: Actually,
I broke my platforms,
so I'll just have to use my
imagination for some of this.
SAM: We need modeling
clay, quick!
TALIESIN: Fishing wire, we can just string
it from the top of the set.
MARISHA: Yeah, yeah, just
attach it to a string.
MATT: There we go.
J'Mon, they kind of stomp
their way into the room,
stepping over
you, Scanlan.
Stepping
past you, Vax.
Nestles in, kind of
surveys the territory.
"A different color
than I was expecting."
And releases a blast
of fire breath
upwards in
the direction--
TRAVIS: Smoke 'em if
you got 'em.
C'mon, J'Mon.
LAURA: ♪ J'Mon ♪
TALIESIN: ♪ J'Mon ♪♪
MATT: That is a 23.
Okay, makes
the dex save,
so Raishan pulls
out of the way
with a benefit from
the haste spell.
However it does still
take damage.
Half damage
from the spell.
That's 16d6 damage.
-LAURA: Wow.
-TRAVIS: 16d6.
Well, that might actually help.
LIAM: Nobody expects
the Marquette inquisition.
MATT: That is 58
points fire damage,
half of that to 20...
29, whoo, pardon me.
LAURA: Did you just burp
or did you just--
MATT: I did.
MATT: Twenty nine points of
fire damage to Raishan
from Devo'ssa's
Flame breath.
J'Mon Sa Ord, as you know.
TRAVIS: Wow.
MATT: She makes a concentration check.
Succeeds.
TRAVIS: Damn it.
MATT: So, the haste
remains viable.
Okay, that ends
J'Mon's turn.
Pike is up.
LAURA: Okay.
Pike...
MARISHA: Go on, girl!
LAURA: She's gonna cast
Mass Healing Word.
Can she get the most people
in her radius?
MATT: What's the range on it?
LAURA: It is a 60 foot radius.
SAM: Radius?
MATT: Yep, that's the biggest
radius, it'd be right there.
In the center,
just under
J'Mon's giant
brass dragon wing.
LAURA: Okay.
SAM: It's not gonna heal
Raishan, is it?
-LAURA: No.
-MATT: No.
LAURA: Heals only
people she wants.
It's up to
six creatures.
MATT: Up to six creatures,
who do you choose?
LAURA: Who all's--
TALIESIN: Raise your hand if you would--
you would like to be--
LAURA: So, that's--
-LIAM: Grog is within range.
-LAURA: Grog and her.
So, that's Grog,
Pike, Vex, Vax, and Percy.
SAM: Well, hey, if
you can do six.
LAURA: And Scanlan.
"Oh, sorry, Scanlan,
I didn't see you there."
SAM: "Well, I'm behind a
dragon, honey, it's okay."
LAURA: Oh, he's gonna
dispel this shit.
TALIESIN: I don't think she can.
LAURA: Okay, she's gonna do this.
SAM: Wait, can she do it
on herself as well?
-LAURA: Yeah.
-SAM: Okay.
LAURA: Nine.
-SAM: Nine-- nine points?
-LAURA: Yeah.
That's a bonus,
I know, I know, okay.
TALIESIN: Nine is good.
LAURA: There's not really
anything else right now.
TALIESIN: Technically, it's
9 times 6,
so you did a
lot of healing.
LAURA: All of her major
spells were used.
-LIAM: Still in the game.
-TALIESIN: Nine times six is a lot.
TRAVIS: Nine points, okay.
TALIESIN: That brings me up
into the 60's.
SAM: Decadent.
MARISHA: Just a-- a nice
southern California day.
TALIESIN: Fifties.
LAURA: And then, can she-- does
she have any movement left?
MATT: No, that was her full
movement to get there.
(indistinct talking)
LAURA: That's true.
She's gonna duck as much
as she can under J'Mon.
-MATT: Okay.
-LAURA: For protection.
And say, "Oh, you look
very nice, thank you."
(laughing)
MATT: There you go.
LAURA: "Thank you for
helping us."
SAM: At this point,
I feel like you guys
are better at
Ashley than she is.
LAURA: No, shut up.
MATT: Alrighty.
TALIESIN: Cast of thousands it
takes to play Ashley.
MATT: Ending Pike's turn,
Scanlan, you're up.
SAM: Oh, oh, shit, I should have
been thinking about what I--
MATT: Yes, you should have.
SAM: Okay.
I will-- I will--
I will shoot some stuff
at Raishan of it all.
MATT: Do it, what are you doing?
SAM: I'm gonna shoot
Lightning Bolt at Raishan.
From my dick.
(laughter)
MARISHA: Yes.
MATT: So, as you begin
creating your incantation
and thrust your
hips forward,
J'Mon Sa Ord turns
their head beneath the wing
in your direction and
arcs a brow, surprised.
SAM: Like, yeah,
this is happening.
MATT: As the bolt of energy streaks
forth from your groin
in the direction
of the dragon.
That is a 15.
It's going to use one of
Raishan's legendary resistances
to resist it.
So half damage.
SAM: Okay, fine, whatever.
TRAVIS: "Fine, whatever."
SAM: Okay.
TRAVIS: ♪Feel the heat.♪
SAM: Wow.
-SAM: 35 halved.
-MATT: 35 halved.
SAM: 17.
MATT: That's a
good roll.
SAM: That is a
It was mostly
sixes and fives.
MATT: Alrighty.
And do you wish to move or
you gonna stay where you are?
SAM: Oh.
No, I would
like to move.
I would like to move forward
a bit still within the--
the Devo'ssa range.
MATT: Like by Pike and
Kima over here?
SAM: Yeah, oh, can I move to
the other side of Devo'ssa?
MATT: Yeah, you can move
just underneath,
running between the legs
and get about there.
SAM: And yeah, shoot, is anyone
else-- how's Gilmore look?
MATT: Gilmore is standing
and seems to be
doing alright,
but seen a lot struggle
from the last battle
and is currently about...
You can see
a little bit of blood
dried and curling from one side
of the mouth.
Hair is mussed up
and looks to be
a few burn marks
across the skin
and is kind of a little out of breath,
but is standing.
TALIESIN: It's the level two
Mike Tyson's punch out.
MATT: Yeah.
Gilmore's
roughly half out.
-SAM: Okay.
-TALIESIN: I knew that would break you.
TRAVIS: I love that reference.
SAM: So I will use a Healing Word
on Gilmore.
Why not?
'Cause I don't
want to use any--
I got one more Inspiration,
so I'm not gonna use that yet.
So, yeah, I will--
I will heal Gilmore.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: Oh, yes, sorry,
I got to roll.
Nine.
MATT: Total nine,
great, alrighty.
That ends your turn?
SAM: Yes, yes, yes.
MATT: Alright, Percival,
you're up.
TRAVIS: Nice job.
TALIESIN: Okay, I don't
have it marked down
that I burned
my action surge,
but I think I burned
my action surge.
MATT: You did, yes.
TALIESIN: But I still do have two
points of Cabal's Ruin.
-If I recall.
-MATT: You do, yes.
TALIESIN: Okay, just
making sure.
Alright, so, I'm going to--
from my little
vantage point,
take a shot with Bad News.
See how this goes, and I'm
gonna burn a Grit for advantage.
Let's do this.
♪
Yeah.
I mean, that wasn't fine,
but we could do better.
Yeah, that's
already better.
TRAVIS: Come on.
TALIESIN: Thirty points to--
30 to hit.
MATT: Thirty does hit, yes.
TALIESIN: Alright.
Let's use these,
they're sparkly.
Two 12 plus six plus,
I'm gonna throw
2d6 worth of electric.
2d4 worth of electric.
Learning how to use--
Oh, 1d6, no,
never mind, here we go.
So, let's add.
Empty out Cabal's Ruin.
That's awful.
♪
10 points of damage plus 6
points of lightning damage.
TRAVIS: How's that terrible,
that's not terrible.
-TALIESIN: For me.
-LAURA: For him.
MATT: You watch as you send
the last bit of the charge
through the cloak as the
energy shoots up your arm
into the gun and as you fire,
it travels with the bullet and
bursts into this kind of weird,
reverse shock wave
and the energy returns
and slams for a second
time into Raishan's body.
TALIESIN: Nice, I have
one more shot.
So, I'm gonna
take my last shot
although there's
no more electricity.
That's probably
not gonna hit.
That's 18 to hit,
that does not hit.
-MATT: It does not.
-TALIESIN: That does not hit.
But at least it
doesn't backfire.
MATT: It hits the side of the hide and
ricochets off the dragon's skin.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna start running.
I know you don't have
the little plastic thing,
but I'm feeling a little clumped
over there,
so I'm gonna start running
up the wall at an angle,
so probably three up and three--
three up and three side.
MATT: We'll mark you at
25 feet up on the wall.
Just keep that in mind.
Okay, ends Percy.
Top of this now is
another lair action.
♪
(indistinct talking)
SAM: No, he could do that.
MATT: Alright.
♪
TALIESIN: It's like watching
some very, like, complicated...
MARISHA: Like, chess.
MATT: The magma over
here begins to bubble
and you watch as one of
these strange protrusions
from the rocky ground
begins to bow upward
and then crack open as
another familiar cloud of gas
begins to spill
out in this area.
TRAVIS: But you're
totally immune.
MATT: Vax, Vex, Scanlan.
I need you guys
to make constitution
saving throws.
SAM: Nope.
LAURA: This is just the worst.
-MATT: J'Mon.
-LAURA: ♪ J'Mon ♪♪
MATT: Does make it, yes.
SAM: Four.
-LAURA: Fourteen.
-LIAM: Eighteen.
-MATT: Okay, you do make it.
MATT: Eighteen, yes, the two
of you manage to succeed.
Pike as well?
TALIESIN: Oh, yeah, medicine
won't heal it.
LAURA: Hold on.
TRAVIS: That's gotta make it.
-LIAM: Thirteen.
-LAURA: Fourteen.
MATT: Okay.
So, this cloud is still kind
of permeating this area.
Obscuring it slightly.
Ending that now
it is Raishan's--
SAM: Wait, what did I do,
what happened to me?
-MATT: You rolled a four.
-SAM: Yeah.
MATT: So, when your turn
comes around next...
-SAM: I die.
-TRAVIS: I'll let you know.
MATT: No, you'll just be
coughing and incapacitated.
The coughing fit
that this poison gas
creates is so bad
that you can't do
anything but hack.
TRAVIS: It is called LA Smog.
MATT: Yes.
Now, being Raishan's turn.
Still hasted, pardon me.
Raishan is going
to dart backward...
and snatch up this
one egg with her claws.
Grabs it and kind of
carries it up underneath.
MARISHA: Bitch cares.
-LAURA: She does care!
-MARISHA: She cares!
LAURA: Let's kill
them eggs.
TALIESIN: Care Bear stare!
SAM: Wait, maybe she's just
trying to be a good mom.
TALIESIN: She's gonna
throw it at us.
MARISHA: Google Donkey Kong.
TALIESIN: She could go all
Donkey Kong on us.
MARISHA: Yeah, yeah.
(indistinct talking)
LAURA: (yells)
MATT: So, that's 20 to get there
and back to grab that.
She kinda swoops
down, grabs it.
Moves forward
ever so slightly
this way, and...
No, from back here.
Is going to release a giant
burst of poisonous gas
outward, affecting--
Kima shrugs it off,
Pike shrugs it off.
Grog, you shrug it off
cause you resist the dispel
that didn't work earlier.
Gilmore ate the Feast earlier
and is also unaffected.
However, I need...
LAURA: Gilmore
didn't get the Feast.
MATT: That's right, cause you can only
have so many people eat from it.
Alright, I need Gilmore,
Vax, Vex and Scanlan
to all make
constitution saving throws.
SAM: What about Devo'ssa?
-MATT: Yes.
-TALIESIN: Wow.
That's not happy.
Such a pretty die.
LAURA: Did you say Pike?
Did you say
Pike as well?
MATT: Pike didn't
get dispelled.
So Pike is immune.
SAM: I got a nine, Matthew.
-MATT: You got a 9?
-SAM: Constitution?
-MATT: Yes.
-SAM: Nine.
MATT: Not you, Percy.
TALIESIN: I didn't have to roll.
I'm just mocking him.
-MATT: Vex?
-LAURA: Fourteen.
MATT: Okay.
You guys and Scanlan all suffer
83 points of poison damage.
TRAVIS: Oh my God!
MARISHA: How many?
-MATT: Eighty-three.
-LAURA: Eighty-three.
MATT: Gilmore.
TALIESIN: (laughing)
Gilmore makes his save
roll with a 19 plus three.
TALIESIN: So, he gets 40.
MATT: Thanks to your
heal earlier,
Gilmore is still standing
with two hit points.
-LAURA: Wow.
-SAM: That makes two of us, friend.
I'm at two hit
points as well.
TRAVIS: How y'all doing?
LAURA: We're unconscious.
SAM: Did our--
Our bronze brass dragon
get hurt at all or no?
MATT: Brass dragon. But it is
here in a minute.
Rolls a one on
its saving throw.
Gonna use legendary resistance
to make the save.
So he only takes--
they only take--
TALIESIN: Can you arc lightning?
MATT: 41 points
of damage there.
Okay.
So, as this
billows forth...
LAURA: Twins go out together.
MATT: So, Vax, he
falls unconscious.
Vex, you fall unconscious, fall
off the broom, hit the ground.
Taking four points
of bludgeoning damage,
you suffer a death saving
throw from the impact.
LAURA: From like a teeny
little ten foot fall?
MATT: 10 foot drop on your head.
LAURA: That's fucking stupid.
-MATT: It's only a--
-LAURA: She was sitting stupidly!
MATT: It's only a d6
bludgeoning damage,
but when you're
unconscious while falling,
you now realize the downside
of flying all the time.
LAURA: Damn it!
TRAVIS: Didn't you put
air bags on that thing?
LAURA: I did, I have
a helmet on.
Did you-- I put
airbags in the witch's hat.
TALIESIN: It's a football helmet.
TRAVIS: That's right,
it's magic, it goes...
SAM: Yeah, I forgot to tell you,
the witch hat is magic.
TALIESIN: Full of balloons.
MATT: As the poisonous
breath billows out
and everyone's coughing
and falling over,
you watch the twins
fall unconscious,
Raishan kind of grins.
"You've got a
few surprises, I see,
but you're not
the only ones."
LAURA: Oh, no, does she
have more surprises?
TRAVIS: I think that's
what she meant, yeah.
LAURA: I hope that's not--
TALIESIN: There's cake and
ice cream upstairs.
SAM: "I have more surprises."
"Guys, I think she
has more surprises."
TRAVIS: That's literally
what she just said.
LAURA: I just thought maybe
the breath was the surprise.
MATT: And then is going to use
the rest of her movement
to whip over here.
TRAVIS: Damn it, damn it, damn it.
Why'd she have to leave?
I just wanted to
give her a high five.
TALIESIN: You need to heal the living
hell out of these people.
LAURA: Damn it!
She's carrying...?
MATT: She's carrying
two eggs underneath.
TALIESIN: Which means she obviously
can't do claw attacks.
MATT: She still has
40 feet of movement.
LAURA: That's true.
MATT: And is going
to turn back,
and flies there.
TRAVIS: Didn't pick up
anything else?
MATT: No, she grabbed the
two eggs and is positioning.
Alright, that ends
Raishan's turn.
Keyleth, you're up.
TALIESIN: Can you heal?
MARISHA: I'm wondering if
I should drop this
and start doing
beefier stuff now.
LAURA: Yeah.
MARISHA: I think now's the time.
SAM: This has only injured
Vax so far, so...
LAURA: Me and...
TALIESIN: The twins, they're
both unconscious.
SAM: Oh, great.
TALIESIN: With one death saving
throw already failed.
SAM: Great.
LAURA: No, just me.
MARISHA: Okay, I am going
to move from--
LAURA: And Pike's like out.
MARISHA: Over the
lava like this direction.
SAM: She's got some cantrips.
MARISHA: Geez, I can't tell.
-MATT: Which way?
-MARISHA: This way, this way.
See the laser pointer?
No, no, no, I had it.
I had it and
it went away.
-Okay.
-MATT: Over here?
MARISHA: No, it's--
yeah, over there.
-MATT: Over here?
-MARISHA: Uh-huh.
And how far away is
Raishan from me now?
MATT: I'd say roughly
30 feet, 35 feet.
MARISHA: Okay, move
me like one more closer to her.
MATT: There you go.
MARISHA: And how close am I
from the twins now?
I can't see.
MATT: Twins, you're about 30,
another 35 feet from them.
MARISHA: Okay, let me move
five more feet
so I can be within
30 feet of the twins.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: Okay, now I'm
gonna drop my--
MATT: Well, with both twins,
you'd have to move there.
You drop your form?
-MARISHA: Drop my form.
-MATT: Alright.
MARISHA: I hope this is not
a terrible idea.
-MATT: I'll put you there.
-TALIESIN: We're at that point.
MARISHA: We're at that point.
This is Dungeons
and Dragons!
TALIESIN: This is dungeon
and dragons.
MARISHA: I'm going to bust out
the Spire of Conflux.
So I'm gonna bust out the staff
and be like, "You bitch."
And then aim it.
I'm gonna do chain lightning
and can I try and
hit her and the two eggs
and maybe like, since
I still have the storm going,
like, it just looks cool?
(laughing)
MATT: Sure.
LAURA: Doesn't it--?
MATT: Raishan saves.
The eggs cannot
save technically,
so go ahead
and roll damage.
LAURA: Don't you get the
lightning attacks too?
If you're doing
chain lightning,
you still get the other
lightning's that are there?
MARISHA: I have to choose
to make an action.
It's still there,
but I can either like do other
things or choose to do--
LAURA: I understand.
MARISHA: Sorry, I don't
do the-- 10d8.
TALIESIN: Do you need some d8's?
MARISHA: I have one, two,
three, four, five...
I think I'm good,
I'll just roll five twice.
Oh, God, oh, God.
Did she save?
MATT: Yes, she did.
MARISHA: But the eggs didn't?
MATT: The eggs did not.
MARISHA: Okay, that's not
phenomenal.
Three, six, nine,
ten-- nine, ten, eleven.
Plus four is 15 plus...
Okay, okay.
What'd I say, 15?
Twenty-five, 29.
Thirty-six total.
TALIESIN: Oh, wait, wait, wait.
MARISHA: Oh!
Oh, and I get to
reroll this one.
Thirty-six, no,
thirty-eight.
MATT: Thirty-eight, okay.
That would be 29,
no, sorry.
No, from 30, 19.
Nineteen damage to Raishan
and the two eggs--
You watch as the bolt hits,
arcs through her,
arcs through the eggs.
You see the eggs still
carrying them, no visual.
MARISHA: It didn't do
anything to 'em?
MATT: Well, nothing
you can see, no.
MARISHA: Nothing I can see.
Maybe I like
microwaved 'em inside.
Like nuked 'em.
Might have nuked 'em.
TRAVIS: Might have been like Vision
and you made 'em super strong.
MARISHA: Yeah, or I turned 'em into
little Vision dragons.
You know,
one of the two.
Okay, and then
for my bonus action,
I'm going to do a
Healing Word on Vax.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: I'm just gonna
do it at first level.
-Sorry.
-LIAM: No, hey.
TALIESIN: It's back up.
MARISHA: Three plus (indistinguishable)
so nine total.
LIAM: Thank you.
MATT: At the end of your turn,
watching you form over,
hit her with lightning,
hit the eggs
and all of a sudden,
breath come back to the
lungs of Vax on the ground.
Raishan, "Not so fast."
Still clutching the eggs,
her front claws kind
of form this small spiral
as the air grows
surprisingly cold
causing this mist to form
around the extended
ends of her claws.
As she puts
her arms forth,
casting Cone of Cold
outward from her.
LAURA: I wonder if they're elemental,
like, amplifiers.
MARISHA: The eggs?
TALIESIN: I think, I think
maybe they're--
TRAVIS: Just eggs?
TALIESIN: No, no, I think she
may be on to something.
MATT: That's going to be...
I don't know if
it's going to hit.
TALIESIN: No, no.
MATT: Does not hit Gilmore.
However, I need Scanlan...
SAM: Would I be able to
counter spell this or--
or am I already in a cloud
of smoke and coughing?
MATT: Oh, you can't
technically move
cause you're
doubled over.
SAM: I'm already in
the cloud, right?
-MATT: Yeah.
-SAM: Okay.
LAURA: You're in the cloud,
but you can be restored.
Cause you've
been backed up.
SAM: Oh. Backblaze?
SAM: You're slowly becoming
me tonight.
TALIESIN: Can Gilmore
dispel or--
Just throwing
that out there.
I know you're
playing a lot of hands here.
SAM: You're so handsome and
charming all of a sudden.
MATT: What's the range on that?
Unfortunately, Gilmore's
just out of range. 60 foot range.
TALIESIN: Goddammit, okay.
MATT: Good looking out though.
TALIESIN: I'm trying.
MATT: So that is Kima,
Pike, J'Mon,
Scanlan, Vax and Vex
all making constitution
saving throws.
LAURA: I'm unconscious.
MATT: So, you take
another death save.
-LAURA: Cool.
-TALIESIN: Goddammit.
We need to fix that.
LAURA: I've got one save left.
TALIESIN: Please, we got
to fix that.
SAM: Did I-- wait.
Vax-y poo, did I give
you my cold armor?
I mean, Vex-y poo.
LAURA: Yeah, you did,
but it's not attuned.
SAM: You're not
even using it?
MATT: And even then, even at half
damage, she's unconscious.
LAURA: Well, I am, I'm
just not getting cold--
MATT: So you're at two
death saves on impact.
You're unconscious
again to zero.
-You take...
-SAM: I rolled an 11.
MATT: An eleven, yeah.
So you take 43 points of cold damage.
SAM: I'm so dead.
TRAVIS: No, no, unconscious.
-MATT: Unconscious.
-LAURA: You're unconscious.
SAM: Negative 41.
MATT: Both roll for Pike.
LAURA: It doesn't matter
what you're negative.
TRAVIS: Unless it's your
total hit points.
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: Roll for Pike if
you could please.
LAURA: Well,
I wouldn't count it,
but yeah, that was--
that was bad.
It was better when I--
TALIESIN: Well, not anymore.
LAURA: What is this,
what is this?
Constitution,
Five!
Cause I suck.
MATT: Pike takes another
43 points of cold damage.
LAURA: Pike is unconscious.
SAM: The gnomes are down.
Well, at least
we got Kima.
LAURA: Whoa.
The two-- the twins
and the gnomes are out.
SAM: Yeah, whoa,
we're down four?
TALIESIN: We're down four.
-SAM: Whoa!
-LAURA: This is serious, you guys.
SAM: Don't worry, Devo'ssa's here
to give one shot of
28 points of damage.
Come on, Devo'ssa,
do something!
TRAVIS: I would hit the dragon
cause it's low enough,
but it's on the
other side of the map.
MATT: Alrighty, so that's the
end of Keyleth's turn.
It's now Gilmore's turn.
TRAVIS: Come on, Gilmore.
LAURA: Do you have
Mass Cure, Gilmore?
MATT: Gilmore does not
cure, unfortunately,
that's not
his specialty.
TRAVIS: What about Razzle Dazzle?
MATT: He's used a
lot of his spells.
(sighs)
TALIESIN: I have nothing.
TRAVIS: Can he cast like--
SAM: Oh, wait!
Shit.
No, that was poison.
He shot-- Raishan shot
poison at us, right?
TALIESIN: No, cold.
LAURA: Cold the last time.
SAM: No, the cold this time.
The previous time
it was poison.
MATT: Yes.
SAM: Never acid though.
TALIESIN: No, never acid.
MATT: Gilmore rushes around J'Mon
almost as a
defensive stand point,
but also kind of taking
in the circumstance.
Watching this blast of
cold air come through.
Kind of looks around, seeing
everyone on the ground.
It's like,
"Oh God, oh God."
And in a fit of rage and
needing to lock this down,
just gonna go ahead with what
he has left at his disposal
to release a...
All he can really do
is a lightning bolt.
Which Raishan rolls a one.
LAURA: Oh, good, good.
MATT: Uses legendary resistance
to resist it.
LAURA: I have to pee so bad,
I got to get up.
-SAM: How do you want to do this?
-MATT: I know.
Ten points of lightning
damage to Raishan.
LAURA: What I'm scared of is that
I'm gonna be away from the
table when I actually die,
but I have to pee.
MATT: Go pee, it's fine.
LAURA: Just don't kill me while I'm
not at the table, okay, Matt?
MATT: Do my best.
SAM: Hey, when she gets back
let's all be crying.
LAURA: (offscreen) Don't-- I heard that!
(laughter)
TALIESIN: You are the worst person.
Two seconds longer.
-MATT: Grog.
-TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: Actually, no, oh,
thank you so much.
TALIESIN: Oh, yay.
MATT: Thank you,
thank you, thank you.
Beautiful.
They found my base.
TALIESIN: Wow, look at all those
minis that are flattened.
Wake up our healer.
MATT: Look at that.
Looks much more majestic
when it's up in the air.
Oh God.
I'm juggling here.
Stay on there!
Alright, so, at the
end of that turn...
there's two more legendary
actions from Raishan.
She has four,
she has four.
To cast a Melf's
Acid Arrow at Gilmore.
♪
SAM: (snickering)
TRAVIS: Wait, where did Gilmore go,
I can't see.
MATT: He's underneath.
SAM: No one said D&amp;D
was easy, guys.
♪
MATT: Okay, a ranged spell attack.
So, yeah, that hits.
So that is 4d4
acid damage against--
That's five.
Five, ten points
of acid damage.
Gilmore is now also down.
SAM: Oh!
TRAVIS: Is that five total?
TALIESIN: Five down, we
have five down.
MATT: As Gilmore runs
past the dragon,
Raishan just with this
almost underhanded,
flips her claws out
and this one little
greenish dart
of arcane energy
slams into Gilmore's chest.
And he just
falls to the ground.
TALIESIN: We're so fucked.
MATT: Burning into him like alien blood.
TRAVIS: This is some kind
of horrible record.
LAURA: Gilmore just went
unconscious too?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
-TRAVIS: Sit down.
-LAURA: Oh, no!
SAM: Kima, Percy, Keyleth.
It's up to you.
-MATT: Grog, it's your turn.
-SAM: Oh, wait, Grog!
I forgot Grog.
TRAVIS: Hey!
TALIESIN: Is there anything
you can do to fix this?
-TRAVIS: I have a question.
-MATT: Yes.
TRAVIS: So my speed is 50,
but I don't know
if I ever thought of
what my speed
is enlarged-ish.
It's not double, right?
I don't really
have a card for it.
It doesn't say
anything about my speed.
MATT: Wait, for which
one, on the--
LAURA: If he was enlarged.
MATT: If you're enlarged, no,
it doesn't increase
your speed at all.
TRAVIS: Yeah, okay.
MATT: You're still 50,
you're bigger--
TALIESIN: Fuck.
TRAVIS: So, from where I am,
if I wanted to head towards you,
how far could I get?
MATT: You could get...
That far there.
TRAVIS: That does fuck all.
TALIESIN: That-- yeah.
TRAVIS: I could throw the axe
but Pike's unconscious.
-I'm gonna run to Pike.
-SAM: Start saving shit.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: And I have the middle
potion available.
-LAURA: The Greater?
-TRAVIS: The Greater.
MATT: Alrighty, so you're
gonna use your action
to administer the Greater
healing potion to Pike.
Alrighty, go for it.
-SAM: To Pike.
-TRAVIS: How many--
How many is
that, I don't remember.
-LAURA: That's 4d4.
-MATT: Yeah, 4d4 plus four.
TRAVIS: Okay.
Four.
Four, that's two.
Hey, seven and
a four is eleven.
Fifteen.
Fifteen points to Pike.
MATT: Fifteen points to Pike.
TALIESIN: And she still has
her turn coming up.
LAURA: Yes.
TALIESIN: Oh, okay, okay,
that's good.
LAURA: But she has basically
no spells left.
SAM: She's got no spell slots.
Does she have any spell--
higher level spell slots open?
LAURA: She's got a
fourth level spell.
TALIESIN: And then she can
burn a fourth
to heal somebody
at a fourth level.
She can heal you
at a fourth level
because you
need healing now.
MATT: That ends your turn, Grog?
-MATT: Vex, it's your turn.
I need you to make
a death saving throw.
-TALIESIN: Goddammit.
-LAURA: I could die.
TALIESIN: Yep, this could be it.
-SAM: This is the last one?
LAURA: This is my last
death saving throw.
TALIESIN: This is it.
LAURA: No advantage,
no nothing.
TALIESIN: Oh God
fucking damn it.
LAURA: I'm using-- no, I'm
not even gonna say it.
(groans)
-LAURA: I failed it.
-MATT: What'd you roll?
-LAURA: Five.
-MATT: Five.
There, on the banks
of the lava flow
in Thordak's lair,
the breath escapes Vex.
Her body going still
and unfortunately
not cold because
of the vicinity
of the flames,
but Vex has fallen.
-TALIESIN: Okay.
-MATT: Vax.
-LIAM: Death save.
-MATT: With advantage.
-LIAM: I made it.
-MATT: Made it?
That brings
us to Kima.
♪
TRAVIS: Fuck.
SAM: Holy shit.
♪
MATT: Kima, who's-- Pike is
now conscious, correct?
From the potion.
LAURA: Pike is conscious
with 15 points.
MATT: Kima's panicking
watching all this happen
and seeing this
happen in the distance.
Looks to Gilmore,
looks to Vax.
She kind of frustratingly just
throws the sword at her side
and reaches down
and does a level two
Healing Word to Gilmore.
That is 12, so Gilmore
is back and conscious.
MARISHA: As a bonus action, so
can she heal someone else?
MATT: Alrighty.
That ends Kima's
turn is now--
MARISHA: Does she happen to do--
that's a bonus action.
Can she do it twice?
MATT: That was-- that was not Healing
Word, sorry, Cure Wounds.
TALIESIN: Goddammit.
MATT: She's going to move,
stepping over his body,
"Keep it going, friend."
Leaps over him.
Two, three, four, five.
And she kind of runs past,
pulling the sword out again,
looks up at the
dragon and says,
"Alright, show us
what you can do, buddy.
There's a lot
riding on this."
After Kima is J'Mon.
They look down at the
running Halfling.
"Dire as it may be,
that's why we're here."
Let's see if he
gets his breath back.
Nope.
They did not
get their breath back.
TRAVIS: Shit.
LAURA: Just-- bitch--
bitchslap Raishan.
MARISHA: Kaiju battle!
LIAM: Take your earrings off,
come on.
MATT: Rushes up and--
Goes right up into
Raishan's space.
LAURA: Yes!
SAM: Dragon on dragon.
LAURA: He has a base now?
When did that happen?
-TRAVIS: While you were peeing.
-LAURA: That's great.
MATT: So, just rushes up
into Raishan.
You feel the wind
kind of blast past
as the wings of
J'Mon Sa Ord, Devo'ssa,
pick them up and they rush
around strafing the side
of Raishan and unleash a
barrage of attacks against her.
That will be--
First one is 16, no.
Bite misses.
Three and a
two, really?
LAURA: Really?
TRAVIS: No, no, no, no.
-MARISHA: Come on, man.
-TRAVIS: I don't believe it.
-MARISHA: Come on!
-TRAVIS: I don't believe.
SAM: Look at all the notes,
look at all the notes.
TRAVIS: I don't believe it!
MATT: Three, two and one.
That is ridiculous.
LAURA: You know why
this happened?
Cause you took
so long to call--
SAM: Yeah, I know, I know.
They got--
they got bored
waiting at home and yeah.
-MATT: So.
-SAM: It's me, it's on me.
MATT: As J'Mon rushes up
and unleashes, Raishan,
who is slippery
at best, and really,
really, really creepily
deceitful at her worst,
dodges to the side,
so, she's in the shadows
and the cloud of
the storm in the air
to kind of hide her form
as J'Mon reaches out
and starts slashing Raishan,
who's now has this kind
of wild look in her eyes
of now mounting victory.
From a moment
of fear earlier,
she manages to avoid
the first two strikes
and the third one,
the tail slaps against
the side of Raishan's body.
Whack and smacks
to no effect.
TRAVIS: Jesus.
MATT: That ends
J'Mon's turn.
It is now
Pike's turn.
LIAM: Pike, how close
is she to--
-SAM: Book!
-TALIESIN: Book?
MATT: Pike is about
25 feet away.
LIAM: She's gonna run
up, kneel down,
wait, kiss Vex on
the forehead, and say,
"Not like this, buddy,"
and cast Revivify
for her last spell.
TRAVIS: It is her last.
MATT: Revivify is touch
and she's coming up
from unconscious prone
which means she
doesn't have the movement
to get there to touch her.
LIAM: Pike is unconscious?
MATT: Oh, no, she was--
she was--
TRAVIS: Pike was not
unconscious.
MARISHA: She was not
unconscious, she was up.
TRAVIS: She was up
with 15--
MATT: Oh, oh.
LAURA: She had 15.
-But she was--
-SAM: She was lying down.
-LAURA: She was lying on--
-MATT: So, she was prone.
She was prone.
TRAVIS: Oh, why didn't I
just pick her up?
MATT: No, so she can move.
She can't get there.
LAURA: That's okay.
MATT: It's a touch spell.
LIAM: Who's she near?
MARISHA: How much time does
Revivify need?
LAURA: A minute.
TALIESIN: Oh, under
a minute.
Oh, well, she
can make her way--
LAURA: She's got
Sprinter's Boots on!
She just texted.
MATT: Had she used
them recently?
LAURA: We didn't use them
in the last fight
because we didn't
realize she had 'em.
MATT: The internet
will let us know.
LAURA: Well, I-- we didn't use 'em
in the fight with Thordak.
LIAM: She didn't know she had
'em so we didn't use 'em.
MATT: Right, right, so.
SAM: Do you have any
other healing spells
that can work
at a distance?
-LIAM: She's dead.
-MARISHA: She's dead.
She's gonna
do Revivify.
-LAURA: For Pike, though.
-TALIESIN: Yeah, like.
LIAM: So the Sprinter's Boots do
nothing, I mean, I don't know.
MATT: The Sprinter's Boots will
let her double her movement
for a round.
LIAM: So will she get there?
LAURA: She's writing in all caps
"Sprinter's Boots!"
(laughing)
LIAM: Alright, so Revivify.
-MATT: Alright.
-TALIESIN: Oh my God.
MATT: Now, this is mid-combat.
-For the purposes of this--
-LAURA: Oh God.
SAM: How long does
it take to cast?
LIAM: It's instantaneous.
TALIESIN: Less than six seconds.
LIAM: One action,
instantaneous.
MARISHA: Yeah, she did lay out
less than six seconds, man.
MATT: I understand.
So, this-- this is going to
be a rapid resurrection skill check.
LAURA: Oh God, really? Okay.
MATT: So, but this is
only from Pike
because it is
a singular roll.
So.
LAURA: Can Ashley roll, do you
want to roll Ashley?
MATT: As Pike rushes up,
what does Pike utilize
to implore Vex's
soul to return?
SAM: Liam, you answer.
♪
LIAM: My gosh.
She grabs a dagger
out of Vex's belt
and cuts off a
lock of her hair
and presses it
into Vex's hand.
"It's not time,
it's not time for you.
No."
♪
MATT: Go ahead and just roll a d20.
LAURA: She's-- oh!
Oh, no!
Should we read that?
TRAVIS: No.
MATT: A ten?
As the glow from
the outside of her form
that just radiates
with the armor itself,
centrally focuses itself
into her holy symbol
and is sent down the arm.
Each piece of
the plate mail
glowing in succession
like a series
of chained lights
as it reaches the fingers,
touching the bottom of her
fingertips to Vex's torso.
The air seems to go dark
for a moment around her body
before it pulses,
and with that,
you watch as her jaw
moves ever so slightly
taking in, once more, the
warm air of Thordak's lair.
MARISHA: No one else die.
MATT: Pike, want to do
anything else?
Bonus action?
LIAM: Geez, I don't--
LAURA: Oh, she should take-- she should
take a potion or something.
TRAVIS: Yeah, heal herself please.
LAURA: She's got a--
she's got a Greater healing--
Pike has a Greater healing
potion that I know of.
So she can take it.
MATT: Okay.
So that is a
4d4 plus four.
TRAVIS: This sucks!
TALIESIN: I'm almost
of the thinking
that she shouldn't
take it just because--
-Well, no, she's got--
-LAURA: She's got 15 points.
TALIESIN: Well, I mean, but
anything hits her--
half the things that hit her
are gonna even kill that
and that's a
revive from death.
LAURA: That's true.
MARISHA: Yeah, but it's
on her, right?
Yeah, I see what
you mean though.
LAURA: Should she wait,
should she hold it?
SAM: They're in control of her.
TALIESIN: Yeah, you do it,
you do it, you do it.
I'm overthinking this.
LIAM: Yeah, we're talking about
getting people back up.
At this point, not healing
cause any hit is lethal.
So getting someone
on their feet.
TRAVIS: I got some potions
cause I never use 'em, but...
MATT: Yeah, you guys have been
hording potions for a while.
You've been burning
through all of them
from these
two encounters.
TRAVIS: I've got all the
ones I've never used.
LIAM: Who's on the
ground by Grog?
TALIESIN: You.
LIAM: No, I know I am, but
who else is that?
TALIESIN: It's Scanlan, Scanlan's
on the ground still.
LIAM: Is someone up besides me?
LAURA: Well, I want-- it's
an action if she--
if she gives it
to anybody else.
She can't, she can only take it
as a bonus action for herself.
-TRAVIS: Go.
-LIAM: Go.
LAURA: Oh, that's really
good though.
MARISHA: I wonder how bad
Raishan is looking.
TALIESIN: He hasn't said the phrase.
-LAURA: Nineteen.
-MATT: Okay, nice.
Alright, at the end of Pike's
turn, Devo'ssa, J'Mon Sa Ord,
is gonna use two
legendary actions
to attempt a
wing attack.
TALIESIN: Thank God.
TRAVIS: Come on, come on.
MATT: He is now like just
assailing Raishan
with their wings.
So, Raishan has to make a
dexterity saving throw.
That is cocked, try again.
No, that is a failure.
Raishan's gonna use the
last legendary resistance
to resist that.
So instead takes...
TRAVIS: Fuck!
MATT: That's...
MARISHA: She's burned through all
of her legendary resistance?
MATT: Seven points of bludgeoning
damage and is not knocked prone.
That would have
messed her up.
Okay.
TRAVIS: Is not knocked prone?
MATT: No, she is not,
she's safe.
Okay, that brings
us to Scanlan.
LAURA: We just gotta
get out of here.
SAM: Fail.
MATT: That's a death
saving throw off Scanlan.
Alrighty, that brings us
to the top of the round.
Percy, you are in
the back of a wall.
TALIESIN: I'm taking...
MATT: The curse of the unscathed!
TALIESIN: You know, I was gonna take shots
at the eggs, but I give up.
I'm taking just
shots at Raishan.
MATT: Okay, go for it.
TALIESIN: Come on.
Don't be stupid.
-That's stupid.
-MARISHA: Pretty stupid.
LAURA: Oh my God,
we're all gonna--
I'm not gonna say it.
-We're gonna--
-TRAVIS: Don't you-- shh!
LAURA: We're gonna get
through this, you guys.
We're all gonna
get through this.
TRAVIS: ♪ I gotta get through this ♪
♪ I gotta get
through this ♪
♪ I gotta get ♪♪
TALIESIN: Yeah, so I've got--
that's a-- that's a--
-That's a gun jam.
-MARISHA: Fuck.
-MATT: Really?
-TALIESIN: Yeah.
-LAURA: Fuck.
-TALIESIN: Hold on.
LAURA: Oh my God.
TALIESIN: That's a
bad gun jam.
I'm talking bad,
they're both bad gun jams.
Alright, I've got
one weapon left
that can just barely make it,
so I'm just
screaming to the world.
Here we go.
MATT: So you're pulling
out Retort.
TALIESIN: Yeah, Retort is out
and that's a 23.
MATT: That hits.
Two more attacks on that, right?
TALIESIN: Only one more because I took
an attack with Bad News.
MATT: That's-- well, Bad News
takes an attack to reload.
TALIESIN: But-- no, the
first shot went--
MATT: Right, but usually,
it's action.
TALIESIN: Right, so I have two more-- I
have two attacks with Retort.
-So, that's--
-MATT: That hits.
TALIESIN: That's um, oh,
that's nice.
Fourteen points of damage.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: And...
Oh, that was so mean, that
was almost a natural 20.
-Twenty-four.
-MATT: That hits.
TALIESIN: Ah, 16 points of damage.
-MATT: Nice.
-TRAVIS: Nice.
MATT: Let me take some
concentration checks on that.
Yep and yeah.
TALIESIN: And I'm going to reload,
and I'm going to
start running
across the wall
away from the fray.
MATT: Around this way?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: So, you get about there.
TALIESIN: That far.
Getting out of the way.
MATT: Okay.
That ends your turn.
It is now back
to a lair action.
-SAM: Great.
-TRAVIS: Fuck.
MATT: The ground in the
center here quakes
and cracks open as a
familiar burst of magma--
-Everyone in this vicinity.
-LAURA: Goddammit.
MATT: I need Vex.
Vax, you're--
LIAM: Well, I gotta go,
I've got one success.
MATT: Right, but you're still
unconscious, right?
LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: So, you just take-- you just
lose a death saving throw.
As the magma bursts and sprays
around, so you take one.
I need you to make
a dexterity save.
-I need Scanlan--
-SAM: I lose another death save.
-MATT: You lose another.
-LAURA: You got one left, Scanlan?
MATT: I need Pike to make
a dexterity saving throw.
TRAVIS: Me too, right?
MATT: And you too, Grog.
SAM: He's got high dex, right?
Right?
LAURA: Well, this, you know what?
MATT: Gilmore does not make it.
TRAVIS: That's not bad.
MATT: I'm rolling shit
for damage, that's good.
Wow.
SAM: What'd you roll, Laurs?
LAURA: I rolled an
eight for Pike.
MATT: Okay, so--
LAURA: And a one for me.
MATT: Okay, ten points of fire
damage to each of you halved,
so you both take five.
LAURA: Okay, I'm unconscious.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: This is so fun, you guys,
I love this fight.
SAM: Let's go-- oh.
LAURA: Pike's at 29.
TRAVIS: I rolled a 19.
MATT: A 19, okay, you succeed,
so you take half damage.
So you take five, but you're
resistant from the potion,
so half that, so two.
Two points
of fire damage.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: Alrighty.
It is now Raishan's turn.
MARISHA: So not good.
TRAVIS: I just want to go
flip the table over.
MATT: Hasted.
Raishan, by the way, from
the attack from Percy,
the damage, you can see Raishan
is now visibly bleeding.
Parts of the
scales are torn.
You can see now, at a
close up vantage point,
as much as the previous
dragons you've battled
have had a lot
of resilience,
Raishan's taken a
fair amount of damage,
but seems to not be
quite as physically hearty
as what you
previously faced
and is looking
visibly hurt.
Raishan is going
to begin the round,
turning to
the rest of you.
"I have business elsewhere, and
you're being really obnoxious.
Stay down."
And glancing over
is going to go ahead
and with both of her hands,
again, release another...
She is almost
out of spells.
Cone of Cold.
LAURA: Oh no, this is
gonna be Scanlan.
MARISHA: Fuck.
MATT: That is-- I need--
-So, Scanlan--
-TRAVIS: No!
-MATT: Scanlan is...
-TALIESIN: God fucking damn it.
MATT: Frozen, covered
in ice, locked in place.
A solid gnome
bereft of life.
Motionless
on the ground.
SAM: I died as I lived: hard.
(laughter)
MATT: Gilmore takes--
TRAVIS: I heard him say
that before he died.
MATT: Gilmore loses a
death saving throw.
Vax, you take another damage
to your two
failed death saving throws.
Pike needs to make a
constitution saving throw.
Grog, constitution
saving throw.
LAURA: Was I in there?
MATT: You were, so you also--
TRAVIS: Twenty-four.
MATT: Twenty-four,
you succeed.
TRAVIS: Plus 10 for
constitution.
-LAURA: That's good.
-TRAVIS: Fourteen.
MARISHA: Jesus.
LAURA: Eleven for Pike.
MATT: Okay, that's 30 points
of cold damage to Pike.
-LAURA: Seriously?
-MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: She's unconscious.
TALIESIN: Yep.
MATT: Pike is unconscious.
TALIESIN: That's where we're at.
LAURA: We're-- we're--
I don't know how
we're gonna
get Scanlan back.
TALIESIN: I--I have no--
there's no--
MARISHA: That'll be a
later question?
TALIESIN: That may happen.
MATT: So Pike is down.
-TALIESIN: You have a plan?
-SAM: I have a plan.
It involves me humping
a lot of angels in heaven.
TALIESIN: Okay.
MATT: Watching this carnage,
you watch as the spell finalizes
the blast of cold arcane energy
just careening forth
and then fading.
The ground itself, which is
now, normally glowing orange,
is now covered with a
very thin sheet of ice
and you watch steam rise
up from the contrasting heat
and cold
from the spell
effecting the
surrounding atmosphere.
As the mist dissipates,
you see a big toothy grin
curl across Raishan's face.
Little bit of dragon blood
curling past her teeth
from the wounds
that she's suffered.
Glaring nervously
over at J'Mon Sa Ord,
who has taken nearly
no damage at this point
and is currently up
in Raishan's face.
Raishan says, "Well,
I'm afraid I have to get
to the rest of my day.
Die amongst your
friends as you should."
And just tears off of J'Mon
and goes into a
full hasted fly away.
-SAM: Does J'Mon get--
-LIAM: Attack of opportunity, J'Mon.
MATT: J'Mon does,
J'Mon is gonna make
a bite attack
against Raishan.
With a natural 20!
-SAM: Does that grapple?
-TRAVIS: Are you serious?
-MARISHA: Does that grapple?
-MATT: It does not grapple.
But that is...
MARISHA: She'd have to do a
concentration check, right?
MATT: She will, yeah.
That is 18 plus eight.
That's 26 piercing damage plus
she's immune to poison.
She takes no
poison damage.
That's 28 points of
piercing damage to her.
TALIESIN: (whimpering)
MATT: Concentration check,
oh, she's fine.
It's ten plus 14,
so, yeah, she's fine.
So, the haste does not dispel,
however, J'Mon bites out
and takes a huge
chunk of flesh
as the teeth
just scrape across
the back of Raishan's wing
and shoulder like...
(snarls)
But manages to pull
away and at a full
160 foot flying
speed hasted
and just disappears
down the hallway.
MARISHA: Should've done that,
should've done it.
MATT: Into the ashes
and shadow behind.
Keyleth, it's your turn.
MARISHA: Okay, she has 120 foot--
or she just went 160 feet?
MATT: A 160 feet, yeah.
♪
MARISHA: Is she--
But she wasn't--
Fuck me,
oh my God, okay.
Can I still see her
through the tunnel?
MATT: No, she is outside of
your dark vision view radius
and there is no light
in the tunnel ahead
and it is a
slight incline.
You just watch her just...
Disappear into
the dark tunnel.
Currently have no
bead of sight on her.
TRAVIS: Smoke the tunnel, dude.
Maybe you get her,
maybe you don't.
I'm gonna shut up.
MARISHA: It's a range thing.
I mean, could I
try and-- fuck.
-This is really bad.
-TALIESIN: Yes, it's really bad.
♪
MARISHA: She's so far away, dude.
SAM: J'Mon can chase her.
LAURA: But he's there and--
TALIESIN: And she's so much
faster than him.
She's hasted.
TRAVIS: Don't worry, I'm gonna
take off at a run and--
TALIESIN: Yeah.
He can only go
probably half her speed.
TRAVIS: Picture Butterbean
running down an empty street.
MARISHA: 'Cause my--
my question is--
SAM: Jarret's still up there.
MARISHA: She didn't necessarily--
LAURA: Just waiting,
crossbow loaded.
TRAVIS: He's just like...
(whimpers)
MARISHA: 'Cause could I try
and move up
and then do a long range
Wall of Stone spell?
To try and collapse the
tunnel before she gets out?
It's 120 foot.
MATT: A 120 foot range?
The spell from where
you are currently,
which is over here,
she went 160 feet
even further away
from you than she was,
so she'd be beyond
the distance
of the spell
unfortunately.
TRAVIS: Cause if you miss,
you trap us.
LAURA: Yeah, and then
we can't get out.
MARISHA: No, I mean, I can't--
I mean, I could get
us out again, but--
LAURA: A bunch of dead people,
you could get a bunch
of dead people out?
MARISHA: I know.
Okay, wow.
TRAVIS: Indiana Jones and
the Last crusade.
MARISHA: This is really bad.
Okay, I will use...
LAURA: That wasn't her
last spell, by the way.
She's got three spell slots left.
MARISHA: Who's-- yeah,
who's really close?
Who's like one away?
Who's like really bad?
-LAURA: Close to death?
-MARISHA: Yeah.
LAURA: He's closer to
death than me.
LIAM: I'm two failures.
-SAM: Is Pike down?
-LAURA: Pike's unconscious.
-TRAVIS: Oh, she is?
-SAM: Get Pike up.
LAURA: I'm one fail,
he's two fails.
Scanlan's dead.
TALIESIN: Who's got healing spells?
Wake up whoever can heal.
LAURA: I've got Cure Wounds
if I'm awake.
TALIESIN: So, get her up.
LIAM: I can heal people
if I get up.
MARISHA: Okay, it doesn't matter.
Can I kinda jump and make
my way over like,
this kind of...
TALIESIN: Fuck.
MARISHA: This-- can I cross this
tinier lava right there?
Kind of like, or is that
a pretty far jump?
MATT: I mean, you have
to still jump.
So you have to make
an athletics check.
MARISHA: How far of a
jump is that?
MATT: It's about six,
seven feet.
So make an athletics check.
MARISHA: Sure, why not?
Why not at this point?
LAURA: No, Keyleth, no.
MARISHA: Well, that was
a natural one.
TRAVIS: On what, on what?
SAM: Just moving.
MARISHA: Just trying
to jump across
what should have been
literally anything else.
TRAVIS: How many hit
points do you have?
How many hit
SAM: It doesn't matter,
she's not even
gonna get over to
anyone to heal them.
-MARISHA: 60.
-LAURA: I don't know, man, lava.
TRAVIS: One six or six zero.
-TALIESIN: Six zero.
-SAM: She's fine.
But no, she's not
necessarily fine.
LAURA: Lava has a
new rule now.
MATT: Well, not a new rule,
the actual rule.
TRAVIS: The actual rule that we didn't
use the very very first time.
But we felt it last time.
MATT: So, as you rush
over trying to help,
you go to leap,
but your foot catches
what you thought was
solid volcanic rock.
Unfortunately,
it's brittle and broken
and it slips
beneath your foot.
In doing so, you only
get about three feet
before you plant the
lower half of your body
straight
into the lava.
LAURA: Oh my God.
TRAVIS: (laughing)
MATT: That's 53 points
of fire damage.
-LAURA: 53!
-SAM: You're alive!
LAURA: Get up, get out,
you can get out of it.
You've got
seven points left.
TALIESIN: You died as you lived.
MARISHA: A fucking dumbass, yeah!
TRAVIS: I can't see!
It's just a wall of tears.
LAURA: Can she get out
of the lava or is she just in?
MARISHA: Can I get out now?
I'm trying to use my movement
or am I gonna
die if I get out?
MATT: You're essentially prone in the lava.
You rolled a one to jump
and you basically went...
-LAURA: Belly flopped into lava.
LAURA: You mean, she's gonna take
damage trying to get out of it?
MARISHA: Can I get out?
MATT: You're technically prone.
The rest of your movement
will get you up and out,
but it'll just
get you out of the lava.
-LAURA: At least you're out.
-LIAM: Get out, get out.
MATT: So, you'll get out and you'll
be just on the edge there.
LAURA: Oh my God.
TRAVIS: This is the best.
LAURA: This is the worst!
MATT: Wow!
MARISHA: I was like, as long
as I don't roll a one,
that shouldn't
be that hard-- okay.
TALIESIN: Oh, look, someone left a
metaphor on the ground.
(laughter)
Don't step in it
or anything.
Oh God,
it's everywhere.
-TRAVIS: Oh, shit.
-MATT: Wow.
TALIESIN: Well, this
could've gone worse.
MATT: Wow!
TALIESIN: Yeah!
MARISHA: Okay, I'm out
of the flame.
MATT: This whole thing's
a metaphor for 2017.
LAURA: Does J'Mon Sa Ord
have any healing spells?
MARISHA: And I reach over
as a bonus action
and do a Healing Word
to-- to Vax.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: Just--
MATT: What level?
MARISHA: I don't know.
TRAVIS: Come on, stay with it.
-Stay in the fight.
-MARISHA: Level one.
Oh, that's good, that's
four so, nine points.
SAM: Nine points.
TRAVIS: He wakes up!
MATT: Vax is now conscious.
MARISHA: No, I'm sorry ten points,
that's ten points.
-MATT: There you go.
-LAURA: Sweet, even better.
You're double digits.
Scanlan, we've got to just--
we've got to get Scanlan back.
TALIESIN: There's a lot of work
that needs to happen.
TRAVIS: I got her,
I got-- I got Pike.
TALIESIN: Who's up?
SAM: Grog is up.
TALIESIN: I mean, who's next?
TRAVIS: I think it's me.
-LAURA: It's Gilmore.
-TRAVIS: No, it's Gilmore.
MATT: So, Gilmore gets up.
Kind of looks around.
"Where did she go?"
TRAVIS: "Through the tunnel."
MATT: Okay.
He rushes this way
and as he gets
about there, he...
slams into something that
is currently invisible.
You see a slight
ripple of arcane energy
and you see a series
of small glyphs spiral outward
and then it goes
see-through again.
He starts slamming
his fists on it.
"Of course, of course.
Of course."
TRAVIS: No.
MATT: He goes and...
Let's see what
he has left.
TRAVIS: She made a
Lite Brite wall.
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: He's a mime.
MATT: Technically, he looks like a
mime from your standpoint.
MARISHA: Can I turn to J'Mon?
Say, "J'Mon, can you
sense her presence?
She's a fellow dragon.
Do you know where
she might be going
or what she
might be doing?"
MATT: "I haven't the faintest.
I only just arrived."
TRAVIS: Oh, fuck, Thordak is
outside of the cave!
LIAM: Are we out of combat now?
TRAVIS: Thordak is still
in the hallway.
LAURA: The round's still going.
MATT: So we're gonna continue going
through the order here.
LAURA: So, it's Grog,
it's your turn, Grog.
MATT: So, Grog, it's your turn.
TRAVIS: I run to my buddy,
Pike, and I beer bong
this Greater healing
potion into her gullet.
MATT: Okay.
-TRAVIS: What is that?
-LAURA: 4d8 plus four.
I mean, 4d4 plus four.
MATT: 4d4 plus four.
TRAVIS: Eight.
Twelve.
-Twelve points.
-LAURA: So, Pike is awake.
TRAVIS: "Hi, hi!"
-"Go, heal!"
-LAURA: "What's going--"
TRAVIS: "Lot of problems."
SAM: Got any more of
those Revivify's?
MATT: Alright, that
ends your turn, Grog?
LAURA: Actually, she does have
a third level spell left.
-MATT: You do.
-MARISHA: Really?
-LAURA: Yes!
LAURA: She does have a
third level spell!
MARISHA: Well, yes, do that,
do that really quick!
LAURA: She cast Revivify at fourth
level the last time.
MARISHA: Do it, do it, do it.
TRAVIS: The eggs that
remain are toast?
LAURA: Holy shit.
MATT: Two of them are
completely destroyed
and there is one that has
been shot and is leaking.
LAURA: I have it circled.
TALIESIN: Don't worry about it.
Let's get out there.
TRAVIS: Alright, that
ends my turn.
MATT: Okay.
That brings us to Vex.
I need you to make
a death saving throw.
LAURA: Right.
I'm scared of all these dice.
TRAVIS: I'm using what's left of my
movement to go towards that egg.
MATT: Towards this egg?
-TRAVIS: Yeah, the one shot egg.
-MATT: Okay.
♪
TALIESIN: I'm gonna try
something weird.
MATT: That's two death
saving throws on Vex.
-TRAVIS: You failed it?
-LAURA: I failed it.
MATT: Vax.
LIAM: I stumble over to my sister
and cast Lay on Hands and give
her five to bring her back.
MATT: So, yeah, cause you've
been giving it out--
LIAM: I haven't done anything
with Lay on Hands.
Or I might have done it once but
I always do very small amounts.
I have a total of 15 hit points
cause I'm a third level--
MATT: I'm pretty sure
you used it once before.
LIAM: But I've never used more
than five with that spell
cause it's
worthless to heal.
It's just good
for bringing up.
So I have at least
10 hit points left.
-MATT: Go for it.
-LIAM: Five hit points.
LAURA: Yeah, cause the only
time you used it before
was when you BAMFed
up to my broom
after I grabbed
the dagger.
MATT: You're still
prone by the way.
You just basically
crawled over and touched her.
-LIAM: That's fine.
I'm gonna use the rest
of my movement to stand.
MATT: Okay, so you stand up and you
still have half your movement
if you wanted to.
LIAM: Everyone who's
down, who's down?
And I don't mean dead.
-Pike just got--
-TALIESIN: Pike's up.
MATT: Pike is conscious,
your sister's conscious.
-LIAM: Is Kima conscious?
-LAURA: Yes.
Kima's conscious.
LIAM: So, we've got
dead Scanlan.
TALIESIN: And that's--
that's Pike's problem.
LIAM: And that's it, I'm done.
Wait, where's that egg?
-MATT: Which one?
-LIAM: It doesn't matter.
LAURA: It's the last egg.
LIAM: I'm done, I'm done.
MATT: Alrighty, that
ends Vax's turn.
LAURA: Just worried there's gonna
be another lair action
in the same spot.
MATT: Kima rushes up and swinging
her holy sword in the air,
goes for a full swing, noticing
that everybody's now conscious,
goes and takes a full swing
towards this invisible barrier.
As it streaks across, you see
divine energy go flying off
in a shower of sparks and
a giant shimmering,
shaking visual on this--
this force wall that stands here
in the center of the hallway.
As she finishes her attack,
it shimmers unscathed.
She goes for a
secondary attack.
Strikes again.
This time as it
strikes across
the sparks are even brighter
and you can see the impact
almost pushing her back
off of her feet and
as the blade comes
to the end of
its second arc.
She looks up.
The wall still stands.
TRAVIS: You are shitting me.
It doesn't flicker,
doesn't--
LAURA: It needs like a
dispel or something.
MARISHA: Oh my God, I could--
Oh my God, I could!
TALIESIN: Alright, that's an option.
MATT: Alrighty that
brings us to...
-MATT: J'Mon.
J'Mon rushes.
Flies up to the edge and
kind of takes a moment
streak a few claws across it.
And where the claws streak,
you can see the shimmering
of this force wall.
TRAVIS: Well, phone's out, oh God.
MATT: "The phone's out, oh God"?
SAM: He's calling an Uber
because he knows
we're gonna kill him
after this is done.
MATT: Come on, four percent,
I got four percent left.
SAM: Four percent, get
this man a charger!
-MATT: I know.
-SAM: Taliesin!
LIAM: No, no, no.
Let's start a
YouTube video on it.
SAM: Can you run
this over to Matt?
MATT: Yeah.
J'Mon, with each strike, is like
testing the boundaries of it
across the sides of the
tunnel and just goes...
"This magic holds."
TRAVIS: What?
It holds?
"It--it holds?"
MATT: Fun charger.
TALIESIN: Let me know, I've
got maybe a plan.
Yeah, you've got that.
That's an option,
I've got another plan.
You know my plan, my
plan kind of sucks, but.
MATT: I'm not getting a charge.
SAM: Give it somebody else.
There's a button.
MATT: That's alright.
It happens.
Anyway.
TALIESIN: No, no, it
should just start.
-SAM: No, there's a button.
-TALIESIN: Oh, there is a button.
SAM: There's a button,
he'll find it.
MATT: J'Mon, oh, J'Mon gets
the breath weapon back.
And kind of pushes...
both Kima
and Gilmore aside.
"Excuse me."
And unleashes a blast of burning
hot breath across this wall.
As it hits, it
just curls across
and spreads across
the side of the walls
as the dragon shields
both Kima and Gilmore
from the blast.
As it finishes, the flame
has been split the entirety
and has no effect
on the wall.
TRAVIS: Holy shit.
LAURA: I wonder--
I wonder if the
beehive thing above us,
that the holes are
covered in magic as well.
TRAVIS: Are you conscious?
LAURA: Am I-- I am conscious.
TALIESIN: I say, well, maybe killing
the eggs, I don't know.
Kill the eggs.
MATT: Pike.
TRAVIS: Or maybe it's like a
Pacific Rim--
LAURA: But I don't know
what that says.
SAM: I--I can give it to you.
LAURA: But it's now.
My question is,
Pike runs up, thank you.
Oh, oh!
If she runs up, is
she gonna be able
to get her hand
on-- on Scanlan?
MATT: Well, she was--
She was prone, right?
She just came back
to consciousness.
So she gets up
for half her movement.
TALIESIN: We got a minute.
Got a minute.
TRAVIS: I would have picked
her up after the last time.
I was being pissed about-- I
mean, you know, she's so tiny.
MATT: Being a gnome, it's
one of those things
where 25 feet halved
and you always round on
the lower end of the scale.
At ten feet, she's not close
enough to touch Scanlan.
Yet.
MARISHA: Even with the
Sprinter's Boots?
MATT: Sprinter's Boots
already got used.
It's got one round use.
LAURA: She says "She can use the
Sprinter's Boots twice"
in all caps.
MATT: Alright then.
TALIESIN: The caps are what
make it worthwhile.
MATT: I'll trust her.
TRAVIS: She's on a 30 second delay
so she wrote that
before we said it.
LAURA: Actually she did write
that before we said it.
-MATT: Good, alright then.
Then that will be just enough
to put her up next to Scanlan.
LAURA: Okay.
So, Pike puts her hands on
either side of his face
and says, "Scanlan.
Your letter to me
was wonderful
and I want to do
what you asked
but I can't raise Kaylee alone,
I need you to come back."
And she casts
Revivify on him.
MATT: Okay.
Go ahead and
roll a d20.
LAURA: I'm so scared.
Thirteen?
MATT: Thirteen, okay.
As she implores to
the spirit of Scanlan
in this frozen form,
you watch as
the icy crystals
that have coalesced
around his form
and locked him in his place,
his face kind of--
This frozen
look of horror.
The ice begins to turn
into mist around him
and his color begins
to return to his skin.
His expression relaxes
as his eyes suddenly focus
and Scanlan, you find
yourself conscious again
looking up at Pike.
Tears in her eyes, pulling her
hand back from your shoulder.
Looking up into
the dark, you know,
glowing lit interior
of Thordak's lair.
SAM: Don't cry.
I'm just a little cold.
LAURA: "Warm up.
Does anybody
have a blanket?"
-SAM: "Just hold me."
-LAURA: "Okay."
-TRAVIS: She sent a picture.
-LAURA: She did.
She sent a picture
of the Sprinter's Boots cards
with two uses.
TRAVIS: "Used twice
while in rest..."
MATT: There we go.
Cool, that's what
I wanted, thank you.
So make sure everyone has
their equipment cards on them.
Alright, so that
finishes Pike's turn.
Scanlan, you're
conscious now.
SAM: Hi.
TRAVIS: Welcome back, we're
still fucked by the way.
SAM: What's going on?
TRAVIS: They sealed us in here
with a giant magic
screen across this door.
Dragon's breath does
nothing, Kima does nothing.
You know anything
about this?
Any limericks for
magic cave doors?
SAM: Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
LAURA: Glad you're
back, Scanlan.
SAM: Thanks, thanks.
I've got one
thing up my sleeve.
It's a dog that can
run around and help us.
That's about it.
LAURA: Are we gonna have
to take a short rest?
TALIESIN: No.
SAM: I don't know,
I don't know.
What-- there's
magic there?
I can't do
anything about that.
LAURA: Can I-- can I--
I know I'm gonna--
Can I broom up
to the holes?
God, I'm so scared to
get on this broom again.
TALIESIN: Well, it's not--
we're still--
LAURA: Oh, in our order?
MARISHA: We're still
going in order?
MARISHA: Do you still have a Mansion?
MATT: Well, right now, as we're
getting back into this.
Percy, what are you doing?
MARISHA: I have a crazy plan.
LAURA: Did you let the dog out?
SAM: No, I don't know what--
TRAVIS: Who let the dog out?
LAURA: Scanlan, did you
let the dog out?
SAM: Keyleth, do you
have a crazy plan?
MARISHA: You only have
to cast the Mansion Door
within line of
sight, correct?
SAM: Yes.
MARISHA: Okay.
SAM: I don't know that
that's true actually.
Three hundred feet,
300 feet range.
LAURA: Do you have it left?
-SAM: I do.
-TALIESIN: Yeah.
MARISHA: Okay, two things.
One, before we start burning
our seventh level spells,
I still have
Stone Shape.
Can Keyleth go up to the
wall and do I have enough--
is there just enough
room in the corridor walls
that I could
Stone Shape--
SAM: I could Dimension Door
out of here.
LAURA: Why would you just--
LIAM: You get a tunnel
for all of us, mate.
SAM: Yeah, that would just be me.
MARISHA: Can I Stone Shape a tunnel
kind of around the thing?
Or is--
MATT: First things first,
Mordenkainen's
Magnificent Mansion
is a one minute
casting time.
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: So you could do it, but
in the process of doing so,
you'd probably go through
about 10 different lair actions
in here.
TALIESIN: Yeah, there's that.
MATT: So, Keyleth, you're using,
you said, stone--
MARISHA: Can I Stone Shape a
little passage around?
Do I have just enough
kinda to where I can--
where the barrier is
I can kind of carve
a little corridor around?
LIAM: Around or under?
MATT: It would be very tiny
and you'd have to crawl
through to create enough--
Cause you're not quite sure
how thick the barrier is,
so you have to be--
have to roll an
investigation check
and based on your
roll, I'll let you know.
MARISHA: Okay.
TALIESIN: This is a plan.
MARISHA: Eight.
MATT: Eight?
You're not sure,
you can give it a shot.
MARISHA: I'm-- might as well
give it a shot, I mean--
MATT: Before it gets to you, it does
come back to a lair action.
LAURA: Wait, but--
SAM: On my turn,
I drank a potion.
MATT: Okay, so take
your healing.
SAM: That's it.
TALIESIN: Has my
turn not come up yet?
LAURA: I hate that we can't get
out of this fucking area!
MATT: Sorry, I asked
you what you were doing.
TALIESIN: Oh, I want to
try something stupid.
MATT: What do you want to try?
TALIESIN: I want to try and run
headlong at the barrier.
MATT: Okay.
Well, you have to--
LAURA: Don't get too close
into this area, Percy,
cause this is where the fucking
lair action keeps coming up.
TALIESIN: I want to stay
on the wall.
MATT: Stay on the wall, okay.
Leaving you roughly there.
So even a full turn,
that's as far as you could
get on a double run.
TALIESIN: Yeah, and I'm up
on the wall still.
MATT: Cool.
Alright, now--
now this happens.
With this, the
quakiness of the lair
seems to be subsiding
a little bit.
There is a tremor
on the ground.
It only effects those
directly around the barrier,
so that's my people.
Everyone succeeds,
so no one falls prone.
So no effect on that
lair action, per se.
Alright, past that.
You can see in
the distance,
past the wall,
dark in the tunnel,
which is almost pitch
black beyond the radius,
you see this slight
purplish glow
and then a flash
of purple energy.
TALIESIN: God, fucking damn it!
MARISHA: Talking to Thordak!
SAM: Should I go?
LAURA: What are you gonna do?
SAM: Distract it, do something.
TRAVIS: You're gonna be
all by yourself.
MARISHA: Okay, I'm gonna
Stone Shape
and try and just
cast a little,
even if it's a corridor
just right around.
MATT: It's a touch spell so
you have to get up to it,
so you're back there.
So you just get up to
the edge of the doorway
and the wall
with a double run.
-MARISHA: Okay.
-MATT: Okay?
MARISHA: I'm go ahead and
can I use a bonus action.
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: I'm gonna use
my-- no, no, no,
I'm gonna just drink a
healing potion real quick.
Just one of my Greaters.
MATT: Okay, go for it.
So it is 4d4 plus four.
Alright.
Gilmore.
TALIESIN: This poor book
has seen better days.
MATT: Gilmore doesn't
really have anything
that can be of
aid right now.
MATT: Gilmore moves
over towards you.
Preparing for
what you're up to,
and just kind of puts his hand
on your shoulder, Keyleth,
and goes, "Whatever you're
doing, I'm right behind you.
Don't worry."
TALIESIN: Hold you up so
you don't fall.
MATT: Grog, you're up.
MARISHA: I'm not feeling very
confident right now.
TRAVIS: You look like you're up to
something, do you have a plan?
MARISHA: I'm trying to Stone Shape
a corridor through this,
but I don't know if
it's going to be enough
to get through
the thickness.
-TRAVIS: Right, as a backup plan...
TRAVIS: How big is
J'Mon Sa Ord?
Like a big dragon
or just like eh?
MATT: About the same
size as Raishan.
TRAVIS: So, we couldn't like
all Falcor on J'Mon
up to the spider network of
tunnels in the ceiling, right?
Like we couldn't ride him.
MATT: Raishan and J'Mon have a
very similar physicality.
Like their bodies can, much
like a cat can get really thin,
just enough to fit
through the tunnels, maybe,
but not with any riders.
You guys would probably
be squeezed off
or crushed in
the process.
TRAVIS: Could she get us up there
and then follow us up
through the tunnels if we--
TALIESIN: We don't know
where they go.
TRAVIS: It's better
than this place.
They're exhaust tunnels.
TALIESIN: That's fair, although I
will say, before we leave,
we should probably make
sure all those eggs are down
-before we leave anyway.
-TRAVIS: That's my idea.
And then, I'm
gonna end my turn.
LAURA: Are you gonna run
and hit an egg?
TRAVIS: Oh, yeah!
LAURA: There's an egg
left over there.
-TALIESIN: Hit an egg.
-TRAVIS: Shamone!
Yeah, I'll just
run towards egg.
Ooh!
I'm gonna use all three
of my attacks on that egg.
MATT: Go for it.
Go for it.
MARISHA: Egg doesn't know
what's coming.
TRAVIS: That's a-- that's a 33.
-MATT: That'll hit.
-TRAVIS: Oh, minus five.
Okay.
That's a 31, no, 39.
MATT: Okay, so the first strike
just cleaves through
the egg entirely.
-TRAVIS: Oh.
-MATT: I know.
You impact at the point of the
bullet that Percy left earlier,
which kind of left that
spider web crack in the front
and that just causes
the entire thing to buckle
under the sheer force
of your axe as it swings.
The egg gets cut
in half, tumbles over,
splattering primordial
dragon whelp gore
and you can see
the remnants inside
of what is now a two-parter
primordial dragon whelp.
LAURA: Did it look
like Thordak?
TRAVIS: Did any dragon parts
spill out of the egg?
MATT: Yeah, as it flew
off and kind--
TRAVIS: Could I grab a piece
of it, take a step back
and try and like throw
it towards the wall
to see if it bounces
off as well?
Just in case it's like a,
you know, lair barcode?
MATT: Sure.
TRAVIS: Hey, we got through!
MARISHA: They got the key card.
TALIESIN: Multi-pass.
MATT: As you pull it up,
and this creature is,
nearly identical to the one
that you pulled out earlier.
It's still deep red crimson,
but like fully, fully
primordial in its visual.
You take back a chunk of it
and you throw it at the wall
and it just
passes through.
(gasps)
SAM: What just happened?
-MARISHA: Shut up!
-LAURA: You were right!
SAM: What did he just do?
TALIESIN: You solved it!
SAM: How, what did he do?
LIAM: Destroying the last egg.
SAM: Fucking guy!
LAURA: Or by--
MARISHA: Or by-- it's
like he said.
We cover ourselves
in dragon goo
and then we
can walk through.
TALIESIN: One of the two.
TRAVIS: Residual goo in my hand, I just
like rub it all on my face.
MATT: It smells terrible.
TALIESIN: You can hop in the egg.
It's basically
a hot tub.
MARISHA: We didn't destroy
all the eggs, right?
MATT: Currently, you destroyed
three of them
and two were
lightning baked
and taken off
by Raishan.
SAM: My voice
is my passport.
MARISHA: So, do it.
It's hard to say.
TALIESIN: I love that movie.
LAURA: Maybe we should
hold onto a piece
and try to
pass through it.
TALIESIN: Hello.
MATT: Well, that
finishes Grog's turn.
Vex?
LAURA: That's me.
I used a level-- did I use
a level four spell already?
Shit.
MATT: I'm pretty sure you guys
went down guns blazing.
TALIESIN: Somewhere in the world, there's
a whole chatroom of people
yelling at you
telling you--
LAURA: Oh, that's
right, I did.
I did use it
cause I was--
MARISHA: Yeah, I was gonna
say, "somewhere"?
LAURA: So I have a
level three left.
Who needs healing?
Me and Pike
and everybody.
TALIESIN: There's always--
everybody needs healing.
-MARISHA: Me.
-LAURA: You do.
SAM: I got single
dig going on.
LAURA: So do I, I got five.
TRAVIS: Single dig.
LAURA: I got five points,
how many you got?
SAM: I got eight or nine,
I can't remember my math.
It's pretty bad.
Wait, if I had one,
plus eight would be nine.
LAURA: So you have
nine points.
I'm gonna take
a healing potion.
I mean, I'm gonna cast
Cure Wounds on myself.
-MATT: Okay.
-SAM: Oh, yeah, you do your thing.
MATT: 3d8 plus whatever your
modifier is, go for it.
TALIESIN: It's all good.
MARISHA: Kind of.
TALIESIN: No, it's not, I know,
but like, it's looking better.
MARISHA: Well, we're not all dead.
We just can't die anymore.
TALIESIN: And worst case scenario, we're
stuck in here for another round.
LAURA: So, 20 points.
-MATT: Twenty points, okay.
-LAURA: Okay.
TALIESIN: And you didn't
even burn a spell yet.
LAURA: Can I run over
and get some
dragon guts on my hand
and then to try to put
my hand through the thingy?
MATT: With your speed and getting up,
cause you were prone.
LAURA: Please let me
out of this spot.
MATT: That close right there.
You can't quite get
to the dragon guts.
That's as far
as you can get.
TALIESIN: It may just
be that it's down now,
but it may be
the dragon guts.
MATT: Alright, so that
ends Vex's turn, Vax.
Whatcha doing?
LIAM: I'm just gonna move
towards the gate.
Put my hand out and
see if I can go through
or if I get stopped.
MATT: You walk right through.
TALIESIN: Alright!
LAURA: Oh!
MARISHA: It's the eggs,
it was the eggs.
LIAM: Alright, everybody!
Quietly.
MARISHA: Hang on, hang on.
I'm feeling very guilty
because it was my rage
and anger and
want for vengeance
which made me run in here
blindly towards her,
maybe we shouldn't do it
again is all I'm saying.
TALIESIN: No, too late.
Got to finish this off.
MARISHA: Okay.
LAURA: Does your guilt have
a Mass Cure Wounds?
In that case,
doesn't matter.
MATT: "Forward, now!"
And all of you
just start...
MARISHA: Avengers Run
down the hall.
MATT: Like crawling
over all of you.
TALIESIN: Avengers, it's
clobbering time.
SAM: I--I grab Kima and I say,
"Get ready to hit a dragon,"
and I'm gonna Dimension Door
me and Kima to Thordak's body.
-MATT: Okay.
-LAURA: Oh, geez.
MATT: Kima goes, "Wait, what?"
As soon as you
grab the shoulder
and you both
suddenly vanish
and reappear at
Thordak's body.
You both land with
a flash of arcane light.
As your feet
hit the ground,
it is an empty tunnel.
So, no Raishan.
-There is no Thordak corpse.
-LAURA: Fuck.
-SAM: There's no Thordak's corpse?
-MARISHA: There's no Thordak's corpse?
-MATT: Correct.
-LAURA: Fuck!
Fuck.
LIAM: She just wanted
to talk to it.
TALIESIN: She may have
taken him somewhere.
TRAVIS: Talk to it, my ass.
She didn't want
to talk to it.
MARISHA: Or she raised him.
Jesus.
LIAM: One last roll
in the hay.
MATT: As you guys approach, Gilmore
steps up and goes,
"I think I have
a pretty good idea
what that flash
we saw was."
-MARISHA: What?
-TALIESIN: Teleport.
MATT: "Getting the
hell out of here.
Son of a bitch!"
He takes a rock
and throws it.
Hair's kind
of tussled.
MARISHA: Vex, can you sense
dragons anywhere nearby?
LAURA: Can I sense anyone but J'Mon Sa
Ord as far as dragons go nearby?
I drop down to my
knees and concentrate.
-MATT: No.
-LAURA: Nothing!
Nothing.
She's nowhere.
Fuck.
MATT: And that's where we'll
end tonight's episode.
(all groaning)
We have a flight
early in the morning.
TRAVIS: Oh!
LAURA: I can't believe
that we all came back.
TALIESIN: I can't believe
we all lived.
MATT: I can't believe
you all lived.
TALIESIN: That should
not have happened.
MARISHA: That was
really scary.
LAURA: It was just
giant clusterfuck
from like halfway through
with just everybody
falling down
and trying
to get back up.
MATT: Well, if--
If you had fallen
into the lava,
by the way, if you
had rolled poorly,
you would have been submerged
in lava, which was...
LAURA: Unconscious.
MATT: Well, that-- that's
18d10 points of damage.
If that had exceeded
your max hit points,
you would have been instantly
dead and turned to ash.
LIAM: Been nice if I'd
cut out her tongue.
LAURA: So, gone, gone-gone.
-MATT: Yeah.
There were a
few close calls there.
TRAVIS: She was like three.
I think there
were like nine.
MARISHA: Yeah.
LAURA: And then if you hadn't
counter spelled the color...
MATT: Oh, yeah, the
Prismatic Spray.
That would have
been real bad.
SAM: Who was she
shooting against?
-TALIESIN: Everybody.
-MARISHA: It's a spray.
MATT: It's a cone that big.
TALIESIN: So it would have
been almost everybody.
MATT: Just so you guys know,
cause it's a fun spell
to kind of talk about.
TALIESIN: It is.
MATT: And each of you
would have been hit
with a different
colored ray.
I would have rolled a d8
to see what color had hit you.
On a one, you take
10d6 fire damage.
On a failed save, half.
An orange, take 10d6 acid
damage, save for half.
Yellow: 10d6 lightning damage.
So, just randomly
all of you guys
basically just take
10d6 of something.
Green: you take 10d6
poison damage, half save.
Five, 10d6 cold damage.
Six, on a failed save,
you're restrained
and you have to keep making
saves or you turn to stone.
Seven, you're blinded
and you have
to keep saving.
A successful save ends it,
if you fail the next save,
you will be transported
to another plane.
LAURA: What?!
SAM: There's one where you
get to do two things.
MATT: On an eight, on an eight,
I roll again for two rays
against that person.
-LAURA: Oh my God!
-TRAVIS: For two rays?
SAM: What if you
keep rolling eights?
MATT: Keep rolling eights,
you're gonna be fucked.
It's a fun one.
I like that spell.
LAURA: Wait, what is a 10?
Is 10 insta-death,
what is 10?
MATT: It's one d8, so ten would be
instant death, it would be.
If I roll a
10 on a d8, sure.
You are so done.
TALIESIN: The other
plane of dimension
is like literally
the Beetlejuice,
like send you
to the sandworms.
You're just--
MATT: Oops.
TALIESIN: And that's-- you're
out of the fight
until they can go find
you if anyone's left.
After everyone else
has taken 10d-- suck.
MATT: So, guys, we'll pick this up
again next week on Thursday.
Find out
where Raishan is.
TRAVIS: Maybe.
MATT: With two eggs and the corpse
of Thordak, The Cinder King.
LAURA: Well, hopefully,
oh my God.
TALIESIN: Red eggs and ham?
TRAVIS: Yeah, she just escaped
with two Iphone 7's.
MATT: You start with
a disadvantage.
TALIESIN: I just want the internet to
do a Dr. Seuss red eggs and--
I just want her
with like a little
red steak and two little red--
That's all I want.
MATT: Alright, guys.
You guys, we'll see you
at MAGFest this weekend.
We'll see you
there shortly.
SAM: Remember, bring
your magazines
and have Matt and
Marisha sign any magazine.
TALIESIN: Highlights.
MARISHA: Yeah, all magazines.
We will sign them.
LIAM: I mean, you're gonna say,
you don't know,
but if J'Mon had not nurked
those three attacks that round,
might she have gone down?
MATT: She came pretty close.
LAURA: Oh, yeah, if J'Mon had not
gotten three, two, one.
MATT: Three, two and a one.
MARISHA: That sucked.
MATT: That really sucked.
MARISHA: I was about to lay some serious
damage when she ran away.
I was gonna bust out a seventh
level blight and then she ran.
MATT: I wasn't getting-- cause that
the fire breath is nasty.
MARISHA: Yeah, and he didn't
fucking recharge it.
TRAVIS: If your highness wasn't smart
enough to break another egg...
LAURA: I got to attack
one time that round.
Every other round was
just trying not to die.
LIAM: He should have stretched
before the fight.
-MATT: But anyway.
-MARISHA: Happy New Year.
MATT: Happy New Year!
Well done, guys,
you survived.
-MARISHA: Yeah.
-TALIESIN: Yay.
MATT: Mostly.
Thank you so much for our
sponsor tonight, nobody.
2017.
You guys
are our sponsors.
Well, every
week you are.
So thank you for all
your wonderful support.
Happy New Year, welcome
to the chaos of 2017.
We're there
alongside you for it.
We'll see you
guys soon and...
Is it Thursday yet?
Have a good night.
♪