MATT: Cassandra, remembering this, drags
her body
through what remnant is there
on the ground.
There's a big groove left behind her as
she's
being dragged through it. You get
to the second
trap that she marked, and you guys make
your way
around it. You make your way to
where the road
diverges, the one way to the castle, and
the one
to the acid pits. And Cassandra
heads towards the
acid pits.
LAURA: Cassandra, what are you doing?
TRAVIS: She's throwing them in the acid
pits.
MATT: She doesn't look back at you. She
just keeps
walking. You follow her for
about five minutes.
MARISHA: Are we sure this won't make
anything bad
happen if we throw a body
into the acid pits?
TALIESIN: I think it's fine.
TRAVIS: I think it's acid.
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: After about five minutes of
following her,
the path leads up and
then crests, and there is a
room that smells awful. It's similar to
the acrid
scent the room was filled with
when the acid was
pouring into the room. There's a whole
series of
other chemicals and inside,
you can see there's a
number of laboratory set-ups near you.
You get the
feeling this is probably
where a lot of this
particular acidic concoction that was
fine-tuned
for this stone of Whitestone
was created, or at
least, honed by Ripley. Without a beat,
Cassandra
walks up to the edge and just
throws Delilah's
body in. (plop, sizzle) Then it
disappears beneath
the surface as the
hissing, bubbling noise takes
over the silence of the room. She sits
there and
just watches it sink.
LAURA: Well?
LIAM: She brought a lot of ill to this
world.
Don't feel too bad.
MATT: Cassandra turns back around.
TALIESIN: She was too dangerous to let
live.
MARISHA: What about you? How do you
feel?
SAM: How's that gun barrel of yours?
MARISHA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: I pull out the broken barrel
and inspect
it.
MATT: Looking at it, you can see,
Delilah's name
is missing from the
barrel entirely. Cassandra's
name is still on the barrel, and so is
Ripley's.
Go ahead and make an investigation
check.
TALIESIN: I had some thoughts but yeah.
11.
MATT: Okay. Just looking at it, it looks
like the
names are there, emblazoned as
to where they were
before.
TALIESIN: I'm going to just take the
broken gun
and point it at my sister.
What do I feel?
MATT: Currently, nothing.
TALIESIN: I think I'm all right. I think
I may be
all right.
SAM: Why don't you toss that thing into
the acid just
in case?
TALIESIN: I'm going to do something
else.
SAM: Are you going to shoot your sister
like you
just pointed your gun at her?
What was that
about?
TALIESIN: You were the one who wouldn't
give me
the other gun.
SAM: I gave you the other gun.
TALIESIN: I'm going to go over to the
little lab
setup. Is there some acid
there?
MATT: Go ahead and make an intelligence
check.
TALIESIN: 17.
MATT: 17? Yeah, a brief look around you
can see
there are many different
compounds, different
strengths of acid, what a lot of the
initial
experimentation was.
TALIESIN: I'm going to start trying to
scar her
name off the barrel.
MATT: Okay. You take a moment and
eventually
manage to scar and dissolve
enough of the exterior
of that barrel until the name is no
longer
visible.
TALIESIN: I think it's fine.
SAM: (scoffs) You think it's fine?
LAURA: Lovely.
TALIESIN: You're going to have to have
some
faith.
SAM: I don't have any faith! Here, we'll
make a
deal. I'll let you keep that gun
if you give me
the other one.
TALIESIN: No.
(laughter)
LAURA: So glad that your smoke monster
is
seemingly gone, Percy. That's
wonderful news. The
spinning orb of death, however, is still
back
there, so we should probably figure
out what to do
about that.
TALIESIN: Well, I think perhaps we can
talk to
Keeper Yennen. Perhaps put
together some priests
to deal with that. Enlist the help of
the entire
town now that there's no
longer
a revolution to be fought.
TRAVIS: Yeah, that's a solid plan.
MARISHA: Oh, the revolution.
TALIESIN: We forgot about that.
MARISHA: We should go stop the fighting.
Right? We
should probably let them know
it's over.
LAURA: Probably.
TRAVIS: Well if they're fighting,
wouldn't it mean
it's not over?
MARISHA: Well, I'm sure they don't know
that the
Briarwoods are dead.
TALIESIN: So perhaps if we tell everyone
the
Briarwoods are dead. Cassandra?
TRAVIS: Maybe we'll see Ripley on the
way out.
TALIESIN: Wouldn't that be nice?
SAM: I just had a thought, Percy. I cast
Friends
on him.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: I think I know how to fix your gun,
if you
hand it to me.
TALIESIN: Never in my right mind would I
hand my
gun.
MATT: Go ahead and make a-- it'd be a
persuasion
check. And you go ahead and
make an insight check.
But you have an advantage on it. No, he
has
advantage on the persuasion, you do
not have it.
LIAM: While they're talking, can I
attempt to pull
it off of his belt?
MATT: Pull it off of Percy's?
TALIESIN: My insight is 21.
SAM: I rolled a natural 20.
TALIESIN: You are going to cost me so
much money.
LIAM: I see Scanlan kill it, and I just
step
back.
MATT: Okay. You look down at this gnome,
and while
he's normally pretty silly and
jovial, in this
moment, there's an honest spark of his
own
inspiration in his eyes.
TALIESIN: (whimpers) I'm so upset that I
have to
do this.
SAM: Wink!
TALIESIN: Going to kill you. I'm going
to kill
you.
TRAVIS: You don't know. He's your
friend. You're
not mad at all.
TALIESIN: For another three minutes.
LIAM: Yeah, roleplay for three minutes,
Taliesin.
TALIESIN: I hand him the broken gun.
MATT: Begrudgingly, you reach out and
place it in
his hand and release.
SAM: I say, thank you, Percy. I think,
in due
time, you will thank me
for this. And I toss it
into the acid. As I say, when the spell
fades
he's going to be super pissed,
somebody protect me!
MARISHA: Okay.
TRAVIS: You want to hop on my shoulders?
SAM: Yes. I go run and jump on Grog's
shoulders.
MATT: As you watch it arc forward, in
your head,
you're like, "That fucking
gnome." The spell
fades, you hear him say that, and just
as it
(plop, sizzle).
TRAVIS: You're not going to get that,
are you?
TALIESIN: I reach in to try and grab it
out.
LAURA: No, Percy! And I reach out and I
grab his
hands.
TRAVIS: He threw it! You threw it,
though, right?
TALIESIN: No, he dropped it!
MATT: He lobbed it. It wasn't a huge
throw.
MARISHA: I cast Hold Person at 3rd
level.
MATT: On?
MARISHA: Percy!
LAURA: As I reach up and I grab his
hands as
well!
TALIESIN: That was so expensive!
MATT: Make a wisdom saving throw with
advantage.
MARISHA: Son of a fuck.
MATT: Heroes' Feast, workin' against
you!
LIAM: You're the lord of Castle
Whitestone.
TALIESIN: Wisdom saving throw?
MATT: Yes.
TALIESIN: 18.
MATT: What's your DC?
MARISHA: My difficulty class? 18.
MATT: You're like, "That cost a--
(cracking)"
MARISHA: (laughs) I always fail rolls
against
Percy! It sucks!
MATT: A few moments pass. You don't even
see it
beneath the surface now. You just
see a little bit
of some fume released from whatever slow
process
is dissolving your gun.
LAURA: I step in front as he's
unconscious and I
go, Percy, dear.
You'll thank us for this later,
I know it.
TALIESIN: He's paying for a new one.
LAURA: I kiss his cheek and say, I'm so
sorry.
TALIESIN: He's paying for a new one.
MARISHA: We'll get you a new one, Percy.
TALIESIN: I'm going to have to-- oh god!
MATT: As you're watching this, from the
fume, a
small plume of black smoke goes
(whoosh).
LAURA and MARISHA: See?
MATT: And that cold nugget in the center
of your
chest is gone.
(cheering)
LAURA: It feels good, doesn't it?!
MARISHA: Doesn't it feel good?
TRAVIS: You fucking genius!
LAURA: It feels good!
(laughter)
TALIESIN: It was so expensive.
TRAVIS: Aw, come on!
TALIESIN: Oh, just throw the carpet in
there now,
why don't you?
MARISHA: Oh, Percival, that hurts.
MATT: Cassandra steps up to you and
takes your
head in her hands and forces
you to look at her
and goes, "Brother. We've all made
sacrifices for
this." She slaps you.
TALIESIN: (yelps)
MATT: Oh! That's a 21. 19 plus two.
SAM: He's held right now.
MARISHA: Still holding him in place.
LIAM: I hold my fist way up high to
Scanlan on
Grog's shoulder for a silent
little exploding fist bump.
MATT: And she looks to you and goes--
Cassandra
gives you a look to--
TALIESIN: You were never Mother's
favorite.
SAM: Let's not be petty.
TALIESIN: She told me!
SAM: Let's not be petty, Percy.
MARISHA: You sure you want to let him
go? You
sure? Did you hear what he just
said to you?
You sure?
MATT: It came out as (muffled angry
sounds).
MARISHA: I let it go.
MATT: Okay, your muscle control comes
back to you
and Cassandra is holding
your freshly slapped
face, gives you a look and goes,
"Brother. Let's go to our
people. Let's
tell them that for the first time in
"five years Whitestone is free."
TALIESIN: Oh god. Yeah. I'm letting it
go.
MATT: She reaches over and she takes
your arm in
her arm.
TALIESIN: Oh god.
MATT: She takes your arm in her arm and
begins
walking both of you back towards
the tunnels.
TALIESIN: That one was enchanted. Okay.
Two
enchantments. Yeah, all right.
MATT: And with that, we're going to go
ahead and take a
quick bathroom break.
Meet you guys back here in a
few minutes.
MARISHA: But you're still alive!
TALIESIN: I'm not alive!
LAURA: You're not controlled anymore!
[break]
MATT: Welcome back, folks! So. Let's go
ahead and
pick up where we left off. So,
as you guys return
to the undercroft of Whitestone,
Cassandra
carrying you, arm in arm. You
make your way up
through the stairs to the main base
floor of
Castle Whitestone. Are you guys
heading towards
your-- where are you heading from here?
MARISHA: I'm going to head straight for
the front
door and look in-- is there a
balcony on top?
MATT: You can check for the second floor
if you
want to.
LAURA: Overviews the city?
MATT: You have a pretty high view. It's
already
elevated on this platform, so
even from a ground-floor
area you can look down into the city.
TRAVIS: Front door.
MATT: Front door? All right, Grog walks
up to the
front door, being careful of
the scattered
caltrops you guys left there. The door
is still
ajar from where you left it. As
you step out and
look into the daylight, and it's at this
point
now, probably mid-afternoon,
pushing into evening.
You guys have been traveling underground
for quite
some time and taken a few
short rests, and have
had a lot of conflict and things happen.
So you
started at the start of the day.
You're now
pushing into towards dusk. But as you
open up and
look outside, with what
daylight is still there,
you see little plumes of smoke coming
from the far
city. Down the pathway that
leads up to Castle
Whitestone, you see about 70 to 100
armored
humanoids marching up towards
the front of the
castle.
SAM: Humanoids?
MATT: Bipedal.
TRAVIS: Can I pick up my caltrops?
MATT: You begin to pick up your
caltrops.
LAURA: I know what this is.
TRAVIS: Well, they're good guys.
SAM: No, it could be an undead army.
MATT: Make a perception check.
LAURA: I know what this is. Do I need
roll
perception if I know what it is?
MARISHA: Yeah, I was going to say.
TRAVIS: Wow! 19 minus...
MARISHA: 20.
TALIESIN: 27.
SAM: Five.
LAURA: 15.
MATT: All right. As you guys get your
weapons at
the ready--
TALIESIN: 25, sorry. Did the math wrong.
MATT: 25, okay. Percy and Vax, you
notice the
people approaching, spattered
in mud and various
types of ichor or blood. As they get
closer, you
can see beneath the helmets:
tired human faces.
Stepping up the side, weapons at the
ready. As
they approach the very front
of the line, you see
Keeper Yennen, equally exhausted,
stepping
forward, essentially ready to
storm the castle.
You see behind them as they approach a
scattered
cluster of broken corpses,
some human, some a
little less human. It looks like the
rebellion
army seems to have cut its way
through the
remaining defenders of Castle Whitestone
and are
making their way towards the
front of the castle.
As they get closer, they meet your gaze,
and the
front of the group draw their
weapons, and Yennen
steps forwards a little bit. "You there!
Percival."
TALIESIN: I step forward.
MATT: "Vox Machina. Are your wits about
you?"
TRAVIS: Yes?
MARISHA: Yes.
TALIESIN: The Briarwoods are dead.
MARISHA: It's true.
LIAM: Serpent's head has been cut off,
but there
is much to do.
MARISHA: Is it still cloudy?
MATT: It's a little cloudy. It's not
rainstorm
ready, but there's still sort
of an overcast feel.
MARISHA: I'm going to go ahead and at
third level,
because that's all I got
left, cast Skywrite
again, and throw up the de Rolo crest
once again
in the sky.
MATT: Okay. As you begin to coalesce the
clouds
and the symbol and the shapes,
you see a bunch of
the soldiers look around and Yennen
steps forward
again towards you and
goes, reaching up holding
his holy symbol of Erathis to his chest,
he goes,
"Are you certain this is done?
Percival."
TALIESIN: There's still a great evil
beneath the
castle, but the Briarwoods
are no more.
MATT: He turns around, looks to his men
who are
all looking at him expectantly.
"Well, you heard
"the man. The Briarwoods are dead.
Whitestone is
free once more!" He looks
up to the sky as the
symbol finishes from Keyleth's spell.
"The de
Rolos are in power once again!"
At which point the entire crowd shouts
"yeah!"
Their weapons to the sky, and as
the shouts begin
to echo down into the valley of
Whitestone, you
can see little lights
begin to burn in the distance,
little notification lanterns that are
being lit
and set at windowtops, at the
top of the mountain,
and you can see this look of relief and
joy on
every soldier's face as they all
realize that the
death they were all marching to face is
no longer
a threat. Cassandra, at this
point, is still
standing behind you at your side, and
really for
the first time since all of
this went down
beneath, you see a smile on her face.
Yennen turns around again and approaches
you all.
(sighs) "I don't know what to
say. Well, come.
"There's much to discuss. Let us step
from this
foul place for the time being.
Men! Walk through,
"make sure it's clean." And the some of
the
soldiers--
MARISHA: No!
TALIESIN: There's still a matter of some
things
beneath the castle that we must
deal with first.
MARISHA: No one should be allowed in for
right
now, until we figure this out.
MATT: "Very well. Men, seal the doors,
seal the
entrances. Keep watch."
MARISHA: We really need to rest.
MATT: "Then come. You've certainly
earned it." And
he motions to a few of
the guards.
MARISHA: What time of day is it? Do we
have a
sense? Is the sun still up?
MATT: The sun's still up, but you can
see from the
light source and the
darkening of the sky and the
color pushing from a general white-grey.
It's
going a little more reddish-orange.
MARISHA: Before we take a rest, I'm
going to look
at Percy, and I'm going to
be like, I'll catch up
with you guys. I think the people need
to see the
sun. And I'm going to go into
my air elemental
form, go up into the sky above
Whitestone, and do
my Whirlwind ability
and start trying to just push
all of the clouds out of the way to let
the sun
in.
MATT: All right, as you guys begin--
LAURA: Oh, did she freeze?
SAM: She's frozen in a beautifully
surprised
expression.
MATT: She can still hear us.
LAURA: Oh, she can still hear us but
she's
frozen.
SAM: Surprise!
MATT: You guys begin to march down
towards the
city with the rest of the
army. A group of about
ten men stay behind just to guard the
castle. As
you make you way to the
northern side of
Whitestone and you enter the streets
again, you
can see families beginning to
walk out of their
homes in the streets. In the entirety of
your time
here in Whitestone, most folks
that didn't need to
be out in the open stayed indoors, and
you begin
to realize this seeming ghost
city was hiding a
lot more life and a lot more hope than
you had
expected, and you see families,
and children,
stepping out, and as you walk through
the streets
you can see the kids wave.
You meet eyes with some
of the possible widows, who mouth to
you, "Thank
you".
LIAM: Seeing that--
TALIESIN: Can we pass by the Alcove?
LIAM: Seeing that, I'm going to do the
buddy arm
around the shoulder and pull
my sister in close.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: (clears throat) I walk up to a
particularly
handsome widow, and I say,
your husband--
LAURA: Pike is right here.
SAM: Oh. Your husband died for a good
cause,
thanks, bye.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Pike is shocked. Pike is
shocked and
offended.
SAM: Why are you looking at me like
that, Pike?
Pike, stop it!
MATT: As you walk away, she looks really
confused
and clutches her chest in
horror for a moment as
one of the soldiers walking with you
steps by her
side, looking at you
curiously, and gives her a
kiss on the cheek. She goes, "Who was
that man?"
SAM: Oh, sorry.
TALIESIN: Can we-- definitely want to
go, let's stop
by the Alcove.
MATT: Okay. You eventually start making
your way
towards the Alcove as you
enter deeper into the city.
LIAM: Pike, you there? Can you hear us?
MARISHA: Have I cleared up enough of the
sky at
this point?
MATT: We're going to get to that right
now,
actually.
MARISHA: I want to get to that.
MATT: As you guys are stepping-- I'm
sorry, what?
SAM: No, it's okay.
MATT: Pushing further in you can see now
the
clouds beginning to dissipate, and
also for the
first time since you've been here you
see blue sky
directly above the city.
The vibrant
orange-red-purple colors of the sunset
now come
cascading along the city of
Whitestone, and
there's a collective (gasps), an inhale
and gasp
of awe from the soldiers and
the people alike as
this opens up above you. You begin to
walk past.
The Alcove's to your left, if
you wish to--
TALIESIN: I want to stop in.
MATT: Okay. As you start heading towards
the Alcove
you can see Jordana is
already out on the front
stoop looking up at the sky. She looks
over and
sees you. "Percival!"
TALIESIN: I give her a big hug.
MATT: It takes her by surprise at the
moment, and
then she gives in and
continues to give the hug back.
TALIESIN: This would not have been
possible
without your help. Thank you
for everything.
MATT: "Of course." She leans into the
hug a little
bit, then nods and then
raises her head. "Did you
"see my father?"
TALIESIN: I have not. We have not
searched the
castle yet, though.
LAURA: We just left it? We haven't
searched the
castle?
MARISHA: We searched a little bit.
LAURA: But there could be live people in
there
when we sealed it?
TALIESIN: We don't know. It's not
airtight or
anything. I mean, they're
breathing.
SAM: Ripley's gone and also there's a
goliath on
the loose.
MATT: As you say this, Keeper Yennen
goes, "Not
anymore, there isn't. Follow
me."
ALL: Ooh.
SAM: Are there any young boys around?
MATT: He stops in his tracks and looks
over his
shoulder and goes, "What?"
SAM: I just need a young, fleet-footed
boy.
TRAVIS: See, the last time I asked for a
young boy
people gave me shit, too.
TALIESIN: No, we're going to give him
shit.
There's no problem here.
MATT: He slowly turns away and keeps
walking
forward.
SAM: Or a girl! No, wait, that sounds
weird.
TRAVIS: Yep. You can't say it in a right
way. It's
impossible. Innocent request.
MATT: The people have begun following
behind your
procession towards the
center of the city.
LIAM: Bring me your smallest, most
helpless
child.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: Oh god.
TRAVIS: That's fucked up.
TALIESIN: That's going to explode.
SAM: All right. Show us what you want to
show us,
Yennen.
MATT: You see behind you soldiers
reuniting with
their families, friends
gathering in the streets,
and the people of Whitestone are now
beginning to
join the sides of your
procession towards the
center of the Sun Square in the middle
of
Whitestone. As you crest into the
outskirts of the
square, Yennen gives a couple of
whispered orders
to a couple of the
soldiers, who rush off. You can
see people are now gathering in the
center and
there's actually people
gathering around the Sun Tree.
As they all step to the Sun Tree, it's a
little
quiet, and Keeper Yennen reaches
up and pulls his
holy symbol of Erathis again, looks up
to the tree
and looks back at the rest
of you and goes, "For
"generations, it was those of the Zenith
who looked
over this tree and these
people here, and it was
"by the evil that once held foot in this
town that
Father Reynal, the last of his
line, was slain. We
"will work to find those who wish to
take up the
mantle to clean and rebuild
the Zenith, the
"pinnacle of Pelor's grace here in
Whitestone. But
until that I, Yennen,
swear to make this tree's
"safety my responsibility. This symbol
of hope,
this center of the crest of
your family has held
"the slivers of light in our hearts for
a very long
time.
"Let us all take a moment and thank the
heroes who
made this freedom possible:
to the strong mountain
"of joy and bravery, Grog. To the
gentle, to the
kind, to the just soul,
Pike. To the swift of bow,
"keen of sight, and the most adorable
creature to
accompany her--" as Trinket
steps forward and
nuzzles your side-- "Trinket. By the
agility, by
the cunning, by the loyalty
of Vax. By the
"cleverness, by the wit, and the strange
interests
of Scanlan. By the honesty, by
the nature and
"connection with the world, and the
wonder of
Keyleth. And by the strength
of blood, and the
"willingness to sacrifice-- "
ASHLEY: (mic bump)
MATT: "Pardon me."
(laughter)
MATT: Damn it.
SAM: Start that one again?
LIAM: It's still very beautiful.
MARISHA: So beautiful.
TALIESIN: Two years on a sitcom. I can
hold this
all day.
(laughter)
MATT: God damn it.
LAURA: Percival's just waiting for his
introduction.
LIAM: To the stone-cold motherfucker on
air.
MATT: "To the return of those valiants
we once
thought lost, and those who rise
up to restore the
"joy of these people. Percival. May we
raise our
weapons, our glasses, and our
children, who accept
"this future to rebuild. Raise to Vox
Machina.
Hyah!" And everyone raises as
one loud--
TRAVIS: Yeah! Vox Machina!
MATT: As the sun slowly sets, the light
coming
through in beautiful colors now.
You see what was
once a very bleak town suddenly be
renewed with a
spectrum of new accents.
You begin to hear music
being played, as now the celebration
begins with
the sun's setting. Folks are
turning this into a
full celebration now. People are
starting to bring
out food and--
MARISHA: Block party!
MATT: (laughs) You feel this sense that
this is
the first time in a long time
the people have ever
really been allowed to be happy about
something.
And the energy is infectious
in itself. As the
celebration begins, though, Yennen puts
up his
hand and people begin to slow and
calm as
men begin to bring forward two
individuals in
chains. One of which you
see is a half-orc female
in dark brown leather armor. She is
chained and
thrown onto her knees onto
the ground, and she
spits; you can see there's a few cuts
across her
face and she looks dirty. And
right next to her,
taking four men to do so, a goliath
who's bruised
is also thrown onto his
knees and they're both
just held at that place.
Yennen says, "The two remaining new
nobles, given
power here as they aided
the Briarwoods in taking
"this city. We have Duke--" which the
people spit
at the sound of the name--
"Goran Vedmeyer. And
"Countess Jazna Graben. You have been
found guilty
of treason against this
town, of the
"responsibility of many lives lost,
innocent. And
for furthering the plans
of the evil that has
"oppressed us so long. I would wish that
you, the
ones who freed us, deliver the
judgment."
TRAVIS: (laughs)
LAURA: Come on.
TRAVIS: No, that sounds fair. I've known
to
preside over many legal matters in my
time as
Judgeface of Northwind.
LIAM: Define "legal."
MARISHA: Define "Judgeface."
TRAVIS: It would just baffle all of you.
It's all
right.
SAM: Grog, if I may. I can assist you in
this, if
you'd like.
TRAVIS: Oh, why of course, Sub-judge
Scanlan.
SAM: Thank you, Grog. Percival, this is
your
kingdom, so if you--
TALIESIN: I leave it to you.
LAURA: No.
TRAVIS: Yes. Even better.
SAM: These two have done much violence
to this
place. They represent all that
is evil.
MATT: "Wait." And Goran, who is now down
on the
ground, looks up at you and goes,
"I know you."
SAM: Never saw you before, friend.
TALIESIN: This is what I really wanted
to see.
SAM: You have a lovely house, by the
way. Or had
one.
(laughter)
MATT: Spits on the ground at your feet.
SAM: Might need a new roofer. Anyway. In
a show of
grace and to demonstrate our
new hope that we have
for this place, I suggest that we don't
kill these
two.
TRAVIS: What?
SAM: But rather force them to help
rebuild the
place that they helped
destroy.
LAURA: In chains. Very heavy chains.
SAM: One of them at least is extremely
strong. The
other one must have some
sort of skill.
MATT: She for the first time looks up
with this
gnarly toothy grin. You can
see these partially
broken and jagged teeth in her mouth,
and she
goes, "Come closer. I've never
tasted gnome."
SAM: Okay, so maybe we'll kill her.
LAURA: Would you rather die?
TRAVIS: What kind of weapons did these
two have on
them?
MATT: The men look about themselves and
Yennen,
"Not entirely certain. However,
she has been known
"to carry a quiver or two, and this one
here wields
a blade as long as his
body."
LIAM: The Briarwoods are broken and
gone. You can
die today, or you can take
your licks and help
rebuild this city. No one is here to
protect you
or save you. You can work
hard, start again.
MATT: Make a persuasion check. With
advantage,
based on their current
circumstance.
LIAM: Intimidation, you said, or
persuasion?
MATT: Whichever you'd prefer.
LIAM: It's average, it's 13.
MATT: 13? Okay. You can see the goliath,
Vedmeyer,
lowers his head. "I accept.
Jazna?"
She looks over. "It seems you lack what
has kept
me alive all these years: a
spine. Kill me. I'd
"rather not stay at your beck and call."
TRAVIS: Okay.
TALIESIN: Grog.
TRAVIS: I reach over and I take out my
greataxe
and I aim it for her neck.
MATT: Okay, as, did you swing or just
aim it?
TRAVIS: Yeah, swing for the neck.
Beheading-style.
MATT: Make a strength check.
TRAVIS: Natural 20.
(laughter)
LIAM: Merry Christmas, Travis.
MATT: As you pull the axe out and you
walk
alongside with it almost like a
cane,
look down at her--
TRAVIS: Yeah, like a cane.
MATT: (impact noise) And with speed and
deftness
where no one sees the blade
make contact, there is
a moment where the head just drifts off
the form,
leaving the base, the throat
cleanly cleaven.
Cloven, if you will, sorry. There's a
moment of
pause before the blood begins
to pour from the
wound, it was so fast and so immediate,
and the
body just slumps forward.
There's a gasp in the
crowd suddenly, and then a cheer as the
locals now
see one of the people that
probably oppressed,
tortured, and killed many of their folk
now lies
on the ground, killed.
TRAVIS: I look at the axe and look at
the blood
covering it and I look over at
Duke Gonad and I
say, so, where are you from and how did
you come
to be in the service of the
Briarwoods?
MATT: "I was hired in Wildmount."
TRAVIS: Do I know where that is?
MATT: You don't. You've heard it said
before.
You've heard it mentioned, but
you have no idea
where it is.
TRAVIS: Right, the holy lands of the
sacred-- all
right.
SAM: Are you okay, your honor?
TRAVIS: Yes, thank you for-- I am quite
tired.
Would you like to take it from
here?
SAM: No.
TALIESIN: While we always must dispense
our
justice, this is now a town of mercy
as well. And
I will expect nothing less from all of
us than to
give what we have lacked for
so long. Duke.
SAM: Let hers be the last blood shed.
TALIESIN: Earn your life again.
MATT: He nods and looks down. You can't
tell if
it's shame or just defeat, but
his shoulders slump
and that little bit of fire that was in
him when
he arrived is broken. The men
look at you, they
get your nod and they lift the chains
and pull
them off while a couple of the
men pick up the
body of the half-orc woman and pull them
out of
the crowd. The music swells up
once again, and the
celebration continues without a beat.
You can now
see tables being brought out
to the center and
glasses are set about and drinks are
being poured
as a giant central table
right at the base of the
Sun Tree is set for you.
TALIESIN: They've just had this shit in
a
Tupperware container, like in those
big bins in
the back for the last five years with
like
duct-tape lids.
MATT: It's not a grand meal, there
hasn't been a
lot of time to prepare for
it, but basically what
it looks like is whoever is preparing
dinner or
whatever food was readily
available, they're just
bringing it out. It's more of like a
share-with-whoever's-there type effort.
MARISHA: Aw, it's a potluck.
MATT: Kind of.
SAM: I find a young boy.
MATT: Yes, Scanlan?
SAM: Or a soldier, and I give him 15
gold and I
say,
for the love of god, find me a fucking
beret.
MATT: "All right, sir." And the boy
takes the gold
and rushes off, looking
in his hands at the boon
he's been given by this
practically-same-height
man. They don't
see gnomes here very often; it's
been very confusing.
TALIESIN: I want to take some time to
tell Keeper
Yennen about what is beneath
the tree and let him
start to macerate some theories on what
to do--
TRAVIS: Macerate? That's a big word.
MATT: After you finish this
conversation, he sits
there and--
TALIESIN: It's a word for big name.
Thank you. Do
it.
MATT: A few moments pass before the boy
returns,
in his hand a (singing)
raspberry beret, the kind
you find in a secondhand store.
SAM: Oh, feels good.
LAURA: Make it look cooler on him,
because he made
it look dorky.
TALIESIN: It's a beret. I don't think he
made it
dorky. I think it comes with
that already sewn in.
LAURA: There it is, looks good. It looks
good,
Scanlan.
SAM: Thank you, young boy. Whatever your
name was.
What was your name, young boy?
MARISHA: Make it good.
MATT: "Randall?"
SAM: Thank you, Randall. You've made me
a very
happy small man.
MATT: And he brings you the change.
SAM: Oh no, keep the change, it's all
right. Go
buy yourself a goose. The
biggest goose in town.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: With a beret.
MATT: And he darts off excitedly. You
catch him
out of the corner of your eye
like stealing a swig
of beer--
SAM: Brandon Gilmore, that was his young
name.
LAURA: Brandon Gilmore?
SAM: Yes.
MATT: Thank you, Brandon. So after you
finish
regaling this tale to Keeper
Yennen, let's see if
I have a proper song for celebration.
TRAVIS: I'm doing my best to empty the
cask of ale
into the town patrons and
myself.
TALIESIN: I don't know if that's-- less
aviary than
celebratory.
MATT: Yeah, unfortunately.
MARISHA: Can Keyleth go over and check
out the Sun
Tree?
MATT: Sure, as you're walking over
there, we'll
finish this conversation
here. Yennen nods to
himself and goes, "That is
disconcerting. I'll
reach out to a few
of my contacts, see who we can
"bring here to inspect it. I may go down
tomorrow
myself and have a look. Is it
safe?"
TALIESIN: No. There are traps. We've
marked them.
It's also disturbing.
MATT: "All right. I'll bring a trusted
team down,
then. If there's anyone you
know who has vast
"historical or arcane knowledge, I would
recommend
possibly having them come take
a look as well.
"Unfortunately, I'm rather limited in my
teachings."
SAM: Pike?
LAURA: Allura?
SAM: But she's not in town.
TALIESIN: We can send word.
MATT: "Please do."
LAURA: What about Ryndarien?
MARISHA: Eskil?
MATT: There was Eskil Ryndarien, the
archmage in
Westruun.
LIAM: Yes. Either, both.
MATT: "Good, good, yes, anyone at all.
Maybe I'll
be able to glean something,
but unfortunately most
"of our books were confiscated when the
town was
taken. However, I appreciate
that, and at least
"for the time being, there doesn't seem
to be any
dead rising from the grave."
SAM: If I may, Percy, may I make a
suggestion?
TALIESIN: Is it going to be throwing the
rest of
my guns into a pit of acid?
SAM: No, but it will be spending some of
your
kingdom's money.
TALIESIN: Replacing the guns that you
threw into a
pit of acid.
SAM: Let's not talk about the guns.
TALIESIN: I really can't think of what
else I'd
want to talk about. Please, go
ahead.
SAM: If most of their books have been
taken from
them, perhaps we could use
some of the treasury to
build a library.
TALIESIN: That is not a terrible idea,
and it's
possible that the books are
still within the
castle.
LAURA: It's possible that the Briarwoods
have
hoarded all of them. In fact, we
might find
something about this entity inside the
castle.
TALIESIN: And we do need to build three
new
structures where the lords' houses
were, and I
find the idea of rebuilding those
mansions to be a
bit distasteful.
SAM: Perhaps we could even name one of
the
libraries Gilmore's Glorious Books.
TRAVIS: Set up a satellite chain?
TALIESIN: We will discuss it. It's got a
ring, I
will admit.
MATT: While you guys are having this
conversation--
LIAM: Oh, I was just going to add to
that, I'm
sure the man can help
in this city's time of need.
TALIESIN: You were doing something, as
well.
MATT: Yes. Keyleth, at this point, as
you've
walked away from this
conversation, you approach
the Sun Tree. It stands there with a
little bit of
light as the sun's just
now passing over the
distant mountain range that surrounds
this valley.
The sky's growing more
purple and dark blue. But
now lights have been lit and lanterns
have been
brought to the center, you can
see the Sun Tree in
full before you.
MARISHA: I reach up and I put my hand on
it and I
cast Commune With Nature. Do I
gather anything?
MATT: What does Commune With Nature do
in full?
TALIESIN: It lets you commune with
nature.
MARISHA: Essentially.
MATT: Oh, look at that, first page I
open up to.
Okay.
TALIESIN: It's like a DM version of
natural 20.
LAURA: It is. Except he does it all the
time.
MATT: Okay, so which do you want to
know, of all
the things that you can
choose from?
MARISHA: Oh, what are my choices?
MATT: You can choose from terrain or
bodies of
water in the vicinity;
prevalent plants, minerals,
animals, or peoples; powerful
celestials, fey,
fiends, or elementals
or undead within 300 feet of
it-- or sorry, within three miles of it;
influence
from other planes of
existence; or buildings.
MARISHA: The influence of other planes
of
existence sounds promising.
MATT: Okay, you gain three facts. So,
first off,
you notice as you touch the
Sun Tree and you cast
the spell, whereas previously you felt
just dead
wood and a lack of any
presence, there is a small
seed of life in the tree once again.
MARISHA: That's good.
MATT: We'll call that the first one, as
a given.
As you inquire about any other
planes of
existence, you do sense that at least
some element
nearby relates to a realm
of shadow.
LAURA: That's obvious.
MARISHA: Yeah, sure, okay.
MATT: And what's the third one you want
to know?
MARISHA: Oh, I get a choice?
MATT: Yep.
MARISHA: I didn't know I had a choice.
MATT: You don't have to ask anything
else if you
don't want to, if you got
everything you wanted.
MARISHA: I want to know if-- god, so
many options.
Is it going to be a good
growing season this
spring? Crops going to be good? It's
going to be a
good harvest moon?
LAURA: Ask how it's feeling, can you ask
how it's
feeling?
MARISHA: How's it feeling? Can I ask the
tree how
it's feeling, can I be like,
"Hey tree. How are
"you doing today?"
MATT: That is very Keyleth.
MARISHA: You doing all right? How do you
feel
between all this, about all this?
MATT: You sense--
SAM: Hey, boo.
MARISHA: Hey, boo.
MATT: You sense weariness, like
something very old
that has been asleep
for a very long time has
woken up.
MARISHA: Does it feel positive?
MATT: Positive.
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: The Sun Tree, seemingly kept at
bay, locked
away, what bit of its life
force it managed to
maintain had been contained for so long
and is now
finally free.
MARISHA: Can I just say, good morning,
old
friend.
MATT: You sense the tree saying, "The
sun just
set. It's not morning."
MARISHA: I go, oh shit. And then I turn
to Percy
and I say, the tree talked to
me.
TALIESIN: In that ancient way that trees
talk.
MARISHA: You just had a smoke monster
you were
talking to, is it that hard to
believe?
MATT: (Ent voice) It's... not...
morning...
TALIESIN: Thank you.
LIAM: I watched her walk up to the tree
and I
followed her--
TRAVIS and SAM: Oh no.
LAURA: Here we go.
LIAM: Here we go. I follow her up and I
don't say
anything, but I see one hand
on the tree and
without saying anything--
TRAVIS: I walk up behind Vax and I pants
him.
LAURA: Yes!
TRAVIS: And I grab the back of his
collar and pull
backwards.
SAM: That's the revenge.
LIAM: Are you going to roll anything?
MATT: Okay. So.
LIAM: I'm not sure what he did though.
Pantsing?
TRAVIS: I grabbed your pants and I
pulled them
down to your ankles.
LIAM: But what's the part about the
collar?
TRAVIS: I grabbed the back of your neck
and pulled
you backwards with your pants
around your ankles.
LIAM: Okay. He's got to roll, but if it
happens,
it happens.
MATT: Right. I would consider this a
grapple
check. So it's your athletics
versus your
acrobatics.
LAURA: What about the pantsing? Is that
included?
MATT: That is the pantsing.
TRAVIS: 20, plus--
MATT: Wait, natural 20?
TRAVIS: No, 19 plus-- 26. My athletics
is plus
seven.
LIAM: I rolled a 32.
TRAVIS: Damn it.
MATT: As you reach out and are about to
grasp the
sides, he leaps straight up in
the air and then
lands a foot in front of you. You grab
nothing and
see him glance over his
shoulder and tsk-tsk.
LIAM: I knew that was going to happen.
TRAVIS: That's all right. It could've
been now.
It'll just be worse later.
SAM: Nice try, Grog.
LIAM: You already took my left nut off
my body.
TRAVIS: Oh, please. That was but
appetizers for the
main course, my
friend.
LIAM: All right, so that's challenge
number one,
now challenge number two.
So, I still don't say
anything besides (inhale) as I jump to
the side
really fast to not loose my
breeches. And she's
got one hand on the tree, and I just
quietly, with
her free hand and my free
hand, try to lace my
fingers with hers.
MATT: Against the tree?
LAURA: Oh my gosh, you guys are
boyfriend and
girlfriend now.
MATT: As you finish your awkward
it's-not-morning
conversation with the
essence of the Sun Tree--
TALIESIN: It's morning somewhere.
MARISHA: As I'm talking, good morning,
Sun
Tree.
MATT: You feel a strange alien hand in
your left
free hand for a moment,
unexpectedly.
MARISHA: I jump and I yank away
instinctually.
MATT: Okay, she pulls away from it and
looks over
her shoulder with a bit of
surprise and sudden
horror.
LIAM: I shrug and look.
MARISHA: I was just talking to the tree.
It talked
back.
LIAM: I don't say anything.
(long pause)
MARISHA: (giggling) Everyone is hiding.
SAM: I'm giving them privacy.
LAURA: You get privacy. It's your
moment.
MATT: So? Vax just stands there, not
saying
anything, just looking at you.
LIAM: I already said it.
MATT: Don't look at them.
MARISHA: I'm sorry. I don't know. I'm
really
confused.
LIAM: Vax says, all right. And walks
off.
MARISHA: Wait. I'd be lying if I said
often at
night when I go to sleep, your
face isn't the last
thing that crosses my mind. But with the
weight of
the world and the weight of
the
contact-embarrassment from our fellow
party,
currently, it's hard to focus on.
(hesitantly) You
said that when you were near death. We
say a lot
of things when we're near
death. How do I know
that's what you were truly feeling?
LIAM: I didn't say it out loud, I just
thought
it.
MATT: No, you told her.
MARISHA: Oh yeah, no, you said that out
loud.
Yeah, no, that wasn't in your
head.
LIAM: I wore a mask for a long time,
where I grew
up. And I'm not going to do
that anymore. I'll wait.
MARISHA: Wait?
LIAM: For you.
MARISHA: Okay. I don't know what else to
say right
now. I'm really tired. Really
tired. I think
there's also a part of me that's just
afraid.
LIAM: I feel like I'm going to get
pantsed by a
goliath at any moment.
Don't do anything. Don't
change anything. I haven't lied. I've
told the
truth. If you'll have me, I'm
yours. If you don't
want me, I understand. And that's all
there is to
say. And then I actually
walk off.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: I stay by the tree.
MATT: Okay. As this is happening and he
walks off,
you guys are there at the
table, just now noticing
the both of them have been missing. You
see
Keyleth, stunned, standing by the
Sun Tree as
Keeper Yennen approaches you once again
and goes,
"My friends. We have a lot of
work to do and it
"would not be fair for me to assume, as
you've
already done so much for us, but
it has been a
"while since we've had much to celebrate
in this
town, and this evening seems a
fine
"improvisational event. But we have two
weeks until
the Winter's Crest festival
would be happening
"here in Whitestone, something we have
not
celebrated in near five years. I
would just ask,
"should you be interested, if you would
wish to
stay with us these next couple
of weeks to help us
"rebuild and perhaps aid in preparing
the first
real shining moment in
Whitestone's history since
"you were gone."
LAURA: Percival?
TALIESIN: I would be very grateful.
LAURA: We're here.
TALIESIN: We shall.
MATT: Cassandra nods, as well.
LAURA: Keeper, may I ask for a small
request?
Could you maybe send a
wonderfully worded letter
to Uriel and let him know how we saved
the day and
how much you love us?
MATT: He looks very confused. "I imagine
that
could be-- I assume that could be
done, yes."
LAURA: That would be wonderful. Make
sure you
mention how terrible the
Briarwoods were and how
Vox Machina saved the day. Truly saved
it--
SAM: We can write it for you if you just
want to
sign it at the bottom.
LIAM: That guy's going to wake up this
morning and
go, "oh, I'm an asshole."
LAURA: Please? Yes, that would be
wonderful.
MATT: "All right. It'll be done."
LAURA: Thank you.
TRAVIS: Facepalm.
LIAM: "Aw, what was I thinking. Oh."
MATT: And so as the rest of you join in
the
merriment, or whatever else you wish
to do for the
evening, looking about post-sunset as
night
descends on Whitestone, to the
first clear sky
since you've arrived. To the first
evening where
you can hear smiles,
cheers, and laughter, we'll
pick up next week with the Winter's
Crest festival
in Whitestone.
(cheering)
LAURA: You should've kissed her, it was
the
perfect moment!
LIAM: I already did it.
LAURA: No but it was the perfect moment!
LIAM: You don't want it to happen
anyway.
LAURA: I don't care, this is out of
character! It
would have been the
perfect moment!
LIAM: I never said I was smart.
MATT: It makes for fun drama. That was
crazy.
TRAVIS: How am I going to beat your
acrobatics?
LIAM: You are not.
ZAC: So we gotta get ready for Critmas.
So we're
going to go offline and back up
so we can make
sure we get this episode uploaded to you
guys on
Monday. The longer the video,
the longer it takes
to transcode and sometimes makes it take
longer to
get up, so we'll be going
offline and then
right back up for Critmas, guys.
LAURA: Yay!
MATT: See you back here in just a few
minutes,
guys. Don't leave. We'll be
here!