MARISHA: And I cast my Skywrite spell--
ew, I just
spit-- and I use the smoke in
the distance and as
it's rising up into the sky, start
drawing out the
de Rolo family crest in
the smoke.
MATT: Okay. You begin to take the plume
of smoke
and filter into the dark rain
clouds and you make
the smoke go to a thicker, thicker black
and take
the next few moments to begin
sculpting in the air
until eventually we have a very
well-defined de
Rolo crest now staring
down at the entire city of
Whitestone.
SAM: Oh! Something's happening!
Something's
happening in the sky!
MARISHA: That's me.
SAM: I think it's a magic wielder of
some sort.
Something-- I must flee!
(laughter)
MATT: All right. Investigation checks
from both of
you.
LAURA: Okay.
TRAVIS: Did I find anything on
Smash-Face?
LIAM: (sighs) That's what you rolled the
last
time.
LAURA: I know!
TALIESIN: 16.
LAURA: I've got to put this one away for
a while.
MATT: What did you roll?
LAURA: I rolled a nine.
MATT: Okay. The two of you take a while
upstairs
looking about the rooms. You
manage to acquire
from just some of the local bits of
cabinets and
dust, you gather about 230
gold pieces.
LAURA: 230?
MATT: Just loose gold pieces that are
around.
There is a nice jewelry box that
seems to contain
most of the jewels and gems that this
individual
likes.
LAURA: I'm going to take the whole
jewelry box and
sort through it later.
MATT: Okay. So say a box of Tylieri's
jewelry
would be what you've marked
down.
TALIESIN: Tylieri family jewels.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: That won't be confusing at
all.
MATT: There you go. You do notice,
however, that's
all you're able to find
for the most part, other than
some few bits of clothing and outfit.
The master
bedroom has no bed.
LAURA: Does he sleep in a coffin?
TALIESIN: We're going to finish
searching
downstairs and then find the
entrance to the--
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: I'd like to wind my way up there,
as well.
MATT: Okay, as you make your way up
there you
notice them stepping out.
LIAM: Yeah. I'm still curious. I want to
go have a
look as well.
MATT: Go for it. Investigation.
LAURA: That's better, thank you.
LIAM: 16.
MATT: 16? You look through the room.
Most
everything of interest has already
been picked
clean. This room also doesn't seem to
see much use
other than the clothing
that's in there. This room
is used for dressing and presentational
purposes
but other than that, as a
bedroom, it's pretty
useless. As you guys go downstairs,
we'll say for
the sake of brevity you
take a little bit of time
to start looking through. You know
you're a little
pressed for time because
you can feel the energy
in the town begin to rise and you start
hearing
noises. You keeping an eye out?
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: The people that rush into the
rooms are now
rushing back out, some of
them wearing leather
tunics and small bits of armor, their
weapons
gathered, and they're forming
small bands.
MARISHA: I come over the speakers once
again, the
ear pieces. "I think it's
time to go. Whenever you
"guys are ready, I want to light this
bitch up."
TRAVIS: We need to check all the rooms
that go
downstairs first.
MARISHA: All right, quick.
TRAVIS: "Got an empty house." I run out
to the
door to the left. To the
uncovered areas.
MATT: Okay. You go over to this hallway.
You
eventually smash the door, doesn't
take too long.
It leads into what looks like a small
study or
some sort of an office room. A
big blue rug, a
desk with a chair, some papers strewn
about.
TRAVIS: Can I grab the rug and yank it?
MATT: Yeah, pull the rug off, reveals a
hatch.
TRAVIS: (excited shouting) I found a
hatch!
LAURA: (cries out in pain) No need to
yell!
TRAVIS: Oh sorry. (quieter) I found a
hatch.
TALIESIN: Quick, I just want to do a
quick round
of the downstairs room
before going to the hatch.
MATT: Okay. Glancing about, you find
what looks to
be a general sitting area,
a music room, or a
place where you would host guests. Also
in fair disuse.
And then beyond that,
you find a room that's
pretty bland, with a staircase that
leads down
into what was once servants'
quarters that has
been converted into a torture room.
LAURA: Oh, lovely.
MATT: It's a little nicer in its
presentation and
tools than the duergar
torture room that you
encountered in the Underdark, but this
looks to be
like Tylieri had a definite
interest in
entertaining unwanted guests.
TALIESIN: Okay.
TRAVIS: Vax or Vex, will you come check
this hatch
for boobies?
(laughter)
LIAM: I jog on down.
MATT: All right, make a perception
check.
LIAM: Yeah. That's a 23.
MATT: Yeah, it does not appear to be
trapped.
TRAVIS: No boobies.
LIAM: Okay. You want to open that, big
guy?
TRAVIS: Yeah! (growls)
MATT: (vroom) The hatch comes up. There
is no
ladder; it's just a ten-foot drop
down into a
basement.
TRAVIS: Okay, I jump.
MATT: Land down there. A 20 foot by 20
foot room.
It's very musty. However, you
do see in the far
corner there is a pad of fresh earth set
up, and
there is a dark box.
TRAVIS: Um.
MATT: About eight feet long.
LIAM: I hear him say "Um," and I jump
down, too.
With the Flametongue dagger
out for light.
MATT: Okay. The room lights up a little
bit and
you can see across the way there
is a not
super-detailed, but a fairly
well-crafted coffin
on the opposite side
of the room.
TRAVIS: Ooh! I bet there's treasure in
there!
LIAM: You might be right. Yeah, let's go
have a
look.
LAURA: Is there treasure? Did you find
treasure?
LIAM: "Hold, please." Perception check
the coffin.
That's a 20.
MATT: Okay. The coffin does not appear
to be
trapped?
TRAVIS: Can I open it?
MARISHA: He said that with a question
mark.
MATT: It's always fun to do that.
TRAVIS: Well, should I just smash it?
LIAM: I really feel like this could be--
LAURA: Smash it!
TRAVIS: Three, two. Grog smashes.
LIAM: I kick it off with the end of my
foot.
Little bit. Or try to.
MATT: Okay. (boof) The lid flies off and
then
slams on the ground. A smell hits
you that's just
like musty old mildewed earth. The
inside of the
coffin is, it's lined with
like a fine purplish
velvet material, the smell quickly
fades. It looks
like there are some
small baubles in there,
keepsakes. There is what looks to be a
cape or a
cloak that is laid across the
bottom of this for
comfort.
LIAM: Roll it up. Put it into my
satchel. I'm
going to take a dagger out
and I want to cut all
the way up through that purple velvet.
Just see,
just in case.
MATT: Okay. You cut through the purple
velvet.
Rummage through underneath. It
appears to be the
back of the box.
TALIESIN: I'm going to check his desk
upstairs for
anything interesting.
MATT: Okay. Want to make an
investigation check?
TALIESIN: Natural 20.
MATT: As you're rummaging through the
notes in the
desk, a lot of them are
ledgers involving the
trade in and out of the city. He has his
hands
dabbling in elements of the timber
trade, elements
of the actual trade of whitestone. He
talks about
the-- and you understand,
the reason that
Whitestone itself is-- the stone that's
mined here
is so popular for
construction and architecture
and other elements is the stone that
these
mountains are made of, when
properly prepared,
there is a faint bit of residuum that is
naturally
ingrained in the rock here. No
one really knows
how it came about, but whatever it is,
while it is
not inherently magical, it
makes it a little bit
easier, faster, and cheaper to enchant
the stone.
So when it comes to, you
know, enchanting a
teleportation circle permanently
somewhere or for
traps or things-- not
actual objects but actually
enchanting anything made of stonework.
It's easier
to enchant, and that's why
the whitestone of this
area is sought after and a good trade
element. So
there's notes about that.
But the stone trade has
been halted, all stone has continued to
be mined,
but it's not being
transported.
TRAVIS: Is the desk made out of the
stone?
MATT: No, there's just notes about it.
So all the
whitestone that is being
mined is not being
exported. It's being kept here,
somewhere.
LAURA: They're making something big.
TALIESIN: They're making something big.
LIAM: I think we need to get out of
here.
TRAVIS: I was going to ask, are you good
with the
coffin?
LIAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Okay. I smash the shit out of
it, in an
effort to see what's
underneath.
MATT: Okay. You take about 30 seconds of
extreme
violence against the wooden
coffin, killing it
into chunks and blocks. You get the
feeling that
this may have been the
place the mist was
trying to get to. But it did not make
its journey.
It got scattered by druid
Sunbeam and destroyed,
and the coffin is left in ruins. You
do-- even you,
Grog-- absorb the fact
that when a vampire goes to
mist form, you get the feeling that this
is the
home it needs to come to, to try
and survive.
TRAVIS: Not anymore.
MATT: Not anymore. Not that one.
MARISHA: Do I see anyone coming?
MATT: Oh. You see another zombie giant
coming up
the way. You can see people
attacking it, it's
just thrashing them about, but this one
seems less
bothered by the group and is
now moving towards a
specific area, moving towards the fiery
plume
in the distance. They're all
gathering in that
direction.
MARISHA: But no one seems to be rushing
towards
this house?
MATT: Not at the moment, no.
TRAVIS: This one's not on fire. Yet.
MATT: All right, you all gather, you can
hear the
rainstorm itself is coming down
in sheets. What
do you want to do?
TRAVIS: Light this candle!
LAURA: Should we light this on fire,
too?
TALIESIN: Burn it to the ground.
MARISHA: "Everyone out." And I start
casting a
Flaming Sphere.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: We're out by now.
MARISHA: Everyone out.
MATT: You guys all step out into the
rain
(whooshes) pouring down. What bits
of guard blood
that have been pressed against you
washes off.
TRAVIS: Aw.
MARISHA: I peek in this foyer. And just
(boof),
right in the middle, and take a
minute to
move it all around.
MATT: A Flaming Sphere begins to
corkscrew around
this room, up over the
banister, up to the upper
area, and like an artist, you paint this
entire
room with flame until the entire
interior of this
main foyer is just an inferno. You can
hear the
flames licking and the light is
very bright. You
end up backing up and you can see
people,
unarmored folk in nearby homes
that are pressed up
against their windows watching this
happen and
whispering to each other. The
children, those that
are kept guarded and are not part of
this
rebellion, they are watching this
with smiles.
MARISHA: Okay, I think that's good
enough.
Let's go.
TALIESIN: Head back to the curiosity
shop.
LAURA: Yeah, sneaky, stealthing.
MATT: Okay. As you guys run off into the
alley
behind--
LAURA: Pass Without a Trace I cast on
all of us.
MATT: Okay. How many more spells do you
have at
that level? Because you used it
several times
today.
LAURA: Yeah, I'm fine with Pass Without
a Trace.
That's a 1st-level. 2nd-level,
but I'm fine.
TALIESIN: Back to the alcove, then?
MATT: You guys all dart off into the
alley under
the cover of the shadows of
the storm and the
rainfall, to head towards the alcove,
and we'll go
ahead and take a quick
break.
(cheering)
MATT: A quick break, I know I always say
that, I'm
not going to say five minutes,
but.
SAM: This one's a real quick break.
MATT: We'll take it real quick because
we want to
try and get through as much
of the story before we
get to Critmas.
LAURA: Critmas!
LIAM: Critmas! Crimmas.
TALIESIN: Oh dear god.
TRAVIS: It's going to be a thing.
MATT: Which is going to, which is going
to take
some time tonight. Be back here
in a few minutes
guys, we'll see you in a sec.
TRAVIS: Pizza!
[break]
MATT: Welcome back. So. Jumping back
into the
chaos, the party has scattered
back into the
rainstorm. I would like everyone to make
a stealth
check.
LAURA: Oh, right. Plus ten for
everybody.
MATT: Plus ten.
LIAM: I did all right.
TALIESIN: I rolled my disadvantage.
TRAVIS: Does it matter on a one?
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: Ten?
MATT: Total ten?
TRAVIS: Total ten. 11.
LAURA: 11, technically.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: 29.
LIAM: 43.
SAM: I'm not there.
TRAVIS: 43?
MATT: Well, you're making your own
stealth,
though. You're invisible, so
just roll twice.
SAM: Natural 20.
MARISHA: 28.
TALIESIN: 30.
MATT: Okay. So making up for the
bounding chaos
that is Grog throughout
the city, you manage to
still make your way largely as a group
stealthed
to-- are you heading to the
alcove, you said?
TALIESIN: That's where we had our little
crash-base set up, right?
MATT: Correct. All right. You make your
way to the
alcove. As you're darting
through, you can see in
the distance small pocketed sounds of
yells and
the occasional sound of some
sort of large-scale
crumbling or crashing of wood and
stone.
Occasionally, darting past the
streets, you see
militant occupants of Whitestone:
armored, rushing
through, shouting
orders to each other, some
coming back wounded and helping their
friends
back. The midday rebellion has
definitely started,
and you get the sense that the initial
surprise
has been effective, but the
longer this runs, the
longer this wears on, the more and more
of a body
count this will be.
TRAVIS: Seeing the chaos, can I get the
Dust of
Tracelessness and start trying
to sprinkle it
behind us?
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: Guys, we should do something.
LAURA: I know, we really should.
SAM: Am I with these guys yet?
MATT: You have not, but you all meet up
back at
the alcove, communicating over
your earpieces. You
make your way to the front of the
building. The
doors are closed and
locked.
LIAM: The alcove?
TRAVIS: Closed and locked?
LIAM: I'll see about that. I'm going to
check the
door.
MATT: Go for it.
LIAM: That is ten. 23.
MATT: Okay. Seems to be a fairly simple
lock.
LIAM: All right.
TRAVIS: Look for an ambush around. Can
we look
around?
LAURA: Yeah, perceive it?
TRAVIS: Rooftops? Sides of the building?
MATT: Make a perception check, guys.
MARISHA: All of us?
SAM: Me too?
MATT: Not you, you haven't gotten there
yet.
LIAM: 20.
TRAVIS: I actually rolled a 17.
MARISHA: 12.
TALIESIN: 24.
LAURA: 26.
MATT: Okay. Looking about, there doesn't
appear to
be any set ambush or anybody
else here. You do
hear the soft sound of pacing footsteps
in the
interior.
LAURA: Should we knock on the door?
TRAVIS: Canvass the building.
LIAM: I can get in there and see who
that is. I
can go in, yeah.
LAURA: They're right on the inside.
LIAM: I thought it was upstairs, or you
said right
on the other side of the
door?
LAURA: Right on the other side of the
door.
MARISHA: Oh, for crying out loud. I push
past
them I just go, Jordana! Jordana,
it's us!
MATT: Okay, there's a pause and a voice
goes,
"Who's us?"
LAURA: Oh. Crazy grandma!
MARISHA: And Vox Machina. (quietly) Does
she know
we're called that?
LAURA: No. I don't know. (louder) Crazy
grandma
was staying with you. Crazy
peasants.
MARISHA: Allies.
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
MARISHA: Son of a-- nine?
LAURA: Can I help?
LAURA AND MARISHA: Crazy grandma!
MARISHA: Crazy grandma can help!
MATT: I'll say since you're backing her
failure
up, go ahead and make it with
disadvantage.
MARISHA: Hey, you don't have to call
it-- that
sounds so sad when you say it
like that.
LAURA: 18.
MATT: 18. There's a pause. "Crazy
grandma? Come
in." You hear the sound of
a locking sound and the
door opens up ever-so-slightly. A very,
very dimly
lit interior, there's a small
lantern, a hooded
lantern across the room. Other than
that, you see
the shadow of Jordana as
she ushers you all in out
of the rain.
LAURA: So, hey guess what? It's started.
MATT: "Yeah, apparently." She closes the
door
behind you, looks out the window
that has the
curtains closed and goes, "Okay. So.
It's
underway. It's not safe to be here
right now."
LAURA: No.
MATT: "Did anyone see you come in?"
LAURA: No, no.
MATT: "Good. Who are you?"
LAURA: "Oh. Well." How about Seeming?
This whole
time, have we looked like
crazy peasants during the battle?
MATT and TRAVIS: No.
TRAVIS: We dropped it.
LAURA: We dropped it?
MATT: You dropped Seeming before all of
this.
LAURA: Okay, just making sure Trinket
wasn't a
donkey that killed the--
MATT: No.
TALIESIN: That would've been intense and
awesome.
MATT: That would've been amazing. Donkey
eating a
vampire head? Aw, man.
LIAM: This is hard to believe, but this
is crazy
grandma.
LAURA: "I'm crazy grandma." I do a crazy
eye thing
just to show her.
SAM: Am I there, Matt?
MATT: You've just now gotten to that
point, you
see the door closing as you
get there.
SAM: Hello. Hi. How'd it go?
MARISHA: Good work, by the way! That was
awesome!
I mean, I saw the fire, I don't
know what you did.
LAURA: So it went well?
SAM: I set fire to the place, some shit
went down,
dinosaurs were harmed, but I
know you got the
smoke signal and used that to attack.
MARISHA: The de Rolos have dinosaurs?
SAM: No, it was me. It's all good,
though. I
caused a ruckus, that's all I
was supposed to do.
TRAVIS: That's it, yeah.
MATT: "What is going on?"
TRAVIS: Right.
TALIESIN: We may have just started a
revolution.
MARISHA: Does he look familiar to you?
LIAM: You don't recognize us, it's not
safe to
walk these streets for
outsiders, so we were using
a little bit of trickery. This is us.
We're the
same people you were dealing
with before.
TRAVIS: Vox Machina.
LAURA: We just need to rest.
MATT: "Okay. You can rest here, but how
long?"
LAURA: Until we're healed, and then
we'll go.
LIAM: Overnight.
MATT: "All right."
LAURA: I feel like we should get word
out to
somebody, though, because--
SAM: To what? To hold the revolution?
LAURA: I feel like everybody's going to
die before
we even get to the castle!
MARISHA: That's the thing. I don't know
if this is
the time to rest.
LAURA: But we don't have any spells.
MARISHA: I'm okay. We can maybe make do.
LAURA: I can't make do.
TRAVIS: You might be cool, but we're
fucked.
TALIESIN: How about we stay here until
4:00, 5:00
in the morning--
MARISHA: What time is it now?
MATT: Right now, I'd say you're close to
three in
the afternoon.
LAURA: How do we tell the people to like
hold
off?
SAM: We need to briefly quell the
rebellion?
MARISHA: We started something. We can't
stop it
now.
TALIESIN: We're going to be indoors. It
doesn't
matter what time we go to attack
the castle.
SAM: Let's spread word. We can spread
word. Let's
find a few--
LAURA: Can we send off a message?
MARISHA: We sparked a hope in people. We
now have
innocent peasants, people who
are not fighters--
SAM: Can you Skywrite something like
"attack
tomorrow" or "hold"?
LAURA: What if we all take off in
separate
directions and we tell all the
peasants we find
that are fighting the time that we're
going to
attack?
TRAVIS: Aren't there a bunch of zombie
stone
giants walking around?
LAURA: Well yeah, we'll have to be
sneaky about
it, but we'll spread the
rumors around. I look at
Jordana. Joanna?
MATT: Jordana.
LAURA: Jordana. And I say, can you get
word out
to people?
MATT: "To a few, maybe. I don't want to
go outside
right now."
LAURA: I don't blame you, dear.
TALIESIN: Let's let her stay. I say we
just rest
up and we attack tonight.
TRAVIS: Tonight?
MARISHA: What if there isn't a town to
defend
tonight?
TRAVIS: Aren't they stronger then?
TALIESIN: It's going to be indoors,
anyway.
SAM: First of all, it's raining outside.
It's
daytime. There's no vampires out
there right now,
right? They don't like water, do they?
LAURA: No, they don't like running
water, in fact
they hate running water!
I didn't think about that.
MARISHA: It's a lot of running water,
though. I
think they're all right with
rain.
TRAVIS: Yeah, they said a river is what
the...
right?
SAM: I'm sure they don't like it. In any
case, the only
thing that our rebels are
rebelling against right
now are six zombie giants, one of whom
I'm pretty
sure they killed already. Did
I see them?
MATT: Best you could see, that group was
doing
pretty well and was hacking it
down. Lost a few of
their number in the process.
MARISHA: Did we ever get a count of how
many
zombie giants there were?
SAM: There were six.
MATT: There were six that you saw while
you were
doing your overall flight.
LAURA: What, so we go out and fight
zombie
giants?
SAM: No, but maybe we could--
MARISHA: Why not? We are the most
capable people
in this town right now.
LAURA: Well. We could go fight zombie
giants and
then tell everybody to wait.
TRAVIS: Nah, it's going to fuck us.
We've got to
rest.
MARISHA: Why don't we take a short rest,
heal up a
bit, get back out there, take
down some giants.
What do you guys say?
SAM: I admire this fire in your eyes,
but it's so
stupid.
LAURA: What if we run out and tell
people to stop
fucking fighting and wait
until tomorrow?
LIAM: They won't. The giants are going
to keep
smashing them.
SAM: What time did he say it was?
TALIESIN: It's about three. We could
just do a
round of the front courtyard
and see what's going on.
LAURA: Fuck! Fine.
TALIESIN: Try and sleep through the
night.
LAURA: All right. We fight until we
absolutely
can't fight anymore.
TRAVIS: What about the people who
absolutely need a
short rest at the
minimum stay.
LIAM: We stay for an hour.
TALIESIN: We're short-resting right now.
LIAM: Rest for an hour.
MARISHA: This is going to go on for a
while, but
the longer we wait indoors,
the more people are
going to die, and if we're killing
people to try
and save the masses--
which is how I'm justifying
this whole thing, by the way-- I feel
like we
can't leave the masses to their
own devices.
SAM: Wait a second, what about that,
what about
that cleric, the religious
man that you've talked
to. Could he get a message out to
everybody?
What's his name?
LAURA: At this point, though, it's
chaos.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MARISHA: We literally lit the fire and
we can't
stop it now.
SAM: Archibald? Is that his name?
TRAVIS: Yeah, they're standing up for
themselves.
TALIESIN: We also, somebody-- there's
the point
that somebody is informing on
us.
MARISHA: Someone is informing on us.
SAM: What are you talking about, why?
TALIESIN: They were ready for us. They
knew we
were coming.
SAM: Of course they knew we were coming,
we killed
one of their--
LAURA: They said there was an informant.
They said
that there was an informant
when we were there.
TRAVIS: Who did?
LAURA: That guard. He said our contacts
were
right. Our informant was correct.
Somebody is
informing on us. It could be you.
LIAM: I insight-check this woman.
MATT: Go ahead and roll insight.
LIAM: 14.
LAURA: Can I say it? Because I just
said, "It
could be you." Can I do the
same thing?
MATT: Sure, go ahead.
LAURA: All right. That's terrible. Okay.
So.
SAM: What do you want to know?
MATT: Best that you can tell, she just
looks
genuinely scared and is
uncomfortable with your
presence right now but is letting it
happen. She's
still getting over the
fact that you guys look
entirely different than when you first
talked to
her about staying here.
LAURA: Well, short rest and then we head
out? We
do some attacks and--
LIAM: I've never fought a zombie giant
before.
LAURA: No, but everybody else is doing
it. Those
peasants are doing it.
LIAM: That's what I'm saying. Let's see
what we're
up against. Let's take a
breather and let's go
pick one off.
MARISHA: Jordana, do you have any books
here on
zombie giants?
MATT: "For the most part, necromancy is
not
studied in this town. At least, we
never had to
"deal with it until recently, and we
haven't had
the opportunity to really
study since."
MARISHA: Well, I mean, zombie combined
with
giants. We've fought zombies and
we've fought
giants, so I'm assuming it with a
vague--
TRAVIS: What?
LAURA: We keep our distance.
TALIESIN: How long does it take to
recharge Hex,
by the way?
MATT: You need a long rest.
TRAVIS: How many Sunbeam hadoukens do
you have
left, Keyleth?
MARISHA: How many hadoukens? As in
Sunbeams? I'm
done on Sunbeams.
SAM: We need to rest.
TRAVIS: If we get a short rest, how many
do you
get?
MARISHA: I'm done. None.
LAURA: We need a long rest to get
spells.
MARISHA: However, if I short rest, I
actually
haven't burnt any of my animal
forms here recently
and I can water elemental up, which
would also
permanently kill them. So I
have other defenses
that could still take down vampires if
we
encounter another one. I'm more
concerned about
these giants right now.
TRAVIS: That's what I'm talking about.
They're
vampires.
MARISHA: No, they're zombies. They're
undead.
LAURA: They're zombies.
LIAM: They're undead.
TRAVIS: Those are two different things,
huh?
MATT: They are two very different
things.
TRAVIS: Grog learns.
(laughter)
MATT: All right. So what's the plan?
LAURA: We short rest and get back out.
LIAM: We take a short rest and then
exterminate.
SAM: Wait, join the rebellion or ride
around town
telling everyone, "quell?"
MARISHA: We're taking down these damn
giants.
These giants are killing people
left and right; we
watched them crush people on our way
here.
TALIESIN: We tell them that they take
cover during
the night.
TRAVIS: I'm going to roll four hit dice.
MATT: Yeah, you guys go ahead, use your
hit dice to
heal up while you're taking
your short rest
for those who've taken damage.
LAURA: Oh, Trinket. Can you heal
Trinket?
MARISHA: I can.
LAURA: Heal him so much. Does Trinket
get... oh,
he does get hit dice.
MATT: Trinket technically does not.
Trinket
requires--
LAURA: It says he does. It's written
down.
MATT: Hit dice?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: Also, another strange
question: what
creates initiative?
Initiative is your dexterity
modifier?
MATT: Correct.
TALIESIN: So with me, it's my dexterity
modifier.
Plus two.
MATT: Correct.
TALIESIN: I'm also currently wearing a
Headband of
Initiative, which I'd
forgotten about.
MATT: Which...?
TALIESIN: Gives me plus two to my
initiative.
MATT: Correct.
TALIESIN: Oh, dear god almighty. Okay.
Thank you.
MATT: Percy, Percy, Percy.
TALIESIN: I don't mean to be doing this.
MATT: No, it's great. Just glad you
didn't take the
Alertness feat. Then
things would have gotten
stupid.
LAURA: Are you healing Trinket?
MARISHA: How much more does he need?
LAURA: He's at 36. He needs 24 more.
TALIESIN: Actually, I'm going to be
using the Hat
of Disguise just because
it's probably safe. Does
anybody want a Headband of Initiative?
LAURA: Yeah. Do you not need it?
TALIESIN: I can't wear two things on my
head.
LAURA: I don't have anything on my head.
TALIESIN: So you've got plus two to
your
initiative, and I'm losing plus two
to my
initiative. It's called a Headband of
Initiative.
MARISHA: You already have an eight to
your
initiative.
LIAM: It's very mystical.
TRAVIS: How much time do we have before
the sun
that is being blocked by the
rainclouds goes
down?
MATT: Well, you guys are taking a short
rest,
about 30 minutes to an hour, so
you have about two
and a half, three hours before it goes
down
entirely.
TALIESIN: That should give us enough
time to do a
quick tour. We already know
their walking route,
and I'm sure that the people are putting
up a
fight.
MARISHA: I'm going to give him a level
two Cure
Wounds.
LAURA: Okay.
MARISHA: So do 2d8 plus ten.
LAURA: Me?
MARISHA: Sure. Me or you. Whoever feels
more
comfortable.
LAURA: I'll do it. It was good.
MATT: During this rest, if you wanted to
spend some time with that cape--
LIAM: I do. I'm going to sniff it and
shake it
out.
MATT: For the most part, it doesn't
appear to be
enchanted.
SAM: No, I can sing a Song of Rest for
all of us.
MARISHA and LAURA: Oh, yeah. Do that.
SAM: It gives us all 1d6. That's pretty
weak.
MARISHA: No, but that's...
LAURA: No, it's fine. He's got extra hit
points;
don't worry about it.
MARISHA: Well, Song of Rest just
happens, right?
Do you get that for
free? You might as well, if
you don't burn anything.
SAM: Okay. (sings) Health! We need some
now.
Health! Not just anybody. Health!
You know you
need someone.
ALL: (sings) Health!
MATT: That's not trademarked at all. I
love it.
All right, so you guys have
rested up. Through the
rest, you occasionally hear voices run
by,
yelling. As you guys get toward the
end of your
rest, you hear the (stomping) large
heavy
footfalls heading nearby.
(groaning, crash) A
loud, heavy impact, and you hear some
short cheers
outside.
TRAVIS: Yes!
LAURA: Yay!
SAM: Oh, he died. That's two down.
Splash two.
TRAVIS: Right out front, we hear it?
MATT: Out front, a little ways off. Not
immediately.
SAM: Do we have horses? We don't have
any horses,
do we?
LAURA: No.
LIAM: They died.
MATT: Yeah, they got eaten by harpies.
TRAVIS: Should we go outside and see how
they're
doing?
TALIESIN: Yeah, let's check it out.
TRAVIS: We go out front.
LIAM: Time to kill some giant undead.
MATT: Okay. Jordana lets you guys out,
locks
behind her.
MARISHA: Do we want to split up?
TALIESIN: No, let's keep together.
LAURA: Actually, before we go, I ask, do
you have
any holy symbols at all in
here?
MATT: "I'm sorry, no."
LAURA: Nothing?
MATT: "No. All those were kept in either
of the
two temples here."
LAURA: Do you have anything magic that
could help
me?
MATT: "I already gave you everything of
magic that
I had here."
LAURA: Oh, right. I forgot we took it.
MATT: "Sorry."
LAURA: Shit. All right, thank you.
TRAVIS: Once we're outside, how far away
is that
giant that was felled?
MATT: As you step outside and look, it's
about 60
feet off, near one of the big
crossroads near this
area. And a zombie giant has been
completely
felled down, and there are
three people now that
are currently in the process of hacking
its head
off just to make sure. It's a
group of about seven
people that live here. They're all
looking pretty
messed up, but they're
all eager and
adrenaline-driven, they're all hacking
away, then
stopping and taking a breath
(breathes heavily).
You hear in the distance, (thunder
crack) bolt of
lightning coming down
from the storm, and as it
echoes, everyone shakes for a second,
look at each
other, (cheers) give a
cheer of victory. They all
hop off the body of the zombie giant and
begin
darting further in towards the
center of the city.
MARISHA: I look up. Is my de Rolo symbol
still in
the sky?
MATT: It's there. It's dissipating
slowly, but
it's still there. It's moved
a little bit off-axis
with the storm.
TRAVIS: So that's it for the big houses,
right?
Just the castle.
TALIESIN: Just the castle.
SAM: Except we haven't killed the
members of one
of the houses. By the
way, my Song of Rest is a d8.
LAURA: Awesome.
SAM: But we haven't killed the last one.
Now, the
one that you guys killed.
What's his name again,
Tylieri?
MATT: Tylieri.
SAM: He was a vampire.
ALL: Yes.
SAM: Because Sylas killed him. Right?
TALIESIN: Yes.
SAM: And then made him a vampire.
TALIESIN: One would assume.
SAM: Didn't he hang him on the Sun Tree?
LAURA: What? No. What? What are you
talking
about?
SAM: I don't know. Didn't that guy that
we
meet...
MATT: You do recall, actually, when you
were
interrogating the driver of the
Briarwoods.
Tylieri was the master of the driver
Desmond, who
beat him and subjugated him
to various forms of
torture and abuse before Lord Briarwood
took
Desmond and, to try and show
extension of faith,
revealed to Desmond Tylieri hanging from
the Sun
Tree. That was true.
TRAVIS: Wow.
SAM: And then he became a vampire. Is
that where
they're spawning?
LAURA: No. Maybe he was already a
vampire and he
hung him from the tree
just to show--
SAM: That doesn't seem right.
TALIESIN: Let's head to the Sun Tree,
why don't
we?
LAURA: Let's head that direction.
TRAVIS: Let's go.
MARISHA: Something to us about how when
people die
in this town. The guy you
talked to at the bar?
SAM: Yes, we talked to a guy at the bar.
What
about him?
MARISHA: He said when people die here
they don't
die.
SAM: Well, yes, we know that, yes.
LAURA: They come back.
LIAM: They could be-- yes, that could
apply, too.
MARISHA: I think this whole damn town--
I think
the whole land is cursed. Is
what I think.
TRAVIS: I think that's--
LAURA: Probably pretty fair.
TRAVIS: Should we go to the tree?
LAURA: Sure.
MARISHA: Why?
TALIESIN: Just to see--
LAURA: We'll make our way through the
town and
look for giants as we make our
way to the tree.
MARISHA: Let's look for giants. Let's go
giant-hunting.
MATT: Okay. All right, so from the
Alcove, you guys
head in a southwestern
motion, keeping off the
main paths best you can. The main chaos
seems to
have died down a little bit in
this area of the
town. You come across another body of a
zombie
giant, surrounded by what looks
like eight bodies
of civilians of the town.
LAURA: Are they all dead, or are they
injured?
MATT: No, they are all very dead. Two of
which are
torn in half and just tossed
to different sides,
one appears to be half-eaten, and the
rest are
just smashed. But whatever
troop was with
them managed to take the zombie giant
down.
Eventually, you make your way to
the center of the
town square where the Sun Tree is and
there is,
across the way on the opposite
side, what appears
to be, in mid-struggle, one zombie giant
that has
a series of spears or javelins
sticking out of its
torso. It's currently swatting at a
group of
individuals that have torches
in the rain, still
trying to get up towards it and push it
backward.
The Sun Tree, at a glance--
roll a perception
check.
MARISHA: All of us?
MATT: Yes.
TALIESIN: One. There's a tree!
SAM: Four.
MARISHA: I rolled a 19, so 29?
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: 23.
LAURA: If my passive perception's higher
than my
roll--
MATT: Active perception and passive
perception--
passive is more something
to keep track when
you're not actively perceiving. So.
Grog?
TRAVIS: Seven.
MATT: Okay. Keyleth, you pick this out
in the
rain, and it's hard to see, but
from this angle,
you see what looks to be eight ropes,
currently,
just dangling free from the
Sun Tree.
TALIESIN: Damn it.
LAURA: Shit.
SAM: The tree is the spawning spot.
LAURA: Really?
SAM: Or maybe one of them.
TRAVIS: Or maybe they cut them down.
SAM: We've got to cut down this tree.
LAURA: Does it look like the ropes have
been cut?
MATT: You can go closer to inspect it if
you
want.
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: You're hearing in the distance the
(roars)
the battle's still raging about
65, 70 feet from
you. You get up behind the tree and you
take the
ropes and inspect it. All the
ropes are very
finely cut.
LAURA: Oh. They were cut. They cut them
down.
TRAVIS: They cut their dead down.
MARISHA: Okay, so the nooses are gone.
MATT: Yeah. And you do see, there are a
number.
This close, you can see there
are loops of rope
all over the tree: some very old and
weathered and
aged, some of them are
torn, some of them are cut,
but the fresh ones that are the longest
currently
and that are placed closest to
where the bodies
were originally there are all very
cleanly cut.
LAURA: Can we spin around and look and
see if
there's anything around that
looks like-- or look
at tracking and see if it looks like
somebody cut
them down or if they fell
on their own?
MATT: You glance around real fast and
you can see
to the south there is still
the battle raging
between the zombie giant and the crew
of
individuals, but you look back where
you guys were
from, and you see a large series of
shapes
stepping through the rain, coming
from the
direction you guys were.
LIAM: I think they cut them down just
like
Tylieri. I think that this is where
they hang them
to ripen, and then when they're ready
they pluck
them off the tree and set
them on their way.
MATT: As you're having this
conversation, you,
keeping your eyes
forward as he's saying this in
your ear, you can see, as the light of
the town is
slowly beginning to vanish
into a sunset--
MARISHA: Is it still raining?
MATT: It is still raining. You see ahead
of you,
coming from the central roadway
into the square of
the town, what you can only surmise to
be anywhere
from 30 to 50 armored
skeletal entities that are
pouring from the north.
MARISHA: Okay. I climb the Sun Tree.
SAM: Wait, what? We've got to get out of
here!
MARISHA: I'm climbing the Sun Tree.
MATT: Climbing the Sun Tree. All right.
You guys
see Keyleth scurry up the Sun
Tree.
SAM: I blow my Horn of Fog to create
a
smokescreen. I don't know what the
fuck she's
doing.
MATT: Okay. (foghorn sound) The slow
horn-blow
comes out, and this fog begins
to fill the area
between this marching skeletal army and
the Sun
Tree where you guys currently
are. Looking over
your shoulder, you can see the zombie
giant
finishes smashing the last
individual in that
crew, picks it up and jams it into its
jagged
giant teeth.
MARISHA: So there's a big army coming
down,
filtering down a street.
MATT: Down the street towards you.
MARISHA: How far away?
MATT: You can't tell now. There's just
fog along
the way.
MARISHA: I can't tell how far away they
are right
now?
MATT: No, you can't see them.
MARISHA: I can't see them?
MATT: No, because Scanlan just created a
whole
bunch of fog between the two of
you. The moment
you saw, they may be about a hundred or
so feet
from you.
LIAM: Keyleth, tell us what you're
thinking,
because the rest of us are
taking this time to go.
TRAVIS: You engage, they'll follow, we
go, we
fight another day, we sleep in
the rafters and
wait until daybreak.
LIAM: Who are you?
MARISHA: I might be able to do
something.
LAURA: What is it? Say it!
MARISHA: I can do a big ice storm or do
something
to take all these fuckers out
at once.
TRAVIS: All 30 to 50 of them? Kill them
all?
MARISHA: It's a big range.
LIAM: No. Keyleth, we've got to go.
TALIESIN: I say we let her hit them, and
we run.
MARISHA: Scanlan, can you drop the fog
just a
bit?
SAM: Nope, not by magic.
MATT: He can't control it.
LAURA: It's on the ground. You can
probably see
above it. Fog is low.
MATT: Well, the fog this creates is a
magical fog
that obscures an entire
area. If you climbed to
the very top of the tree, you might be
able to get
a little bit of a visual.
MARISHA: All right, I'm going to climb
as high as
I can.
MATT: Okay, make an athletics check.
LAURA: I'm going to climb up after her.
SAM: Oh my god.
MARISHA: 11. Acrobatics or athletics?
MATT: Athletics.
MARISHA: Oh, that's better. 15.
MATT: 15. Okay. You make your way up to
the very
precarious top of the branches.
You can feel the
brittleness of it as the tree itself,
its life
force is withered over time and
some of it cracks
and some of the actual bark of the tree
twists off
in your grip as you get to
the very top. You can look
just over the bank of fog that Scanlan
has created
and you can see beyond that.
The number of undead
from this angle, what was initially like
probably pushes closer to about a
hundred.
MARISHA: Okay. And they're like a
hundred feet
away?
MATT: Starting about a hundred feet
away, slowly
marching towards you.
MARISHA: Right where they are, I'm going
to start
a little ahead of where they
originate, I'm going
to start making an ice storm. I'm
pushing all the
way back to where-- just
right down these
fuckers.
LIAM: I'm also just trying to stay
underneath her
as best I can.
LAURA: Stop looking up her skirt,
brother.
LIAM: Is she in a skirt?
SAM: She's been wearing a dress this
whole time?
LIAM: I thought she was covered in
leaves.
TALIESIN: Stop looking up her fig leaf.
MATT: All right. What's the damage on
that? Is it
2d8 bludgeoning and 2d8--
MARISHA: They take 2d8 bludgeoning
damage and 4d6
cold damage.
MATT: Okay, go ahead and roll for both.
And it's a
save for half, right?
TALIESIN: Inspiration?
SAM: Oh. Well. I didn't do it.
MARISHA: 2d8 bludgeoning, that's
seven
bludgeoning... 4d6. Not great at
all. Four, five,
six, seven, eight.
MATT: Total of eight. Eight plus... what
was the
other one?
MARISHA: Seven.
MATT: Seven, okay.
MARISHA: And it's difficult terrain.
MATT: Okay. So the first area. Suddenly
you see
some of the clouds above you
begin to funnel
downward, and a few bolts of electricity
(crackle)
through it. As the funnel
hits, it grows dark, and
then all of a sudden this cold wind
begins to
swirl around it. And with
that, the cloud almost
seems to tear open within itself and a
sheet of
jagged ice and sleet begins to
pour downward into
the center of this undead horde. As it
does, you
can see probably a good 25, 30
of these are just
blown apart, bone shards scattered
around and you
can see bits of rusted
metal weapons and armor
thrown left and right. The ice then
coalesces over
the floor of this area
and some of the skeletons
just slip, but they keep marching
forward. It
definitely took a chunk, but
as it continues
pushing forward--
MARISHA: Now we can run.
LAURA: Good job. I grab the back of her
shirt and yank her towards me.
MATT: You guys make your way down the
tree.
As you get to the bottom of the
tree, the zombie
giant has taken notice of the sudden
flashing of
light and the movement in
the tree and is bounding
towards the tree after you guys.
LAURA: Are we running?
TRAVIS: Are we going to the Alcove or
going to the
treeline?
TALIESIN: I say we go to the treeline,
and I say
that you take a couple shots
as we're heading--
LAURA: I'm definitely doing that, yes.
I'm going
to shoot at the giant as we're
running. Hunter's
Mark him.
MATT: Okay, you Hunter's Mark, turning
around,
looking at the giant.
MARISHA: As she says that, I'm going to
go ahead
and start casting my Call
Lightning spell.
MATT: Okay. So you land and you cast
Call
Lightning. The fog that you
created, Scanlan?
SAM: Yes.
MATT: Has formed up. You start seeing
shapes;
these terrifying skeletal faces
begin to appear
through the fog as the rest of the army
begins to
push through. The clouds
coalescing above Keyleth
as you get your Call Lightning ready,
you marking
the zombie giant, you guys
begin bolting out of
the way. Trinket comes running up behind
you, Vex,
and picks you up onto his
back, and you guys begin
rushing off toward the treeline-- to the
west or
the east?
LAURA: Can I shoot him?
MARISHA: Yeah, as I turn around, I Call
Lightning
on the giant.
MATT: Okay. Go ahead and roll damage on
that.
MARISHA: And it's cloudy, so I get how
much more?
MATT: I don't know, how much do you get
more on
that? Call Lightning would be...
SAM: While you decide, which way are we
going,
Percy? West or east?
MATT: 3d10. It does an additional d10.
It does
4d10.
LAURA: And I'm going to shoot him
through my
Longbow of the Sky Sentinel
as we're going away, too.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: So the passage to the castle
I'm aware
of is to the west, and then
the one that Stonefell
mentioned is to the east?
TRAVIS: Do we go to the treeline by the
castle?
MATT: No, the one Stonefell mentioned
was the
same.
TALIESIN: Was the same?
MATT: It wasn't Stonefell, it was Vouk.
TALIESIN: Yeah, thank you.
MATT: But yeah. He was referring to the
same one.
TALIESIN: Treeline to the west so that
we can
attack first thing.
LAURA: 22. Twice.
MATT: 22 hits.
LAURA: And then three on the last one.
MATT: Okay, yeah.
LAURA: Well, it's technically 14 on the
last one.
MATT: For him? Still hits.
LAURA: Oh, sweet!
MATT: It's a big target. Big target, lot
of hit
points.
MARISHA: And as she's brewing up her
bow, I'm
behind her and just bring down
the bolt for 32
damage.
MATT: Damn. (lightning sound) You can
see the bolt
strikes the front of the
zombie giant right as it
starts swinging after you guys. The bolt
hits its
shoulder and blasts a chunk of
its shoulder blade
off. You see bone shards fire behind,
and there's
a giant piece of its torso
now missing where the
bolt hit. (groans) Stumbles back onto
its back
foot and catches itself, almost
toppling over.
MARISHA: Just start backing up. "Vex?"
MATT: It starts lumbering forward again
as Vex
releases her arrow, which splits
into three.
MARISHA: Vex?
LAURA: 54 points of damage.
MARISHA: Kill it!
MATT: Nice! (impact sounds) All the
arrows
blasting into its body, you can
see they sink in
and burst on the inside. There's a
little, a dull
glow as this burst of
electrical energy hits from
underneath its sickly zombified flesh.
At which
point, there's a slight delay
before it (explosion
sound) bubbles forth and a bit of its
internal
liquid just spews out like a
boil. You can see
it's definitely taking damage, and it
keeps
pushing forward. Yeah, it's still
moving towards
you guys.
LIAM: How far away is it?
TALIESIN: For gods' sakes!
MATT: It's about ten feet from you guys
right
now.
TALIESIN: I pull out Bad News. I'm
shooting it
with Bad News, and I'm going
for an aimed shot to
the legs.
MATT: Okay. The moment it would take for
you to
stop and pull out Bad News, by
the way, the moment
you guys are turning around to attack
it, it has
gotten within range to hit,
so this is all
happening simultaneously, so it's going
to get two
strikes as you guys get your
attacks, as well.
MARISHA: What are you doing?
MATT: So. Go ahead and roll your attack.
LIAM: I did.
MATT: What did you get?
LIAM: 27 and an 18.
MATT: Both hit.
TALIESIN: I got 28.
MATT: Okay. And against Percy, that is a
17 and a
20.
TALIESIN: 17 misses. The 20 hits.
MATT: Okay. You take 16 points of
bludgeoning
damage as its fist comes
down and (whack) slams
into your side just as Bad News fires
off and your
daggers go (dagger sounds)
towards it.
LIAM: Keen Dagger, Flametongue, combined
20 hit
points.
MATT: Okay. Good to know.
MARISHA: And as soon as I'm able, I'm
backing up
and bringing down another
lightning bolt.
LAURA: Well, I've got another attack.
That was
just one attack that I did.
MARISHA: Oh yeah.
SAM: You need your spells. We need to
hide. We
need to run.
MARISHA: It's okay, this is a
concentration spell.
I can keep doing
it. I'm not blowing spells on it.
TALIESIN: 22 points of damage, plus he's
knocked
prone.
MATT: Okay. Easy enough. Through the
daggers--
TALIESIN: Oh, he can make a con saving
throw,
though.
MATT: It doesn't matter. It still
manages to keep
its zombie form, though
it seems like every single
hit you're taking chunks off its body,
but it
continues to push through the
damage until
eventually it swings at you with the
hit, Bad News
goes off as it blasts
through the center of its
torso and takes out the back of its
spine. It
can't keep its physical form
together, and as its
body lunges forward, you throw both of
your
daggers, which go (thoonk thoonk)
into each of its
eyes. It falls forward. The torso seems
to roll on
impact and come after you
like a slow-moving
boulder for a few feet, but since you're
all
moving forward, you manage to outrun
it, just
barely keeping out of the way. The
legs
walk on their own for two more
steps before it
just falls forward into the mud,
relieving all its
intestines into the
rain-soaked ground.
SAM: Let's get out of here!
MARISHA: Go, go, go. Run!
LAURA: Pass Without a Trace!
TRAVIS: Aggressive flower girl.
MARISHA: Do I see any other-- as we're
running
through--
LAURA: Just run, Keyleth!
LIAM: I grab Keyleth by the arm and I
just pull
and run.
MATT: You guys go running back and as
you're
looking over your shoulder you
can see the
skeletal army swarming the center of the
square
and pouring into the streets. It
seems that the
Briarwoods had their own reserve
anti-riot
campaign at the ready.
LAURA: Oh, are they going to take out
everybody?
MARISHA: We can't go, we can't go!
SAM: We have to go. We have nothing
left.
MATT: And with that, we're going to
conclude
tonight's session.
(groaning)
MATT: We'll be returning next week on
that note.
TRAVIS: (laughs) You son of a bitch, I
love it.
MATT: All right, so we're going to take
a little break
here while we set up for
Critmas. Quick one, very
quick, we'll be back here in just a few
minutes,
for those who want to hang in
and watch how
ridiculously amazing this community is.
LAURA: Oh my gosh. There's like, there's
a lot.
MARISHA: Yeah, you guys are crazy.
LIAM: Buckle up!
MATT: All right, quick break. See you in
a
second.