MATT: Everyone, welcome to the new
episode of Critical Role.
This evening, we luckily
have Ashley Johnson
back in as her character Pike.
Unfortunately, Laura
Bailey will be gone for
most of the game, possibly,
she might come in,
'cause she's busy recording
a show with Wil Wheaton.
It's gonna be a great
show, but we'll miss her,
until she shows up.
However, we shall see what
the next chapter has in store
in just a moment.
In the meantime,
let's go ahead and get you situated
with the character backgrounds.
TRAVIS: Right, listen up.
If you have ale, then you have
a friend in Grog Strongjaw.
A goliath of towering height and size.
This barbarian has an appetite for the two
great loves in his life:
combat, women, and ale.
(record scratch)
Wait.
Easily the brains of the group,
Grog is often consulted
for his vast knowledge
of shapes, colors, and
(giggles), shiny things.
But also ale.
In his early years, armed
with his two handed gray axe,
Grog often enjoyed proving his might
amongst the ranks of his
family's wandering herd.
But after coming upon
an unsuspecting elderly
gnome in the woods,
he objected to the killing
of such an innocent life.
A creature of impulse, Grog
felt only pity for this,
this terrified little thing.
His disobedience cost him dearly.
Beaten bloody, and banished
by the herd leader,
his uncle Kevdak, Grog was
abandoned, and left to die.
Exiled from his herd,
it was then that the
relative of the very gnome
he fought to save, saved him.
It was the kindness of a
gnome cleric named Pike
that healed Grog, bringing
him back from death's edge.
And they have remained
close friends ever since.
Most nights, Grog can be found challenging
entire taverns to wrestling matches.
Or accompanying Scanlan
to the nearest house,
where you pay for lady favors.
Also ale.
MARISHA: A first impression of Keyleth
would leave you with little information
on the half-elven druid.
You might even think that
her social awkwardness
due to her sheltered
upbringing is kind of sweet.
Of course it would be
unwise to underestimate her
based on first impressions.
(thunder clap)
Under that unintimidating, petite frame
is a vicious beast,
waiting to be unleashed,
whose natural powers have
made even the fiercest
of champions pee their pants.
Literally.
(giggles)
Born to the air tribe of the Ashari people,
Keyleth was raised with
a deep love of nature
and the elemental magics.
It is her people's inherent duty
to protect the delicate areas in Tal'Dorei
where the four elemental planes
begin to bleed with this realm.
Since she was a little girl,
she had quite a knack
for air manipulation,
and beast shaping abilities.
Well, if you consider
kittens and flying squirrels
to be little beasts.
Which, I do.
Anyways.
It wasn't long before the
headmaster of the tribe,
her father, Korren, realized
her true prodigious abilities,
and she was inveterated to succeed him
as the next headmaster.
Just like that, her jovial
childhood was stripped,
and replaced with endless
spell memorization,
teachings from ancient traditions,
and exceedingly high expectations.
Every druid leader-to-be
must embark on a journey
to seek out the sister tribes
in order to introduce
and establish respect
amongst the fellow headmasters.
They call this the
Aramente, or Noble Odyssey.
When her father felt she was ready,
he set her on the path to
truly discovering herself,
not knowing when or if
she will ever return.
As she hiked down the
mountain towards Stilben,
she meditated on the task ahead.
Part of the Aramente is proving yourself
a strong warrior, a valiant protector,
and a wise, and compassionate leader.
With this knowledge,
one thought plays in repeat in her mind:
Is she even worthy?
TALIESIN: Percy was the
third of seven children,
born to a noble family who
lived far to the north,
in the ancient castle of Whitestone.
With so many siblings to
share the burdens of lordship,
Percy turned his
attentions to the sciences,
engineering, and naturalism.
One day, a mysterious couple
named Lord and Lady
Briarwood came to court.
During a feast held in their honor,
the Briarwoods violently
took control of the castle,
killing or imprisoning everyone
who would stand in their way.
Percy awoke chained in the dungeon,
only to be freed by his younger sister.
Together they fled, chased
by the Briarwoods' men.
As they ran, Percy's sister
took several arrows to
the chest, and fell.
Percy kept running,
eventually jumping into a freezing river,
and floating unconscious to freedom.
He did not remember waking
up on a fishing boat.
He barely remembered the next two years
as he slowly made his way
as far south as possible.
Then one night, Percy had a dream.
A roaring cloud of smoke
offered him vengeance
against those who destroyed his family.
When he awoke, Percy began
to design his first gun.
(gunshot)
SAM: Oh, you haven't heard
of Scanlan Shorthalt?
Well gird your loins ladies
because he has his eyes on you.
A talented musician, master of disguise,
and dashingly handsome in his own mind,
Scanlan sings songs almost as much
as he sings his own praises.
Born a poor gnome,
Scanlan used his endless
charm and soaring tenor voice
to croon for coin and
support his single mother.
One day he was discovered
by a half orc promoter,
and joined Dr. Dranzel's
Spectacular Traveling Troop,
where he learned the ways of the world,
and honed his skills as
a bard extraordinaire.
A loner much of his life,
Scanlan has never quite come to terms
with the violent death of his mother
at the hands of a goblin invasion.
While his years on the road provided many,
shall we say, educational
experiences with the opposite sex,
deep down Scanlan yearns for
the one thing he's never known:
the true love of a fellow gnome.
Still, Scanlan considers
himself a lover first,
performer second, and
fighter a distant third.
On the battlefield,
he'll support his allies,
but rarely draws blood,
unless it's to protect fellow gnome, Pike.
Count on Scanlan for a hearty laugh,
a rollicking song, and
a twinkle in his eye
that melts hearts, and
makes the females swoon.
(sputtering)
ORION: Greetings, and salutations.
I am Tiberius Stormwind.
I hail from a town called Tirex,
located in the heart of Draconia.
Born from a politically respected family,
at the age of 15, I succeeded
in passing the sorcerer's right,
showing prodigy-like control of my magic.
The judges in the Draconian high council
were amazed at how powerful my spells were
for how long I had been training.
At 20 years old,
I was the youngest appointed
member of the magic guild
in Draconian history.
For the next few years I almost went mad
from the malaise of being a guild member,
as it's rather boring.
However, one day I
happened upon a chamber,
unused for quite some time.
In the room were stacks of books and maps,
of the surrounding cities and areas
around the known world.
For months I would frequent the chamber,
and learn of artifacts from legend.
After a long period of research,
I made a list of artifacts
that caught my eye.
I brought these findings
to the high council
and was told that all of the information
in the chamber I stumbled
upon was either believed
to be fiction or unsolvable mysteries,
and hence were lost forever.
I found those answers to be unacceptable.
A year later I devised a ruse,
and managed to convince the city council
to lend support in me leaving Draconia
on a mission of peace and diplomacy
for the surrounding kingdoms,
going from town to town and making friends
and allies in and for
the name of Draconia.
Being a red dragonborn,
I had quite the task on
my hands, in that respect.
But it was exactly what I needed,
so I could explore the world
and find these artifacts,
as I felt the truth was out there.
Some may describe me as buffoonish,
but I say poppycock to all that!
(sputtering)
I am much sharper than
most give me credit for.
I just don't pay attention
to things sometimes.
I've also been known to be rather cunning,
loyal, happy go lucky,
and, well, dangerous.
I can't help but show my true
scales every now and then.
But overall, I think I'm quite
friendly for a dragonborn.
LIAM: Never entirely welcome
in the company of elves or men,
Vax’ildan learned at a young
age to skip past formality,
preferring instead to
invite himself in your door.
Along with twin sister Vex'ahlia,
Vax was born by a chance encounter
between elven royalty and human peasantry.
Raised by their mother
in their early years,
the twins were eventually
sent off to their father
in the elven capitol of Syngorn.
But their cool reception among
the elves there never warmed,
and their time in the capitol didn't last.
The siblings stole away one autumn night,
and set out on the open road.
After a few years of wandering,
they eventually decided
to return to their mother,
and journey back to the lands of their youth.
But instead of finding
their childhood home,
they returned to a pile of rubble.
Their mother was gone,
their home burned to ash.
Pressing the townspeople for answers,
they learned of the day the dragon came.
(roaring)
With their ties all severed,
Vax’ildan and his sister set out
to find their fortune together in Tal'dorei.
An outsider since birth,
Vax quickly learned
to solve life's challenges
in his own particular way,
often by side-stepping them entirely.
And when his knack for circumventing
adversity isn't enough,
(drawing blades)
the way of blades the
elves schooled him in
more than makes up the difference.
LAURA: Like so many half elves,
Vex'ahlia has spent most of her life
suffering the cool reception of a people
who don't fully accept her.
Born of a human mother
and an elven father,
who only later in life took an
interest in their existence,
Vex'ahlia and her twin brother Vax’ildan
quickly realized the only
people they could truly rely on
in this world were each other.
It was at the age of ten when the two
were taken from their mother,
and brought to live in Syngorn,
the isolated elven city
for which their father
was an ambassador.
He quietly took them in, but
always kept an icy distance.
And after too many years
of disdainful looks,
the pair decided to leave
his indifference behind
and set out on their own.
Vax took to the cities,
stealing small trinkets
and learning the ways of a thief.
While Vex kept to the woods.
She preferred the isolation.
Always the keen observer,
she learned to hunt,
and to track, to spy, and to shoot.
And through a series of fateful events,
earned herself a companion
in the form of a bear--
her own stolen trinket--
to fight along side her
and protect her fiercely.
Also he is adorable.
And gives expert massages.
TRAVIS: Right, listen up.
If you have ale, then you have
a friend in Grog Strongjaw.
A goliath of towering height and size,
this Barbarian has an appetite
for the two great loves in his life:
combat, women, and ale.
(record scratch)
Wait.
Easily the brains of the group,
Grog is often consulted
for his vast knowledge
of shapes, colors, and
(giggles), shiny things.
But also ale.
In his early years, armed
with his two-handed great axe,
Grog often enjoyed proving his might
amongst the ranks of his
family's wandering herd.
But after coming upon an unsuspecting
elderly gnome in the wood--
MATT: Welcome back.
Unfortunately, we don't have
Pike's video ready yet.
I'm working on it.
ASHLEY: My bad.
MATT: This week got away from me,
and Ashley got it to me a little late,
but we'll have it up
next week, don't worry.
However we are happy
to have Ashley with us.
(all cheer)
She's come down from her BAFTA cloud.
(all laugh)
Which is amazing, congratulations again.
ASHLEY: Thank you guys.
MATT: So yeah, as a heads up too,
if you wanna do any quick
announcements real fast,
I think you had an announcement
you wanted to make.
ASHLEY: It's my mom's birthday today.
(all cheer)
MATT: Happy birthday Ashley's mom, yay!
ASHLEY: Her name's Nancy.
LIAM: Hi Nancy.
TRAVIS: Happy birthday, Nancy.
Totally watching this right now.
MARISHA: Is she watching?
ASHLEY: She probably is.
(all laugh)
MATT: Well, hello!
Also for those who are
Hearthstone players,
the new Black Hawk Mountain
Expansion came out today,
in which I voice Nefarian and Ragnaros.
(all cheer)
My vanilla-WoW-playing self
from back in the day
is nerding out over that, so enjoy that.
Anyone have anything
else they wanna announce
or talk about?
Are we good to start?
SAM: Hi, mom!
MARISHA: Hi, mom.
MATT: All righty.
TRAVIS: I don't think my mom knows
what the internet is.
ORION: Related, I leveled my
undead holy priest to 64
last night, on Warcraft.
ZAC: We're just
about a thousand happy--
MATT: Congrats.
Way to go, level 64.
So you're just barely into
burning crusade, good man.
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: I got one too.
My brother who also works in video games
gave a talk at GVC this year,
and it just went online,
and not now but later you should watch
Alex Jaffe's talk on metagame balancing.
It's really really fun, it's fabulous,
and you learn a lot.
MATT: There you go, Alex Jaffe, look it up.
MARISHA: Alex is brilliant.
MATT: All right guys, so, getting
to the game at hand.
So little overview for the story,
the party has been sent
to the city of Kraghammer,
through a friend of theirs
named Arcanist Allura Vysoren.
A good friend of hers and a folk hero
throughout the land known
as Lady Kima of Vord,
who's the halfling paladin of Bahamut,
has gone missing.
She went on a vision quest
as part of a pilgrimage she's
been on for the past year,
and sensed a dark evil brewing
far beneath the city of Kraghammer.
Disappeared into the city and
hasn't been seen for weeks.
So Arcanist Allura asked the party,
hired them essentially, to
go and see her whereabouts.
Upon getting to Kraghammer,
they interacted with some
of the local characters,
eventually found theirself talking
to Lord Nostoc Greyspine, who
owns the mines at the very bottom
of Kraghammer proper.
After a brief encounter
with a mutated abomination
of a Naga creature,
they were then hired by lord
Nostoc to go into the mines,
find whatever's creating
these abominations,
destroy whatever is the source of them,
and he will pay well and also pay for each
creature head that is
brought to him individually.
After getting into the mines,
a few battles ensue with
some of the local denizens,
couple of the umber hulks,
that were turned into snails,
and other interesting circumstances.
The party then found
what looked to be
an entirely abandoned goblin city,
and a series of goblinoid corpses,
many of which had bored
holes in their skull
in various states of decay.
They found a long bridge
across an open chasm.
Upon traversing it,
Scanlan went invisible,
and found what looked
like a duergar war camp,
which are like ashy-skinned, evil dwarves
that live deep underground.
Watched a dwarf get executed
by what appeared to be
some sort of strange alienoid creature,
that was revealed to be an
illithid, or a mind flayer.
A being that is psychic
and consumes brains.
ASHLEY: Brains!
MATT: Upon returning,
the party had a plan to lead them
off of a illusionary cliff,
that went pretty well.
Ended up taking out a significant portion
of the charging army at the time.
Vax here, however, got
stunned on the way across
by the one mind flayer, nearly fell,
however was saved by Tiberius
at the last moment.
Nearly lost their magic
carpet, but it was retrieved.
ASHLEY: Wait, you still have
the magic carpet, right?
MATT: Yeah, it got recovered. Barely.
MARISHA: We got it back, it's okay.
TRAVIS: Not thanks to some.
MATT: (laughs)
After brief discussion, Keyleth and Vex
decided they didn't want to listen
to anyone's bullshit,
and hijacked magic carpet,
flew down into the chasm below,
and discovered behind one of
the underground waterfalls
some sort of a
mind flayer who was
cast out from the society,
covered in rags, kind of
a twisted physical form,
and after a very tense discussion
seemed to befriend it under the guise of
mutually agreed retribution
against those that are oppressive
to this whole chasm area.
MARISHA: Clarence.
LIAM and SAM: Clarota.
MATT: Clarota. I don't think he'll
take kindly to Clarence.
However, this is where we
left off the previous game.
ASHLEY: So nervous.
MATT: As you guys have gathered up,
and you've finished your luxurious song
to try and ease his torn form,
he finishes tapping his
toe in spite of himself.
Looks about the rest
of the group and says,
once again, not vocally,
but speaking directly into your mind,
through a horrifying whispered voice
that you cannot even close
your ears to get rid of,
"I think it's best we rest out of sight."
He points across the chasm,
to the war camp that is
looming across the way.
He begins to dart off
towards the abandoned
goblinoid village.
ORION: I guess we should follow him, then.
SAM: Yes, that's wise.
TALIESIN: I think that's a great idea.
SAM: We follow.
TALIESIN: No, nothing can be there.
MATT: As you guys make your way in
toward the goblinoid village,
you can see Clarota who
is genuinely hovering
about a foot off the ground,
and kind of just coasting
around in a very creepy way.
Finds one tent, opens up and looks inside,
"Here, here we can talk."
Darts inside.
TRAVIS: We follow.
SAM: We do follow, yes.
MATT: As you're following--
TRAVIS: Oh crap.
SAM: Oh God, we're dead.
TRAVIS: Why?
Why would he touch his dice?
We're gonna die!
MATT: As you're following towards
the center of this town,
you, see in the distance,
a small light moving,
back from the direction
where you first saw
that duergar camp, where
Grog was assaulted.
TRAVIS: I don't recall that.
LIAM: Look back the way we came,
there's some sort of light up ahead.
ORION: That can't be good.
LIAM: Stay with Clarota, I'm
gonna go take a look,
Scanlan, come on.
SAM: I'm coming with.
MATT: Both of you guys roll stealth.
TRAVIS: I'll stay outside the
tent if somebody wants
to ask him how to get a
Magneto helmet like his.
(all laugh)
'Cause I'm gonna need that.
ORION: I'll talk to him.
SAM: It's just a roll? Not great.
Nine!
LIAM: 29.
TALIESIN: That's a number.
MATT: So, as you
officially vanish into the
ether and surrounding darkness,
Scanlan, who still has that song
stuck in his head from earlier,
his slow jam is just...
(laughs)
Abstractedly humming to
himself without realizing,
and calling a little bit of attention,
at which point you began
to hear some footsteps
in the distance that come
to an immediate halt.
LIAM: Grab Scanlan, put my hand
over his mouth, and say,
Quiet, man, what's wrong with you?
SAM: It's a nervous habit! I'm sorry!
(all laugh)
LIAM: With great power comes great
responsibility, shut up!
SAM: It's a gift I have to
share with the world!
LIAM: Later, later.
Save it for the mind flayer.
So with him tucked under
my arm like a football,
I start to creep further.
And try to make out--
if there's light from the lantern,
I can see in dim light, thanks to
daddy's blood, so.
I'm gonna try to figure
out what it is exactly
that I'm seeing.
MATT: Go ahead and make
a perception check.
SAM: I also have low light vision.
MATT: You can make perception
check with disadvantage,
because you're under his arm.
LIAM: Perception check? Oh.
SAM: Nope.
LIAM: Do I have any advantage on that?
MATT: No.
LIAM: 11.
MATT: All right.
Actually, directly
looking in the direction
of that duergar camp earlier,
you can see behind a pillar
that's blocking your view,
it's obstructing your view
of the actual camp proper,
you can see some movement in the light.
You hear some shuffling,
it sounds like plate.
You hear a voice just kind
of muttering to itself.
A familiar, female gnomish voice.
LIAM: Pike?
ASHLEY: Hey guys!
(all laugh)
ASHLEY: It's me, Pike!
LIAM: Jeez, where have you been?
ASHLEY: Oh man, I've had quite a time.
I've missed you guys terribly.
A lot has happened.
I'm sure for you guys as well.
SAM: Not so much.
ORION: I say into my thing,
"Scanlan, what the hell's going on?"
SAM: Don't worry, it's a friend,
we'll bring her back soon.
ORION: Okay, well,
there's a mind flayer here.
SAM: Keep him busy.
He likes slow jams.
ORION: Right, right.
MATT: As you guys take a look at Pike,
you notice she's fully armored, but dirty,
she's got sweat across her face,
looks like she may have
had a couple scuffles
on the way through here.
ASHLEY: I did.
MATT: She's got a wild look to her eyes.
SAM: Oh my God.
MATT: Genuinely relieved to see you.
Pike, you've managed to come down here
through the front of the mines,
which for the most part have been clear.
You follow what details you can
after asking around
and discovering that the rest of your party
had ventured below without you.
You've followed the tracks best you can,
and are glad that you at
least chose the right path
and ran into them before you ran into
something far more dangerous.
What you were inspecting
was this campsite
that appeared to have been abandoned.
What caught your eye
was against the stone wall
right above the ring of stones that form
the fire itself,
there is a giant symbol
carved into the stone
that is a protective sigil of Bahamut,
the platinum dragon,
which is a religious symbol of protection,
used in different divine rituals.
LIAM: We were looking at that,
we couldn't make heads or tails of it.
You ever seen that before?
ASHLEY: No.
(all laugh)
MATT: Go ahead and make a religion check.
LIAM: Are you sure?
Think about it, just for a moment longer.
ASHLEY: Well give me, actually,
let me rethink on this.
I think maybe--
MARISHA: So wait, are we all reunited?
LIAM: Oh, it's a natural 20!
MARISHA: Oh, welcome back Pike!
TRAVIS: The first roll.
MARISHA: Are we all reunited?
LIAM: You just forgot.
ASHLEY: I just-- you know what?
Actually, now that I'm thinking about it.
(all laugh)
MATT: You clutch your
holy symbol instinctually
as you reach up and run your fingers
along the stonework,
tracing the carving across the stone.
As you do, your eyes close,
and you feel the warmth
of Sarenrae's presence
fill your mind for a second,
and for a split moment,
you can see a well-armored, very driven,
female halfling with hair pulled back
into tight brown braids,
a dark green cloak
thrown over one shoulder,
who's currently carving
that symbol into the stone.
You're seeing Lady Kima of Vord,
the one who left this symbol,
to protect her campsite
as she made up camp here.
You don't know how long
ago this transpired,
but this was definitely
left by her in this tunnel.
LIAM: What is it?
ASHLEY: It was left by a woman.
SAM: Lady Kima,
the one we're trying to find?
ASHLEY: Yes, Lady Kima.
LIAM: How did you know that?
SAM: Me and Pike are like--
TRAVIS: Oh, Jesus.
SAM: It's so great to see you, you
look fantastic by the way.
ASHLEY: I don't feel fantastic.
SAM: Bring it in, bring it in, give me a hug.
Ooh, you smell a little.
I like it though.
Somehow it works on you.
LIAM: We're in a very complicated situation,
a lot has happened to us.
We found sort of a war camp down here,
and there is sort of a
being, I don't know what to call it.
He's got a little of
this going on, and he
speaks and lashes out through his mind.
We fought a huge force down here,
and then we ended up
falling into a cavern,
and then Keyleth and my sister
found another one, what are they called?
They're called--
illithids.
SAM: Yes, yes.
And we found a rogue one,
and we may team up with
him-- or her?-- to go back
and get revenge and maybe
kick some ass in the camp.
LIAM: This just happened.
He seems extremely dangerous, however,
the forces we faced in the other illithid
seem maybe worse.
So that's where we're at.
SAM: So welcome back.
Great, sounds like a fun time.
SAM: Let's rejoin our friends, shall we?
ASHLEY: Let's go kick some ass.
SAM: So we trot back over to
the dead goblin village.
MATT: All right, you make your
way back to the tent
that was originally scouted out.
The rest of the party's there waiting
as Clarota is awkwardly
sitting in the far end,
just looking out as all of you
slowly approach and enter the tent.
Not speaking, just reactionary,
and keeping a watch on all of you.
ORION: I turn to Clarota, I'm like,
"Ooh, that's our friend, Pike.
"She's a good ally.
"Hello, Pike!"
ASHLEY: Hello everybody.
ALL: (gasp) Pike!
ORION: Sometimes we hug as allies, Clarota.
MARISHA: Where have you been?
ASHLEY Well, I had quite a time.
When we were up on the tower,
I noticed something,
and I felt...
I had to leave,
because I started to
have a vision.
ORION: Oh, those are fun.
ASHLEY: I feel like I should talk to
you guys about this later,
just because--
SAM: It's personal?
ASHLEY: What is your name? I'm so sorry.
I'm Pike, it's very nice to meet you.
MATT: You get a better look as
you approach this entity.
You see what looks like a very tall,
thin, gaunt-looking humanoid
with a hood over the head
as you approach.
You get a better look
at the facial features.
Smooth, kind of dull, bluish-purple skin.
These sunken, creepy,
yellowish green eyes,
and instead of where a
mouth or nose would be,
you see four slightly twitching tentacles.
Barely obscuring what looks like
a round lamprey-like toothed maw.
LIAM: Pike, this is Clarota.
We've just met.
ASHLEY: Can I shake his hand?
MATT: Do you wanna reach your hand out?
ASHLEY: Yes.
MATT: There is no physical response,
the hand is not extended, but you hear,
in the middle of your
mind, at full volume,
a creepy whispered voice go,
"Are you to be one of our allies as well?"
ASHLEY: Yes.
Of course.
MATT: "Very well, she may stay."
ORION: Thank you very much, Clarota.
ASHLEY: I take my hand and
scratch the back of my head.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: I take Pike and I kind of
pull her out of the tent
really quick, and I'm like--
SAM: Girl talk.
MARISHA: Okay he's like a mind flayer,
and we found him in a
hole under a waterfall,
but he's cool, but he wants vengeance.
ASHLEY: Is that-- the thing is
covering, so he can't be--
MARISHA: He's like outcast, yeah.
But he's gonna help us fight
all of his tribe who hates us.
LIAM: Clarota.
ASHLEY: Do we know for sure
he's helping us?
ORION: Yes.
MARISHA: Yeah.
LIAM: Can you help us understand your kind?
Your history?
How you've come to be here and who this
individual is that is
fucking with your shit?
(all laugh)
MATT: Proverbial statement, I like that.
At which point Clarota's eyes narrow,
and you can feel just the
general mood and energy
of the inside of the tent grows dark.
It grows mildly
tense.
Suddenly you feel this
presence, a voice once again,
fill your mind as Clarota says,
"Seven years since I discovered my curse.
"My form was struck with
the brand of the Arcane.
"And these foul arts proved
difficult to conceal.
"My brethren could sense my impurity,
"my deviation, and cast me out.
"I was severed from the Elder Brain.
"And chased on threat of
death, should I return.
"I wandered these tunnels in squalor,
"feeding on what paltry
filth I could ensnare,
"and fleeing from the ones
I could not face alone.
"In my wandering, I discovered
a duergar stronghold,
"with a magma pool,
"and it proved to be a
decent source of sustenance
"for some time.
"Paying off the occasional straggler.
"Suddenly a great battle took place.
"It appeared something
had sieged the stronghold.
"Reading the surface
thoughts of the deep dwarves
"I encountered in the following weeks,
"I found a shift of power.
"Whatever had taken this hold had now
"demanded fealty of them.
"And they accepted when
faced with annihilation.
"This entity that took
the duergar by force,
"they called K'varn.
"I caught no sight of it.
"But the fear I could sense,
"from within these doors
were so primal, so great,
"that I knew to keep a distance to be safe.
"But four months ago
one of my estranged people,
"was captured by these ash-skins,
"and brought within the obsidian walls,
"for what I assumed was interrogation.
"Long after, the bulk of
the Duergar people marched
"in packs through the long, deep tunnels
"that led to my people's colony
"and attacked.
"Strangely, before much
bloodshed could occur,
"which I only assume was the
next step in this onslaught,
"the fighting stopped.
"And the colony allowed
the ash skins to waltz
"directly into the temple,
unharmed, unchallenged,
"where our Elder Brain resides.
"It wasn't until after I
discovered whoever this
"K'varn is, they themselves
infiltrated the temple,
"and somehow took the Elder
Brain under their own control.
"I watched as my people had
their will robbed of them.
"And they took the will of all the others
"that lived and breathed in these tunnels.
"Now, a terrible army is
forged of both factions.
"And they walk under the
banner of this K'varn.
"Since this, I've fled
back to the higher tunnels,
"and scrounged for materials so I could
"shield myself from
the iron grip influence
"of the now enslaved Elder Brain.
"It took me weeks.
"But I'm confident I'm
safe from its influence.
"For now."
TALIESIN: Is that the thing that
you wear upon your head?
MATT: As it pulls the hood back,
you see once again this kind of haphazard,
metallic cluster of patches of metal,
and iron, this dull kind
of blue metallish glow,
that you can only now
see once he's sitting
in near pitch darkness.
As he reaches up and
runs his finger along it,
"Yes.
"This I feel can protect me.
"But I think...
"I think there is a way to change
the tides of this circumstance,
"I feel that if I could
somehow free my people
"from the influence of K'varn,
"release its hold on the hive mind,
"my people would allow
me to rejoin the colony.
"To be one again with my family.
"My brethren."
LIAM: I have a few questions.
Is that all right?
MATT: "Yes."
LIAM: You and your brethren, without this,
do you think as one?
MATT: "We think as individuals,
but the hive mind connects us all.
"The hive mind gives us
knowledge, history, direction.
"It is the source of our family."
LIAM: So, one individual of your
family sees something,
the entire hive sees the
same, is that correct?
MATT: "Yes."
ORION: Oh dear, that's no good.
(all laugh)
LIAM: And you mentioned the Arcane
being a stigma upon you?
MATT: At which point it turns its gaze away,
and slinks down
into its form slightly.
LIAM: What do your brethren put their faith in,
if not the Arcane?
MATT: "They put their faith in
the arts of the mind.
"Both understanding,
"manipulating, controlling, and devouring."
ORION: Clarota, we've already
allied ourselves with you,
as we've already agreed.
MATT: "You'll help me free my people?
"To be family again, to belong."
ORION: As we said, yes.
But the thing you wear on your head,
it would make us all the more
equipped to take on this task.
It's against such powerful mind
creatures, such as yourself,
I know my way around a
couple Arcane things,
but nothing of the mind control sorts.
If someone like me were to be influenced,
it would be very bad for our group.
Even yourself, perhaps.
It would do well to at least maybe show us
how you built it, and--
You get what I'm getting at, right?
TRAVIS: I would like a steel beanie as well.
ASHLEY: Basically, where do we get one of those?
MATT: "It would take weeks to build another."
TRAVIS: Weeks?
TALIESIN: I would like to take a
look into it if possible,
and see if it makes sense. I am a builder.
MARISHA: Maybe we can figure out
something a little bit more jerryrigged.
TALIESIN: If we were all hidden, we would
have a distinct advantage.
TRAVIS: I have a very large bronze
pot in the bag of holding.
Could I wear that on me noggin?
TALIESIN: If you like.
MATT: It gives you a look in response and says,
"This protects me from the
influence of the hive mind,
"my preexisting connection."
TALIESIN: Could we be hidden from them?
Would there be a way
to cloak ourselves from
their understanding?
MATT: "Stay hidden from the others.
"Their sight is the mind's sight.
"The Elder Brain is a collection of
the once living mind flayers
"of my people."
LIAM: I have one more question,
and we have allied ourselves
to you, that's true.
But I'm curious to know,
hopefully our goals intertwine,
and we want the same thing.
But once that is achieved, and it will be,
what happens then for the Illithid?
Do you return to your home below?
Do your people harbor any
ambition to
move upward into Kraghammer?
MATT: It looks to the side and says,
"Our ambition is to
pursue the continuation
"of our knowledge-seeking.
"We have no interest in the surface.
"We only wish to spread
our dominion here below.
"Expand our great city of Yug'Voril."
LIAM: I'm sorry, what was that name?
MATT: "Yug'Voril."
ORION: Sounds like a lovely town, Yug'Voril.
MATT: "It's beautiful."
TALIESIN: I feel that we could
come to an arrangement.
LIAM: I do as well.
TALIESIN: We would require of
you, at the very least,
safe passage once we have helped you
reunite with your people, for ourselves,
and for a friend of ours
who's lost in the darkness,
who we are here to retrieve.
MATT: "For this deed, of freeing
my people from this
"insidious presence that is K'varn..."
TALIESIN: Freeing all of our people.
MATT: "I believe this could be arranged."
LIAM: Scanlan, does he speak true?
SAM: Uh.
Let's find out.
(all laugh)
SAM: I'm gonna just see if
I can detect any lies.
MATT: Go ahead and make an insight check.
SAM: What am I adding to this?
LIAM: Insight.
SAM: Oh.
13.
I'm not an insight person.
ASHLEY: Oh, can I--
TRAVIS: (scoffs)
LIAM: 20 over here!
TALIESIN: What are you doing?
TRAVIS: She's rolled twice.
ASHLEY: Assisting, assisting.
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: All of your 20's,
running out.
MATT: It's too late for the assist,
unfortunately, 'cause it's already rolled.
LIAM: But can she suss him out?
MATT: Best you can tell, those
who are looking into it,
he seems to be speaking
from a point of desperation,
and intent, as he has no other option.
He is genuinely--
You can see it in the way he talks,
and the way he speaks about his family.
He's a little crazy.
The isolation has put him to a point
where he wants to return to his people,
and will do whatever it
takes to get back with them,
however, he also seems to be,
in a weird way that you can read,
appreciative that you're willing to help,
and seems to be, on his part, genuine.
As a note, music's not playing?
I don't know if there's a reason for that.
TRAVIS: Did he say his eyes, the flayer's eyes,
are what put people in
trances, or their minds?
SAM: Yeah, the eyes, the eyes.
TRAVIS: So if we wear helmets,
it's not gonna help us.
SAM: No, the helmet is what separates
him from his hive mind.
It wouldn't help us at all.
TRAVIS: I'll still wear the big
bronze pot on my head.
MATT: You put the pot on your head.
It's clunky.
TRAVIS: On my whole head.
MATT: You cannot see with the pot on your head.
TRAVIS: No, but I'm protected from the flayer.
SAM: Can you bore two like, ghost holes in?
TRAVIS: I don't need it, I have
incredible warrior skills.
TALIESIN: Do their powers work with reflection?
MATT: "No, they can peer into your very mind."
TALIESIN: But if we approach them
using a reflective surface
to view them, can they peer into our minds
through a reflected surface?
MATT: "If they know you're
there, you're in sight,
"they can read into you."
TRAVIS: Shit.
MARISHA: They can read our minds.
MATT: "If you are obscured, unknown to
them, then you are hidden.
"They cannot sense you, but
if they know you are there,
"they can peer, they can pry."
LIAM: Is there any way to be hidden for us?
MATT: "Hidden from sight.
"Be hidden from knowledge.
"Be hidden from them."
MARISHA: Clarence?
Sorry, Clarota.
SAM: How about Clay?
MATT: "Clarota!"
TRAVIS: Jesus.
MARISHA: Sorry, Clarota.
I just have one quick question.
Why would you want to rejoin your colony
after they've banished you?
Why not leave?
MATT: "I have nowhere to go.
"They are my essence, my connection.
"I long to return.
"It is the way of my people,
"I understand this curse I hold.
"I spite myself, I look upon this disease,
and spit.
"But perhaps,
"with this deed, they can overlook it."
MARISHA: You're not diseased, you're special.
TRAVIS: Oh, God.
SAM: Question, Clarota.
MATT: "You know nothing of my culture.
"You presume too much."
LIAM: I think we do understand
your desires though,
and we can align ours with yours.
So let us speak of specifics, Clarota.
SAM: Strategy.
LIAM: Strategy.
SAM: Number one, that assortment of
dwarves and some of your friends
and ogres over there on the
other side of the chasm.
Is that something that we
need to face headlong,
or can we maybe surpass them,
trying to find K'varn, or this
temple that you speak of?
MATT: "We may if you wish.
"Their stronghold is far below.
"The magma leads the way.
"However, if I know what I've seen,
"the general resides in that camp.
"I know no way within the stronghold,
"without the brunt of their army.
"Perhaps the general can be
pried for information.
"If you bring him to me."
SAM: "Bring him," so you won't be
accompanying us on any adventure, or...?
MATT: "I will be coming."
ORION: We have to fetch him.
SAM: And the general is in that...
ORION: Where you were, right?
SAM: Yes, yes.
So we have to go over.
ASHLEY: Did you say something about a temple,
or did I completely misunderstand?
MATT: "There is a temple in our city.
"Where my people reside, that
is where the Elder Brain sits."
SAM: We'll get there eventually,
but first step is this smaller
force across the chasm.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we're gonna put the beat down.
(all laugh)
ORION: Well said, Grog.
MARISHA: You said there was a big army front,
guarding this general?
Of duergar?
SAM: Well, the general's right across the chasm.
MARISHA: Oh, he's just right across the way?
MATT: "Their forces are gathering there.
The bulk of their army
"currently is divided between that
and the stronghold below."
LIAM: Percy shot this one, I think.
TALIESIN: I did.
LIAM: I think it's important to point out
that your kin, this general,
is aware of at least three of us,
of my dragonborn friend, the
singer over here, and myself.
SAM: I don't think he knows about me.
TRAVIS: No, you were invisible.
LIAM: Just us, then.
ORION: I don't even know if he saw me.
He saw my funny cards.
LIAM: True, it could be just me then.
ORION: Oh, I cast Prestidigitation on Pike
and I clean her up real quick.
LIAM: You look lovely.
How do you think your
kin will react to that?
What will their response be
if they know that outsiders have come?
If they've seen just me at this moment,
plus a few illusions.
MATT: "They will be prepared.
"So you must find another way in.
"You must think how to not be seen."
TRAVIS: Think.
(all laugh)
ORION: Don't worry, Grog.
MATT: You've never ever, in your life,
ever heard someone else
chuckle inside your brain,
but you hear within the center of yours:
(chuckles) "Think, yes."
TRAVIS: Oh ho, it echoes in the pot.
(all laugh)
But I start laughing to myself.
(silly laughter)
LIAM: Can I assume that you
would have already given us
any advice by now if you knew a way?
Are we stuck with our own resources?
MATT: "I've only watched from a distance.
"Getting too close was too dangerous.
"I only read surface thoughts.
"If I were seen, I would be nothing,
"I would be destroyed."
LIAM: So no back doors, no secret
entrances that you know of,
into the camp, anywhere near this general?
MATT: "None."
LIAM: Fuck.
TRAVIS: What's in the bottom of the crevasse?
SAM: It's water and magma.
TRAVIS: Can we pick up the little loch ness monster
and throw it at him or something?
SAM: Oh yes, down below, in the waters,
our allies - Vex, and uh, somebody.
(all laugh)
Found some creatures under the water,
snatching bodies as they fell.
Keyleth.
Yes, I forgot who went.
ORION: Her majesty, Keyleth.
SAM: Pike's beauty distracted me,
you shouldn't have cleaned her up so nice.
ORION: I'm sorry.
SAM: Anyway, there were some creatures
down below in the waters,
are those anything that we could use,
or should we just avoid them?
MATT: You see it actually hisses for a second,
as soon as you mention this he goes,
"No, avoid.
"That creature is older than all of us.
"It resides there, an ancient mind.
"One that should be
"Kept at bay.
"An aboleth."
SAM: Do you need a lozenge?
(all laugh)
MATT: Its eyes narrow once again,
not quite understanding the words you use,
seemingly amused.
SAM: It's a gnome thing.
MATT: As a brief aside, too,
I checked the connection on my iPad,
I'm playing music fine, and
the connection's in the iPad,
I don't quite know where
it's losing its connection.
But I think we need some music.
SAM: All right, so let's review
our options, shall we?
TRAVIS: We're gonna charge in there.
SAM: We can't charge, there's a chasm.
LIAM: How did that go with
the little brain thing?
Not too well.
TALIESIN: The chasm is a problem.
SAM: Master switch.
MARISHA: An entire colony of mind flayers.
SAM: We could fly in, right?
LIAM: The bridge is gone, we have to--
SAM: We can fly in death from above.
TRAVIS: I don't know if I can.
SAM: Well, we can figure out a way.
Enough of us can turn into flying things
to get you there.
TALIESIN: We also have a flying carpet.
We can repair the bridge if we had to,
at least put a rope across.
ASHLEY: I think--
SAM: Or we could disguise ourselves somehow.
ASHLEY: I think I know where we need to go.
SAM: What?
TRAVIS: Really?
MARISHA: Really?
LIAM: Get out of this city.
MARISHA: Please, do tell.
SAM: So, hold on--
(static)
(music)
MATT: There we go.
SAM: There's music.
ASHLEY: Oh wait, I think I read this wrong.
(all laugh)
SAM: Pike, don't toy with our emotions.
TRAVIS: You just got back.
ASHLEY: So you guys haven't gone to the war camp.
SAM: We have.
ASHLEY: You have.
SAM: We been there and we quickly retreated.
LIAM: Scanlan took a poke about.
He boofed himself out of sight
and had a look around,
and then we returned to the edge of it,
and I kind of flipped the bird at them,
and taunted them a little,
but most of us haven't been in.
ASHLEY: Have you been to the lake?
TRAVIS: None of us went in the water.
SAM: Lake?
No, there's no-- what, there's a lake?
ASHLEY: Isn't that where that thing is?
TRAVIS: The bottom of the crevasse, right?
LIAM: Under the bridge, there was--
SAM: No, that's rushing water, that's not--
MATT: The area after the big drop
that was at the bottom,
there was a lake of water.
And there was a waterfall
coming out of the natural--
LIAM: And the ogres were getting
sucked under by something.
TRAVIS: So we didn't go down there.
MARISHA: Is there something under the lake?
ASHLEY: Well I just--
I don't know if I should
be talking about this
in front of him.
TRAVIS: We could go away from him for a second.
LIAM: He will probably hear the
thoughts inside your mind.
ORION: Clarota is totally fine
to talk in front of. He's amazing.
ASHLEY: Earmuffs.
(all laugh)
ASHLEY: Well, shall I share a vision I had?
LIAM: I think so, Pike. I think at this point,
we should just move forward.
ASHLEY: In this vision that I had,
I was pulled down toward the mines.
Into the tunnels, below where
the dwarves were working.
MARISHA: Through the lake?
ASHLEY: Well, past the goblinoid creatures,
and past a great underground lake.
Past a jagged onyx colored fortress,
framed in molten rock.
TRAVIS: We haven't been there yet.
ASHLEY: Past a field of broken glass and bone.
Have you seen any of this?
TALIESIN and MARISHA: No.
TRAVIS: I don't think an onyx fortress.
ORION: Those last things sound terrible.
LIAM: Yes, that all sounds shitty.
(all laugh)
LIAM: The last thing we've seen is the lake,
and we didn't go too close to it,
because a couple of
ogres fell in from above,
and they disappeared like
something grabbed them.
TRAVIS: We didn't have him fly down there
and get a close look.
LIAM: No, we haven't had a look around.
ASHLEY: I wonder if there's like--
MARISHA: I can cast Water Breathing on all of us.
TRAVIS: Why don't we send one,
like Mars Rover over here,
and have him go check it out?
MARISHA: I can always turn into, like, a whale.
LIAM: Perhaps, but the water
breathing sounds good to me.
I feel like a head-on--
TRAVIS: Isn't there something in the water?
LIAM: -- run into the chasm is a bad idea.
ORION: I pull out my empty bottle,
and I go, and I have this!
LIAM: Yes, he's got a bottle, plus,
we've killed a fucking dragon.
I know it's not an easy
task to accomplish,
but we're pretty badass, I think.
We might have a good chance.
MARISHA: So wait, is going through the lake gonna
get us through to the general?
LIAM: Well, we don't know.
TRAVIS: We haven't been down
to the water's surface.
SAM: What's the best-case scenario?
What, we come up behind them?
It's still gonna be a fight.
TRAVIS: But maybe there's a
different vantage point.
SAM: We can fly over them,
that seems like a pretty
good attack point.
TALIESIN: Some of us can fly over them.
MARISHA: Well we can figure out
to where where all of us can fly over them.
I'm more concerned about us cloaking ourselves.
Even if we're flying they're still
going to see us.
SAM: There's an ancient death thing down there.
TRAVIS: He might die, didn't say it was foolproof.
SAM: I don't know, man, he's volunteering you.
ORION: Wait, what's going on?
LIAM: I mean, our options are:
we can vote on it,
although we all know Keyleth is just
gonna go fucking do whatever she wants.
Our options are--
MARISHA: That was one time.
LIAM: Just the one time.
MARISHA: Just one time.
TRAVIS: Never to be forgotten.
LIAM: Our options are a headlong advance
into the middle of their camp.
That's a big fucking force.
SAM: Or some sort of disguise, distraction.
TRAVIS: Tiberius.
MATT: Is the stream down by the way?
ZAC: It goes down every two hours
and 17 minutes, it's
been doing that for--
It comes right back up.
MATT: All right, so let us know when it's back up.
SAM: Two hours and 17 minutes,
that sounds like Lost or something.
TRAVIS: Tiberius.
Do it.
MARISHA: Amityville Twitch stream.
TRAVIS: Go fly all the way down
to the water's surface.
Like Michael J. Fox in
Back to the Future 2,
and check out if there's any other tunnels
that we haven't seen, or ways to go.
ORION: Isn't this the same water that you bended?
MARISHA: I think so.
TRAVIS: We didn't go down to the
water's surface though, did we?
MARISHA: Well, we went over the top of it,
and kind of looked down.
TRAVIS: Oh, we did? We went all the way down?
MARISHA: When I was bending the water back,
we were kind of in that area, right?
That was that area, but the lake--
SAM: Do it smart.
Let's go bomb them.
ASHLEY: What if, I mean--
TRAVIS: Can you freeze it?
ASHLEY: Do you guys wanna like,
put me down on a rope,
and I can just run around,
see if there's any openings?
I mean I have a lot of armor.
LIAM: Go fishing with you?
MARISHA: Go fishing, yeah.
ASHLEY: Well no, just like halfway,
and then I can run around
and look for tunnels.
Well some of us can fly, so we're okay.
MARISHA: I can attempt to try and
drain the lake a little bit.
LIAM: And Keyleth said that she
can cast Water Breathing,
can help us breathe
underneath the surface.
TRAVIS: We have two underwater breathing potions.
MARISHA: Control Water's a level five spell.
MATT: I realize that.
But that's a lot of water.
TRAVIS: But remember, we're
slow as balls in water.
LIAM: You were having trouble, if I recall,
just getting the waterfall
out of the way to create,
I mean it was amazing, but--
MARISHA: I managed to get it stopped--
LIAM: I know, you fucking saved the day,
but we're talking about--
MARISHA: A lake.
LIAM: Yeah, Lake Superior.
SAM: This is not just a lake,
there is a death monster in there.
If we go under the water, we're dead.
TRAVIS: Can we stand on it?
Anything, if we wanna fight it?
Or are we gonna be
fighting it in the water?
TALIESIN: Well, we can all have Water Breathing.
TRAVIS: Yeah, but we'll be slow.
SAM: And we'll be underwater,
where there's a death monster.
TRAVIS: I'm not worried about
that part of the question.
LIAM: There's 50 to 100 fucking creeps up top.
SAM: Well, then let's come up with a good plan.
ASHLEY: Maybe there's hidden stairs
or something,
like in Indiana Jones?
TRAVIS: Can you electrify the
water and fry the guy?
LIAM: Hold up, hold up.
ORION: There's only 26 people up there.
On our last count.
TALIESIN: Before the ones we killed, or after?
ORION: After.
LIAM: Those are the ones we saw, though.
How do we know how far back the camp goes?
How many are in the gate behind it?
TRAVIS: Don't a couple of you have Lightning?
Can't you deep-fry the water?
MARISHA: I mean, I can make a giant whirlpool.
LIAM: Wait a second, wait a second.
Clarota, you've been
listening to our thoughts
for the last ten minutes.
SAM: And what clear thoughts they have been.
LIAM: What do you think?
What do you think?
MATT: "What resides in that lake is
"something you wish not to tamper with.
An ancient mind."
TRAVIS: Blah blah blah.
Hodie-fucking-ho.
MATT: "It clouds the water with its own filth.
"You find yourself unable to breathe air."
MARISHA: Didn't that happen already?
MATT: "Its mind, it takes--"
LIAM: Have you seen it?
MATT: "Yes."
LIAM: It's big?
MATT: "It's rather large."
ASHLEY: Is it like a many-armed
...situation?
(all laugh)
MATT: "One could say, yes."
ASHLEY: Okay. Swell.
LIAM: What's the sitch?
MARISHA: So we can face Cthulhu, or
little Cthulhu minons,
seems to be our choice.
ORION: Clarota.
TRAVIS: Why don't I have Lightning, I swear.
Can't you fry the water first?
See if it hurts it?
SAM: We can fly overhead and just
Lightning the shit out of it.
TRAVIS: Do that, please.
'Cause maybe there's a
way-- there's a tunnel,
and we come up behind
them or whatever it was.
LIAM: That illithid took out my
brain from like 100 feet.
SAM: You know what-- wait, wait, if I may.
When I was there, I saw the main general
control all of them instantly,
when he was about to make
a sacrifice, or feed,
or whatever he was doing.
No offense.
He instantly had all of their command.
If we could somehow get to him, and
cut off that connection, distract him,
influence him somehow to
command them to all jump
in the lake, for instance.
That would get rid of a
lot of them all at once.
LIAM: Can you make me invisible?
SAM: I can get you there.
I can make you unseeable,
but not invisible.
LIAM: What?
TRAVIS: What's the difference?
SAM: I can make you a fly.
TALIESIN: May I examine-- without removing--
may I examine your device?
TRAVIS: Oh, shit.
MATT: Make a persuasion roll.
TRAVIS: Oh man, Percy, Percy.
SAM: What's he doing?
ORION: He's asking to--
TALIESIN: 16.
LIAM: What's he doing?
SAM: Touching the hat.
MATT: He glares at you and says,
"Our agreement does not
include this interaction."
TALIESIN: It may be the key to
returning you to your people.
TRAVIS: Tiberius.
ORION: Yes?
TRAVIS: Would you go fry the fucking lake?
TALIESIN: I won't touch. I will just look.
ORION: I'm reading my book.
TRAVIS: No, I want you to--
MATT: It kind of bows its head,
but does not move closer.
It just slightly shows
you an element of it.
TALIESIN: Can I understand how it functions?
MATT: Best you can tell
it looks like a skullcap
that's been kind of
decently made for what it is,
but you can see some of
the hammer marks on it,
or whatever it was put together.
It appears to be a very simple
piece of metallic material.
TALIESIN: So it's magic.
MATT: It looks like it is some
sort of enchantment,
probably what's causing the effect.
It's not any mechanical
device that causes it.
TRAVIS: (metal clanging)
TALIESIN: So there'd be no way to
build something to create a feedback loop?
MARISHA: Ooh.
I see what you're getting at.
TALIESIN: I wanna try and see if there's any way
that I can take a look at this
and figure out a way to build some sort
of feedback system.
MARISHA: We need to build a coconut radio.
SAM: We don't even have a laboratory.
TALIESIN: He wants a coconut radio.
ORION: I love coconuts.
MATT: You have never interacted with
anything psionic-based before.
The time to research that,
and the materials needed
to do it would take months.
TALIESIN: Plan two--
LIAM: This is a fairly shitty situation.
TRAVIS: While all this is going on!
TALIESIN: Because if they can't see,
what if we blind them?
LIAM: How?
MARISHA: With some sort of interference?
TALIESIN: With a really bright light.
ORION: Oh, I love doing light things.
TALIESIN: What if they are so blind
they can't actually see us coming?
MARISHA: I believe Pike and I both have
access to spells like that.
SAM: I assume that would make
us pretty blind as well.
MARISHA: Not necessarily.
ASHLEY: Not if we wear our--
SAM: -- sunglasses?
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: Can I attempt to build sunglasses?
SAM: Before we build sunglasses--
MATT: You can probably make a couple
with the materials you have on hand.
You are limited when
it comes to resources,
as you are currently halfway underground.
TALIESIN: Even better.
TRAVIS: Vax could show his ass,
that's a pretty white light.
TALIESIN: That's as white as it gets.
LIAM: It's pale as shit. When I go to the beach,
I don't tan, I stroke.
SAM: But I thought we established that
they don't need visual contact to influence us,
they just need to be able to be aware--
TALIESIN: Once they have visual contact
they can influence us,
but they need to make that visual contact
in the first place.
MATT: "The dark, deep dwarves,
"they hate light. This I know."
MARISHA: I think it'll stun them long enough
for us to get across.
TALIESIN: If we could perhaps put some Light spells
on the back and the front of our shields,
so that we are guarded from it.
ORION: If you can make a pair
for our friend here,
that would help him out, I assume.
MARISHA: Wait, that's not a bad idea.
Pike, can we temporarily enchant
the magic carpet as a spotlight
as we fly over?
As a light death ray?
LIAM: We've seen you surrounded
in radiant light before,
you think you can do that to the carpet?
ASHLEY: I mean, I have--
MARISHA: We should have Daylight.
Where's my book?
Where's my Player's Handbook?
LIAM: And Clarota, while
they're figuring that out,
if we remain to be hidden
or blind our opponents
as we approach your kin,
will not know our
thoughts 'til they see us?
MATT: "Yes.
"They need to look into you,
by knowing you're there."
LIAM: Can I fight one of your
kin with a blindfold on?
MATT: "Perhaps."
TRAVIS: I thought if they could see you--
ORION: Clarota.
The mind hive that you possess,
how close can one be
before it actually affects?
Say 100 feet, caught my friend in mid air,
alas, in their run-in.
Is its range about--?
MATT: "That's about the distance, yes."
SAM: You may not know the answer to this.
I don't doubt your knowledge and wisdom,
but I happen to have a
ring with mind shielding,
will that aid me in any way?
MATT: "It may.
"If it gives you resistance to psionic influence,
"it would be of aid, yes."
MARISHA: Daylight.
TRAVIS: Do we have a plan?
LIAM: It wouldn't be hard to get hold of
some pitch down here, some tar.
SAM: To burn?
LIAM: No.
If you can be invisible,
and you have a ring of mind shielding,
and you can carry a bucket of
pitch to that motherfucker,
you can splash it on its
face, cover its eyes,
and it's helpless.
TALIESIN: My God.
SAM: Or I can hang that big
brass pot on its head.
TRAVIS: But I'm wearing that.
LIAM: Yes, but it could take it off, possibly.
If you smear sticky shit on its eyes--
SAM: So wait, I just have to blind it?
LIAM: Then it can't control--
SAM: Well, I happen to have a Blindness spell!
MATT: "It may still try, but to be blind,
"it would be very difficult for it to pry
into your mind."
SAM: Could it still control the others, though?
MATT: "Probably.
"That is a permanent enslavement."
SAM: So you want me to go in there, solo,
invisible, and try to blind this thing.
LIAM: No, not solo.
SAM: I'm in!
LIAM: I like your idea of turning me into a fly.
You and I go in--
TALIESIN: And we've got Light spells.
MARISHA: Pike and I can cast Daylight
on our magic carpet.
ASHLEY: I can cast it onto my shield,
and then on the carpet, and
we would have a double--
MARISHA: I have to take a nap, though.
What's that?
LIAM: But that could get us in close.
Scanlan and I could get in closer,
and blind it, and I could
stab it in the head.
MARISHA: I mean, technically I can also turn into
something flying,
I could back you guys up,
if someone else wants to take the carpet.
SAM: We can all get there.
We can all get there.
MARISHA: I can cast Daylight on your helmet.
On your pot helmet.
TRAVIS: Really?
MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: That I'm game with
MARISHA: All right.
TRAVIS: I'll be like a lighthouse, walking around.
Crushing life.
(all laugh)
MATT: You'd be the cover of
John Carpenter's "The Thing."
LIAM: Did everyone hear Percy,
that's a good idea.
TALIESIN: Two fronts.
LIAM: Yes, two fronts.
SAM: What is it?
LIAM: You and I separate from the group,
they go in shining like a beacon,
you and I (buzzes) in,
and while the illithid is focused on them,
we go in, you blind him,
and I stab him in his maw.
It's pretty good.
SAM: That's a suicide mission.
TRAVIS: I like it, let's do it.
LIAM: What else are we going to do?
TALIESIN: I'm behind this plan.
SAM: Surgical, special ops, seal team six.
MARISHA: What does Vax have to say about this?
LIAM: Vex, you mean? My sister Vex?
MARISHA: Yes, that one.
LIAM: That's a good question.
SAM: Oh, Vex, you look so tired.
MATT: Vex, your sister seems genuinely perturbed
by the circumstance, but looks to you and says,
"Look, I found him, you
deal with the situation.
"Just tell me what to do."
SAM: She's so like that.
(all laugh)
ASHLEY Let's do it.
LIAM: I gave up trying to
understand her years ago.
MARISHA: Do you know what time it is?
I'm feeling a bit nappy.
ORION: Your hair looks fine.
LIAM: Well, I--
SAM: Wait-- (shushes)
MATT: "If you need rest, then rest.
"Time of day has no bearing down here."
MARISHA: I have to rest so I can--
I'm gonna read up on this Daylight spell,
so that you and me can both cast it.
ASHLEY Yeah, we'll just take a nap and just get,
you know, rest our muscles,
and get ready for the fight.
TRAVIS: I'm gonna read up
on this Chopping Head spell.
Yep, I'm read up.
SAM: I'm gonna sing a little song to inspire
a couple of my allies here, if I can.
MATT: Okay, I would recommend
doing it after rest.
The dice would go away while they rest.
SAM: Okay, forget it.
MARISHA: I go ahead and I light an incense
in our teepee, and I make some flowers grow.
That's better. That's nice.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna do a little bit of work
on that first trick arrow.
On the trap arrow.
Since I've got a little time.
MATT: Go ahead and make a roll.
TALIESIN: That's a--
What am I rolling?
MATT: Your engineering-- your tinker's kit.
TALIESIN: Oh, it's just an intelligence roll, right?
MATT: Plus your tinker's kit proficiency.
It's down underneath your skills.
Proficiency, at the very bottom left.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I don't have a number for that.
MATT: You can add your proficiency modifier
to your intelligence check.
Add your intelligence modifier plus four.
TALIESIN: Ah, thank you.
17.
MATT: All right, and so what are
you trying to accomplish
with this arrow again?
TALIESIN: I was just trying to make
an entanglement arrow.
It's a trapper's arrow.
MATT: Okay.
You manage to work out what
seems like a tanglefoot bag-type
detonation, where if an arrow were fired,
it would be a grapple check
against the individual,
probably give them
penalties until they're able
to break free of the grapple.
So yeah, success on that one.
TRAVIS: Nice job, Doogie.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna be Hawkeyeing
Laura out at some point,
I got a couple of them.
ORION: Before I retire, Clarota,
you said you wanted to
speak with me later.
Anything in particular,
or you wish to save it for after the battle?
MATT: "Perhaps after.
"I just am curious about the source
"of your Arcane power."
ORION: Ooh, I'd be happy to discuss it.
I could learn a great
deal from you as well.
MATT: "Later."
ORION: Later, of course.
I go to my books.
MATT: So Clarota closes his eyes,
and kind of goes into a meditative stance.
The rest of you, those
who have spells to choose,
go ahead and choose
your spells accordingly
for the next day.
TRAVIS: Rub it in.
I'm sharpening my ax.
MATT: Good. Good.
TRAVIS: It is good.
SAM: Just doing my vocal warmups.
♫ Me me me me me me me me me ♫
MARISHA: I'm meditating.
SAM: ♫ Molto bene, molto bene,
molto bene, molto bene ♫
TRAVIS: The human torch was denied a bank loan.
(all laugh)
MATT: So as you all have your evening's rest...
Not very comfortable.
Number one, you're in the middle of a tent
of a goblinoid city. Second,
just the general proximity
of sleeping near an illithid,
you just have a general
sense of unsettling dreams,
imagery that is disturbing.
Pike, you have many flashbacks
to the vision you had,
and actually wake partway through the night
in a cold sweat.
As you wake up, you all
kind of slowly come to,
it's about four hours
into the evening's rest.
You feel a slight tremor,
a familiar tremor that
you felt once before in this cavern.
(rumbling)
You feel the ground begin
to vibrate and shake.
TALIESIN: I get up and look around.
SAM: Is Clay awake?
(all laugh)
MATT: Eyes are open, just sitting there.
SAM: Clarota, do you know
what that rumbling is?
MATT: "There are many creatures
that live in this rock.
"You'd best be still."
SAM: Ooh, still.
MATT: "Still."
ORION: Don't move.
TRAVIS: So, vocal warm ups.
MATT: Everyone make a stealth check.
MARISHA: Oh!
TRAVIS: Fucking nipples.
MARISHA: Pooper.
TRAVIS: We get advantage on that, right?
MATT: Nope!
ORION: 16.
SAM: 14.
MARISHA: 19.
TALIESIN: 18.
LIAM: 20.
ASHLEY: One.
TRAVIS: One.
(all laugh)
MATT: Two natural ones?
TRAVIS: Yup!
SAM: After her two natural 20's.
LIAM: Nothing to add.
ASHLEY: Nothing to add.
Well I'm new to armor, you know.
MATT: You both rolled natural ones.
Those both count as two failures.
ASHLEY: Fuck.
MATT: Thankfully, the rest of your group
all rolled pretty high.
So it was four versus five.
ORION: Yes!
MATT: You guys just barely succeed.
As you all hold still, barely breathe,
the rumbling intensifies,
and goes on for a good
minute, minute and a half,
before it eventually subsides.
TRAVIS: Aw.
Thought we were gonna get a warm up.
MATT: Fades into the distance.
Rumbling is complete.
It appears to be no issue.
Clarota says,
"Many of these creatures,
they pick up on movement,
"in that sound, be wary."
LIAM: What creatures are you speaking of now?
Is this something--
SAM: The rumbling creatures.
LIAM: But what are they?
ORION: Probably buttholes.
MATT: "I've only got glimpses."
LIAM: This is something worse
than umberhulks, I assume.
MATT: "Larger, yes."
SAM: All right, we've all rested up.
LIAM: Buttholes in the underdark!
SAM: I had a crazy dream.
It said if Geek &amp; Sundry got to 1,400 followers,
there would be some sort of a giveaway.
ORION: Oh, I had the same dream, Scanlan!
SAM: Wow!
MATT: Yeah guys, just so you're aware,
every 50 subscribers we get,
we are giving away an awesome
Geek &amp; Sundry game package.
ZAC: Ethanmyhead just won one.
MATT: Oh, there you go, congratulations!
We already got a winner.
We'll be putting those out for every 50
subscribers we get tonight.
We'll be choosing one to
win that awesome award,
our wonderful package,
so keep that in mind.
SAM: So the plan is again, you and I,
stealth. The rest, attack with light?
What's first, what's second,
what happens here?
LIAM: Well, I need to take a moment to find some--
I'm gonna look around and
see if I can find any pitch,
anywhere in the goblin camp.
MATT: Okay, go ahead and make a survival check.
Actually, this would be investigation.
LIAM: Investigation.
I got the exact same number, 12.
MATT: Takes about an hour.
You manage to find, essentially, a few piles of
rather disgusting,
sticky, goblinoid refuse,
that you imagine will probably
stick and burn pretty well.
In a pitch-type way, yeah.
LIAM: Goblin shit?
MATT: You find just a whole
bunch of goblin shit.
LIAM: Let's cook it up a little.
TALIESIN: How do you feel about
lacing it with gun powder?
SAM: I'll make some fire for you.
LIAM: Feel pretty good about that.
MARISHA: Goblin molotov cocktails? I like that.
TALIESIN: Goblin poop cocktail.
LIAM: So here's how I think this goes.
I think the team
infuses the carpet, and any shields,
or head pots they have with radiant light.
They go in and make a big
stink on the side of the camp.
You and I go in, you're invisible.
I'm a--
SAM: Fly, flea, mosquito,
dragonfly, whatever you'd like.
LIAM: Yes, let's say fly.
We go in, find the illithid, and then
we pop in,
you yell, "Hey, Spanky,"
throw goblin shit in its face.
SAM: Or I try to blind it with magic.
LIAM: Yes.
TALIESIN: Both.
ORION: Both! Why not both?
LIAM: We want to increase our odds.
As soon as he's blind,
I go in for the kill.
And then it's on us to deal
with what happens after that.
TRAVIS: It's playtime.
LIAM: It's playtime.
SAM: Might I suggest one other wrinkle.
LIAM: Yes, please do.
SAM: Remember there are some
dwarves being held captive.
We can make our way to
them and release them.
TRAVIS: We don't need all of them, though.
Just to cause further distraction,
or to get some allies on the inside.
LIAM: It's possible they could
be weary, frightened.
TALIESIN: Mind controlled.
LIAM: Seems unreliable-- yes, mind controlled.
TRAVIS: They're probably ready to fight, like me.
(all laugh)
SAM: Grog, we understand, you
want to bash some things.
LIAM: Your time to kill is coming.
SAM: All right, is there anyone else in the party
who could help us with stealth, or anything?
ASHLEY: Definitely not me.
SAM: Okay.
TRAVIS: Clang clang.
ASHLEY Clang clang clang clang.
MATT: As a note, just remember.
Because you're the one who walked through.
There is essentially a shanty town,
a tent city of war tents.
With a few rock formations.
You also notice that, or
you remember last time,
that there was the main square
that had the raised platform.
And then there was the
small stone barracks,
where it seemed both the mind flayer
and the duergar general both went back in.
SAM: So we gotta go into the barracks.
MATT: Well that's where you
saw at least they were
last time you were there.
LIAM: That's our starting point, I imagine.
ORION: Well, there's two targets.
SAM: So we gotta get in, and then get in.
LIAM: The main thing is to get the illithid,
because if he's out, nobody's--
Then they're all separate.
He's playing chess with all his minions
until we take him out.
TRAVIS: I hate chess.
ORION: So we all strike right on him.
You two are going to
take that little journey.
The rest of us, what shall we do?
I have many options and they're all fun.
So Percy.
Your sniper rifle.
I should think that you want to post up
and start taking out position.
TALIESIN: I'll do that at first,
but then eventually
I'm going to just have to
jump into the fray.
ORION: Yes, of course, onslaught
to the rest of the camp,
that we'll go about it too, right?
Make a bunch of noise, a bunch of light.
SAM: How are you going to get Grog over there?
MARISHA: I'm gonna put a giant
sunlight beacon on his head,
and I'm gonna release him to the wilds.
LIAM: Yes, but there's no
bridge, we talked about--
MARISHA: Oh, how are we gonna
get him over it?
LIAM: We have an infinite amount of rope.
SAM: How do we get it over there?
LIAM: Tiberius talks about making
him light as a feather.
TRAVIS: Or you can fly me.
SAM: Yes, you can fly him, right?
ORION: Perhaps you can fly.
TRAVIS: Why don't we turn my
pot into a lighthouse,
and then you fly me
over, and I'll do like,
abominable snow man walk.
MARISHA: I like that.
LIAM: Clarota, is there anything you can do
to help us on this endeavor?
MATT: "I can try to cloud his mind
with mine,
"but you have to swear
to protect me from harm."
LIAM: You have our word.
SAM: -- that we will try.
(all laugh)
MATT: "Then I will come.
"You must work swiftly.
"If we can leap most of the city,
"get to that barrack, storm it,
"and take out the mind flayer that resides."
SAM: Let's set down right in
the middle of the thing.
MARISHA: Well I was gonna say,
can we set down where
we're kind of backing you guys up,
holding the fort down while you guys go?
LIAM: There's no bridge.
SAM: We all have to get there.
MARISHA: I'm not worried about that.
LIAM: Get over together, get to the edge.
SAM: Yes, but where are we going to make land?
In the middle of the shit,
next to the barracks?
MARISHA: I say we might as well
go closest to the barracks as we can get.
SAM: Okay, then you and I
can get in the barracks.
LIAM: That's a good idea.
If we go as high as we can,
and just hug the ceiling
of this motherfucker,
and then go down in the middle.
And as we're going down,
you turn me into a fly and go invisible,
and that's when all hell breaks lose.
TRAVIS: I like that part.
Let's do it.
LIAM: No time like the present.
TRAVIS: Hands up if you're in.
MARISHA: I'm gonna start buffing people like crazy.
ORION: I cast Stoneskin.
TALIESIN: Gonna be buffing us
like a vampire slayer.
MARISHA: Oh! Joss Whedon
up in this bitch!
SAM: Question to the dungeon master.
MATT: Yes.
SAM: I think my Polymorph spell
is a concentration spell.
MATT: It is, yes.
SAM: I'm going solo.
(sighs)
TRAVIS: Do it.
SAM: I can get you in.
I can make you a fly,
but I can't be invisible at the same time.
LIAM: I will sneak through.
If shit goes south, I will
peel off and join the others.
MARISHA: Well, I can cast Pass
Without A Trace on myself,
and as long as we hug close to me,
there's an area around me
that's like a dark shadow.
We get like, all stealthy.
SAM: We're going in.
LIAM: We're just gonna have to improvise that.
We'll do it live, we'll do it live.
MARISHA: Wait, wait, wait! Don't go in yet.
Let me buff people.
MATT: You said you were casting Stoneskin?
Stoneskin is concentration.
The moment you cast another
concentration spell,
it goes away.
ORION: Oh, right.
So I don't cast it, then.
(all laugh)
God damned concentration spells.
TRAVIS: I would like to cast, um.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: Blood Lust on myself.
Blood Lust.
MARISHA: I go ahead and I cast
Enhance Ability on Vex.
ALL: Vax.
LIAM: Sorry, everybody does it.
Our mother did it, I do it sometimes.
MATT: To increase his dexterity?
MARISHA: To increase your dexterity.
MATT: So essentially you have advantage
on dexterity-based checks, yeah.
MARISHA: Which is your stealth, right?
MATT: Yes.
MARISHA: And then I'm gonna go ahead
and let me keep track of all this.
And I'm gonna go ahead and cast Daylight
on Grog's helmet.
Are we ready for this, are we going?
SAM: Yeah, let's go.
TRAVIS: Let's do it.
MARISHA: And I'm gonna go ahead
and cast Daylight on--
SAM: Wait.
TRAVIS: What?
We're trying to sneak
over them before we land.
Don't cast Daylight on anything yet.
We don't wanna be bright
and shiny in the sky.
MATT: A giant flare coasting over the city.
TRAVIS: We'll be like UFO's.
LIAM: (hissing)
MARISHA: I'm gonna go ahead and
cast Pass Without A Trace
on myself.
MATT: All right, so that's preparation there.
SAM: I'm gonna sing a little
ditty to inspire Vax.
♫ I didn't see the Vax
♫ 'Cause he's so goddamned stealthy
♫ Da da da da da da da da
TRAVIS: Was that "I Saw The Sun"?
SAM: Yes it was.
(all laugh)
MATT: That wondrous rendition allows you
a d8 inspiration dice, hold on to that.
ORION: Is everybody finished?
LIAM: Vox Machina, let's do this shit.
MARISHA: I turn into an eagle,
and I'll take the gnomes.
MATT: All right.
Scanlan.
Pike is heavy with the plate mail,
but it's still enough to carry
with your giant eagle form.
LIAM: Tiberius, Percy, and I are on the carpet,
and Tiberius, are you good
to help Grog fly across?
ORION: Fly.
MATT: At which point you feel this
strange lifting sensation,
for a second your stomach
kind of has butterflies,
and you realize that you
can just think forward,
and you drift forward.
Think back, you drift back.
Think up, you drift up.
TRAVIS: Amazing, don't puke in the helmet though,
that would be gross.
(imitates puking)
ORION: Am I light enough for him to take me in?
TRAVIS: I can't see anything.
Just a cauldron on my head.
ORION: For him to carry me.
MATT: For him to carry you?
Yeah, yeah.
ORION: I hop on your back.
Let's go, Grog.
TRAVIS: Great.
MARISHA: I guess the rest of them are on the rug?
TRAVIS: I can't see, so you gotta tell me.
I start flying the wrong way.
ORION: Back up, the other way,
other way, very good.
MATT: You actually clutch Grog
by the sides of his face,
and start steering him.
(all laugh)
ORION: Wherever I move your head,
just tilt that way.
SAM: Are we all in flight now?
LIAM: We're all taken care of, yes.
SAM: And the carpet?
LIAM: Tiberius, Percy, and I are on the carpet.
SAM: What about Vex?
Is she with us?
ASHLEY: She's on the carpet.
SAM: She's staying behind.
MATT: Vex, for the time being,
because it's just easier
to organize for that,
is coming on the carpet with you guys,
and is preparing in case she is needed.
TALIESIN: She's just quiet
'cause she's feeling smug
about the last game.
LIAM: Yes.
MATT: She's feeling smug about
making another RPG right now.
LIAM: She'll be back.
SAM: I wanna see how you fly, Grog.
ORION: It's really rickety!
TRAVIS: It's one arm in and one forward.
(all laugh)
ORION: Just think.
LIAM: Do you propel yourself with thoughts?
MATT: It's an awkward zig zag.
TALIESIN: Do you think happy thoughts?
MARISHA: I'm gonna fly in the middle
between Grog and the carpet,
that way my Pass Without A
Trace encompasses everybody.
MATT: All right.
LIAM: I turn to Scanlan and say, Scanlan,
we are probably going to die today.
It has been an honor.
SAM: It has been an honor.
ASHLEY: You won't die today.
SAM: Only one of us will die.
And it won't be me.
I can be invisible.
(all laugh)
ORION: You're not listening, it'll just happen.
LIAM: What were you saying Tiberius?
ORION: Nothing.
LIAM: Don't play it that way,
what were you saying?
ORION: I was saying, if you're all finished,
I'll just make you invisible
right before it happens.
MATT: You guys are all coasting over the chasm.
Now you're over the top
of the large bridge,
and the 200-foot-wide
open hole in this tunnel
that leads to the lake below.
As you glance down, you
can see just a little bit
of a trickle from the soft red light
that is deeper inside.
You can see the small streams of lava,
they're just slowly pooling at the bottom
on the outskirts of the lake proper.
As you begin to make it to the other side,
you can see tiny shapes moving in this
barely lit war camp of the duergar.
As you're coasting over,
and Clarota is along with
you guys with his hood up,
he kind of whispers into
all of your heads, just,
"Beware that some of these armies
"carry abominations created
below within my city.
"I know not what to expect from them.
"So be wary."
As this happens, everyone
make a stealth check.
Everyone, because of the
Pass Without A Track,
everyone gets a plus ten
to their stealth check.
TRAVIS: Plus ten?
MATT: Plus ten.
Thanks to Keyleth.
SAM: Thank God.
MATT: Keyleth, however, you
are carrying two gnomes,
so you have a disadvantage on it.
ASHLEY: Oh no.
LIAM: It's all right.
MARISHA: Even with the plus 10?
18?
MATT: 18.
SAM: 15.
TALIESIN: 22.
TRAVIS: 27.
SAM: Wow.
ASHLEY: 23.
LIAM: 28.
MATT: All right.
You guys begin to crest over
the very top of the war camp,
and looking down you can see now,
there are what looks to be the beginnings
of tunneling siege
engines being constructed.
SAM: What? Siege?
MATT: Siege.
You can see giant wheeled
carts with drills up front,
giant auger bores that are
being currently constructed.
You can see what looks
like a series of weapons
being stacked at the ready.
You can see there is a preparation
for some sort of attack
on the city above.
LIAM: Want to take Kraghammer.
MATT: Continue to press ahead.
There does not seem to be
any reaction to your flying.
SAM: Don't say anything.
LIAM: This close to the ceiling.
ASHLEY: Good thing we didn't cast the light.
ORION: We can all talk to each other.
SAM: Whisper to each other.
Shut up!
MARISHA: Oh, cool.
SAM: Just wait 'til we get there.
MATT: You guys make it towards the
center portion of the city.
TRAVIS: Roll shake it, roll
shake it, roll shake it.
TALIESIN: Die rolls.
MATT: You can just start beginning to see
the opening in the
center of this war camp.
There is a circle where there
are no tents constructed,
you can see what looks to
be a small wooden platform,
and there is a stone
building that is of
makeshift functional construction.
Not pretty, but functional,
looks like a barracks,
or some sort of a large bunker.
Right on the northern
side of that opening,
that center portion of the war camp.
That would be what you saw,
both the general and the mind
flayer head of this encampment
go into last time you--
SAM: The barracks.
MATT: Yes.
SAM: With a roof?
MATT: There is a roof to it,
you don't know if there's any roof access.
But there is a roof.
LIAM: Tiberius, can you turn me invisible now.
ORION: (sputtering)
SAM: But we're still in the air, right?
He's gotta concentrate on that.
LIAM: He's sitting on the carpet.
SAM: Yeah but he's--
MARISHA: Thinking about--
SAM: Him flying.
ORION: I cast invisibility on you,
that's when everything happens.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: Just falls from the air.
LIAM: So are we floating above?
MATT: You guys are currently
floating about 100 to 150
feet above the war camp,
you do not appear to
have been noticed yet.
TRAVIS: Get down there and wing it.
SAM: Should we land on the roof?
Or do we land right
outside the barracks door?
What do we do?
ASHLEY: Roof, roof, roof.
SAM: You guys wanna stay up and we'll go down?
TRAVIS: You go!
Yes.
SAM: Yeah?
TRAVIS: Yes!
MARISHA: We can start on the roof,
that way that gives us time.
LIAM: But I can't go invisible
while you're flying.
TRAVIS: Who needs you to be invisible?
You're a stealthy bastard.
ORION: We land on the roof, we get in there,
I cast Invisibility on you,
and then you go do your thing.
LIAM: We're running the risk of
as we come down on Duergar,
going (groans).
ORION: We would risk that anyway, either way.
SAM: I'm so scared right now.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: Why don't we land on the roof
and we all lay flat,
except for the people that are going in,
and you cast Invisibility.
SAM: This is the exact
conversation they had
when they were about to go kill Osama.
(all laugh)
ORION: Wait, I have an idea.
TRAVIS: Oh God.
ORION: Is there enough weight
for me get on the carpet
at this point?
ASHLEY: This is fucking stressful.
MATT: You can certainly try.
There was weight, but you're not
aware of how much was on it.
ORION: Yes I do, it's 1000 pounds.
MATT: You don't know how much
weight is on there, total.
ORION: Everybody, how much do you weigh?
SAM: Don't ask a woman that!
ORION: I'm sorry, Your Highness,
but I need to know.
The idea is if, I can
step off on the carpet,
and hang with you guys,
then Grog you can float down to the
whatchamacallit, and take Vax here,
then I can, oh shit, I need
to be near you to cast it,
damn it!
(all laugh)
MARISHA: Let's just land on the roof.
ASHLEY: Let's land on the roof.
LIAM: We're gonna go in, we're
gonna hit the roof,
you turn me invisible,
he turns him invisible,
you guys light up the
night, and we just do it,
we just gotta go.
ASHLEY: We're lighting up now?
SAM: You light up on the roof?
Let's look for access first.
Don't light up 'til we give the go aside.
ASHLEY: We're still not safe stealthy.
ORION: We need to wait before we light up.
LIAM: If anyone takes notice,
then turn off the lights.
SAM: By the way--
TALIESIN: Do not light up until you see the black
or greens of their eyes.
SAM: By the way, Clarota--
Clarota you have definitely
picked the right people
to assist you.
MATT: There's no verbal response,
but you do just emotionally
sense a slight hint of regret.
(all laugh)
MATT: Emanating from the mind flayer.
SAM: We got this!
All right, let's go land on the roof.
LIAM: All right, let's do it.
MATT: You guys descend.
ORION: Down, down.
MATT: Eagle flies down, you both,
(wind rushing),
as part of the landing,
everyone make a secondary stealth check.
TALIESIN and MARISHA: We still have that plus 10?
MATT: You still have the spell.
ORION: Oh yes!
MARISHA: Oh, that was cocked.
TALIESIN: Yeah!
MARISHA: Oh, no!
TALIESIN: You're a terrible person.
SAM: 30.
ORION: 20.
MARISHA: I'm like those boobies, that
crash land when they fall.
MATT: You rolled at disadvantage?
MARISHA: Well, I rolled a one.
MATT: Okay.
Two failures.
TALIESIN: That's a 15, 29.
TRAVIS: 23.
ASHLEY: 21.
LIAM: 28.
MATT: Pass Without A Trace is the saving grace.
A bit of a harsh landing,
from your perspective,
but thankfully you have two
small gnomes to break your fall.
ASHLEY and SAM: (groan)
MATT: You drag them a little bit
across the stonework on the top.
It's not stonework, actually.
Most of this whole thing, is stonework,
it looks like the roof
of this is made of
like a thick scavenged wood.
Whether it was taken from the surface
or from the mines itself,
it is just wooden planks
that are all keeping--
ASHLEY: Let's go in through the roof.
TALIESIN: It's reclaimed, it's very nice.
LIAM: If that thing sees us, though,
it could be game over.
I still think we should stick to the plan
of blinding it.
ORION: Yeah, do it.
SAM: So some of us need to go inside.
LIAM: You and I.
TRAVIS: Yeah, the two go inside, and if shit
goes down, we light it up.
LIAM: I will fucking yell into my
earring if shit goes down,
and you guys gotta pray for me.
TRAVIS: Go find shit!
SAM: We look around for any roof access.
TRAVIS: Come on, Chip 'n' Dale.
MATT: Looking around, there is no roof entrance.
It looks like it is
purely a functional roof
for any weathering, rocks,
you do see there are a few small rocks
and pieces of cavern that
may have plummeted here.
SAM: No chimneys.
MATT: No chimneys, no nothing,
there doesn't appear to be a fireplace,
or any sort of interior like that.
Glancing over the sides, you
can see that on the floor--
You can't really tell if
there's two floors or not,
it looks tall enough to have two floors,
but you don't see a set of windows
or anything that belies that to you.
May just be a really tall single floor.
But there are a couple
of small window openings,
one on each side of--
[static]
SAM: We're gonna go--
LIAM: Tiberius, could you do me a favor
of making me disappear?
ORION: Yes, when I do this, though,
it's going to be very cool.
(all laugh)
LIAM: Holy shit, where are my hands?
ORION: Right?
MATT: You immediately disappear from view.
You currently, visually do not exist.
MARISHA: And you still have my buff.
TRAVIS: We're like, flat on the roof, right?
MATT: You guys are all on the
roof now, you're fine.
Your Fly spell vanishes,
you feel your weight
return to you for a second.
For a split moment you're a little sad,
'cause you were having fun.
TRAVIS: Oh.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: I was a dancer.
SAM: We can see the window,
we pick one of the sides,
I don't know, west side.
MATT: West side!
SAM: Is it a single pane?
Is it an openable window?
MATT: As you glance over, it is just an opening.
There is no glass.
There is nothing blocking the way.
It is about roughly big enough to fit
a normal-sized half-elf or human.
LIAM: I take Scanlan by the scruff, and
swing him down.
SAM: Oh, I turn invisible.
MATT: As you grab him and
you're bringing him down,
you cast Invisibility on yourself,
you both vanish now,
all the rest of you are
kind of holding your breath,
hoping that now that you don't
know what's happening,
it's gonna go well.
LIAM: I'm scaling in after him.
LIAM: Go ahead and just make
an acrobatics check.
SAM: Don't roll a one, please don't drop me.
LIAM: 18.
MATT: All right, yeah, you're good.
You gingerly scale down the wall,
the stones thankfully are
just haphazardly put together,
where there's enough grip
space for you to catch on.
SAM: I have a climbing kit!
(all laugh)
LIAM: We're in, we're in.
MATT: Little late for that, but okay.
(all laugh)
MATT: You lower him down, you bring him inside,
you step down through the opening,
into the center of the hallway.
SAM: We can't talk to each other.
TRAVIS: Yes we get a map, finally!
SAM: We can't signal each other,
and we don't know where each other is.
I hold his hand.
(all laugh)
LIAM: We're holding hands, I'm
leaning way down on the side.
TRAVIS: 'Course you are.
LIAM: Sam and I have done this before.
ORION: I use my earring.
SAM: I'm not gonna talk back to
you, so whatever you say.
ORION: Just to remind you of how
these particular things work,
I'm not actually talking right now.
So you can just talk to each
other through the rings.
MATT: As the two of you step into this room,
you look about you,
and there are some ramshackle,
makeshift beds in the room.
Five to be exact, from right to left.
This appears to be one portion
of a barracks-type sleeping arrangement.
Beds are empty, they're kind of tossed,
they're not like well-kept or anything.
There's sheets kind of tossed about,
and it smells awful in here, but it--
LIAM: First, I just heard
Tiberius' voice in my head.
So I'm going to test it out and think.
Scanlan, can you hear me?
SAM: Can I hear him?
MATT: From?
LIAM: I heard Tiberius whispering about.
SAM: From thoughts only, can I hear him?
MATT: No.
LIAM: I tug on his hand to keep
going into the barracks.
SAM: I notice that his hand
is weirdly cold and sweaty.
MATT: Yeah, not weirdly.
LIAM: You just lean to
live with the stage fright,
you never move past it.
Should we pause right now?
MARISHA: You didn't bring your stuff?
LAURA: I didn't have it!
ORION: Come on in!
LIAM: Look, my sister's here.
LAURA: Hello!
LIAM: We'll make it work.
We'll bring you up to speed later,
you're on the roof of
Osama Bin Laden's house.
(all laugh)
LIAM: So question for the DM, I'm invisible.
Do I need to stealth, do I stealth?
MATT: There's still a stealth
check 'cause you're invisible,
but noise is still a factor.
You just have
advantage on your stealth check.
LIAM: So, I think we should probably stealth.
And start moving in.
SAM: Yeah, that's, we tug each other.
MATT: Beyond being invisible, you
guys make your stealth check.
SAM: I mean, I'm invisible,
and I rolled a five.
MATT: You have an advantage, you roll twice.
'Cause you're both invisible.
SAM: 13.
LIAM: 20.
MATT: All right.
You both feel you're stealthed,
there is one opening into a hallway here.
LIAM: We have, does anyone have a laser light?
TRAVIS: Yep.
LIAM: All right.
TRAVIS: Squeeze it together.
Press the little button.
LIAM: Squeeze it together?
Ah, there we go.
Okay so we're going to go down here.
MATT: Down to this one.
As you guys step out,
you can see immediately
there are two duergar guards
right by a door that leads
to a central chamber.
LIAM: So we're gonna go this way.
MATT: All right.
Immediately you see--
TRAVIS: I like how you guys have
different-colored lightsabers.
MATT: Two more Duergar guards.
TRAVIS: (lightsaber noises)
LIAM: All right, I'm inching up,
I'm pulling Scanlan behind me,
but I'm inching up to this
door, just peeking through,
seeing what I can see.
MATT: Okay, looking inside, you
can see these small symbols,
basically just red stone, the glow stone,
that lights the underground caverns here
and in a large portion of Kraghammer,
are just embedded in the
wall in a small sconce.
Peering through here, you
see one against the wall,
you also see along the edges here,
what looks to be racks of spears and pikes
and hammers and various war
accoutrements of weapons,
just hanging, and there's a set of armor,
over a small, wooden
arrangement, the armor itself
is just being stored there.
This looks to be like a fast-grab armory.
LIAM: Okay.
I pull Scanlan by the hand,
and we enter into this room.
SAM: This is so romantic.
LIAM: It's just like
the day we met, Sam.
MAT: You guys enter.
LIAM: Quietly walking this way.
We're past the door, that
looks like the front door.
MATT: It is the front door,
it is currently closed, though.
LIAM: We're gonna keep going this way.
SAM: Oh man, we're doing-- we're flanking!
MATT: Just come out this way.
There is one duergar here.
There doesn't appear to
be a doorway or entrance
to the central chamber on
this side of the hallway.
SAM: That's pretty good.
LIAM: I still have the pitch in a bucket.
The shit in a bucket
in my hand, by the way.
SAM: We can take these guys,
I'm not worried about that.
LIAM: But we'd make noise.
How far apart are the two
duergar standing in that door?
MATT: They're about five feet
apart, just enough space,
like one is on each side of the doorway.
LIAM: Okay.
SAM: Wait.
What are those red things right there?
MATT: Those are the small sconces
with the glow stone,
the red stone that lights the--
SAM: So we're trying to get there.
ORION: -- with Greater Invisibility,
so you can attack,
and you'll still be invisible.
LIAM: I pull a gold coin out of my pocket,
and throw it in this corner.
SAM: This is straight up Metal Gear.
(all laugh)
MATT: Go ahead and just make a
general dexterity check.
LIAM: And because of Keyleth, I
have advantage, correct?
MATT: Yes.
ORION: Sure do.
LIAM: So this is, what is this?
MATT: Just a dexterity modifier.
LIAM: So that's a 17.
MATT: All right, you--
(coin ringing)
Ringing sound, both of the
duergar kinda look over.
They look at each other.
Grunt for a second.
This one nods her head
and begins walking over
to inspect it, this one stays at its post.
MARISHA: (Metal Gear voice) Must have been my
imagination.
(all laugh)
LIAM: I pull Scanlan behind me,
and tiptoe right behind this asshole.
TRAVIS: Do it! Put it in him!
LIAM: And take out my vorpal blade.
And reach out and grab him by the hair
and stick it in the back of his neck.
SAM: You got my dice.
MATT: All right, so, as you reach up,
you grasp the back of this really nasty,
wiry, thick duergar hair--
LIAM: I'm so tense right now.
MATT: You yank the head back, and
take the base of the blade,
go ahead and make an attack roll.
It's a surprise roll,
so you have an advantage on the attack.
LIAM: Okay, good.
MATT: I believe you have a bonus too,
if you get the attack.
LIAM: Yes.
MARISHA: Sneak attack?
LIAM: Well, I get--
Yes, I get
advantage, but you can't triple
up on advantage I believe?
(loud bang offscreen)
SAM: What was that?
MATT: That was to freak you out.
All right, so just double-checking here
as part of your ability.
SAM: Remember every 50 subscribers
gets a free giveaway.
ORION: Subscribe now, kids.
ASHLEY: What is that smile?
MATT: If you score it, and the creature
is surprised,
it is a critical hit,
that's the other thing
I was going to mention.
LIAM: Thank you.
So this isn't a dexterity
check, this is an attack.
MATT: This is an attack.
LIAM: Okay.
So that's a 26.
MATT: That is going to hit, and
that is a critical hit.
Go ahead and roll damage with Sneak Attack.
TALIESIN: Yeah!
LAURA: Die die die.
LIAM: I'm sweating.
Okay, that's two plus seven is nine.
That's nine, that's just that part.
Six.
Seven.
Nine.
14.
And 19.
Which is, what's doubled,
the Sneak Attack damage?
MATT: The Sneak Attack damage
and the dice damage.
MATT: And the dice damage, 19 plus, is 26,
52.
MARISHA: Oh!
TALIESIN: Whoa!
MATT: As you pull the head back,
you can hear a slight,
a slight (gurgles) is about as much noise
as can make it out before the blade just,
right out the front of its throat,
blocking any passage of the air.
As you hold it, you twist the blade,
it goes limp in your hand,
but you catch it and
keep holding it there,
so it doesn't make any noise.
You're now clutching a dead duergar.
SAM: Easy, easy.
ASHLEY: (shushes) Night-night.
LAURA: Oh yeah!
TRAVIS: Lean him up against the wall!
Like he's standing there.
LIAM: Just had a thought,
I'm going to sit him
back against the wall,
and let him slide against
it, and grab Scanlan,
and into the room.
MATT: Into this room?
MARISHA: There's Scanlan.
TALIESIN: He's still standing up, kind of.
LAURA: Why is he leading
Scanlan, what's happening?
LIAM: (shushes)
SAM: While I'm invisible, I
look around for traps.
I'm just gonna see if
there's any trap doors.
MATT: Go ahead and make a perception check.
SAM: Not great?
LIAM: I got a 28.
SAM: Nine.
MATT: You notice no traps. What
you do notice, though,
is there a giant kind of war room table,
at the top of this raised platform.
It's about six feet up,
and there's a stairway
that leads up to it.
You see at the table.
One of the illithid mind flayers.
The armored general that you saw before.
And there are two other duergar currently
at the table.
TRAVIS: Nope, nope, nope, nope.
ASHLEY: Stay invisible.
SAM: We can't communicate.
TRAVIS: You guys have got seconds until
that other guard comes back.
LIAM: We can't talk.
MATT: You hear footsteps behind you.
LIAM: I put the bucket of shit
into Scanlan's hands.
LAURA: What are you doing?
LIAM: Give him a little nudge,
a gentle little nudge.
SAM: I step forward into the room,
and I hurl it at the fucker's face.
The mind controllers.
LIAM: And I'm rolling behind
him at the same time.
Behind the illithid, ready to go.
MATT: So I'll say you go up here as well?
LIAM: Oh yeah, behind him, behind him.
LAURA: What is happening?
MATT: Make a stealth check, both of you.
TRAVIS: Oh God, oh God.
Oh God, over extended.
SAM: Wait, do we get the plus ten to stealth?
MATT: No.
LIAM: Plus advantage, oh thank christ.
SAM: 19.
LIAM: Using Scanlan's advantage, so 16, 29.
(sighs)
MATT: Okay.
You slink up behind, seemingly unnoticed.
There's a slight twitch
to the mind flayer's head,
for a second, as you go ahead,
and take a big ol'--
SAM: Bucket of shit!
MATT: And fling it.
(all laugh)
MATT: Go ahead and make an attack roll.
It would be, you're not proficient with
goblin shit buckets, unfortunately,
so go ahead and roll a d20,
and add your dexterity.
ORION: (groans)
SAM: My dexterity?
MATT: Dexterity or strength, whichever's
higher, strength higher?
SAM: No, no, strength is not higher for me.
Oh, it is higher!
So 19.
MATT: All righty.
TALIESIN: Oh my God.
MATT: You fling it as the Invisibility
spell wears off of you
as part of the attack,
you fling the bucket.
A spray of thick, green,
goblin fecal matter
goes streaking through the air
as the illithid turns, its eyes wide,
to see you suddenly appear,
and then suddenly see this
entire batch of thick goblin shit
just (splashes) across its face.
Suddenly you see his tentacles
writhing,
as it screams, all of
you hear in your head
a scream.
LIAM: I'm stabbing, I'm stabbing!
ORION: I cast Stoneskin immediately.
MATT: As this happens, you cast Stoneskin,
you go in for the blade,
and you hear a counter voice in your mind.
ASHLEY: Fuck.
MATT: Clarota going, "Now."
MARISHA: I cast Light on Grog's head!
MATT: Your head comes to an extremely bright glow,
all of you averting your gaze.
LIAM: This is stealth, right? Stealth for me?
MATT: No, you're invisible.
LIAM: Oh, okay.
SAM: Attack, attack, kill him!
LIAM: 29! 29!
MATT: That definitely rolls to
hit, you have surprise.
Go ahead and roll.
LIAM: That's a critical, right?
I'm assassinating this mother fucker.
MATT: It's a critical, technically. Yep.
SAM: We're going for the general?
LIAM: The illithid can control us all.
ASHLEY: Should we go in?
ORION: We don't know anything.
MATT: So, roll damage on this.
LIAM: Roll my damage.
ORION: We just heard a scream.
Oh, we can act on that.
TRAVIS: And I rage.
MATT: Stone skin. Light on his head.
TRAVIS: Rage.
MATT: Going into a rage.
ASHLEY: Daylight on my shield.
MATT: Daylight on your shield.
LAURA: I'm so happy to be here.
(all laugh)
MATT: I will say for the purposes of this battle,
there is no Trinket here,
because Trinket would not have fit
across the way to get there.
LAURA: Okay.
TRAVIS: Didn't you give her an arrow?
TALIESIN: Yes, and you have an entrapment arrow
now.
LAURA: Okay, I get ready for that.
LIAM: Okay, DM?
62 into the back of his head.
TALIESIN: Oh, shit!
TRAVIS: 62?
ASHLEY: How?
LIAM: Critical hit.
MATT: You take the blade, and
as it pierces the back--
LIAM: Oh, it's a poison one by the way.
ORION: Damn!
MATT: It pierces the back of its skull,
you feel the muscles in its neck
tense in reaction to the blade,
but the blade slips past.
You can see a gout of purplish-black blood
begin to spill from its neck,
as it instinctually reaches up,
and pulls the blade from
the back of its head.
What's the DC on the poison?
LIAM: I have no idea.
MATT: It should be on the blade info.
LIAM: Poison dagger.
TALIESIN: Fuck.
Ah!
LIAM: I think it's oh, it's 15.
TALIESIN: This was a good plan.
MATT: The poison does not seem to take effect,
the body resists it.
It is still alive.
But it's clutching the back of its neck,
as it turns around going (sputters),
you can see its blood
spurting out of its mouth,
and its eyes are now
just burning with rage.
All the rest of these duergar are now reaching
and pulling their weapons out.
Everyone roll initiative.
(all yell)
LAURA: I don't have my stuff with me.
LIAM: Natural 20.
MATT: Oh, shit.
SAM: Let's kill some bad guys.
TRAVIS: I don't know what you're doing.
MATT: All right, so.
25 to 20?
LIAM: 20. Natural 20.
MATT: But you have no bonuses?
You should have your dex bonus too.
LIAM: Oh yeah, that's a 25.
MATT: So, I'm gonna say you're
probably going in first, buddy.
TALIESIN: Yeah!
MATT: All right, 20, 25 to 20, anyone else?
LAURA: Oh, I think I got like a 21.
MATT: What'd you roll?
LAURA: I got 16 plus--
MATT: Yep, that'd be 21, yeah.
All right, so.
19, anyone?
TALIESIN: 19.
MATT: 19, nice.
LAURA: No.
TALIESIN: Gonna wing it.
MATT: 18, anyone?
TRAVIS: 18.
MATT: Nice.
ORION: I got 16.
MARISHA: Do you have like a picture,
or a file anywhere, saved of your--
LAURA: I got jack shit!
MARISHA: Of your sheet?
LIAM: We snuck into the war camp.
LAURA: We're in the war camp?
LIAM: We all landed on the top
of their main building.
MATT: So, what's your?
SAM: 14.
ORION: I have 16.
MATT: 16, all right, so Tiberius.
Scanlan, what was yours?
ASHLEY: Nine.
MARISHA: Also nine.
ASHLEY: Not to brag.
TRAVIS: Ashley's first two rolls were 20s.
MATT: All right, top of the round
is Vax, with initiative.
LIAM: I'm just gonna (grunts) in the
back of his head some more.
I'm still invisible according to Tiberius'
Greater Invisibility spell.
ORION: No no no, as soon as I cast Stoneskin,
you were attacking,
that's why I said this is all going--
MATT: You are now visible, you are not stealthed.
LIAM: Stab him in the back of the head.
For assassinate, do I get
the critical still here, DM?
MATT: No.
You've gotten the one hit, it
is completely aware of you,
it is not a surprise attack.
LIAM: So this is a 28.
MATT: It is so aware of you,
it has never been more
aware of you in its life.
(all laugh)
LIAM: I just rolled a 28.
MATT: Okay, that definitely hits.
Attacking with your off hand?
LIAM: Oh, so this is my bonus attack?
MATT: Yeah, you get the one attack,
then you get the bonus hand.
Which is just dice damage.
LIAM: Okay, this is fire.
My flame tongue dagger, I
got two plus six is eight.
MATT: Eight?
LIAM: Eight.
MATT: All right.
And your other attack?
Are you doing your bonus attack?
LIAM: Was that the bonus attack?
Or was that my main attack?
MATT: This is your new combat round,
that was your main attack.
LIAM: That's a nine, and here
comes my bonus attack.
Okay, 14.
MARISHA: Kill him.
LIAM: 24.
MATT: 24 hits.
LIAM: Here comes my keen dagger.
Which is an eight.
MATT: Eight damage?
LIAM: Yes.
MATT: So the first strike,
you swing across with
the flame tongue dagger.
As it backs up, you put another gash
across the front of its
neck and chest area.
It reels back and is looking
at you with angry fury.
You feel this coming shake,
this horrible force of severe retribution
coming to your mind, and
as you're bracing for it,
you take your other blade,
you see its mouth opens up
with frustration and anger
as its tentacles kinda curl back,
and just go in for the grab.
You place the blade
squarely into that maw,
you feel the scraping of its
teeth across your knuckles,
but it doesn't matter,
because whatever anger and
light was once in its face,
goes dark and dull.
(all cheer)
MATT: As immediately it crumples to the ground,
lifeless, pull the blade from the maw,
mind flayer down.
(all cheer)
MARISHA: Yeah Vax!
MATT: He was next, but not anymore.
As it falls to the ground,
all the rest of the duergar immediately
have a reaction.
We'll get to their turn in a second.
Vex, you're up.
So you're on the roof, up here right now.
SAM: Gotta get inside first.
LAURA: We have to run down in?
MATT: Run down, you're on a wooden roof surface,
you heard before there's an entrance here,
and an entrance there.
LIAM: Windows are swing-down-in-able.
SAM: Unless Grog can just
tear through the roof.
LAURA: What was your initiative?
LIAM: It's wood.
TALIESIN: You can hold initiative.
LAURA: I guess I'll hold, I'll hold,
to see what the hell's happening.
MATT: So you hold on that.
It is now this dude's turn, the general.
He, unaffected by this, it seems,
just angrily leaps on to
the table, runs across,
(groans), and jumps down towards you.
As he does, you see his
physical form seems to enlarge.
His actual small dwarvish
form begins to swell,
his muscles tense.
He's about the size of a normal person,
if not a little bigger right now.
He comes at you with this giant black,
jagged metal war hammer.
(groans) Comes down to swing at you,
as he comes down, you
see it burst into flame.
There's fire now surrounding
the head of this war hammer
as it arcs toward you.
SAM: What?
MATT: That is going to be a
24 to hit.
LIAM: Oh, it hits, but I use Uncanny Dodge
to try to swoop out of
the way as best I can.
MATT: All righty. You suffer--
That would be...
12 plus six fire damage,
so, 18, reduced to nine.
You take nine damage from the strike.
As it strikes down, it
goes for a back swing
to attack you a second time.
That is going to be a 15 versus AC.
This time you just dodge
completely out of the way.
Derge out of the way.
MARISHA: Derge.
LIAM: Er mah gerd, I derged.
(all laugh)
MATT: Percy, you're up.
TALIESIN: Just in case, I'm going to push off
and wait for Grog.
So I'm holding my turn.
MATT: Okay, Grog, your turn.
TRAVIS: Right, so we're on the
roof of the thing, right?
MATT: Correct, you are.
TRAVIS: I'm in a rage, I take
the pot still on my head,
and I pick up my ax,
and I draw one gigantic
smash through the roof
of the building.
MATT: Go ahead and make a strength check.
TALIESIN: God, yes.
ORION: This is all you're good for.
MARISHA: Yes, come on Grog.
This is all you're good for.
TRAVIS: 15.
MATT: 15?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: All right.
MARISHA: Come on.
SAM: 15?
MATT: You bring your ax up,
you bring it down on
top as hard as you can,
go ahead and roll ax damage.
TRAVIS: Is that a d12?
MATT: It's a d12 plus your strength modifier.
Plus two 'cause you're raging.
TRAVIS: Do I get advantage on that?
MATT: No.
TRAVIS: Seven.
LAURA: Plus two 'cause you're raging.
TRAVIS: Nine.
MATT: Nine damage, okay.
As you swing the ax down,
slam, it hits the wood.
With the sheer weight of you there,
and most of you guys conglomerated
at that point,
the actual roof breaks open and splits,
into a small space.
You slide down in the process.
ASHLEY: I jump on to Grog's foot.
(all laugh)
MATT: All right.
Go ahead, both of you
make an acrobatics check.
ASHLEY: Oh, I wouldn't have had to do it.
All right, well, I'm in the building.
TRAVIS: 21.
MATT: Acrobatics check?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: Pike?
You have disadvantage 'cause
you're in plate armor.
ASHLEY: Six.
MATT: All right, so Grog, you
manage to land on your feet.
Pike, you actually
plummet off and fall off
to the side, right there.
You are currently prone,
and from the fall,
which you guys both dropped down,
you managed to reduce the damage,
but you from the fall, you take
eight points of fall damage.
You are now flat on your back,
the wind knocked out of you for a minute.
SAM: Pike!
ASHLEY: I'm okay, I'm okay!
SAM: Oh okay, thank God.
MATT: All right.
That brings us now,
Vex and Percy are the same.
TALIESIN: You first? Or should I go first?
LAURA: Let's go down at the same time.
TALIESIN: We'll go, we both jump
down at the same time.
MATT: Both jump down,
go ahead and make your
acrobatics checks, guys.
TALIESIN: 20.
LAURA: Oh, I rolled really bad.
MATT: What did you roll?
LAURA: I rolled a two, but I
add it to my acrobatics.
MATT: Yes, which is?
SAM: Which you don't know.
LAURA: Which is like, I bet.
MATT: Your acrobatics, as you're proficient in it,
and you have plus five dex,
so that would bring it to 11?
LAURA: Yes.
MATT: Or no, 12.
LIAM: Did you bring any Wheaton
power from the other room?
(all laugh)
MATT: You just barely land on your feet,
you do take fall damage,
but you don't fall prone.
You take eight points of fall damage.
Percy, you manage to land fine,
without any damage, on your feet.
On the ground, both of you
kind of three-point landing.
Avengers style.
TALIESIN: Do I have time to get a shot off?
MATT: You do, that was your movement.
So what's the deal?
TALIESIN: Wow, I'm taking a second,
and I see that Vax is getting attacked,
and I'm gonna just take a shot at the--
The guy with the hammer.
The biggest thing I see.
MATT: Do you have your glasses or goggles on?
TALIESIN: Yeah, that's right, I have a helmet.
So yeah, I'm wearing the helmet.
I'm cool with that.
MATT: So go for it.
LIAM: Do it, Starlord.
TALIESIN: Ah! A natural 20.
(all cheer)
MATT: Against the general,
or one of the duergar?
TALIESIN: The general.
LIAM: The guy on the table attacking me.
MATT: Yeah, you can just barely see him,
the stairway is up there.
TALIESIN: Doesn't matter, as long
as I have-- partial cover,
it don't matter.
MATT: Right, I know, and he does have,
he has three-quarters cover
because of the distance,
but you natural 20'd, so it doesn't matter.
TALIESIN: I can ignore it, I ignore
three-quarters cover.
MATT: You do, because--
TALIESIN: I'm awesome.
MATT: Yep.
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: So that's double 1d-- I should have gotten
some bonuses on that, I'm an idiot.
Plus five.
It's just double dice damage?
MATT: Double dice damage, then add your modifier.
MARISHA: Woo!
TALIESIN: That's 19 points of damage.
MATT: To the general, nice.
MARISHA: Nice.
MATT: (explosion)
He gets shot in the back
of the shoulderplate,
you hear it ricochet and a little bit
of blood begins to streak
off the back of his head.
He looks over his shoulder
with an angry grunt,
you can see now this dwarf,
who's still swelling in size.
It looks, (growls), an
angry nostril flare.
You, have your bow ready?
LAURA: I wanna do Lightning Arrow on the guy
attacking my brother.
MATT: That guy there?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: Okay, go ahead and roll to attack.
LAURA: Ugh, I don't think I hit.
MATT: What'd you roll?
LAURA: I had rolled a four.
MATT: A four, you had a plus 11 to hit,
it's going to be a 15,
unfortunately you miss.
The arrow streaks past.
Yeah, the arrow just ended up
striking the wall back here
and (explosion) arcs
lightning throughout the wall,
unfortunately does not--
LAURA: I Hunter's Mark him anyway,
just for future stuff.
MATT: You used your--
LAURA: That was a bon--
MATT: You used your bonus action
to cast Lightning Arrow.
LAURA: Oh! So I get a regular attack now?
MATT: Well, that was part of your regular attack,
like your next arrow you fired.
LAURA: I get it.
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: You're going off-book, this is cool.
MATT: I think, let me double-check
real fast, just to be sure.
Because I don't wanna screw
you out of a cool turn.
LAURA: That is mine!
MATT: Next time bring your sheet.
LAURA: I'm sorry.
MATT: That's okay.
Yeah that's a bonus
action to cast lightning,
into your next arrow you fire,
however, you do have two attacks.
So you can shoot a second time.
It just isn't affected by Lightning Arrow.
LAURA: I roll 14.
MATT: That does hit, go ahead and roll
damage
there's 1d10, plus--
LAURA: I think it was 1d8, actually.
MATT: Oh, for the longbow?
Okay, 1d8 plus five for your dex,
and then plus two for the bow.
Plus seven.
LAURA: Ten.
MATT: Ten damage, all right.
So first arrow just
streaks off, hits the wall.
As he's kind of staring at Percy,
he looks towards you, and as he does,
the second arrow
sticks into the plate,
he kinda looks at it.
(grunts)
Just snaps it off in the armor.
Grabbing his two-handed sword, or sorry,
the war hammer in the other hand.
Minis, it's confusing.
All right, that ends your turn.
Grog, the light that is
beaming from your helmet
currently right now is
filling up the room,
and it is extremely bright,
most of you guys can handle it.
You see all the duergar at
the table like (groans),
bunch of duergar come running in as well,
as they run in, they're
having to shield their eyes,
but it's actually physically hurting them
to be in that room right now.
They're like (groans).
Keeping it at bay, this
one attempts to run in,
this one's kind of making its way over.
These guys here, this one's
gonna go ahead and run here,
this one's gonna go
ahead and come to Grog.
These two are gonna come up behind.
SAM: Is that guy the general?
MATT: That guy's the general, yes.
This one's gonna come up behind to you.
All right, they have
disadvantage on their attacks.
ORION: Nice.
MATT: Because of the light.
(all cheer)
TRAVIS: 'Cause I'm so bright.
MATT: Attack against you.
MARISHA: You're the brightest
tool in the shed today.
MATT: That is a 17 versus AC.
You just dodge out of the way.
Next one, its
war pick against you, Grog.
ASHLEY: Get skinny, get skinny.
MATT: That is
20 versus AC?
TRAVIS: That hits.
MATT: That hits, all right.
You take eight points of damage
as it slams you with its
war pick in the chest,
you can feel it kind of gets about
a half an inch of depth into it,
but you just kind of shrug it off,
and flex your muscles and it
pops it out of your torso.
TRAVIS: That's cute.
MATT: The two against you.
That'll be a 19 versus AC.
LAURA: Oh, yeah, that hits for sure.
MATT: And a 17 versus AC.
LAURA: That--
hits.
MATT: All right, so you take two hits.
That's 11 damage.
And 13 damage as both of them
start whaling you from behind
with war picks.
LIAM: Vex'ahlia!
I yell.
LAURA: 13 and what?
MATT: All right.
Next up is the one that's attacking you.
SAM: Scanlan.
MATT: Scanlan, that's going to
be, at a disadvantage,
a 15 versus armor class.
SAM: 14.
MATT: 14? That still strikes you.
You take eight points of
damage from the war pick.
Slamming you over the shoulder.
SAM: (yells out) Ah, I'm so awesome, Pike!
(all laugh)
MATT: That ends their go, Tiberius, you're up.
ORION: I'm still on the roof, right?
MATT: You're still on the roof, yes.
ORION: What can I see, like if I go down,
what can I see?
MATT: You look through the hole,
and you can see pretty much
the entire battlefield.
You're just up here
looking down through it.
ORION: Oh, wonderful.
MATT: You're currently the
only one still up there.
ORION: Yes, I think I'll stay right
here, thank you very much.
And how tall is the roof?
How high is it?
15 feet?
MATT: It's about 25 feet up?
ORION: Okay, wonderful, wonderful.
So, let me see here.
This is fun.
MATT: You are technically, because I can do it.
TALIESIN: Gonna use one of the
little lifties, aren't you?
MATT: I am.
MARISHA: Finally.
LIAM: Bring the fire, Tiberus.
SAM: Oh.
Toys.
MARISHA: Now he's getting out toys.
TALIESIN: Aw yeah.
SAM: Come on, do something.
ORION: I'm waiting for him to do something,
'cause it's so cool.
MARISHA: I got him this for
Christmas two years ago,
and he's finally using it.
MATT: You are up here right now.
ORION: Awesome.
TRAVIS: Three-dimensional fighting.
LIAM: Toys, toys.
MATT: Is that visible?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
Sweet D&amp;D rave.
ORION: Okay.
I'm going to--
I see the two guards behind Vex, right?
Is that what's going on?
MATT: Yep, right there.
ORION: And then the one duergar in front of Grog?
Is that what's going on, too?
MATT: Yep, right there.
Great, I will cast
Grand Columns
under all three of those
dudes, and pin 'em.
Right up against the roof.
With my columns.
LIAM: Clever girl.
MATT: The?
ORION: Pillars, yes.
MATT: But those pillars only go 15 feet up.
ORION: No, they go up to 25.
MATT: 25? Oh nice.
ORION: Yeah.
MATT: Okay.
ORION: That's why I always ask that question.
It does 66 bludgeoning
damage when it's pinned.
ASHLEY: Bye bye.
SAM: If they don't make their save.
MATT: All right, so.
Go ahead and what is your DC on that?
Your spell DC?
ORION: 17.
MATT: 17, all right.
All right, the heartiness
of the duergar resilience
gives them advantage on
saves against spells.
They all make their saves.
SAM: What?
MATT: But they are still up
on these platforms now,
raised above.
So what is--
Does it do any damage if
they make their saves?
ORION: (reading)
SAM: Come on iPhone, come on iphone!
MARISHA: You're supposed to know everything!
SAM: iPhone five!
This is the Fifth Edition.
ORION: Why doesn't it say?
I guess it doesn't.
It doesn't say.
MATT: So they are currently--
SAM: What is this madness?
TALIESIN: Oh, you're crazy.
ORION: Oh, wait a minute, no.
You make this call.
If a pillar is prevented
from reaching its full height
because of a ceiling or other obstacle,
a creature on the pillar
takes 66 bludgeoning damage
and is restrained, pinched
between the pillar and obstacle.
The restrained creature can use an action
to make a strength or dexterity check
against the spell save DC. On a success they are
no longer restrained, and must
either move off the pole,
or fall off of it.
So they still, it still happens,
but they're not pinned by it.
Got you, okay.
So go ahead and roll
damage for all of them.
MARISHA: Woo!
MATT: Good to know.
(sings) New spells that just got released.
LIAM: There's magic in the dwarves.
SAM: Magic in them.
LIAM: The duergar.
MARISHA: ♫ A whole new spell
TALIESIN: ♫ A fantastic way to die
MARISHA: ♫ No one can tell us no
ORION: 27 damage.
MARISHA: ♫ Except for Matt
(all laugh)
MATT: All three of the duergar are crushed.
SAM: To death?
MATT: Against the ceiling.
ORION: I did 27 damage to each one.
TRAVIS: Nice!
MATT: Splat, splat, splat, they're all slammed
into the ceiling,
you can see limp dwarf arms and legs
now dangling out of the stone pillars
that are now permanently
embedding them into the ceiling.
LIAM: Yeah, son.
SAM: Crazy room!
ORION: I go like this, hah!
I use two of my sorcerer points,
and I cast Quicken Spell,
and I look at the general, and I--
Because of my books I've
been tampering with,
I cast Blight on his eyes.
Okay.
'Cause I wanna.
(all laugh)
MATT: What's the-- the DC is 17, you said?
ORION: Yes.
MATT: All right, natural 20.
So he makes his save.
(all groan)
ORION: He takes 8d8 damage, and if he saves,
he takes half the damage.
MATT: Okay.
ORION: 10, 15.
LIAM: They were all eights, right?
MARISHA: Well, he does all of them
and then divides.
SAM: But you said half.
MARISHA: He rolls all of them and then divides.
SAM: I see.
ORION: 15 plus, what is that, ten, 14.
MARISHA: Your first one was--
ORION: 29?
MATT: So we'll say a solid 14 points of damage.
All right, gotcha.
No other effect, just the
damage from Blight, right?
ORION: Yeah, because he made his save.
MATT: All right, Scanlan, you're up.
SAM: Oh, okay.
I'm going to, (groans).
God there's so few people to kill now.
(all laugh)
SAM: You did it all, is it
just us and the general?
LAURA: Wait, that guy behind you though.
MATT: Just you guys, the general.
There's a guy right behind you.
Those guys got slammed.
SAM: Okay, I'm gonna cast
Dominate Person on the general.
TRAIVS: (laughs) What does that do?
ORION: Oh shit.
TALIESIN: No.
LIAM: He's a power top.
MATT: With advantage, he
rolled a one and a two,
on the saving throw.
(all cheer)
MATT: That's ridiculous, okay.
SAM: I'm going to
Dominate him and inform him,
I can give him a command, right?
Yes.
ORION: You can make him do whatever.
SAM: I'm going to tell him to stand down,
and tell all of his allies to stand down.
MATT: All right.
He turns around.
Gives you a look, a strange look, he goes.
"Men, all of you, drop your weapons!
"Now.
"We are surrendering to
our new infiltrators."
He throws his war hammer to the ground.
The rest of them all kind of look around.
Go ahead and, I'm gonna have
you make intimidation check
on his behalf.
SAM: Okay, on his behalf?
MATT: Yes.
SAM: Do I add mine?
MATT: No, I'm just considering
that, so you rolled 11?
SAM: 11.
(sings along with the music)
MATT: The three other duergar look confused,
look at the dead mind flayer,
look at their general
telling them to surrender,
and they all kinda throw
their weapons to the ground,
and stand there with
their arms to the side,
kind of waiting for
what's gonna happen next.
As you finish that,
Clarota slowly drifts down.
SAM: Oh yeah, Clarota, thanks
for all the fucking help.
(all laugh)
LAURA: Oh no.
This is gonna be bad.
MATT: Clarota just kinda looks around.
Says, you hear this voice in your mind go,
"I had my doubts, but, well done."
ORION: Thank you.
MATT: So.
That ends that turn.
Scanlan, do you want to move at all?
Are you going to stay where you are?
SAM: I'm gonna stay where, well,
I'm gonna move just a couple feet
away from the guy right behind me,
and I'm going to, as my bonus action,
might as well give Grog some dice.
And also just tell everyone,
remember, let's not kill the general,
we need him for information.
LIAM: Probably if anyone tries to hit him,
he'll snap out of it, so.
SAM: That's it.
I also take a little poo in my pants.
TALIESIN: Small kilo.
SAM: This is still--
A battle? Even though.
No combatants?
MATT: I mean, if you guys are deciding
not to fight anymore,
what's your plan?
MARISHA: I--
Come on down and I say, good work guys.
That was cool, that was great.
SAM: He's under my spell.
LAURA: Perhaps we should tie him up.
MARISHA: That's what I was gonna say,
I cast Grasping Vine
and I just take a vine
and I tie his hands behind his back.
And kind of grapple him.
SAM: So that'll break the spell.
MARISHA: Well no, I'm not damaging him, I'm just--
LIAM: Hugging him.
MARISHA: Yeah.
LAURA: Hugging him with vines.
TALIESIN: Vine hugs.
MATT: As this is happening, you
guys feel a familiar tremble.
SAM: Oh no.
Be quiet.
MATT: In the ground.
LIAM: DM is out of his mind.
MATT: Everyone make a stealth check.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: Damn it.
ORION: Oh, that's a 20.
SAM: That is a 20.
MARISHA: (whimpers)
This is the second time I
rolled a one on my stealth check.
TALIESIN: Wow.
MARISHA: I'm not stealthy today.
ASHLEY: 17.
LIAM: 18.
LAURA: 19.
TRAVIS: 14.
TALIESIN: 23.
LIAM: Pretty good overall.
ORION: Two.
SAM: 22.
MATT: All right.
There is the rumble,
gets louder and louder,
and you can see the duergar
looking around nervously.
The rumbling kind of fades for a second.
And with a cacophonous cracking sound,
the stone floor beneath
you
splits open.
SAM: No!
MATT: Right here.
LIAM: (groans)
MATT: Percy, make an acrobatics check
and try to avoid whatever
is coming through.
SAM: Whatever? It's a dragon!
TALIESIN: 18.
LIAM: It's a worm.
MATT: All right, you manage to
just pull out of the way.
As a large--
LAURA: What the fuck is that?
MARISHA: : What is that?
MATT: A large armored four-legged creature
comes bursting out of
the ground around you.
ORION: Oh great, it's a rock butthole.
(all laugh)
MATT: Lets out this horrible
screeching growl,
has this kind of hungry look in its eyes.
MARISHA: Can I reactionary real quick,
take my Grasping Vine and just lift him
and kind of put him in the corner
to keep the general safe?
MATT: Unfortunately, no.
ORION: Is he rooted?
MATT: He is currently--
Is considered grappled.
LIAM: I have a question.
MARISHA: I was just trying to keep him safe.
LIAM: Can we take a potty break before?
SAM: A potty break?
No breaks tonight!
LIAM: No breaks?
MARISHA: No breaks.
MATT: We're pushing through.
You need a bottle.
MARISHA: Exercise your kegels.
MATT: If you really need to go, you can.
When it's not your turn.
LIAM: No, I'm fine.
SAM: Just pee on Ashley, it's okay.
CREW: Suck it up, man.
MATT: As this entity comes burrowing up
from underneath the ground,
it immediately makes a
strike against--
SAM: Guys, this is so exciting.
And Laura has no idea what's going on.
LAURA: No clue, good times.
MATT: This is gonna be a bite
attack against you, Percy.
That is, all right, 24 versus armor class.
TRAVIS: Shit, bite is at 24.
TALIESIN: Yeah, that--
That hits.
MATT: As you reactively attempt
to move out of the way,
this creature comes
tearing out of the ground.
Gets its bearings, rears back,
and this giant, toothy
maw comes clamping down
onto your entire torso.
You suffer 36 points of piercing damage.
SAM: Oh!
TALIESIN: The fuck?
MARISHA: 36?
MATT: 36 points of piercing damage.
That's going to end its turn.
MARISHA: Shit.
MATT: Pike, you're up.
ASHLEY: Okay, well.
TALIESIN: That hurt.
ASHLEY: I'm still prone?
MATT: You are prone,
you can use your movement to get back up.
ASHLEY: Okay, I use my movement to get back up.
Do I also get an attack for doing that?
MATT: You still have your action,
and your bonus action,
it's just your move.
ASHLEY: Okay.
I will use Guiding Bolt, and
I'm gonna shoot that thing.
MATT: All right, go ahead and roll for the attack.
SAM: That's my girlfriend.
TRAVIS: Come on, Pike.
MARISHA: Does this guy appear to be messed up
by the Daylight at all?
ASHLEY: Okay.
Do I add anything?
MATT: You add your spell attack modifier,
it's on your spell sheet.
So the top of your spell sheet.
ASHLEY: Sorry guys.
Oh sweet, okay, so.
That would be 25.
MATT: That definitely hits.
So, Guiding Bolt, what does that do?
ASHLEY: So I roll, where'd it go, I roll 4d6.
I roll 4d6.
MATT: 4d6, go ahead and do that.
ASHLEY: Yes.
16.
MATT: 16, all right.
So you reach back,
clutching your holy symbol.
You get back off the ground,
release your hand as this
suddenly flaring blast
of divine energy comes cascading
out of the front of your palm,
blasting into the side of the face,
nearly searing one of
the eyes of the creature.
It rears back, brings
one leg up instinctually,
(growls) slams the ground in the process--
How you doing?
That's disadvantage to your next attack.
LIAM: Aw!
ASHLEY: Wait, what are you at?
TALIESIN: I'm at 38.
MATT: It lands, puts its foot
back on the ground,
and kinda gears its attention towards you.
It's angling around the room
for what should be its next meal.
Anything else you wanna do?
ASHLEY: Can I give him a healing potion?
Can I heal him?
MATT: He's too far away.
You could use your bonus action
if you wanna use Healing Word.
ASHLEY: Okay, I'll use Healing Word.
MATT: Okay, so go ahead and roll that for him.
While you're doing that, brings us--
So Clarota now gets its action.
MARISHA: Yeah, Clarota!
MATT: Clarota now looks wide-eyed, seeing this happen.
You hear a slight voice in
the back of your head go,
"This is complicating."
As it rears back,
you hear the slight
echoing, screeching sound,
that just manages to skirt the outside
of your mental capacity.
You feel like if you were any closer,
or if it was directed towards you,
it would be a horrible
ringing pain in your head.
You're just peripheral to it.
It makes its attack.
Unfortunately, the exterior, the bulette,
and/or its mind shielding is too strong,
it seems to have no
effect on the creature.
SAM: Damn it!
Clarota, worthless!
MATT: A bulette, is the entity.
That ends its turn,
top of the round, Vax.
LIAM: Okay, I think, where's the laser?
Here it is.
It looks like I have
just enough squares to go
one two three.
Who's this right here?
MATT: That's a duergar.
Weapon on the ground, not armed right now.
LIAM: Can I get to here on a turn?
I can't tell.
MATT: What's your movement?
LIAM: It's 30 feet.
I'll use my bonus action to
click my haste boots together.
MATT: Okay, then you can definitely do that.
LIAM: Okay, and since Percy
is right up against it,
I'm able to deal Sneak Attack damage,
because there's another one of its foes.
MATT: Exactly, yes.
You don't get an advantage on the attack,
but if you attack, you do it.
LIAM: So I'm gonna try to strike
him in his underbelly.
MATT: All right.
Even the underbelly
itself is heavily armored,
you have to kind of gauge
quickly where the plate is.
LIAM: 20.
MATT: 20?
20 hits.
MATT: Go ahead and roll with
your Sneak Attack damage.
MARISHA: So 20 hits?
LIAM: Oh, and it was--
Never mind.
So three.
There we go.
22.
MATT: 22 damage?
All righty.
Got it.
Cool, that brings us to--
The general is going to
attempt to make a saving throw.
SAM: Shit.
He can do that?
MATT: Every time he gets a turn round,
he gets a chance to break out of the--
And he does.
SAM: Oh, he broke out?
LAURA: (gasps)
MATT: Shrugs off the mental influence
of the Dominate spell.
However, he is not currently armed.
He uses his
movement, or action to
pick up the war hammer.
Fury and anger is in his eyes.
MARISHA: He's still grappled.
SAM: No no, he just broke out, right?
MARISHA: Oh, from the grapple, too?
MATT: Yeah, he used his whole turn
to break out of the grapple
and grab its weapon, that's all he can do.
SAM: Where is he?
MATT: Right there.
LIAM: To fight the bulette?
Or to--
MATT: You have no idea.
LIAM: Oh, we don't know, oh.
He could just be reacting to the bulette.
MATT: The flames on the hammer are out too.
But it picks up the war hammer,
it's cold black steel currently.
TRAVIS: We got our Davy Jones in the room,
he'll take care of the dwarves.
MATT: That brings us to...
Grog.
TRAVIS: (groans)
Kitty!
I would like to go into a frenzied rage,
and charge at Clifford the big red dog.
(all alguH)
MATT: You leap off the higher platofrm,
come rushing out with your ax in the air,
as you come down using the
full weight of your body
behind the attack, go ahead
and roll your three attacks.
TRAVIS: All right, I have nine, eight, 17.
SAM: You have one dice from me.
I've inspired you.
TRAVIS: Oh.
SAM: (singing) Grog. Grog.
TRAVIS: Is it a 20 or is it a what?
MATT: You get to add a d8 to an attack roll.
SAM: If you have a shitty attack roll,
add a d8 to it, if you have a shitty roll.
TRAVIS: 17.
ORION: Grog, smash right
through his plate thingy.
MATT: Barely hits.
TRAVIS: 19.
MATT: Hits, all three attacks hit.
TRAVIS: Yeah, that one hits, 16 plus eight.
MATT: So all three attacks hit,
roll damage for three hits.
As you come now, just
slamming your grey ax,
into the side of this armored beast,
just over and over again.
Cleaving this nice little wide section
of its armor on the side.
LIAM: Take his fucking head off.
TRAVIS: 14.
21.
21 again.
ASHLEY: What?
TRAVIS: 22.
LAURA: Oh, so.
22, 21, and 14.
SAM: Whoa.
LAURA: I was doing his math.
(all laugh)
MATT: 21, 22, and 14 you said?
ASHLEY: 57?
SAM: 57.
TRAVIS: I don't wanna do math and show you all up.
LIAM: That's a level nine barbarian.
MATT: So, slam him, you see a portion
of its side armor splits,
you can see a little bit of
that dark red, fleshy interior.
You do a significant amount of damage,
and leave a nice little
weak point in its armor.
However, it still doesn't seem
to be entirely phased by the damage,
it just kinda shrugs at the damage,
and kinda glares at you for a second.
One of its eyes that was focused
on Percy and Keyleth,
now looks over
at you Jurassic-Park style,
with the t-rex up at
the side of the vehicle.
Vex?
LAURA: I back up a little bit.
Yeah, like that.
And I'm gonna cast Hail of Thorns on him.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: Sounds nasty.
LAURA: Right?
I'm gonna shoot like a regular attack.
MATT: So your bonus action to cast
Hail of Thorns,
and then you attack
with the arrow, go for it.
LAURA: Yes.
MATT: You're adding 11 to it.
LAURA: Okay, good, then that'd be
18.
MATT: 18? 18 hits.
LAURA: Yes, so I was casting that
as a level three spell.
I roll 3d-- that means I roll 3d10.
MATT: Against the creature?
LAURA: Against 14 which is my
spell level thingy.
TRAVIS: 3d10.
LAURA: Yeah, 1d10 for damage.
MATT: Yep, go for it.
LAURA: That is an eight-sided dice, yay!
MATT: There yougo.
LAURA: An eight.
MATT: That'd be 25.
LAURA: I get another attack,
so I'm gonna do that.
Natural 20!
(all cheer)
MATT: Nice, all right, go ahead and roll damage,
double the dice and add
your modifier of seven.
LIAM: That arrow just went slow mo.
LAURA: Double the dice.
15.
MATT: 15, all right.
So what happens here is
you pull an arrow out,
as you whisper a couple of
words under your breath,
you see all these thorny
spikes being to shoot out
the shaft of the arrow.
You release it and as it strikes
in the front of its face,
the arrow actually splinters,
sending a bunch of these
thorns all over its torso,
piercing an inch or two into its armor
with each blast of these thorns.
It kinda rears back and
tries to shake itself off.
As it does, you get a little bit of a look
as Grog backs away from it,
checking to see the wound he left.
You take your secondary arrow,
aim for the red soft spot,
boom, slips right past the armor plating,
doing the extra damage on the interior
of its physical self.
Awesome, that's your turn I believe.
ASHLEY: Good turn.
MATT: Percy, you're up.
TALIESIN: Okay, is my hand still stuck in its
mouth?
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: I would like it to be.
MATT: If you'd like to, yeah,
you could've left it there.
TALIESIN: Do I have an advantage to hit
if my gun is in its mouth?
(all laugh)
MATT: You are considered grappled
if you leave your hand there.
You can remain grappled for
advantage on the attack roll.
TALIESIN: Done.
So I get to roll twice?
MATT: You do.
MARISHA: This is a whole new
meaning to point-blank.
TALIESIN: 19.
MATT: 19, that'll hit.
TALIESIN: Okay, I spent some grit on this,
and did some interesting modifiers.
MATT: How much grit did you spend?
TALIESIN: Two points of grit.
MATT: Okay, this is the--
TALIESIN: The Deadshot.
And I also took a negative
five hit for a plus ten damage to this shot,
and I'm using my fire modifier.
I'm just being an asshole.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: That's amazing.
TALIESIN: That's...
16 and 20, 35 points of fire damage
inside of its mouth.
MATT: So, your hand inside,
you pull back and fire,
knowing which barrel is next.
You hear this dull(muffled explosion) sound,
and its eyes kinda pulse for a second,
in intense fury and pain,
smoke just billows out
the sides of its mouth,
and its nostrils, and it begins
to kind of shake its head,
lifting you about a foot off the ground,
painfully, but you think
it's worth the deal.
Well done.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
LIAM: Aw man.
MATT: I will say that ends your turn.
LIAM: Thank you Gary Gygax, wherever you are.
(all laugh)
MATT: All right.
The duergar, currently
seeing the situation,
and the change of tone, go
and grab their weapons.
TRAVIS: Change of tone.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: Shit got real.
MATT: This duergar is going to move up,
back to you, Scanlan, as it sees
that you were the one that
took over the general.
SAM: Dicks, bring it.
LIAM: Dicks.
MATT: This one comes rushing in.
MARISHA: Aw, come on.
LIAM: Freakin' tank in the room.
MARISHA: There's a bigger problem, bro.
MATT: Opportunists, man.
It rushes after you, actually.
LIAM: ♫ Why can't we be friends
ALL: ♫ Why can't we be friends
MATT: All right, the attack against you, Scanlan.
That is gonna be a 17 versus AC.
All right, this one is actually
also physically growing
in size as it comes towards you.
SAM: It's getting hard.
(all laugh)
MATT: You suffer
16 points of damage.
ORION: Such a bummer.
MATT: As the war pick comes
slamming into your side.
You see it's coming, but
you're just not fast enough.
It hits you, on impact,
it may have cracked a rib,
you're not sure.
The one that's coming
up against you, rolls,
that's going to be a
17 versus armor class.
LIAM: Fuck you.
MATT: You see it and just duck out of the way,
its war pick slams into
the stone wall next to you,
with a horrible screeching stone sound.
High-AC rogue, yo.
All right that ends their
turn, Tiberius, you're up.
ORION: I'm looking in, I'm
like, oh, that's no good.
I look at where he made
the crack in the armor,
where is that, is that in the head?
MATT: It's in the head area, right over here.
ORION: Right, awesome.
I'm going to kind of motion
towards the mind flayer,
and give a telepathic wink.
MATT: It is on the ground.
ORION: Yeah.
SAM: Are you flirting with it?
MATT: You make a telepathic wink.
ORION: And I'm going to cast Telekinesis,
and I'm going to pry open the metal.
I'm not going to target the creature,
I'm going to target the armor.
TRAVIS: Nice.
MATT: Interesting thought, okay.
See if it-- the 17 is the DC?
ORION: Yes.
TRAVIS: This could be cool.
MATT: All right, it fails.
So here's what happens.
For the effect of this.
It suffers, I'm gonna say it suffers
about 2d6 points of
damage from the tearing.
So go ahead and roll that.
ORION: Six damage.
MATT: So six damage, however,
you have effectively reduced
its armor class by five.
TRAVIS: Yes!
MATT: In doing so.
SAM: Ooh!
ORION: And I'm going to spend
two more sorcery points,
and do the spell again.
I'm going to do a--
I'm gonna do Firebolt, right in the hole.
And I'm going to use my metamagic wand
to fire the spell.
MARISHA: Fire in the hole!
MATT: All right, go for it!
SAM: He has so many dice, it's crazy.
ORION: Oh, that hits.
TALIESIN: Actually, does that
crit? Does your 19 crit?
MATT: No.
Usually, 20 is only crit, except for,
I think he has a bonus ability.
SAM: Critical Role by the
way, name of the show.
(all laugh)
MATT: It's okay, you're good,
and you're a fighter,
which means eventually you'll end up
with four attacks per round anyway, so
you're fine.
ORION: Can't do that.
TALIESIN: I'm looking forward to it.
MATT: Damage, what you got?
Scanlan, you're on deck, by the way.
SAM: I'm ready.
ORION: I zap him, I zap him for one.
MATT: Okay.
(all laugh)
ORION: No, no no no, I empowered it.
Full, it takes ten damage.
'Cause I empowered the spell.
MATT: That's correct, so.
As you pull down with the ray,
it streaks down across the
ceiling portion of the building,
right into the fleshy,
exposed part of its armor,
now it looks like it has
this giant jagged scar
in the side of its head,
where you can see muscle and sinew
pulsing with each of its movements.
You blast into it,
you can see this darkened black portion
of its interior flesh, it's now charred,
slight embers beginning to percolate
and burn on the outskirts of the impact.
Well done, you gonna stay where you are?
ORION: Yes.
MATT: Scanlan, what you got?
SAM: Okay, I'm going, I know
he'll get a hit on me,
but I'm gonna run away
from the guy behind me,
run straight at the general,
and just open out my arms
in an outstretched big hug,
and I'm like, come here
big guy, come here!
And I give him a big hug,
and upon touching him,
I cast Banishment on him
and send him to another dimension.
ORION: Nice!
MATT: All right.
(all laugh)
MATT: As you move away, the duergar
is going to attempt to make,
as a reaction, to make an attack on you.
SAM: It's okay, it's all cool for Pike.
MATT: That's going to be a
13 versus armor class.
SAM: Does not hit.
MATT: You hear it coming, as
you're walking, "buddy!"
(all laugh)
MATT: Duck under a war pick.
MATT: With advantage on its saving throw.
What's the DC?
SAM: DC?
MATT: The DC on your spell?
SAM: Well, if I'm doing it
through my cone, it's 19.
MATT: I will say for this, you do
not have it through your cone,
because you had your arms
open, you didn't specify,
however, it still fails
it's saving throw. The
general, as you reach up,
he has his war pick ready.
Pulls back its war pick
as the flames burst in.
(all laugh)
MATT: Then blinks out of existence.
(all cheer)
ORION: Nice move.
ASHLEY: One down, one down.
SAM: Oh, he's gone, oh, where did he go?
I don't know.
MATT: How long does it last, by the way?
SAM: It's concentration.
(all laugh)
MATT: Okay. All right.
LIAM: Scanlan Shorthalt, playing Vegas,
ladies and gentlemen.
SAM: Do I get a bonus?
MATT: You do get a bonus action.
SAM: Okay, I'm just going
to sing a little ditty
to Pike, just to give
her a little inspiration.
I'll just do some pelvic
thrusting--
a little (guitar),
that's a flute, by the way.
(all laugh)
ORION: Super, play that thing.
MATT: His electric flute gives
you a d8 inspiration dice,
so you can add that to any attack rolls.
LIAM: He can do anything with any instrument.
ASHLEY: Sweet licks on your flute.
(all laugh)
MATT: All right, so, Keyleth.
MARISHA: So, upon seeing this big thing crash in,
and I'm like, oh.
Now you're really angry.
But I just kind of analyze
him and I say okay,
and then I go, (grunts),
and I turn into a rhinoceros.
ALL: Ooh!
MATT: Okay, I don't have a
rhinoceros mini on me,
so we'll use a bear for the time being,
but we'll know it's a rhinoceros.
SAM: Why don't you have a rhinoceros?
MATT: 'Cause I was not prepared for such things.
LIAM: Way to slack off, Mercer.
MATT: Hey, I'm gonna order a
rhinoceros now, you happy?
I'm gonna go to Toys R Us.
TALIESIN: Get the whole animal collection.
Actually got them, the whole set.
MATT: So you transform into a rhinoceros,
now basically facing an armored beast
with an armored beast.
MARISHA: Kaiju battle.
(all laugh)
MATT: Whatcha got, whatcha doing?
MARISHA: I'm charging him.
TRAVIS: Activity in the Breach.
MATT: You leap down, go in for the attack,
this duergar already used its reaction,
so it can't attack you.
MARISHA: So if he fails to save, I knock him over.
That's plus seven, so 19?
MATT: 19 does hit.
MARISHA: Awesome!
MATT: Does save though, is not knocked over.
MARISHA: A strength save?
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: Aw, damn it.
MATT: This is a big creature.
MARISHA: He does, I do
2d8 of bludgeoning damage.
MATT: Go for it.
MARISHA: Seven, nine, 14 damage.
MATT: 14 damage, all right.
You have multi attack or
did you get the one hit?
MARISHA: Well, I charged, yeah.
MATT: Okay yeah, so the charge is the hit.
But you slam into it, your horn gores,
you can see actually,
you slam it into the
side of the armor wound
that Grog left and then
Tiberius pried open.
Part of it gets pulled back,
and you see a quick
splatter of some sort of
bloody splash as you're
staring to actually
pull apart its interior.
The horn is jabbed in there,
and it manages to shrug
it off at the last point.
You do significant gore to its side.
LIAM: Good musical riff.
MARISHA: Oh, wait.
No no no, that's right, keep going.
It's actually 15 damage.
I always forget that I have a plus
one to attack.
MATT: 15? Yeah, don't forget that.
You need to remember that.
After taking the arrow wound,
and after everyone else
attacking around it,
it's going to try and get
a different situation.
It's going to jump.
It rears back, and leaps into the air.
SAM: Oh jesus.
MATT: Landing right on top
of Clarota and Scanlan.
SAM: Oh no!
ASHLEY: Wait, does he get, do we get--
MATT: You guys all get attacks
on it as it jumps away.
MARISHA: We all get attacks?
MATT: Yes, you do.
SAM: Do I?
MATT: No, you do not.
MARISHA: We get advantage, right?
MATT: No.
TALIESIN: Did he take me, no he didn't take me.
MATT: No, actually, you are still in its hand.
In its mouth, it carries you with it.
MARISHA: 19.
MATT: Okay, so 19, you hit.
LIAM: 24.
MATT: Hit.
TRAVIS: 26.
No, it's the three of you, so that's it.
So all of you guys just roll
damage for a basic attack.
SAM: Come on, kill him before he gets to me.
TRAVIS: 24.
MATT: 24 damage?
24 damage you said?
Nice.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
ASHLEY: Was I close enough to
him to get an attack?
MATT: No you weren't, unfortunately.
LIAM: 11.
MATT: 11, all righty, and?
MARISHA: 17.
ASHLEY: Yeah.
MATT: So, as it lands.
All of you guys have to make a strength
or dex saving throw, your choice.
For Percy.
TALIESIN: Dex.
MATT: And Scanlan, and I'm rolling for Clarota.
Clarota fails.
TALIESIN: 20.
MATT: It's okay, it's okay, Scanlan.
It's okay, you can do this.
MATT: What'd you roll?
TALIESIN: 20.
SAM: He's coming back from the other dimension.
I rolled a nine.
ORION: Did it hit the floor or did you go again?
SAM: No, I used the one that
rolled on the floor.
LAURA: Roll it on the table, that doesn't count.
MATT: So Clarota is not prone.
SAM: Dungeon Master, does a
roll on the floor count?
What happened?
MATT: I usually roll on the table.
I usually prefer to roll on the table.
SAM: It's even worse.
(all laugh)
LIAM: That'll learn ya.
MATT: You guys are knocked prone on the ground,
and you all take 14 points
of bludgeoning damage,
plus 14 points of slashing damage.
As he just lands on top of you.
Yeah, so 28 points of
damage, as it crushes you,
and its claws sink into you.
Clarota takes the same.
LIAM: Did it drag Percy through the air?
TALIESIN: Yes it did.
LAURA: It did?
TALIESIN: My arms are still stuck in its mouth.
MATT: You're not knocked prone,
but you do take 14 points
of crushing damage,
as its mouth bites down on
your arm again, for free.
TALIESIN: That's fine.
MATT: It's going to actually release you, Percy.
So you're there.
MARISHA: Think your arm might be a
bit busted.
MATT: It turns, and makes a bite
attack against Scanlan.
SCANLAN: As he does
I distract him.
(air horn blowing)
(all laugh)
SAM: Playing my shawm.
MATT: That's the sound a shawm makes?
SAM: Cutting Words reaction.
MATT: Okay, so as your reaction,
go ahead and do that, so roll the d8.
ASHLEY: (imitates horn)
TRAVIS: It's like the start of a Pitbull song.
SAM: Six.
MATT: Okay, he rolled a 27.
Reduced it by seven to 19.
So even with the reduction, it's not enough,
you're on the ground.
It sinks its teeth right into you.
You take, let's see.
LIAM: These games keep getting better.
MATT: You take 41 points of piercing damage.
LAURA: Oh my gosh.
LIAM: Scanlan!
SAM: No worries, I'm just at negative 36 now.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: Really?
SAM: Yep.
MATT: Okay, so.
MARISHA: Wait, how did that happen?
TALIESIN: That happened fast.
LIAM: He's unconscious, he's in bad shape,
but we're gonna get him.
MATT: Scanlan's looking rough,
Scanlan is now just being thrashed around
in the mouth of the creature.
TRAVIS: How many hit points do you have?
MATT: His limp arms and legs
just (thumping)
as it's kind of just running him around
and across the air.
LIAM: Hashtag save Scanlan.
Strings of gnome blood are
being flung across the room.
LIAM: Oh, he's so little though, he's so little.
MATT: Pike, your turn.
ASHLEY: Okay, so time for a Cure Wounds.
So I guess.
Let's see.
MATT: You can't even see him right now.
If you want to Cure Wounds,
you have to touch him.
ASHLEY: I'll go, yeah, I'll go.
SAM: I'm being thrashed around.
ASHLEY: Can I just go, he's over there?
LAURA: He's in the mouth of the thing.
LIAM: She's 25 speed.
MATT: So you can move five squares.
ASHLEY: Okay.
MARISHA: Didn't you get that speed boost?
ASHLEY: How close can I get to him?
I can't see the lines in the squares.
ORION: Don't forget your boots, Pike.
ASHLEY: Oh, I have sprinter's boots!
I have sprinter's boots.
Okay, so I'm gonna use
my sprinter's boots.
I can--
While you wear these boots,
you can use a bonus action,
and click the boots' heels together,
if you do, the boots
double your walking speed
for one minute.
MATT: So you can move ten squares,
takes your bonus action.
ASHLEY: So then, I'm so sorry, I
can't see the squares.
So if I can get ten to get over there.
MATT: So you go one, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, there is a ledge there,
and he's blocking the way up, so nine, ten,
make an acrobatics check to actually
jump and climb up onto the--
LAURA: Oh no.
MATT: With disadvantage, 'cause
you have plate armor.
LIAM: But what about her--
MATT: Disadvantage, you roll
twice and take a lower.
ASHLEY: Wait, wait, hold on.
Can I cast Guided Strike?
Which adds ten to--
SAM: I gave you a dice.
I gave you a dice.
LIAM: Which means you're--
Ten.
MATT: Total of ten?
LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: That's exactly what you needed.
(all cheer)
MATT: That was the baseline. You run up,
it takes all the strength you can feel,
you're gonna be sore in the morning.
All your muscles tense
as you pull yourself up,
with all the inertia from the run,
your parkour up to the top, land,
Scanlan's there, currently
being flung around,
you manage to reach up and grab him,
and get in a brief tug of war
with the bulette creature.
ASHLEY: Hey, get away from him, man!
MATT: As you cast Cure Wounds.
Go ahead and--
ASHLEY: So that's Mass Cure Wounds, so does that heal--
MATT: Is it Mass Cure Wounds, or
just doing Cure Wounds?
ASHLEY: I'll just do Cure Wounds.
MATT: So at what level are you using?
SAM: Don't chintz out.
ASHLEY: I'm gonna use it at the highest-- I'll use it at fifth level.
SAM: Cast whatever you can cast.
LIAM: It's one or multiple people.
SAM: Can you do it at a higher level?
ASHLEY: Yeah, I'll do it at my highest
level that I can cast,
which is--
SAM: Let's not cheap out on Scanlan here.
ASHLEY: Sorry guys, I'm just warming up again.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: Let's not skimp on Scanlan.
LIAM: Remember when I brought
you back from the dead?
Remember that? Remember that?
SAM: Remember when my kiss
healed you from death?
Just throwing that out there.
ASHLEY: -- which I think is eight.
MATT: So it's 5d8 + 5.
5d8 + 5 is how
much you're healing him.
LIAM: You're gonna be all right.
ASHLEY: My spell attack bonus, plus eight?
MATT: You don't have to worry about the bonus,
you're just touching him.
ASHLEY: So 5d8 + 5.
MATT: Is what you're healing him, yes.
All right.
SAM: That's three.
LIAM: I think you did it four times, yeah.
ASHLEY: 18, plus five.
SAM: I thought that was three, no?
ASHLEY: Yeah, 23, 23.
SAM: Plus five.
LIAM: That was plus five.
LAURA: Are you still unconscious?
SAM: But now I'm only negative 11.
ASHLEY: Wait, what?
SAM: I've taken almost 100
points of damage in this.
MATT: You're unconscious, how it works in this,
and this is different from Pathfinder--
Yeah, you go to zero and you stay there.
You are now up to 23.
LIAM: You don't go below zero, you hit zero,
and you're there, making
rolls to see if you die.
LAURA: You only have three chances if you roll,
fail, three times, you die.
MATT: And if something hits you
while you're unconscious,
it's an automatic fail.
Now you're 23 hit points.
SAM: Hey, I feel great, guys!
(all laugh)
MATT: You're still in its
mouth being shook around.
SAM: Oh shit!
(all laugh)
SAM: What is this ride?
This is crazy!
MATT: Pike, that's your turn.
ASHLEY: I can't do anything else, right?
MATT: Clarota's going to get up.
LIAM: Come on Clarota, show us what you got.
MATT: Clarota looks pretty rough.
Rears back.
LIAM: Got to bring that mental power
and that arcane magic, let's do it.
MATT: Taking a cue from the opening you left,
Clarota pulls back its hand,
you see a familiar spark
of bluish electrical energy
as Clarota reaches for
unleashing a torrent
of electrical arcane energy forward,
into the form of a Lightning Bolt.
Blasting across the bow
of this giant creature.
Let's see.
Does not make its saving throw, so it's
32 points of lightning damage.
LAURA: Clarota!
MATT: As the back of its armor is now seared,
and you can see parts of its armored flesh
are kind of blackened and
charred and slightly crimping.
Vax, you're up.
LIAM: Okay,
so I've got enough room
to run up to its anus,
which I'll do.
TRAVIS: As you always do.
LIAM: It's got plenty of people around,
so that means I can Sneak Attack him.
MATT: As you rush past, before you attack?
This duergar that was right by you,
that has currently grown to a larger size
gets a free swing at you.
LIAM: Ain't no thing.
MATT: That's going to be a 21 to hit.
LIAM: Okay, that hits.
MATT: All right, with its war pike it takes--
deals 14 points of damage to you.
LIAM: Who cares, I'm saving
my gnome friend, okay.
Here I go.
14, it's a 25 to hit his butt.
MATT: 25 hits.
LIAM: This is my keen dagger, with vorpal blade,
two plus seven is nine, that's just nine.
Where's a pencil, that's a pencil.
And then we add my Sneak Attack damage,
which is six, seven, ten.
15.
21, plus nine, is 30.
MATT: All right, nice.
LIAM: To the butt.
Specifically to the butt.
MATT: As you rush up,
you take a moment as it's thrashing about,
and you can see what looks, anatomy-wise,
to be probably where it
expels whatever it eats.
LIAM: The hole? Right in there.
MATT: You go ahead and just
slash and eviscerate there.
LIAM: How do you like me now?
MATT: Even back there it's heavily armored,
it takes, you carve through, and it--
You've definitely left a lasting
impression on this bulette.
LIAM: Pucker up, baby, pucker up.
SAM: Hashtag, armored anus.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: What, what, in the butt.
LIAM: This is D&amp;D in 2015, people, 2015.
So that's the first attack, right?
Now I get a second attack?
MATT: The general also, by the way,
appears as the
concentration spell was lost
as you were unconscious.
SAM: I must have stopped
concentrating for some reason.
MATT: However, it is right
in front of, it's like.
It's now in his face.
LIAM: Second attack.
22.
MATT: That hits.
Okay, and that's a four plus ten,
ten points of fire-based
damage to the butt.
MATT: All right.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: Preparation H?
Fire damage to the anus.
MATT: That brings us to his turn.
LAURA: The general's?
MATT: The general's turn, who now
is there from the bulette,
sees it, looks over and sees you.
TRAVIS: It's right in front of him!
MATT: Kind of sitting there
with your bloody hand.
It's still flaming, swings
back, and goes for your head.
TALIESIN: God.
MATT: That is a 23 versus armor class.
TALIESIN: Ah, yeah, that's gonna hit.
Armor class sucks.
MATT: Plus the fire damage.
ASHLEY: What are you at?
TALIESIN: I'm at
39 I wanna say?
MATT: Well, you take 31 points of damage.
Including the fire damage from the pike,
it goes for its second attack against you.
TRAVIS: This thing sucks.
MATT: That's gonna be a 22 versus armor class.
TALIESIN: That's gonna hit.
LIAM: It's a tank.
TRAVIS: One.
MATT: You take...
That's gonna be 21 points of damage.
TALIESIN: I'm out.
Okay, Percy being pummeled
and pummeled again.
Loses, your gun falls from your hand,
as you slump to the ground,
your eyes roll back,
unconsciousness and darkness.
SAM: We're droppin' like flies!
MATT: Taking you.
That brings us to--
ASHLEY: Everybody knows shit's fucked.
MATT: Grog.
TRAVIS: What, me? Bah!
How tall is the thing?
MATT: Tall? I'd say it's probably about...
20 feet tall? 15, 20 feet tall?
TRAVIS: Can I climb up on its back?
MATT: It's not your size, it'd be really, really
tight, pinning in there.
TRAVIS: I would like to run up to its right side
and flank it.
MATT: Over here?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: So you run around.
Which you can do, 'cause
you're a freaking barbarian.
TRAVIS: (snarls)
MATT: All right, go ahead, you're
making your attacks.
Go for it, three strikes against it.
TRAVIS: 21.
Hits, right?
MATT: 21 definitely hits.
TRAVIS: 16 plus eight, hits.
MATT: Definitely hits.
TRAVIS: Natural 20!
(all cheer)
TRAVIS: Does that mean I get extra?
LIAM: Double damage, it means double damage.
TRAVIS: Oh, double damage, okay.
MATT: So first strike.
ASHLEY: Kill him, kill him, kill him!
TRAVIS: 16?
MATT: 16 damage?
TRAVIS: Yes.
LAURA: 21.
TRAVIS: 21, thank you.
LIAM: Stay in school, kids.
TRAVIS: Stay on the table.
MATT: It's the critical now,
so double the dice roll.
TRAVIS: 20, thank you, and.
15, plus that, 20.
MATT: You double the dice,
then add the modifier.
TRAVIS: Oh, double the second one.
LAURA: So that's 40 on the last one.
SAM: Jesus.
LAURA: So 61, 76.
MATT: How do you want to do this, Grog?
(all cheer)
ASHLEY: Oh, you killed him?
LIAM: Yes!
MATT: How you wanna do this, Grog?
TRAVIS: I would like to chop
down into the fleshy bit,
and after I've sliced--
MATT: The fleshy bit is on the
opposite side, by the way.
So you're now at an unarmored side.
However, it's still holding
Scanlan in its mouth,
shaking him around, so,
how do you wanna finish it?
TRAVIS: Can I get to its mouth at all?
MATT: I could say for the flavor of this,
yeah, you manage to just
barely make it over here.
TRAVIS: I would like to swing through
and catch the corner of its mouth,
open its mouth wide, and
then I'd like to reach in,
and with my teeth, pull its
fucking tongue out of its head,
and start thrashing it side to side.
(all laugh)
MATT: First you rush up with your ax,
using all of the aggression,
you take it and swing it,
barely leaving you with a shave.
You gash the side of its mouth,
and draw this giant wound open.
As it does, you actually snap,
and cut through the tendons
that clench the jaw,
causing it to fall open and slack.
Scanlan spills out of its mouth,
hitting the ground with a dull thud.
As its mouth is now open,
it kind of rears back.
You shake your head angrily,
as the froth is gathering at
the corners of your mouth.
You drop your ax from
one hand, grab the jaw,
reach in, bite down on
its giant meaty tongue.
Using your hand at the back of it,
you pull and yank and you feel the muscle
tearing and tensing before,
eventually it comes free,
and is now dangling about 25, 30 pounds,
of very very wet, tongue meat.
With your third attack,
how do you finish it?
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: What do you after you're biting
its tongue in your mouth?
MATT: That's what I'm asking.
TRAVIS: That's a good point.
MATT: It's looking really rough,
but you still need to get
that final death blow.
What are you doing with this, Grog?
ASHLEY: Rip him apart.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'm gonna King Kong his jaw.
I'm gonna take the broken
part, the top of his head,
and just pull apart.
MATT: Okay, so you drop your ax entirely,
the tongue still dangling from your mouth.
You reach and put one foot up
into the bottom of the jaw,
using your other hands you push and push,
you hear it crack, and pull,
as it tenses and is trying to push down.
It has no tension because
the jaw was destroyed.
You pull back and hear a sickening snap,
as the armor plate buckles underneath
where the neck joint would
be on such a creature.
Its eyes kinda roll back for a second,
and it begins to slacken.
As it does, you reach up with your fist,
and penetrate the bottom of
where its brain would be.
With a sickening (suction) sound,
it goes entirely limp and
collapses on the ground.
LIAM: And that's why you're on the team.
(all cheer)
TRAVIS: And as it falls,
the tongue that's hanging in my mouth,
I look to one of the
dwarves that's left, I go,
who's next?
(all laugh)
MATT: We're gonna end it there for the night.
(all groan)
MATT: Damn guys, well done.
TALIESIN: I'm sleeping.
SAM: Oh, Percy's dead, hashtag save Percy.
LAURA: I want more chicken.
MATT: Before we finish, I'd say go ahead
and throw a heal up on him.
MARISHA: Oh yeah.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
ASHLEY: Good plan.
MATT: It's nasty, man.
You guys picked that, by the way.
LAURA: Oh seriously?
TRAVIS: They did?
You dicks!
TALIESIN: You suck.
ZAC: That was the chat room.
ORION: Try harder next time.
MATT: We'll be doing more of
those as time goes on.
Not all the time,
but whenever I have the
opportunity to put it in there,
I'm gonna start asking for you guys
to help me figure out what
to throw at these adventurers.
LIAM: You sadists.
(all laugh)
ZAC: We shouldn't tell them the other options,
should we,
just in case we wanna save them.
MATT: Oh no, they'll come back in, don't worry.
ASHLEY: 25.
TALIESIN: Oh wow, I feel much better.
ZAC: So you guys, we're gonna
be doing a Q and A.
MATT: Yeah, for anyone who wants to stay over.
ZAC: Anyone who wants to stick around,
the audience has a ton of
questions for you guys.
For the audience, it's a sub-only Q and A,
so if you're been wondering
whether or not you should sub,
let me give you some reasons why.
Number one, you can ask
these guys questions
in a little bit.
Number two, every 50 subs,
we're giving away tabletop promo kits
that are like $250 worth of special stuff,
and we will ship that internationally,
doesn't matter.
Even in Antarctica.
We want someone in Antarctica
to do tabletop day,
do you know anyone?
MATT: I don't.
ZAC: We had someone last year.
MATT: Well shit, we gotta reach out then.
ZAC: They're gone, they were
like the only people there,
and they're gone.
MATT: There's nobody there left,
they were the last bastion.
Well, somebody needs to move to Antarctica
in the next few days and let us know,
so then we can totally use that.
ZAC: We also do a Minecraft
server, for subs only,
but if you want in on that,
there's no automated message
for that server info,
so just make sure and message
the Geek &amp; Sundry account,
and we'll get you that sub IP address
for the Minecraft server.
I know we have more,
there's lots more stuff.
We do some other sub-only
chats throughout the week.
lots of emotes, other fun stuff.
But we're gonna go ahead
and roll some videos
while we get set up for the Q and A.
This was a lot of fun, oh!
I would like to challenge
you guys to do a quick
little donation drive for the charity
that you guys support.
MATT: Yeah, for 826LA.
Had it going up in the chat room,
if you have the opportunity,
you wanna help support these children
getting side educations and tutoring.
ZAC: You guys
wanna tell them about,
just to get them psyched up for it?
'Cause we can get that command going.
MARISHA: Yeah, 826LA, they're a
non-profit organization
that helps primarily with literacy
and creative story children for children
between the ages of like five and 18.
They have a really
great young authors book
that you can buy that's a collection
of all of the kids' book,
and you can also go and check
out the time travel mart,
there's one in Echo Park and then
there's also one in Marina Del Rey.
But you should just google 826,
'cause I know there's one in Seattle,
I know there's one in like Atlanta.
New York, San Francisco.
There might be an 826 in your city.
LIAM: 826LA probably, right?
MARISHA: 826LA is who we're raising money for.
But yeah all of the 826 store fronts
are a little bit different,
depending on where you go.
They're super cool.
MATT: Guys, please, check it out, it's awesome.
It's a good group of people,
what they do is fantastic.
If you have the opportunity please do,
go ahead and donate to the charity.
MATT: Well, thank you guys so much for tuning in
for the fourth episode of Critical Role,
with the grand return of Pike, our cleric.
(all laugh)
MATT: Necessary.
Glad to have you back,
I'm sure everyone here is
glad to have the healer back.
LAURA: Especially today.
TALIESIN: Very happy today.
MATT: And a surprise return of Laura, so.
LAURA: What a time to join the game.
MATT: Heck yeah.
All right guys, well, we're
gonna take a little bit
to set up for the Q and A.
Those who can stay, feel free to,
those who can't, totally understand.
We have kids and families to get to.
Those who can will be here for the Q and A
for the next hour or so.
ZAC: One more thing,
just so they know we're following through.
We have the picture for you guys to sign.
So Niareth won this, when
we reached 1,000 subs,
so I think Pike is all
that's left for that.
MATT: Pike is left to sign
this Player's Handbook.
SAM: I haven't signed it.
ZAC: And then we've got the picture.
So we'll pass that around
while we're doing the set up.
MATT: Do any of you have the gold marker?
ZAC: I'll find it.
MATT: All right, cool.
Yeah guys we're gonna go
ahead and set up for this,
we'll see you in a little
bit for the Q and A,
thank you everyone for watching.
Thanks guys.
Awesome day at Critical Role, thanks.
ASHLEY: Bye!
WIL: Hey nerds, I'm Wil Wheaton, I know right?
And guess what?
It is back.
International Tabletop Day has returned,
this year on April 11th.
What is that, you say?
What is Tabletop Day?
Well, if you don't
know, then shame on you.
International Tabletop Day
is a worldwide celebration
dedicated to the tabletop games we love
to play with the people we love.
People we like, people
we've never even met before,
it doesn't matter,
last year we had over
3,000 registered events
across seven continents
and over 80 countries,
that is amazing!
But this year we're going
to make it even bigger.
"Will Wheaton, how can
we make it even bigger
"than last year?"
That's what she said.
Start now.
Trend #TabletopDay on Twitter,
because that was awesome.
Broadcast your plans on the internet,
make a video, share
pictures, start a blog,
create a dating profile for
other sexy gamers in your area,
whatever you want.
Celebrate it in your own way,
but we wanna hear from you.
Be sure to use #TabletopDay,
or @TabletopDay to let us know.
It is up to you, world.
Visit TabletopDay.com
to register your event,
or find one near you.
You can also download exclusive content
and check out some of our favorite games.
We will be streaming our own live event,
here in Los Angeles for you to watch.
And there will be more on that soon.
You love tabletop games, and we love you,
so join us in the global celebration,
on April 11th.
Play more games.
Hey everybody, I'm Wil Wheaton,
and I am coming to you semi-live
from the Twitch TV set here
at the Geek &amp; Sundry stages
in beautiful downtown Burbank, California.
I am here to tell you
everything you ever wanted
to know about Tabletop's RPG show,
coming this June, but were afraid to ask.
Or have been asking for close to a year
and I've been saying,
"We'll tell you at some
point in the future."
You can consider this
the big announcement.
It was incredibly difficult
to cast this show.
We needed people who were very comfortable
improvising, who had experience
playing role playing games,
and who were available when
we planned to shoot the show.
It was surprisingly difficult
to get a pool of people
who fit all of those criteria,
and choose the most awesome among them.
So your cast playing in
this wonderful show are:
Yuri Lowenthal, Laura Bailey, Hank Green,
and Alison Haislip.
I'm really excited to have
these people all together.
They're all my friends,
they are all wonderful storytellers,
and they are going to
be a tremendous party
of adventurers.
I'm only gonna try to
kill them a little bit.
The most frequently asked question
since I announced that
there was going to be
a Tabletop RPG show is, hey Wil Wheaton!
Why are you so awesome?
The second most frequently
asked question is,
what system are you
using to power this game?
First and foremost,
I needed a system that
was going to support
the way I play roleplaying games,
and that is telling a
story collaboratively
with a group of players with me as the GM.
I looked at some very well known systems
like Dungeons &amp; Dragons,
and Savage Worlds,
I looked at systems that
I love, like Fate Core,
and I even looked at the
True 20, a d20 modern system.
And I really wanted to use something
that was released by an
independent publisher.
I wanted to bring
something to the forefront
of the roleplaying world
that maybe not as many
people are familiar with
as I want them to be.
But I wanna play the way that I played
when I was falling in love
with roleplaying games
when I was a kid.
I wanna be able to sit around on a couch
and some chairs with my friends,
not have to worry about a map
on a table in front of us,
and just work together
to use our imaginations
to tell a story.
But there's a system that I really love
that's elegant, it's easy to learn,
it's easy to teach, it's
very easy to understand,
and it really just gets out of the way
when you want to tell a story together.
And that is the Adventure Game Engine
that Green Ronin Publishing used
to drive the Dragon Age
tabletop roleplaying game.
I asked the developer three years ago
to please make generic,
so that we can build a
setting and put on top of it.
They said actually this is
something we really wanna do.
And it's come together.
We have been able to work
together with Green Ronin
to develop the fantasy
Adventure Game Engine.
This is gonna take a lot
of the things you know
from the Dragon Age RPG,
and put it all together
to support our world,
which I have had the best time creating.
I sat down three months ago
with some amazing writers,
and just started brainstorming
about what kind of world
we wanted to explore.
But what I kept coming back to is,
I love science fiction,
and I love fantasy.
Why not put them together?
Why not build a world that is inspired by
the 1978 Heavy Metal movie,
and 1980's amazing Saturday
morning cartoon show,
Thundarr the Barbarian.
I thought it would be great for characters
to encounter goblinoid kind of creatures,
and instead of them using crossbows,
they're using laser rifles.
I've got it all worked out,
we have a huge team of writers
that put all this together
that built an amazing codex
that gave terrific logic to all of these
decisions that we made.
We're not gonna tell you what they are.
You may discover some of
them during the course
of the season.
So what is the name of
this incredible world?
The title of our show is
Titansgrave: The Ashes of Valkana.
You can sort of come
up with your own ideas
about what those words mean.
I know, but I'm not telling.
'Cause that's not how the Wheaton talks.
Titansgrave: The Ashes of Valkana
will premiere right here
at Geekandsundry.com
on June 2nd.
For those of you not in America,
Titansgrave: The Ashes of Valkana
will premiere right here on Geek &amp; Sundry
on two June.
So I hope that you're as
excited about this as I am,
and I hope that you will tune in,
and then watch us for ten straight weeks
of incredible high
adventure story telling,
and until then, play more games.
IVAN: Hey guys, Ivan here, the
host of Game the Game,
on Geek &amp; Sundry's new Twitch channel.
I'm here with Becca, Ify, and Hector,
to get you excited about
International Tabletop Day.
So International Tabletop Day
is going to be on April 11th,
and all of our friends
at AEG have brought us
an amazing edition of Love Letter
in order to play with you today.
That's right nerds.
It's Batman Love Letter.
Now Batman Love Letter is a game of logic,
deduction, and risk,
in which you try to capture or hold
the highest value card in your hand
by the end of the rounds.
In the meantime we'll all be playing cards
in order to eliminate each other.
But whoever has the highest-value card
at the end of the round will win a token.
So who will be the greatest
detective in all of Gotham?
It's gonna be Batman.
BECCA: Oh, no, no, no, no, no,
it'll be Poison Ivy.
IFY: You guys both are wrong,
it's going to be Bane.
HECTOR: It's probably not gonna be Robin.
(all laugh)
IVAN: Now, normally we will
play until seven tokens,
but for the purposes of this video,
we'll play until three.
Whoever gets three is gonna win.
Let's play.
Pass out your cards Becca, one to each.
BECCA: Burn the first?
IVAN: Burn the first.
You have to burn a card
before you even begin,
because there is a mystery card
that isn't in play normally.
So keep that in mind when you're playing.
HECTOR: Burning a card, who are we playing with?
The Batman villain Firefly?
(all laugh)
IFY: Leave the jokes to me, Robin.
HECTOR: All right, fine.
IFY: Just so you know, I'm doing
a set at the comedy store,
and I need three friends to show up.
HECTOR: What night is it?
I'm busy that night.
IFY: I didn't even give you the time yet.
IVAN: Hector, why don't you go first?
HECTOR: Robin.
IVAN: Robin, the man wonder.
HECTOR: Okay, here we go.
I'm gonna play Robin.
I've got protection for
my entire next round.
IVAN: Right.
So every single time you play a card,
normally it has an action
that is attached to it.
So I'm playing Catwoman,
who allows me to look at
another player's hand.
Poison Ivy?
Noted.
Now it's your turn.
BECCA: It's my turn, so I draw a card.
I'm gonna hang on to that one, maybe.
And I also play Catwoman.
And I'm going to look at Bane's hand.
That's terrible.
IFY: You make fun of me but
you lack the understanding
of my strategy.
I will play the Batman.
I can't guess Robin's
because he has immunity,
but I can guess Poison Ivy's.
IVAN: If he can guess correctly,
not only does he get a token,
but she's eliminated from the round,
and now there's only
three of us available.
So it's one step closer to victory.
What's your guess?
IFY: My guess is Two-Face.
BECCA: Incorrect.
IVAN: Robin?
HECTOR: Thanks, Batman.
All right, here we go.
I'm also gonna play Batman.
I'm gonna guess that Poison
Ivy has the Joker card.
BECCA: Incorrect.
HECTOR: Darn it.
Jiminey Jillickers.
BECCA: Now you have to do something
terribly embarrassing, right?
Or is that just Half Scrolls?
HECTOR: Like maybe wear a Robin
costume, cool, sounds good.
Oh, already doing it, great.
So great.
IVAN: I have two cards and I'm going to
also play the Batman.
You've been picked on a lot, Poison Ivy.
BECCA: I've been picked on so much.
IVAN: You played a Batman.
HECTOR: Get him Batman.
IVAN: I'm gonna guess you've got a Poison Ivy.
IFY: You're wrong!
IVAN: (groans)
IFY: No survivors!
IVAN: (laughs)
All right, I'm done, go ahead, Poison Ivy.
BECCA: If anyone's wondering
why so many Batman cards
are being drawn, it's because
there are five in the deck.
There's either one or two
of all the other characters.
So I draw, and I will
play, myself, Poison Ivy.
This card says,
choose any player including yourself
to discard his or her
hand, and draw a new card.
Ivan, you look pretty confident.
Discard.
IVAN: Discard, all right.
BECCA: And draw a new hand.
IVAN: Had a Two-Face.
IFY: It's time for me to draw.
IVAN: I have a hard time thinking that we're
gonna get anything out
of you in that mask.
IFY: Oh, you'll see.
BECCA: I'm sorry, what?
IFY: You'll see.
BECCA: What did he say?
IVAN: I think it's something about seals?
BECCA: Did you need help opening a seal?
IFY: I'll play the Batman, and
I will guess Becca again,
she has the Harley Quinn.
BECCA: Incorrect.
HECTOR: Geez, we're terrible at this game.
IVAN: We're really, really bad.
BECCA: I'm great at it.
IFY: Sooner or later.
IVAN: He's in there, or he's there.
Not there, there.
BECCA: There?
IVAN: There.
BECCA: Where?
HECTOR: I'm going to play my own version of Bane.
That was terrible.
BECCA: You don't have the mask.
HECTOR: Myself and another player
can secretly compare hands,
and whichever hand is lowest is out.
So I'm gunning for you, Poison Ivy.
Because you kissed me that one time,
and then you didn't wanna
hang out with me afterwards,
like that was really mean, so.
BECCA: I had ulterior motives.
IVAN: I'm not looking, Batman's not looking.
BECCA: I'm out of the game.
HECTOR: You're out, yes!
BECCA: I had myself again.
IVAN: Which means you have a
higher numbered card.
HECTOR: Yes, that is correct.
IVAN: Higher than five.
HECTOR: Good detective work, Batman.
Real genius, this one.
IVAN: All right.
This is the last card of the deck,
which means after this, whoever
has the highest card, wins.
HECTOR: Duh, Batman, we know, God.
IVAN: I'm playing Robin, Robin.
All right?
BECCA: That makes me think he has the Joker.
IVAN: Well, we'll find out won't we?
What do you got?
IFY: I had myself.
HECTOR: Boom, Harley Quinn beats Bane.
IVAN: And the Joker beats Harley Quinn.
HECTOR: Darn it.
IVAN: I got you, Joker.
BECCA: Take your token.
IVAN: I will take my narcissistic token
that has my symbol on it.
HECTOR: This is just what Batman
needed, an ego boost.
Batman needed an ego boost, great.
IFY: Robin.
BECCA: The deb chef, the deb chef.
HECTOR: You seem to live with a multi billionaire,
yet can't afford contacts.
What's the deal with that?
BECCA: No burn card, no burn card.
IVAN: Oh, great.
So since I won the last
round, I get to play first,
because I am the greatest detective.
And I got a Catwoman,
which means I think I'm
interested in Bane's hand.
Whatcha got, Bane?
You got crap, is what he's got.
BECCA: Choose any player including yourself
to discard his or her
hand and draw a new card.
Hector, burn your card.
HECTOR: You got it, but it's Robin,
and I'm not gonna tell you again.
All right, I had Batman, which is cool,
because he's the least
value card in the game,
so that's just gonna help me out,
so I'm just gonna grab a new card.
IFY: All right, I'm going to draw.
Draw a card.
Oof, oof, oof, such a good card.
IVAN: Who are you gonna use it on, Bane?
BECCA: It's probably Batman.
IFY: I'm gonna do a Batman card.
Robin, do you have Poison Ivy?
HECTOR: (laughs) No.
IFY: My turn is over.
HECTOR: All right, it's my turn.
Dick Grayson and Jason Todd, Tim Drake,
Stephanie Brown, Carrie
Kelley, John Blake, help me.
Okay, here we go.
My girl Selina Kyle, Catwoman, bam.
And I wanna look at Bane's hand.
Show me back here buddy,
show me back here,
whatcha got?
IFY: Got this.
HECTOR: Okay, good to know.
IVAN: All right.
I'm going to just play my ward Robin.
HECTOR: You're welcome.
IVAN: Grant me immunity.
BECCA: Batman.
I'm gonna guess that Bane has Poison Ivy.
IFY: You're wrong!
BECCA: You'll never have Poison Ivy.
IFY: I'll use Catwoman.
BECCA: To look at another player's hands.
HECTOR: Pause for error.
IFY: I will look at
Poison Ivy's hand.
HECTOR: Don't do it Bane, don't fall
into that venus fly trap.
Get it, 'cause it's a trap, 'cause it's.
It's a plant based pun.
IVAN: Good job.
IFY: Ah.
IVAN: There it is.
Ah!
IVAN: Robin, Robin go ahead.
HECTOR: Okay, here we go.
IVAN: What's it gonna be?
HECTOR: I'm gonna play Batman.
And I'm gonna guess that Bane
Has a Batman card.
IFY: You are wrong.
IVAN: For once he doesn't have a Batman card.
IFY: I want to point out to the watchers.
Hector looked at my hand.
HECTOR: Oh I did, that's true.
IFY: And saw me play the card.
He knew exactly which card was in my hand.
And chose the wrong card.
IVAN: This is why you're the boy
wonder, and not Batman.
HECTOR: I'd like to point out,
that my chest has made
me very uncomfortable,
and I'm clearly out of my element,
and dressing me up as Robin
was a good call everybody,
good call everyone.
Good call guys.
Wow.
IFY: I really thought that
was game over for me.
I was wrong.
HECTOR: Oh my God.
Your annoying voice has
really gotten into my head.
BECCA: That's his greatest power.
IVAN: I also have the Batman.
So we know he doesn't have a
Batman, you know what it is.
Thanks Robin.
Useless.
So I'm gonna guess that
Bane has Harley Quinn.
IFY: You are wrong!
IVAN: Damn.
I tried.
All the clues are there,
just one missing element.
BECCA: I played Batman, I'm going
to guess that Bane has
Two-Face.
IFY: You are wrong as well.
IVAN: He has the Joker then, or something.
How can you throw that many
Batmans at a single man,
and not get what he's got in his hand.
HECTOR: He really did break you, he really did.
And now I'm Nightwing, great,
that's how long that took.
IFY: I'm going to say.
Two-Face can trade hands with Becca.
BECCA: (sighs)
IVAN: That's where it was.
Robin?
HECTOR: It's my turn.
IVAN: Diddly fingers.
HECTOR: You guys think you're gonna win this?
You don't know Dick.
Greyson, because that's my real name.
I'm gonna play
Bane.
BECCA: Bane-in it up.
IVAN: What's up, who's gonna compare?
HECTOR: It's gonna be you, Batman.
Let's see what you got, old chum.
Oh hoh, bye, you're out.
(laughs)
IVAN: Batman card, so.
Batman's out.
BECCA: Batman's the worst.
HECTOR: Oh my gosh.
IVAN: How's it feel to knock a
man down from his tower?
HECTOR: It feels great.
IVAN: Right, okay.
HECTOR: How's it feel for not giving me--
MARISHA: Great for my back.
ZAC: We're live.
MATT: What's up everyone,
we got this camera right
here in the middle, right?
ASHLEY: Hello.
LIAM: Oh, hi.
MATT: Thank you guys for watching.
Hope you enjoyed yourselves.
These guys all being crazy players,
and kicking ass,
and occasionally getting
knocked unconscious,
and nearly eaten.
ZAC: Any mods want to put this in sub mode for us?
Let's do sub mode.
MARISHA: So you have to sub.
Bye everybody who's not a sub.
ASHLEY: Bye!
ZAC: They can still watch,
they just can't ask questions.
ORION: Oh.
Okay.
MARISHA: Well, your word is not important.
LIAM: Laura had to bugger out.
ASHLEY: Wait, is that a little icon of you?
MATT: Yeah.
ASHLEY: What?
ORION: Yeah, he's an emoji now.
ASHLEY: You're an emoji?
MATT: It's weird.
TALIESIN: He's made it.
ASHLEY: You've made it.
MATT: All right, so how are we
doing the questions?
Are we just picking as we go?
ZAC: You can moderate yourselves.
ASHLEY: Laura and Sam did leave.
MATT: Unfortunately.
ASHLEY: Laura had to go to a thing,
and Sam had to go to a thing.
MATT: Sam's thing is kids.
Sam has two kids.
Liam has two kids, but he--
ASHLEY: Hey look at--
(all laugh)
MATT: I am so sorry, everyone.
LIAM: I mean he's pretty good at
Dungeon Mastering, right?
ASHLEY: Yeah, he's pretty good.
ORION: Someone asked what alignment we are.
First question, what
alignment are our characters?
MARISHA: We're all good.
LIAM: Chaotic good.
ASHLEY: Chaotic good.
ORION: Tiberius is chaotic good.
TRAVIS: Chaotic neutral, bitches.
LIAM: What was your first
roleplaying experience?
I saw that go through.
TALIESIN: GURPS in high school.
ALL: GURPS.
MATT: The second edition of Dungeons
&amp; Dragons in high school.
TRAVIS: This.
ASHLEY: Was my first, yeah.
LIAM: This guy just started.
I did AD&amp;D in high school,
and I DM'ed while playing,
which is totally cheating.
This is the first pure
experience I've had.
ORION: This is my first campaign also.
I was a Magic the Gathering fan.
MARISHA: I actually had Matt as my
first DM, way before
All this started.
So I played a few other games, and then,
now I'm back to the OG master.
LIAM: I saw, when and how did you
all start playing together?
The reason this started is because,
I directed Matt as Leon
Kennedy in Resident Evil 6,
and every time he came in he would say,
"hey, you know, I'm running a game,
"you can come in and just do a one off."
And I was like, "oh, I got babies,
"I can't do that, I can't
do that, I can't do that."
And then finally once for
my birthday I thought,
I can do a one off, it'll be
the only time we'll do it,
just see how it goes.
Scanlan and I did a podcast together,
and every week we would do some new thing,
and we're like fuck it, let's play D&amp;D.
We all did it and everybody got snake bit,
and it's been the best
thing that ever happened.
To me at least.
ASHLEY: Yup.
ORION: Our character alignments do matter
on how we play the characters,
an earlier question.
MATT: Yeah, they do definitely matter.
A couple quick answers here.
The conversion from
Pathfinder to Fifth Edition
was decided because, as
we're going on to this show,
and we had so many players,
combat tends to get bogged down,
and a lot of floating
modifiers in Pathfinder.
For large groups like this it's difficult
to keep it flowing and moving.
I felt once I had taken
a look at Fifth Edition,
that the combat system was
a little more simplified,
and a little easier to make
freeform and just roll with it.
So that was a much better decision.
Plus Dungeons &amp; Dragons
generally has a better
name recognition than Pathfinder,
so when you're putting a show out there,
it's probably easier to do
with very minimal transition,
it took a little bit of customizing,
like for Percy's gunslinger.
We just had to customize
it, we made it ourselves.
We sat down.
TALIESIN: Took a day.
MATT: Took a day, and we worked out,
some of the stuff we wanted to keep,
some of the things that didn't break it,
we wanted to make it interesting.
It is a martial archetype
for the fighter class.
So it does give the bonus
a fighter class does.
Nothing is too overpowered about it,
other than just having custom weapons,
and some cool grit-based abilities
that we kinda transferred
over from Pathfinder.
It's interesting.
It's a good challenge
to see how it works out.
TALIESIN: It is, it's working out.
I'm digging it.
I keep reading and finding
things I'm not doing
that could be more interesting, so.
MATT: Keeping your hand and
firing into the mouth
of a bulette is fun.
TALIESIN: That felt great.
LIAM: Travis, everybody's
asking about your shirt.
TRAVIS: Oh.
I think it's a website
called redbubble.com?
I just googled Grog, and there was that.
TALIESIN: Just google Grog.
TRAVIS: I needed it right away.
Right, right.
LIAM: I'm also seeing, why did we switch
from Pathfinder to Fifth Edition?
MATT: I answered that a second ago.
LIAM: Oh, you did?
MATT: Yeah, the idea being that
the reason we switched
was it was easier for large-scale combat,
and the system was a
little more simplified,
and I felt for such a large
party it'd be easier to do.
Plus character creation
for any guests we have
in the future, so that
was the main reason.
I love Pathfinder, but
at this size, it's good.
Answering your earlier question too,
I saw someone ask, a good party size.
Legitimately, my preference is
between four and six players.
This works because
they're amazing players,
and because we keep it very freeform,
and not getting bogged
down in minutia too often.
The four to six players I
think is a good sweet spot.
MARISHA: I see, does Keyleth have limitations
on what animals she can transform into?
Yeah, for the most part
I can only transform
into beasts and I have to be under
a certain challenge rating.
So right now, at my level, I
can only turn into beasts
that are a challenge
reading of three or lower.
MATT: A third of your druid level, right?
MARISHA: Yeah, a third of my druid
level which is nine right now.
But for the most part I can change into
almost anything as long as
it's under a challenge rating
of three.
MATT: Pike, how do you feel about Scanlan?
Do you return his affections?
ASHLEY: Oh, well.
I'm on the fence about him.
He's really pretty
great, but I don't know.
I'm not really sold yet.
MARISHA: You know Pike, I feel
like we haven't actually
girl talked about this.
ASHLEY: I know, we never girl talked about it.
MARISHA: We should.
ASHLEY: I know, we should talk.
I just, I really like him,
I think he's really funny.
I really the fact that
he's a musician, but.
MARISHA: That's hot.
ASHLEY: I don't know, I'm not
really sold on him yet.
MARISHA: I'm just concerned if
he could treat you well.
ASHLEY: Oh no, you know what?
MARISHA: He's got bad habits.
ASHLEY: He likes to frequent brothels
and things like that,
which, you know.
I'd wanna give him his
freedom and his space.
I don't know if I'm into it.
TALIESIN: If I say it so you can understand it,
what's the point?
LIAM: Someone's asking if we like presents.
I think we'd all like fan art.
MATT: Fan art's awesome, we love it.
LIAM: Immortalize our
shitheadedness, that'd be good.
MARISHA: Oh, it's true.
ASHLEY: Another couple people on there
were asking about my ears.
And I really like
supporting small businesses.
And there's a store on Etsy
called Tiny Tangerines,
and she makes these by hand.
And makes like deer, and bears,
she makes a ton of stuff.
MATT: That's really cute.
ASHLEY: Check her out.
LIAM: We still got that little one.
Socrates asked what was a favorite moment
before we started streaming the show?
Our first game was pretty amazing.
MARISHA: Our first game was great,
I've got some good memories from that one.
LIAM: Most of us, I was giggling uncontrollably,
I couldn't believe we were doing it.
And just watching my friends,
who I work with all the time,
just dropping into
character, there was no like,
oh, let's see, what will
I do, what am I doing?
I will move, I will roll.
Like Bailey, Bailey dropped
into character from the get-go,
and was a ringer.
But the moment I was thinking
of was when Pike died.
Pike died.
MATT: Like died died.
LIAM: Shortly before we switched
from private to public.
It was emotional.
A couple people started
crying, I teared up.
We put two and a half years into this,
and we're all very connected to it.
I'm not gonna get into it,
but I've had a hard couple
of years personally,
everything's fine, but this
was like therapy for me.
And to see one of my friends go down?
ASHLEY: It was sad.
LIAM: It was fucking emotional.
MARISHA: I don't think a few people were crying,
I think everyone was crying.
ORION: I was crying.
ASHLEY: I was definitely crying.
I was like, "no, I love
doing this so much!"
I don't wanna, I mean,
when you spend that much time with people,
over two and a half years,
you get so attached,
and attached to characters.
MARISHA: We know these characters almost as well
as we know each other now.
MATT: Factoids, the tower you made for us
in Minecraft is awesome.
Seriously, well done,
look at the pictures,
it's great, we're gonna have
to actually go through it.
MARISHA: Wait, we have a tower?
MATT: A guy built an entire tower for the group.
ASHLEY: No way!
MARISHA: They built a castle Greyskull?
MATT: Essentially, on the Geek
&amp; Sundry Minecraft server.
No.
Wait no I did see that!
It was huge.
ZAC: It towers over the entire --
LIAM: Of what?
MATT: Of him!
Someone made a sculpture of--.
Did you make that or somebody else?
You made that?
ZAC: Oh no.
MATT: Okay, somebody else made it for you.
LIAM: Do we have $50 in the budget
to go on eBay and get a
Castle of Greyskull set?
Put it on the set somewhere?
Let's do that.
MATT: There we go.
I see a couple quick questions.
ORION: To answer your question,
there is an origin of
Tiberius, fully written.
I won't say it all right now,
but he comes from a political family,
and there's a whole
bunch of layers to him.
He is a thought-out character.
The buffoonery is half-planned.
MARISHA: I mean, we're all really
deep, thought out characters.
ORION: Well, they asked if I actually thought out
a story for him.
He does have a thing for
this character named Allura.
MATT: Yeah, Arcanist Allura,
the one that actually
sent them on this mission,
he has kind of a thing for.
ORION: She's super awesome.
Hot, I think she's hot.
MATT: She's pretty hot.
ASHLEY: Super hot.
MATT: The gunslinger class info,
I actually posted on
Twitter a few days ago,
it's in my dropbox if you
look through my Twitter.
It's on there, otherwise,
we'll probably put it up on the website,
when all the website stuff is up there.
I'm happy to release it now.
It's pretty balanced, it's fun.
Might have some tweaks down the road,
depending on how things play out.
You should go to my Twitter,
you'll find it there.
TRAVIS: We're gonna have a website
with all our characters.
LIAM: Yeah, we're working towards that.
MATT: Working on it, yeah.
Like a lot of things right
now, it's a work in progress.
LIAM: Someone asked what kind of
food would everyone like?
ORION: Ooh, like Thai food.
LIAM: I like Indian.
MATT: Ooh, Indian is good.
ASHLEY: I really noticed--
ZAC: Let them know not to order food.
LIAM: Don't, that's a terrible idea.
ORION: We just had a bunch of chicken.
MARISHA: Oh you mean like right now?
Yeah, don't do it right now.
ZAC: If you tell them what you want,
all of a sudden I'll get a call, like,
"your food is on the way!"
MARISHA: Yeah, no, not right now, maybe next week.
TRAVIS: Matt, you're going
to Wizard World in Philly.
But we will not be joining
because we don't own a
private fucking plane.
MARISHA: But I'll be there.
Is anybody else gonna be there?
TRAVIS: Oh really?
MARISHA: We'll be there.
LIAM: Somebody asked something, like,
what do we hope is the
result of this show?
I can't remember the wording.
Obviously we're doing this
because we love each other
and we're having fun
together, but I also hope,
D&amp;D has been, its entire
history has been like,
"oh, it's this weird thing that guys do
"with dice in a room."
Anyone can do this, I love video games,
I work in video games, but
D&amp;D has changed my life.
It is social, it is person
to person, it is real,
because it's people in a
room doing shit together,
and that's kind of lacking
a little bit in our world,
and I would say find some friends.
I mean, I love that there are sort of
online tools to play with
people across the country,
but if you can find three
or four people in your town
to do this, I'd say do it.
Do it.
TRAVIS: Yeah, do it.
MARISHA: There's something really
amazing about the fact
that we're all essentially
kind of building
and communally developing
a story together,
and that's something that not a whole lot
of things can grant you,
and we don't really get
in today's society much.
We're all kinda creating this as a thing.
And I think it's good
that we're like, hey,
this is socially acceptable.
D&amp;D's cool, everyone should play D&amp;D.
MATT: Actually, the IT Crowd episode of D&amp;D
is one of the best on camera examples
of a D&amp;D game night thing.
ORION: That is an awesome episode.
MATT: Fucking hilarious, and a great,
truncated version of this
is kinda what the game is.
So good on you.
ORION: Cut to them weeping.
TALIESIN: So many questions going so quickly.
MATT: I know.
ASHLEY: I want a Grog shirt that says "do it."
TALIESIN: And the kitty shirts were an accident.
This was not planned.
MARISHA: Oh yeah, our kitty shirts.
LIAM: Someone's saying what
edition to start with?
I would start with the most recent,
because you know they're
gonna keep updating
it over the years.
MATT: Fifth is great, Fifth
is a great entry point.
LIAM: It's really loose.
I feel like all of us felt like,
we were doing Pathfinder, and...
Fucking loved it, otherwise
we wouldn't be doing it,
but it was really intricate,
and we were doing it
every six or seven weeks,
when we were off-air, so.
We felt like the rules
were really complicated
and we'd lose track of it.
We loved doing it, obviously,
but Fifth Edition is
really fast and loose.
I recommend that.
And Travis just stuck
his finger in my ear,
he kinda does that.
He hits me in the nads a lot.
MATT: This is a homebrew campaign.
I wrote it all just kind
of for the hell of it.
Custom, don't really base
it on anything existing.
I feel like I'm playing
more in that world,
and I always hate the idea
of, in the middle of DMing,
having to go to a module,
or having to look for a
rule that wasn't my own.
It feels more detached.
There are modules that are great,
and I've run great modules,
but for me personally, with the pacing,
and the flow of the game,
I prefer to do homebrew.
LIAM: Connected to that, someone
asked, if you had any tips,
and I'd like to know
the answer to this too,
because I'm running a game
for my eight-year-old son
and his friends who are about to start,
do you have any tips for new DM's?
MATT: Yes.
Let's see.
I could do a whole panel on that.
Tips for new DMs.
Preparation is important.
You wanna outline cities,
come up with ideas for NPCs,
that you think would be
essential to a story,
or like people that really
run elements of the town.
Simple notes can be
like, they're this race,
this is their disposition,
if you have a particular
voice you wanna try for,
make a note of this kind of voice.
So whenever you come back
to them you have a reminder.
And spend a lot of time
building that structure,
you don't have to be too detailed.
Always leave room to play in the world,
because you never know what
your players are gonna do.
Be prepared to improv.
I prefer loose preparation,
and then just kinda rolling
where the players take you.
LIAM: Although you wrote a
monologue for Clarence, right?
Because that was very intricate.
We were all just ready--
ASHLEY: Yeah, there's no way you
just thought that up.
MATT: There are certain elements,
part of the notes I take
is for certain NPCs
I'll write down key
information that they know,
and depending on how you ask them,
what you say to them,
and what you try and extract from them,
they might give you
some of the information,
they might not, if you coerce
them, or intimidate them.
Or if they're willing to
give up the information,
I have all that written down.
So for that information today,
you guys were asking
him, and since you allied
with Clarence, he was
willing to discuss with you.
So I had all that prewritten,
but depending on how much you said,
it was what you guys asked.
LIAM: Do you have
random encounters ready,
in case we're like,
"ah, fuck it, I don't wanna
go down to the dungeon,
"I wanna go back up and
beat up some dwarves."
Do you have shit kind of ready?
MATT: Yep. I have a stack of different creature
and encounters already prebuilt,
based on what you guys may encounter.
Tonight was an example
of players being able
to pick what happened.
But also it's one of those
things where it depended,
I don't know where you guys are gonna go.
I present a story,
I present an idea of a
general throughline,
but how you guys go
from point A to point B,
that's entirely up to you.
Sometimes that can be a
very long, meandering line,
sometimes it could be a direct ray, so.
TRAVIS: There was a question, how
much do you improvise,
and when is it appropriate to improvise?
MATT: A lot, and always.
MARISHA: Always, yeah.
TRAVIS: The answer is yes.
MATT: I've had whole games where
I've prepared a session,
and none of it happened,
because people just put
an entirely wrong direction.
Not wrong, but a different direction.
So the whole game was just me
pulling everything out of my ass.
MARISHA: Like that time we walked
through the back door
of the Thieves' Guild, that was fun.
MATT: Yeah, there was that.
MARISHA: What's up, Thieves' Guild.
'Sup.
ORION: Donkey Kong, Pikachu.
TRAVIS: What?
ORION: Somebody asked me what my favorite
Smash Brothers character is.
TRAVIS: Oh.
LIAM: Somebody asked how we
pick the character class
that we picked.
When we first started
this game, and I said,
"hey, it's my birthday,
I wanna play a game."
Laura really likes rogues as well,
but I made sure that as
fast as I fucking could.
TRAVIS: She was pissed.
LIAM: So she, yeah.
She plays rogue, in like
Dragon Age and everything.
That shit's a favorite class of hers,
so I know I got it out there.
Also, the reason that we're twins
is because Laura and I have
the exact same birthday,
May 28th.
ASHLEY: I didn't know that.
MARISHA: I didn't know that either.
LIAM: That's why we're twins.
MARISHA: That's cool.
ASHLEY: I knew-- I came in late to the game,
and there were only a couple options left.
And I had never played, so.
I picked gnome because I
was like, oh, that's funny.
And then cleric, I didn't really
realize what a cleric was.
And how detailed it can
be if you've never played.
And important to the game.
So when I started I was like, well shit,
this is a little tougher
than I thought it would be.
But it's been awesome,
I love being a cleric.
LIAM: I'm so glad we pulled you in.
ASHLEY: Me too, man, me too.
Oh, also, someone asked,
who is Pike's deity.
And it's Sarenrae, the goddess of healing
and redemption, among other things.
MATT: Which is carried over
actually from Pathfinder.
Fifth Edition has its own suggested,
there's never a definitive pantheon.
But they have the deity pantheon.
But we're carrying over Pathfinder deities
that were prominently in the campaign
up to this certain point,
because why the hell not?
We're not gonna make her change her deity,
that would be weird.
MARISHA: Travis, how did you pick your character?
TRAVIS: What?
Oh.
I asked what the biggest
playable character was, I think.
One that liked to fight, drink, and fight.
LIAM: One of the greatest pleasures for me,
and I'm obviously a huge nerdlinger,
and this is just me reliving high school.
When I was talking to Sam
about starting all this,
and saying hey, let's get together,
it's what I wanna do for my birthday,
we pulled Travis in,
Travis is fucking tight,
look at him.
He's not the stereotypical D&amp;D player,
and he was as snake bitten as the rest of us.
Play Dungeons &amp; Dragons,
please play Dungeons &amp; Dragons.
TRAVIS: It was so good.
ASHLEY: It's the best.
LIAM: It'll make you so happy.
ORION: What about you?
Keyleth?
MARISHA: I remember at the time I had a,
we were playing another campaign,
and I had like a rogue assassin,
that you were in with me.
And I had a kind of assassin character
who was super seductress,
and really high charisma.
And I remember when I joined this game,
I didn't really know any of you guys
really all that well,
and I was kind of new to this world,
so I ended up going with a kind of druid,
and I kind of deliberately
made her introvert,
in a weird way to kind
of reflect my newcoming
to the group, but I was like,
"whoa, it'll be like I can be quiet."
so Keyleth has a really low charisma,
but I kind of spin it
in that she's naive,
and doesn't really know.
And that's why she says
things like, "but Clarence."
(all laugh)
MARISHA: "You're just special."
Because she's naive, and kind of quiet.
So she was just different than anything
I've played before.
But I really love being a druid.
Druids are great.
TALIESIN: I played a lot in school.
Other than Matt,
I probably had the most
experience playing D&amp;D,
and playing roleplaying games.
TRAVIS: Yeah you did.
Genius.
TALIESIN: So I was really excited by
the gunslinger in Pathfinder
just 'cause it was something
I hadn't done before.
So I found it the most
interesting and unusual,
but I was not, and I also
felt it was a hole within
the group that could be filled very well.
LIAM: Thedouginator
keeps asking you, Matt,
how you brought the party together
the first day of play.
MARISHA: Wait, we haven't heard
Tiberius' story as sorcerer.
Then we can answer that question.
ORION: When this was going on,
I asked Matt if there was a caster yet,
like any glass cannons, and he said no.
So I debated between
a wizard and sorcerer.
When we went over the different mechanics,
how a wizard and a sorcerer works,
I was more drawn to that.
And I'm a huge RPG guy.
LIAM: You're so entertaining.
ORION: To piggyback a quick question,
to seal off the Tiberius thing,
somebody asked if any of our voice acting
influences our characters.
Tiberius, absolutely.
I played Elminster Aumar
in the Neverwinter MMO.
Which is a D&amp;D MMO.
And when we started this
I'm essentially doing Elminster,
but I made him super bubbly.
TALIESIN: No, someone asked how the group, yeah.
MATT: We got together, first
session, essentially,
was in a swamp town named Stillben,
and the group at the time had,
for their own separate reasons,
been in this town, needing money,
and had kind of come
together as a mercenary group
out of necessity.
So the first session was
them having known each other
from a circumstance where they
all ended up helping out
an individual in the city, long story short,
they had a small rapport,
and knew at least each
other were useful,
and needed cash.
And there was a job board in the town.
So the first session was them being hired
to look into a conspiracy
within this swamp
port town, Stillben.
That was their first
real adventure together.
And when that finished,
they kept going from there.
ORION: Uh, troll penis story.
ASHLEY: Troll penis.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: That's fair.
ORION: I know you guys keep asking.
LIAM: Take it away, Mercer.
MATT: There was a battle.
Subterranean battle
that involved the party
sneaking upon a group of two
trolls that were around a fire.
The idea to work past
this came to Tiberius
to transform himself
visually into a female troll
so he could Bugs Bunny them.
Hey boys, you know, that thing.
Not knowing the temperament of trolls,
especially ones that are deep underground,
and don't get to see
female trolls very often,
they immediately just
got extremely aggressive,
and he found himself almost between
a rock and a hard place.
ORION: I was getting raped by trolls.
MATT: The party then descended
upon these trolls,
and in the middle of
battle, at numerous times,
I believe Percy once and Laura the other,
both took specific shots
at each troll's dick.
Rolled a good shot with enough
damage to blow them off.
Now being a troll, they regenerate.
But it was still a good effect,
and when the battle was over,
it was decided by the party to at least
take one as a trophy and place
it in the bag of holding.
TRAVIS: That was decided by me, thank you.
MATT: By Grog, and as such,
it stayed for a while,
until it was used as an
implement of distraction
in another encounter I believe.
TRAVIS: It worked.
MATT: Yeah, it worked.
That was where troll dick came from.
ORION: It was spitroasting.
LIAM: Jake Bodro asked what's it like playing
for three hours in front of 2,500 people?
I think our games have
gotten a little bit better,
only because when we play privately,
there were sometimes lulls,
where we weren't sure what to do,
we would go off to bathroom,
we would take a break.
But now there's a little bit
of the element of theater to it.
Just a sprinkle of it.
And it kinda of gooses the energy up.
ORION: I'm doing the same thing for the record.
TRAVIS: I keep seeing this one.
For the 11 year old Sadie,
the son of Odin shall have that cookie!
MATT: Aw, that's sweet.
ASHLEY: There you go.
MATT: There is one bag of holding in the group,
and Grog always has it.
TRAVIS: A troll dick
and a bulette tongue.
MATT: There are many things
that go into the bag.
TRAVIS: It hasn't gone in that bag.
TALIESIN: Is there still a cow in the bag?
TRAVIS: No, Dork the ox.
MATT: Dork the ox is probably not.
TRAVIS: That's when we first
learned its limitations.
MATT: Why does Scanlan have
so many awesome spells?
Bards in Fifth Edition have one
of the options they can choose.
As they level up,
can choose a couple of spells
from any spellcasting class,
which is great, and the boon that
bards kinda needed to be
more combat-effective.
And you can choose the School of Lore
or the School of Combat,
I think, for the bard.
He chose the School of
Lore which allows you
even more spells from other classes
to boost your repertoire,
so he became a fucking amazing bard.
LIAM: Also, Sam Riegel did a lot
of a capella in college.
TRAVIS: He did, he really did.
LIAM: He helped write several
seasons of The Voice,
which was all about a capella,
so Samis sort of a ringer
for the bard class.
MATT: Yeah, kinda had to happen that way.
TRAVIS: Can Marisha do her dwarf impersonation?
MARISHA: Nope.
LIAM: Yordee yorda--
MARISHA: Yorda youree yourdee yourd.
ASHLEY: Someone asked if Grog could keep
one of his women in the bag of holding.
You can't put living things
in the bag of holding.
TALIESIN: As we've learned.
MATT: You can.
MARISHA: With Dork.
MATT: They just die.
TRAVIS: There's no air, it's like a vacuum.
A magical vacuum.
MATT: Dork the ox did not survive.
TRAVIS: One giant dead ox came out of the bag.
LIAM: Someone keeps asking if any of us
have hirelings, or henchmen,
and the simple answer to that is no.
MATT: That's not true.
LIAM: Just Trinket.
ORION: At our Keep.
TALIESIN: We do.
LIAM: Oh, that's right!
TRAVIS: Yeah, we battle-tested them.
ORION: We have a Keep back in--
LIAM: Right before we started.
TRAVIS: The game before we came here.
After they saved the kingdom of Eman,
the sovereign Uriel Tal'Dorei III,
as part of his gift to the group
for essentially saving his family
and the city itself, had a
Keep constructed for them,
and took about six months or so,
and the Keep was finished,
and then the party's first
session
was them finding who they're going to hire
to take care of the Keep for them.
LIAM: It was like one episode of the Sims.
MATT: Kind of.
It was great too, 'cause Grog's whole idea
of making them to see who
would be the better hire
was to break the pool cue and be like,
"who survives?"
Make them fight, it was pretty great.
TALIESIN: For Tone17, I played
a modified Malkavian,
and a Smetty if you can
believe such a thing,
which was badass.
MATT: There you go.
LIAM: We've been playing for
two and a half years.
Someone wanted to know how long.
TALIESIN: Oh my God, really?
TRAVIS: Did we tell them about your podcast
with the recording of the very first one?
LIAM: If you want, Sam and I,
it's kind of languishing,
but we have a podcast
together called AllWorkNoPlay.
TRAVIS: It's amazing.
LIAM: We're both parents, we have kids,
so we have no time to do anything.
Enough time to take a shit.
The first or second episode,
the first episode is about
us playing the first game,
and there's audio from the first game.
Again, go to iTunes, or to
AllWorkNoPlay on Pod Bean,
and you'll hear about two minutes of us
dealing with a puzzle
that Matt threw at us.
MARISHA: It was timed.
LIAM: Yeah, it was timed, there
was an hourglass going off.
It was us discovering
D&amp;D really for the first time.
AllWorkNoPlay, all one word.
MARISHA: Actually one of my favorite stories
that I tell all the time is about you,
from our first game, 'cause if
you remember, I didn't play.
I just kinda helped Matt help you guys.
I was like a D&amp;D minion.
And I remember I was helping you,
and I remember you were like,
"So, if I just wanted to go
up and punch those guards,
"I could do that?"
And I was like, yeah,
well you would go up,
and you would punch them,
and then Matt would tell
you how you'd do that.
And then you went like
this, you were like.
TRAVIS: Computing.
MARISHA: Yeah, you were like,
"so, we can do anything?"
(all laugh)
MARISHA: And I was like, yeah.
LIAM: Taliesin on game one
was actually not Percy,
he was a dragonborn paladin?
TALIESIN: I was a dragonborn paladin.
LIAM: You fucking blew our minds, we were like,
"what do I do?
"Can I do damage points
to stop this puzzle."
There was this tunnel with
all these moving parts,
we thought we were gonna be crushed,
and he was a dragonborn
for the first episode.
It's in the recording on the
the AllWorkNoPlay podcast.
And he just breathed ice
on this water-based--
TALIESIN: Contraption.
LIAM: And froze it, and everyone was like,
"you can do that?
"You can't just roll dice and hit it?"
And that's when we kind of understood
oh, it's whatever the fuck you want.
TALIESIN: That was such a good game for learning
the basic mechanics.
Such a well put together game.
ORION: Matt does control the
music while we play.
MATT: Yes, I have playlists.
They were much more broad playlists before,
unfortunately on the stream,
we have to use only
approved royalty-free music,
so it took me a while to
figure it out previous to this.
TRAVIS: I do miss those Madonna songs.
MATT: I know.
I used to play a lot of Bush.
MARISHA: Hey, would that count as fan art?
If fans made us music?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MARISHA: Could we then use that?
Yeah? He's nodding.
ZAC: They can send
us whatever they want.
MARISHA: Some consent forms? Yeah.
TRAVIS: If one of your characters died,
would you roll a new character?
ORION: Music people out there.
MARISHA: Any music people.
Anything atmospheric.
LIAM: No, no, that's an important question.
TRAVIS: Ignore it.
LIAM: No, it's important.
Someone's asking, if we die,
would we roll in a new character?
And plus, we just started this show,
so part of us were wondering like,
what if we die the second episode?
What happens?
We recorded this opening
to the show that's coming.
MATT: So here's how I run the world.
I feel that one of the
problems in some RPGs
is that death becomes flippant when magic
allows you to completely undo it.
In my campaigns certain powerful spells
like Greater Restoration, Resurrection,
things like that are a challenge,
meaning you can definitely undo death,
but a lot of it is based
on your capabilities
as a spellcaster,
your attachment to the people
you've been traveling with.
So if ever a character does die,
a resurrection can be attempted,
but it is a challenge.
Which means there's a
possibility of it failing.
In which case, if the resurrection fails,
the soul is lost, the
character is permanently dead.
The player then can leave
and never come back
if they want to,
but they have the option
to create a new character,
and be reintroduced to the campaign
like half a level lower than the rest.
ASHLEY: That would suck so much.
LIAM: When Pike died we had, all of us,
many series of dice rolls to do,
and it was very story-based.
MARISHA: Yeah people are asking how she came back.
LIAM: Yeah, I mean, luckily
we were in a big city,
there was a huge temple.
There were very wise clerics who were good
at bringing people back.
But still, we all had to roll.
There was three rounds we had to roll,
he might have fudged
numbers, I don't know.
But we were all still scared.
We had to all, the majority of us,
had to have good rolls
three times in a row.
Scanlan had to put--
TRAVIS: The tears of three women in the room.
LIAM: The tears, Scanlan had
to kiss her on the head,
he put a figure that he carved of her,
it was very elaborate.
This one was majorly in tears.
Laura was in tears.
ASHLEY: I was in tears.
TALIESIN: Laura was hyperventilating.
ORION: And when that was going on, I remember,
when that went off, being still Tiberius,
I was like in half character but half not,
and I was not crying,
I was like, (grumbles)
the whole time,
and as soon as she sprung back to life,
because the cleric--
MATT: Breathed in her first breath after that.
ORION: We luckily, because I
know it was a tight roll.
MATT: It was a very tight roll.
It was a DC of 14 in the final roll,
and because Scanlan brought
out this figure of her
that he had carved for her
like two months beforehand
as a gift, sets it down and
kisses her on the forehead,
and it was kinda the
final connection point.
He needed 14, he rolled
a 12, but, because he--
There's a plus two modifier to
the skill check, being a bard,
and that was what he
needed, he just made it.
Basic, basic--
LIAM: Someone's asking if we drink while playing,
and the answer is no.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: It's just water in those tankards.
TALIESIN: Coffee.
MARISHA: I almost did, yeah.
ORION: When she came back to
life is when Tiberius,
I was like, "oh my God, she's okay!"
ASHLEY: I think also having--
Because with magic and
everything like that,
just bringing somebody
back to life so easily,
since we don't have that as
much as maybe other games--
It's heightened, so every
time someone gets hurt,
we're all, I think now,
after having that death,
all of us are like, "where are you at?
"Where are you at?"
ORION: Where are you going?
I wish I could turn to
Sam, but he's not here.
ASHLEY: We're all so stressed out now, which is,
it's kinda cool.
MATT: Mortality's a real thing
you have to deal with,
and up until Pike's death it was kind of
a thing people weren't considering.
It just happened so suddenly.
LIAM: One I see keep coming up
since we started is
how would we react to life
if we were our characters?
I don't know, or differently
from our characters?
'Cause I wouldn't stab my
children when they frustrate me.
MATT: I'd be in a padded room.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: I feel like everyone
tries to make decisions
in a game that their character
would make in real life,
'cause that's kind of the point.
I take into consideration
that I have shitty charisma,
whenever I open my mouth.
I feel like we all try and
take into consideration
our background and our alignment,
because that's, you know.
TALIESIN: I feel significantly more
badass than my character.
ORION: I feel...
Tiberius is just me with magic.
So that's how I feel.
TRAVIS: Grog was easy, he makes bad decisions,
which is just all that I do.
MATT: Pike died when they were fighting
what was called a treachery demon,
or a glabrezu,
which had basically infiltrated the
Sovereign Uriel, and the city of Emon.
And when it revealed its final form,
it got one lucky critical hit on Pike
when she was too close, and
just instantly took her out.
That's how she died.
Someone's asking if they can (laughs)
send us equipment we need for the show.
Zac.
ZAC: Yeah, they can.
MATT: What do you need?
ZAC: We'll put it on the wishlist.
MATT: There you go, it's on the wishlist.
ORION: There's a wishlist?
MATT: I didn't know there was
one, but now there is.
ZAC: Castle Greyskull on there.
LIAM: How do we feel about Team Demihooman,
and inspiring them to play
D&amp;D for the first time?
I think the number one
reason we all wanna do this
is because we love each
other, and we love this game.
The second thing is we all knew,
we kind of felt like--
We're gonna make Dungeons
&amp; Dragons cool again.
MATT: Try at least.
LIAM: And make it open for anyone to do,
there's no reason not to do this.
If there's someone you know
who doesn't understand it,
don't worry about it.
Just find some friends
and connect with them.
MATT: I find one of the difficult things
is explaining to somebody
who has never played an RPG,
or a game of D&amp;D at all, they're like,
"how does it work, what is it?"
And it's hard to explain, so if anything,
now we have an example with this show.
Other than the IT Crowd episode,
or the Community episode,
which are both great
examples for quick little
succinct things.
TALIESIN: If we had the power to
bring one guest player
for one session.
ORION: Oh, that's easy.
Tom Hanks, for sure.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: Mazes and Madness.
ZAC: Everyone is asking for you guys
to somehow get Vin Diesel.
MARISHA: I was gonna say, Vin Diesel.
ORION: He lives for this shit!
MATT: Vin Diesel's good.
Top of my list is Stephen Colbert,
because I know he also plays.
ASHLEY: That would be amazing.
TALIESIN: I would love to see Joss Whedon do this.
I admit I would like to
see Joss Whedon play D&amp;D.
That'd be interesting.
ZAC: That might be possible.
TALIESIN: Okay, I'm throwing that one out there.
ORION: What, Tom Hanks isn't?
MARISHA: Felicia's got some.
MATT: But he's also a super fuckin' busy man.
ORION: Guys, tweet at Tom Hanks
to come play with us.
TRAVIS: I'm Morgan Freeman, and I rolled a one.
MATT: Right now, Critical Role Hanks.
See if we can make it trend.
Patton Oswalt would be great.
ORION: That'd be hilarious.
ZAC: What about Dan Harmon,
just so I can get fired, can we do that?
(all laugh)
MATT: Yeah.
Hardwick used to play
D&amp;D with Patton Oswalt
in the mid-2000s.
I can't even imagine what
those games were like.
ORION: I'd like to like--
Amy Poehler, I'd like
to have one of those.
ZAC: She might be open to that.
She's a partner with Legendary.
ORION: I'd love her, Tina, Tina Fey.
LIAM: Someone keeps asking about Troy,
I don't know if Troy Baker is ready.
ORION: I don't think he's ready for this jelly.
You guys think he's ready for this jelly?
I don't think so.
MATT: Whenever it comes up in conversation,
Troy always gives me that look of like...
"All right."
TRAVIS: You can see him swimming
in the infinity of--
MARISHA: "That's not cool."
LIAM: He has some preconceived notions.
MARISHA: "My scarves are cooler than you."
MATT: Once we get him like a proper
plus two enchanted scarf.
ASHLEY: Can we ship Grog and Vex?
TRAVIS: Grog and Vex.
No, I'm here to annoy Vex
by smacking her bear around,
and she's here to tell
me not to kill myself.
"Don't jump into the crevasse,
it's 1000 feet deep."
ASHLEY: Troy Baker is Pike's distanced dad.
(all laugh)
MATT: That's pretty funny.
LIAM: Answer this question I like,
I saw it a couple times,
how did you guys get involved in streaming
for Geek &amp; Sundry?
TRAVIS: Virgin sacrifice.
MATT: The best way I know that happened was,
we had been playing for a while,
and we all work in the industry.
People began to hear about
our voiceover D&amp;D game,
weirdly.
Like I'd come into sessions with directors
I've never worked with
before, they'd be like,
"Oh yeah, you're the guy
that runs that D&amp;D game."
How did that happen? How is that my thing?
I'm cool with it, like heck yeah,
my little high school self is like,
I'm okay with being known about that.
But then over time eventually
Geek &amp; Sundry contacted us.
Felicia had heard about it.
They called me in for a meeting,
and we spent a number of months
trying to figure out what
format we were gonna try,
if we wanna do it like multi camera,
filmed canned episodes,
then eventually the Twitch
possibility came up,
and we were like no,
this is a much better format for us.
And that's kind of how it happened.
LIAM: Are you kosher with me,
you took this film, there's a video of you
breaking the news to us that Geek &amp; Sundry
came to you about it.
Are you kosher with me sharing that video?
MATT: Yeah, I don't see why not.
LIAM: All right, I'll find a way to put it
through my Twitter.
So just keep your eye on my Twitter.
ASHLEY: Wait, what are you sharing?
LIAM: There was a video that Orion took
when Matt told us about
Geek &amp; Sundry coming to him.
And us all sort of toasting and laughing.
ORION: Reacting.
LIAM: Giggling like idiots.
MATT: Why is D&amp;D Pathfinder
making you so much more
attached to the characters
than a regular RPG?
If you mean like a video game RPG?
I mean you get attached either way,
but with this, because you
are so much more fluid,
with how you can influence the world,
and the character, and the
way the character reacts
to the world and how it can
influence it is so much more--
MARISHA: Personal.
MATT: Personal, a good way of putting it.
It's just that much more involving,
and you invest so much
into that atmosphere.
And it depends on the group,
some people just like to do dungeon crawls,
and kill and get loot and experience,
and that's totally cool too.
For me at least.
I like 'em both for different reasons.
I still play the crap
out of video game RPGs.
LIAM: Someone asked if given the chance,
would we like to do a live game
at a convention like Acquisition Inc.?
I'd like to do, although
there's nine of us,
so that'd be kind of--
ASHLEY: That'd be a long game.
ZAC: We may be asking
you guys to do that soon.
LIAM: Oh good, then yes.
MATT: As long as you're handling the tech,
I think we'd be fine with that.
LIAM: I'd like to do it.
ZAC: We may be streaming from Comic Con,
I don't know.
We may be asking if you guys are gonna
go through that hell hole.
LIAM: The answer is yes.
ORION: Can we get a jib? I like crane shots.
MARISHA: Ooh.
ASHLEY: A helicopter? A helicopter shot.
ORION: Put it on the wishlist.
ZAC: Put it on the wishlist, a jib.
LIAM: How many of you aside from Matt
have run a game of D&amp;D or another RPG?
In high school I ran a D&amp;D game,
I ran a Rifts game for a little while.
MATT: Rifts, yes.
LIAM: I ran a cyberpunk game
for a little while.
TRAVIS: Really?
LIAM: Yes.
The last two months I have been helping
my eight-year-old son
and two of his friends
from school create characters.
And I wouldn't have done this if Matt
had not forced this shit into my life.
I wouldn't have done this,
but I'm about to start
running a game for my son,
the half-elf druid, and his two friends,
the dragonborn fighter,
and the dragonborn rogue.
TRAVIS: What if they die?
LIAM: That's just how the cookie
crumbles, motherfucker.
TRAVIS: Oh man, you are teaching life lessons.
MARISHA: Gotta teach lessons.
TRAVIS: Go Fish and then D&amp;D.
TALIESIN: I ran a Rifts game as well in high school.
Then I ran a game of
Vampire the Masquerade,
and I was in a bunch of them.
LIAM: Of course you did.
TALIESIN: Couple rounds of Paranoia, and Hole,
because that's funny.
Hole was amazing.
MATT: Which you gave me books for.
For my birthday, which was awesome.
MARISHA: I was a part of a Buffy the Vampire Slayer
tabletop RPG for a while.
Yeah, it's actually quite fun.
I was a pyromancer.
ORION: Somebody asked a fun one,
they asked if we play,
what's our favorite video game?
MARISHA: What's our favorite video games?
Oh that's a hard question.
ORION: Is it?
MARISHA: There's so many!
ORION: Well we can skip it.
LIAM: Metal Gear, Dragon Age.
ASHLEY: Probably Portal, Portal or Dragon Age.
MATT: Portal's great.
LIAM: Castlevania, Symphony of the Night,
I played 'til I had blisters on my thumbs.
MATT: Symphony of the Night, yeah, dude.
What is a man?
TALIESIN: Borderlands 2, and I'm happy--
ASHLEY: Borderlands 2.
LIAM: Pool of Radiance on my Commodore 64.
ORION: Oh shit.
LIAM: Baldur's Gate, which I
played again on my iPad
a year or two ago.
Somebody, oh go ahead.
ORION: I was just saying.
LIAM: Somebody asked how we focus in the room
with the sexual magnetism
that is Scanlan Shorthalt.
ASHLEY: Ooh, it's tough man.
LIAM: I don't know.
TALIESIN: I wear a codpiece.
I wear a codpiece that
keeps everything in check.
MATT: I'm heavily sedated most of the game,
just for that reason.
Otherwise the clothes
would just come right off.
LIAM: I just let myself get a
gigantic boner every week.
MATT: Does anyone play League?
Generally.
MARISHA: Sometimes.
We're playing Heroes
of the Storm more now.
ORION: I'm a big Final Fantasy fan.
I like all kinds of games.
I definitely would say
if I had to pick one RPG,
cause I'm an RPG guy, I love Chrono Cross,
that'd be my favorite game.
I've played that more than
I have Chrono Trigger,
which is way too many times.
TRAVIS: Dragon Age race/class.
Ash, anybody that plays?
MATT: Elf rogue.
TALIESIN: Human fighter.
TRAVIS: Always the mage.
LIAM: Travis, stupid question, Thor, Odinson,
or Hulk, in a knock down drag out?
TRAVIS: Oh (scoffs).
ORION: Type-0 also, dammit.
TRAVIS: Contractually, Thor, realistically, Hulk.
I mean I am Thor, I
can't say any other guy.
TALIESIN: Hulk's on a scaling power level,
'cause he just gets too mad.
TRAVIS: Yeah let's just be real about that.
That's Hulk.
MATT: Tried new Final Fantasy yet?
ASHLEY: ChocolateSweets a bunch of times has asked
would you guys consider
cosplay for the games?
TALIESIN: Well technically.
We already did.
MARISHA: You'll see, maybe next week?
MATT: He's trying the best he can.
We have an intro coming
up some point soon.
ZAC: Halfway done.
MATT: Halfway done, we all shot
loosely in character costumes
inspired by everyone's characters,
so you'll be able to see that soon.
TALIESIN: If anyone would like to make us costumes.
LIAM: One man doing it all.
TRAVIS: A million arms.
ASHLEY: I think it would be kinda hard for me
to play the game in cosplay,
'cause I have probably the most armor now.
MATT: You do.
You wear the most armor.
ORION: That's a cool question.
If you had to switch characters Matt,
if you had to switch characters,
which one would you be?
MARISHA: If you had to trade places with one of us?
ORION: Yeah, if you would switch characters.
ZAC: That question was Matt included,
question was for everyone,
if you guys could switch
characters with anyone,
who would you pick?
Including Matt.
ASHLEY: I would probably switch
with Liam or Travis.
TALIESIN: Tiberius would be mine, I'd take Tiberius.
LIAM: Scanlan, I would be Scanlan.
MATT: I would be Scanlan, bards man.
Bards are my favorite class.
MARISHA: I'd be probably either Scanlan or Pike.
TRAVIS: I'd be Trinket.
MATT: Yeah you would.
TRAVIS: Why are you peeing on everything?
MARISHA: Bards and clerics are great.
ORION: I'd definitely be Grog.
Just the complete
opposite of what I can do.
TALIESIN: I'm a WoW player on occasion,
I haven't played in ages.
ORION: For the Horde.
MATT: Player wants to play a lizardfolk monk,
what's my opinion about the idea?
That's fine, I mean a player can play
whatever they want to,
as long as you as the DM
want it in your campaign.
Just make sure they have
more to their character
besides "I'm a lizard monk!"
have a good reason why
they trained as a monk.
If they make a cool personality behind it,
work it into the social structure
of their lizardfolk people,
and see whether the monks
will be shunned or accepted,
are they an outcast of the society?
Think of those ideas,
and make a cool character
based on the story,
from a fighting standpoint?
That'd be cool.
I used to play a
lizard monk in Ruins of Kunark
back in the old EQ days.
Oh man.
That was a while back.
LIAM: Someone asked when
Trinket came into the mix.
Day one.
TRAVIS: Day one.
She had that shit like that.
She knew she wanted a pet bear.
MARISHA: He hasn't died yet.
ORION: He hasn't died, it's amazing,
this thing has not died.
He should have died so many times.
MATT: She spent all of her character focus
in having a pet from combat,
and then never puts it in combat,
because she doesn't want it to get killed,
and it's fucking hilarious.
TRAVIS: We put it jeopardy situations before.
MATT: Yeah, you have.
Every time she goes, "never again!"
And I'm like, all right, well.
TALIESIN: The day that bear dies,
it's gonna get ugly.
ASHLEY: It's gonna be bad.
ORION: It's good to change her, as a character.
TRAVIS: Alignment shift.
TALIESIN: So much black to wear.
MARISHA: Douginator asked me a
super detailed question.
So I don't wanna blow over
it, 'cause it was awesome.
He asked me how my path has gone,
and my personal Aramente journey,
and how working with the group has helped
and slowed it down.
For the Air Ashari and
for Keyleth's journey,
it's kind of expected
to take her maybe ten,
maybe 20 years?
It takes her like, the
Aramente is expected
to take a long time,
and part of it is her kind
of proving herself a hero.
So she kind of ended up tagging along
with this motley crew in order to
kind of help her so
she's not doing it alone.
So it's a good thing
that she's tagging along.
But she also has to deal
with sometimes the moral
dilemma of maybe choices that she might
not normally make if she
wasn't with the group
that she has to go with.
LIAM: I see two questions I wanna address.
One is what is each of our favorite kill?
ORION: I was gonna say that was a good one.
LIAM: And the second one is
what's the story behind
the Super High Intensity Team?
(all laugh)
LIAM: Let's start with the kills,
and then we'll get to the SHITs.
My favorite kill, I finished
off a blue dragon we faced.
We all chipped away at this dragon,
someone who had disguised himself as human
for a long time, then we came
to their secret cubbyhole,
and they revealed themselves.
We chipped away and chipped away,
then at the end I sort
of parkour-ran up a wall
and shoved the daggers into its neck,
and just slid down its
entire body and finished it.
ORION: My favorite kill is actually--
LIAM: Until today.
ORION: When Pike kicked the bucket,
and that moment all of us
realized what happened,
and there was an instant
shift in real emotion,
where whatever the hell,
I don't even remember
who we were fighting,
because I went like, fucking cast this,
and everyone's just, kill this thing,
because we all cared so much
in a real life situation,
where we hated this
thing, with real emotion,
and we just slaughtered it.
TALIESIN: The demon-possessed royal
family was my favorite.
LIAM: That was the same thing.
TALIESIN: Yeah, that was my favorite fight.
Just using the light,
also we were shooting,
I was getting to shoot
holes in the glass.
MATT: The entire throne room
had a glass dome overtop,
but because the family had been possessed
by the shades, these shadow entities,
it was all covered.
They were able to force these spirits
out of the physical bodies
without killing them
by being able to tear off the cloth
or shoot holes in it to allow sunlight in
and use that as part of the battle tactic,
it worked out really cool.
MARISHA: Yeah, that was fun.
TRAVIS: My favorite kill wasn't even an enemy,
it was when Scanlan summoned that pony,
when we were facing those five wizards.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: He summoned this pony,
and then I turned and abruptly
cut its fucking head off,
and reached in and grabbed its organs,
and smeared its gore all over myself,
and started screaming.
And Mercer was like, "okay."
ORION: The fight ended there.
MATT: Roll intimidation, with a bonus.
TRAVIS: Butchered a pony for intimidation.
MATT: Yeah, it worked.
MARISHA: I think one of my
favorite Keyleth moments,
it wasn't a kill,
but when we were in the
crazy, Michael Jackson,
Neverland Ranch, sorcerer
dude's plane of existence.
MATT: The Dread Emperor.
MARISHA: Yeah, when we were in
his plane of existence,
and we encountered that
big tree rock monster,
and I just happened to
take Command Plants,
and he happened to be a plant monster,
so it just worked out perfectly,
and I was just like, "we
don't wanna fight you!
"back down."
and avoided an entire battle.
TALIESIN: Getting the magic carpet
was also pretty badass.
MARISHA: Oh yeah, that was a good story.
LIAM: Another fabulous moment that
you guys have to know about
is we wanted to get into
a tower at one point,
and there was a very intelligent sort of
right-hand man to whoever owned the tower.
Scanlan just started fast-talking,
which is his defining characteristic.
Took his finger and put it
right here as a mustache,
and said, "hi, I'm Burt Reynolds."
(all laugh)
LIAM: And he rolled, either
Scanlan rolled a 20--
TRAVIS: I think it was a natural.
MATT: He rolled a natural 20.
LIAM: And you weren't expecting it to work,
in any way, shape, or form, and you went,
"okay."
TRAVIS: Mr. Reynolds.
MARISHA: Burt Reynolds just announced that he's
gonna be at Philly Wizard World with us,
so we could theoretically
tell him that story.
MATT: I have to.
ASHLEY: Burt Reynolds would be a dream guest.
ORION: Him and Tom Hanks.
TRAVIS: He'd have to play on a bearskin carpet.
MATT: The whole family history organized.
ASHLEY: I've only had one kill.
TRAVIS: But, it was what?
ASHLEY: And it was a dragon.
TRAVIS: Yeah, dragonslayer.
ASHLEY: But the thing that I,
probably the whole battle with the family
that was sort of possessed
when I actually died,
that was probably one
of my favorite battles.
Maybe not after I died, prior to.
When I got to finish off the dragon--
TALIESIN: Was that on Christmas?
ASHLEY: The dragon? Yes.
That night was so amazing because we had,
we made it a winter festival.
So we all came in our pajamas.
It was close to Christmas,
that's why it was a winter festival.
It was like our little Christmas party.
MARISHA: Our holiday episode.
LIAM: That was sad for me because it was my idea
but I had health problems at the time
and I had to bow out,
and I was very, very, very sad.
MATT: But you made it to this year's.
I made it the following year, yeah.
TALIESIN: Yeah, we had a whole little
thing, it was really nice.
MATT: I would love to play D&amp;D
with Dame Judy Dench.
MARISHA: Heck yeah.
MATT: You guys can tweet at her
so you can get her to agree.
LIAM: The SHITs.
How did we become the SHITs?
MATT: Yes.
So the party had run into a,
debearded, actually, shaven
dwarf named Grimthorn,
who wanted to represent them for,
what is occasionally, a
roving brawling guild,
essentially.
Like underground fighting
rings that happen
around the world at different
points throughout the year.
It may come up again, we'll see.
But they had to think of a team name.
And Scanlan.
Recommended the Super
High Intensity Team.
Which stuck for a while,
so the group name,
against the better judgement of, I think,
a lot of the group, became The SHITs.
So their name for a while was The SHITs,
they were announced as
The SHITs in the ring,
when they won the tournament.
That was when the pony was cut in half,
to intimidate the opposing team.
TRAVIS: Scanlan's idea also.
ORION: Tiberius and Keyleth were not happy.
MATT: SHITs stuck for a while until eventually
they got rid of the SHITs,
as all of a sudden they
were about to go to the
winter festival parade in their honor
for saving the entire city of Eman,
and the Sovereign Uriel said,
"what should we announce you as?"
and it was decided not
to announce you guys
in front of the city at
your parade as The SHITs.
ASHLEY: I was super into it.
Still love The SHITs.
MATT: Instead the name became Vox Machina.
So if you've heard them say that,
that's the official team name
they've created for themselves as a group.
ORION: With credit to Sam as well,
which was voted down was also
the Brotherhood of the Sisterhood.
Which I was a huge fan of.
I really wanted it to be the
Brotherhood of the Sisterhood.
But Vox Machina sounded cooler.
ASHLEY: The Brotherhood of the
Sisterhood of the Order,
or something like that?
MARISHA: The Order of the Brotherhood
of the Sisterhood.
ORION: So Tiberius recognizes as the
Vox Machina/Brotherhood of the Sisterhood.
LIAM: LargoSensei keeps asking,
what are your most cathartic
voice acting experiences?
I'm gonna guess for Ashley
that's The Last of Us,
since that's your fucking
heart ripped out of your chest.
ASHLEY: Probably, yeah.
LIAM: Gollum was pretty sad for me,
because he's a miserable bastard.
Also Angel from Wolverine, the X-Men.
ORION: Wait, does cathartic mean sad?
LIAM: Well it just means get
your fucking demons out.
Chew it up.
TALIESIN: Mine's really old,
it's probably either
Monster or Paranoia Agent.
I'm gonna go that far back.
Yeah, all the way back.
MATT: Fate Zero for me had a moment
that was pretty intense emotionally,
that I really enjoyed.
TRAVIS: Knuckles the Echidna in Sonic.
(all laugh)
MATT: Sonic Boom, yo.
MARISHA: Boom, Sonic Boom.
TRAVIS: What's that?
LIAM: Infamous, maybe?
TRAVIS: Oh, yeah.
LIAM: Pretty fucking sad.
TRAVIS: Brothers. Brotherhood.
Brotherly love.
ORION: I'd say for me it was doing Type-0.
Not so much the actual lines,
'cause I had a lot of fun.
I don't know if that's cathartic, but.
Completing an actual real life dream goal.
I've said this a couple times before,
but the last day I was
recording the last stuff,
I was literally crying on the way home,
because I finally got to level myself up.
And this thing kept it up,
and it was really cool.
TRAVIS: Matt, who were you in Fate-0?
MATT: I'm Kiritsugu, Kiritsugu Emiya.
TRAVIS: Bless you.
MATT: Thank you.
That's the dark assassin character.
TALIESIN: Saw a question about Percy's home,
and his family.
Percy has a really really big family,
that I don't mention in the video,
and he has not been home yet.
He has no interest in going home yet,
'cause that's terrifying.
So we have not dealt with that.
MATT: That's going to be interesting
when that comes around.
TRAVIS: What's under the freakin' lake?
LIAM: What's under the freakin' lake, Matt?
MARISHA: Yeah, what's under the lake?
MATT: You were told.
ORION: Yeah, it's one of those big--
MATT: Aboleth.
MARISHA: Oh yeah that's right, I did write it down.
MATT: Which you encountered one underground.
MARISHA: Yes, I was a shark.
MATT: Put the slime into the water.
You could only breathe water
and couldn't breathe air.
MARISHA: Remember, 'cause I was like,
"I'm gonna be crafty
and turn into a shark,"
and then I started immediately drowning.
ORION: How do you keep players
from getting OP, Matt?
MATT: Make the monsters more powerful.
ORION: Behind the scenes,
I'm always constantly up his ass,
trying to make Tiberius as OP as possible,
and he's always stopping me a lot.
MATT: Balance is important.
I mean, the characters,
everyone here has really good characters
that have a lot of cool abilities,
but they also have a lot of challenges
that come at them that make them,
not only use those abilities, but also,
monsters can have cool abilities too.
LIAM: Bracheon89, you said
Stephen King plays D&amp;D?
ASHLEY: Yes, that's what I was trying to say.
What?
LIAM: Bracheon, we're going
to wait for your answer.
How do you know he plays D&amp;D?
ASHLEY: Are you sure?
LIAM: Let's get him in here.
MATT: I'd love that.
TALIESIN: The group's worst decision
in D&amp;D was the dragon,
I think.
MARISHA: Oh yeah, Grog?
TALIESIN: Grog.
TRAVIS: Listen, there was a shitload of gold.
ASHLEY: I still don't think that was a bad idea.
ORION: Oh, when he started hoarding all the gold?
MARISHA: We still don't know if that--
LIAM: Takes a lot of stupid.
MARISHA: He might have been an ally.
We might have killed
someone who was valuable.
TALIESIN: You were still freaking
out like a month later,
you were feeling really bad.
TRAVIS: Well, I did almost get us killed.
ASHLEY: I feel like it was a good decision.
MATT: To be fair,
it's the only time I've ever had a player
rage loot before.
(all laugh)
MATT: You went into a rage, and
used it to just loot more.
And then the dragon revealed itself,
and you looked at it,
and you just kept looting.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: You guys take care of this.
ASHLEY: That was hilarious.
MATT: That's Grog.
LIAM: Somebody keeps asking,
and we'll do a show of hands here,
Lord of the Rings or Game of Thrones?
ASHLEY: Oh, come on.
MARISHA: Ooh, that's tough.
LIAM: What do you prefer?
10 seconds to think
about it, and then I'll--
TALIESIN: That's like Star Trek or Star Wars.
MARISHA: Yeah, hard.
LIAM: They're asking the question.
ZAC: Don't be afraid, come on.
TRAVIS: That's tough.
LIAM: Lord of the Rings,
fuckin' Lord of the Rings.
There you go, there's the answer.
ASHLEY: I don't know, man.
TALIESIN: Lord of the Rings, but
I see Game of Thrones on the side.
LIAM: I love Game of Thrones.
MARISHA: Of course we do.
TRAVIS: Lord of the Rings.
TALIESIN: We wouldn't have Game of Thrones
without Lord of the Rings.
MARISHA: That's the thing.
LIAM: Maybe possibly not Dungeons &amp; Dragons
without Lord of the Rings.
ASHLEY: This is true, it's the OG.
I don't know what that even--
TALIESIN: You said that.
That just came out of your mouth.
ASHLEY: Please let's leave it alone.
Moving on.
TRAVIS: That's the OG.
ASHLEY: What is this, what do we have over here?
Well, who was the old gnome that Grog saved
in his intro video?
LIAM: Pike's daddy.
ASHLEY: No, that was my great great grandfather.
TRAVIS: That's right.
ASHLEY: Yes, great great grandfather Wilhand.
TRAVIS: Wilhelm, hand? Wilhand.
ASHLEY: That's right.
LIAM: Wilhand the money.
TRAVIS: Grog has an intelligence of six,
he's gonna get names wrong from time to time.
LIAM: Everybody, if you could
choose whatever fantasy world
to live in, what would it be?
TRAVIS: Marvel.
TALIESIN: Ooh.
ORION: I would live in the...
Next Generation world, universe.
TALIESIN: You had me at Marvel.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
ZAC: Here's the thing,
you could live in Marvel what you live in,
if you couldn't live in
that world as a superhero,
just as a normal person.
TRAVIS: Right, not in New York.
Anybody that lives in New York
in the Marvel universe is just stupid.
Like rent's gotta be $1.50.
TALIESIN: Terrible idea.
MATT: I'd say Myst.
So I can just write my own worlds
to infinity from there.
LIAM: Lord of the Rings.
MATT: Or Amber as well.
ASHLEY: I was gonna say Lord of the Rings.
Maybe Rivendell.
MARISHA: I'm gonna say Final Fantasy 10.
MATT: Grey Havens.
If you're gonna do Lord of the Rings, do
Grey Havens,
'cause you're far enough away from Mordor,
where it's generally
not gonna be a problem.
LIAM: I wanna be one of the Fellowship.
Ashley Johnson lived in a
Marvel universe already, right?
MATT: That's true.
ORION: See, and it's a big hassle.
MARISHA: It was a big hassle.
ORION: Yeah.
MATT: Before the stream, our D&amp;D session--
MARISHA: High insurance rates.
MATT: Before the stream our D&amp;D sessions
would happen once every
month to month and a half,
more like month and a half.
LIAM: Why is Matt Scarlet Witch?
MATT: I'm down with it.
'Cause I alter reality.
Power makes sense.
Our sessions used to be once every month,
or month and a half,
and they would be about
six to eight hours.
But the problem is we'd
play so infrequently,
every session I'd have to
remind everyone what happened,
and it was hard to schedule.
Part of the reason we're
even doing this show,
is because it's technically work,
which allows those of us who have families
and children more of an
excuse to come more often.
So yeah.
LIAM: Googoo17, Arkazey keeps asking,
what's your favorite
nerdy t-shirt you own?
Mine is one that says Mordor World Tour,
it looks like a rock 'n' roll t-shirt,
but it says Mordor World Tour.
MARISHA: That's cool.
Favorite nerdy t-shirt.
TALIESIN: I've got a Sons of Anarchy
Doctor Who t-shirt,
I'm a really big fan of.
I'll wear it next week.
MARISHA: I've got like an army, kind of soldiery,
looking t-shirt that says
Chimera, like Chimera Corps.
MATT: That's actually the one I was gonna say,
that's my favorite shirt too.
MARISHA: I like your displacer kitty you've got.
MATT: Displacer kitty's kind of cool.
Adorable.
TALIESIN: I like your shine on me shirt.
MATT: Oh God.
If you guys haven't watched.
Chris Dane Owens, on YouTube,
Chris Dane Owens, Shine on Me.
It's a music video, watch it.
Chris Dane Owens, Shine, or
Shine on Me, YouTube, do it.
TALIESIN: I love that you own the shirt from it.
MATT: I bought a shirt from it,
'cause it's that amazing,
I had to.
TRAVIS: Did anyone tell Pike that Scanlan
killed the naga for her?
MATT: I don't think someone's done it yet.
LIAM: Scanlan had his first kill.
You saw it, right?
MATT: You saw it on the stream.
ASHLEY: I saw it, me, Ashley saw it,
but Pike did not hear about it yet.
Who knows, that could be the thing
that seals the deal.
I'll be like, you killed the naga?
Okay, let's do this.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: Any betrayals in the game?
MATT: No betrayals, disagreements,
and occasional--
TRAVIS: Trippings and beat-downs.
MATT: And stealing of flying carpets.
ASHLEY: I actually did step,
I kind of did hurt Liam one game.
Or Vax.
LIAM: The game we played together?
We did just the two of us one night.
ASHLEY: There were some of the
girls changing in a room.
MATT: I forgot about this.
LIAM: I was very curious to see you naked.
But that's kinda fallen on the wayside.
ASHLEY: Vax was very curious to see
what a gnome looked like naked.
LIAM: Never seen it before.
MARISHA: So you did a little peeping tom?
LIAM: Why wouldn't I wanna expand my horizons?
MATT: So he rolled stealth.
ASHLEY: So he rolled stealth, and
he did, and saw or whatever,
and then when I came back
out, and I found out about it.
LIAM: Looked good, it was compact.
ASHLEY: It was just a small human.
And I think I stepped on your foot,
and gave you some damage.
LIAM: Maybe a hit point.
ASHLEY: Yeah, a hit point or two.
MATT: You earned it.
ASHLEY: I earned it.
ORION: Somebody, seagullblaster--
LIAM: No, Vax didn't spy on
Vex, sorry, go ahead.
ORION: Asked-- Tiberius said something
about the Palestone,
and what it is, and this is,
somebody asked a different question,
this is kinda gonna answer both.
I, and everybody else,
wrote backstories for Matthew
to essentially give him so he
could construct our universe.
Tiberius' particular quest
is looking for particular artifacts.
Essentially I made him like Mulder.
Nobody believes in the city
that these things exist,
except him, so the truth
is out there kinda thing.
So I made up these five
different artifacts
that do different things.
And I don't know what they do until
I might maybe find them, and if I do,
it's up to him, to Matt,
to determine what they are,
if they are anything.
They might be nothing, I don't know.
I've found one item so
far, and it's awesome,
and all of us have given him bits and pieces,
and that's how he constructs our story
with things that you throw in yourself.
MATT: Yeah, and each player,
all their story lines work into the world.
Not all of them will happen
immediately of course,
some people have had personal encounters
and story encounters already,
some are yet to occur,
and there will be points
throughout the campaign
where the party will probably have to move
and individually deal
with each person's story
to some extent.
MARISHA: Dealt a little bit with each person.
MATT: Touched a little bit like--
In Eman, we've seen Vex and Vax's father.
LIAM: Vex and I ran into to our father again
for the first time in many years,
it was a little frosty.
MATT: Had a new family.
LIAM: Have a little half sister.
TRAVIS: Matt, you have a favorite voice?
And does it hurt to do
the gnarly monster voice?
MATT: If you do it for an
extended period of time
it can be kind of shitty.
ASHLEY: I don't know how you do this new one.
TRAVIS: Breathing in and out.
LIAM: That's inward singing, man.
TRAVIS: It is inward singing.
LIAM: And then I'm fucking singing,
and then--
MATT: Actually, it's funny,
a bunch of my NPCs that
I've done since high school
have ended up turning into
characters I've booked.
I'll go into an audition and be like,
"I'll go ahead and do Nutibe Curios,
"from my Second campaign,"
and I'll end up doing that character.
Alof in Pillars is a character I NPCed
back in high school.
LIAM: That's awesome.
TALIESIN: They still haven't heard my favorite voice
from this campaign yet.
'Cause we haven't gone
back to the city yet.
MATT: Oh, Gilmore?
LIAM: Gilmore is a wonderful
magician who owns a shop.
ORION: Was that the fancy--
LIAM: Yes, in the city of Eman,
he's got a big friggin'
crush on me, and wants me.
Wants me and some day you
and I will actualize that.
MATT: We'll have to roleplay that.
LIAM: Maybe in a game. Maybe not.
TRAVIS: What do we think is
taking over the hive mind?
MATT: What do you guys think is
MARISHA: Well we know it's named--
ORION: Obviously some butthole.
ASHLEY: I think I might have an idea.
TRAVIS: Yeah, you had a vision that we don't even
know about yet, right?
ASHLEY: Well.
TRAVIS: Taking those mushrooms,
having those visions.
ASHLEY: Taking those mushrooms.
LIAM: Someone asked how do game devs find us
for acting work?
We all audition, hundreds
of people audition,
for every role in Los
Angeles, we all just try.
Today I worked on a superhero game,
and the guy who was directing
me for voiceover said,
"hey, so what are you doing
for the rest of the day?"
And I said, well, I'm gonna go to the gym,
I'm gonna do this, then
I'm gonna go do that,
do you know about that D&amp;D show
that a couple of us are doing?
And he's like, "yeah, I heard about that."
And the guy who had written the game went,
"yeah, I've watched every episode."
(all laugh)
MATT: So awesome.
TALIESIN: That's so cool.
ASHLEY: Someone wants to hear Gilmore's voice.
TALIESIN: I think we should save that for,
wait until they actually meet Gilmore.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we can't give it away.
MATT: Gilmore's a fun one.
ASHLEY: Gilmore's awesome.
MATT: Gilmore is very Broadway.
He's very--
TALIESIN: Not the gargoyle.
MATT: No, no.
I could see him being a
character in a John Waters film.
TALIESIN: Oh my God, yeah.
ASHLEY: Totally.
LIAM: Give him a pencil-thin mustache.
MATT: Yeah.
TALIESIN: I'm trying to catch up.
TRAVIS: Greater overall motivations?
MATT: That may or may not be secret,
depending on the characters.
MARISHA: What is each person's
favorite D&amp;D monster?
TRAVIS: A dead one.
LIAM: I liked it when Grog got it on with a,
what was it, a nymph?
TRAVIS: What?
MATT: Yeah!
TRAVIS: You don't know man, I
went through the portal,
handled my business like a champ.
LIAM: In the air.
TRAVIS: I don't kiss and tell.
Nobody knows.
I got what we were supposed to get.
LIAM: A nymph could have attacked us,
but Grog looked her in the eye,
and she liked what she saw.
Then he disappeared for a little while,
and he came back and he
was in a really good mood.
TRAVIS: I flashed her the look, man.
She was mine, what can I say?
TALIESIN: I like the little green gelatinous cubes.
I think they're fun, and
then if you make 'em right,
you can just make 'em out of jello,
and eat them when you're
done, that's awesome.
MATT: I don't wanna answer that
question necessarily,
because I might be using
them in the campaign
at some point.
ORION: Which one?
MATT: Nothing.
ASHLEY: So that means we haven't used 'em yet.
MATT: But overall, I just love the tarrasque
because it's like the game ender.
It's the godzilla.
It's the one DM's move where he's like,
"I'm done with this campaign, hey guys,
"you're gonna fight a tarrasque,
either you're all gonna die,
"or you beat it, and you beat the game!"
So the tarrassque is always fun.
ORION: Is it the final boss?
LIAM: I've always been fascinated with the mind flayers.
You're fucking throwing
an army of them at us.
'Cause they're dangerous.
MATT: Yeah, they're terrible.
LIAM: And they're so outside of the norm.
MATT: And hey you stealthed up,
and pretty much killed
one in one round today.
ORION: That was insane.
When the mud on the face,
and the stab in the
fucking back of the head.
MATT: You guys black ops'ed that entire barracks.
LIAM: I'm proud of the knife.
TALIESIN: I know what you're talking about.
TRAVIS: Grog and Scanlan have no bastard children,
that we know of.
Or that you can prove.
LIAM: Other streamed D&amp;D games,
like Rollplay hosted by itmejp?
TRAVIS: No.
LIAM: No.
Maybe we will, though.
ORION: I won't.
LIAM: Everyone play Dungeons &amp; Dragons.
ASHLEY: My favorite NPC character is
a little butler who I think became--
TRAVIS: Yes!
ASHLEY: He's the cutest little
thing you will ever see,
and I think now he works at--
TALIESIN: He works for us now.
MATT: Yep, you guys hired him,
and he's currently helping
keep your Keep in good shape.
ASHLEY: What's his name?
ORION: The old fellow, right?
MATT: I'm trying to remember, I'll have to
go look at the list again.
I have so many NPCs, I have a hard time.
ASHLEY: He's just the sweetest little thing
you ever did see.
MATT: Grog's flatlined intelligence,
anything like that happen before?
That was the first of
that type of situation.
TRAVIS: I went unconscious once 'cause I fell,
how far did I fall?
TALIESIN: Wow, you fell.
ORION: Oh, that was a crazy one too.
MATT: They were there fighting
in an underground cavern,
and at the very, very top of this giant,
like 170-foot ceiling,
which they had all kinda floated up to,
and put a rope, anchor in.
TRAVIS: I was ready to Toro the bull.
MATT: The first umber hulk you guys ever encountered,
ended up pushing Grog out of the hole,
bullrushing him.
Had the rope tied around his waist,
but unfortunately Grog
weighs about 600 pounds,
rope snapped,
and he took enough damage
to go from full health
to unconscious and
bleeding out in one round.
MARISHA: 'Cause he confused you, right?
And you just hari-karied off the hole?
TRAVIS: I was gonna dodge and be all awesome,
and say ole or some
shit, but I was just out.
MARISHA: That was when I was a spider tiger.
'Cause I cast Spider Climb on myself,
and I was in tiger form,
so I was spider climbing
all over the place.
MATT: That's also one of my
favorite risky rolls,
which was after that happened,
Tiberius, you pushed the
umber hulk onto the ground,
or through the hole, it fell.
ORION: I had this amazing spell with Pathfinder
called Aquasphere, orb, and you can like,
capture large creatures.
I literally can waterbend a sphere
and carry this dude and drop them down,
it was amazing, I miss it so much.
Continue the story.
MATT: So essentially Tiberius decided,
'cause Grog was unconscious,
and the creature was down there.
All of them were stuck 170 feet up,
in this little hive essentially.
Tiberius said fuck it, he
jumped out of the hole,
swan dove down, and cast
Featherfall on himself
at the last minute,
had to make a concentration check
because of the wind rushing past,
and having to cast a spell while falling.
It's a very difficult thing.
He had about a 40% chance of success,
60% chance of instant
death, and he made the roll.
I love risky moments like
that so much, I love 'em.
TRAVIS: It was pretty legit.
ORION: I did it again and held
that fucker, it was intense.
MARISHA: I'm wondering when we're
gonna face a beholder.
MATT: That'll be nasty.
MARISHA: That's my favorite D&amp;D monster.
ORION: With all the eyes?
MARISHA: They're like a big floating head
with a giant eye, and
they've got tentacles,
with eyes on the end of 'em,
and each eyeball does a
different ray of effect.
TRAVIS: A beholder?
MATT: Nasty.
TRAVIS: You know what that is too?
LIAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: They're nasty.
ASHLEY: Bad news bears.
MARISHA: They're super awesome.
One of these days we're gonna fight one.
MATT: One of these days.
LIAM: They're a signature character
of Dungeons &amp; Dragons.
They represent D&amp;D.
TRAVIS: What made the dwarves get
bigger today in the battle?
MATT: That's actually an ability of the duergar.
LIAM: Viagra.
MATT: Yeah.
They can summon through
sheer force of will,
and just the way they've
been bred over time,
they can increase their
form for a short time
to increase their damage,
and be just a general asshole, so.
It's an ability the duergar have.
TRAVIS: Long lost son.
LIAM: I'm gonna guess that none
of us have been to Sweden?
MATT: I have.
ASHLEY: My dad was from Sweden.
MATT: That's awesome. I've been to Gothenberg.
TALIESIN: That's not surprising.
ORION: I have not, but I would like to go.
MARISHA: Yeah, who wouldn't
want to go to Sweden?
LIAM: Makes sense.
Pale and blonde.
MATT: Have you been?
ASHLEY: Never been.
MATT: It's beautiful, I spent two
weeks in Gothenberg, Sweden,
on business years ago.
It was gorgeous.
Food was amazing.
Nothing like walking down the street
and seeing a giant gothic stone structure
with an archway and a gargoyle perched,
and you walk in and it's a 7-Eleven.
It's pretty hilarious.
All the architecture there is old,
but it's been repurposed, it's great.
LIAM: If you had to choose
would you pick to receive an extra level,
or Matt's hair?
MATT: God damn it.
LIAM: Matt's hair.
(all laugh)
ASHLEY: Hair, obviously.
MARISHA: Receive an extra level or Matt's hair.
TRAVIS: You can't get hair like
this without unicorn blood.
My God.
MATT: I'm gonna shave my head one of these days.
LIAM: Shave his head, he can't DM anymore.
MATT: I'd wither.
It's like Sampson.
I would just like become
this little raisin,
I'd be David Tennant.
LIAM: The beholder strikes for the-- mawp. Mawp.
MATT: Let's see.
What are the questions we got up there?
MARISHA: It is 11:38, by the way.
LIAM: What is the most outrageous
and unexpected thing
to come from a natural 20?
That was Scanlan.
ASHLEY: Probably the--
LIAM: Scanlan as Burt Reynolds.
MARISHA: Oh right.
MATT: We'll take about five
more minutes of questions.
Five or ten more minutes of questions,
then we gotta take off.
LIAM: How long will you be doing this show?
30 years.
MATT: Considering we've been playing
for two and a half years,
and everyone's level nine,
we can keep going for quite some time.
Whether or not we continue past that,
means either we do a new campaign,
or we go into epic or mythic levels?
We'll cross that bridge when we get to it.
I mean, I'd love to keep playing
for as long as people wanna play,
but also people get busy, life changes,
we'll see how it goes.
I'm in for the long haul as
much as everyone else is.
LIAM: Matt, multiple people are
asking what the music is
that we're hearing on the show.
MATT: What you hear in the
show is a combination of
a gentlemen named Kevin Macleod,
who has a website called Incompetech,
which he produces really amazing,
royalty-free musical tracks.
I've used them for many
web series for many years.
He's very talented, and I contacted him,
and asked him permission
to use on the stream.
He's like, "yeah, anything
on Twitch, go for it."
And the other half are a
lot of soundscapes I use
from a company called Platemail Games,
which make great custom RPG soundscapes,
and some tracks that are just creepy,
and dwarf cityscapes,
and dark forest night.
It's a great, great resource.
Those are my two big ones
for this Twitch stream.
ORION: And yes, we did roll
for our starting stats.
MATT: Yeah it was 4d6, drop the lowest,
arrange as desired.
So it was a powerful campaign.
LIAM: What was the most nail-biting moment
the group has seen?
It was Pike's death.
MARISHA: Pike dying.
MATT: Definitely.
Do you prefer being the DM,
or do you like mixing it
up and being characters?
I never get a chance to play games really.
It's kind of one of those, always a DM,
never a bride circumstance.
LIAM: You wanna play with my kid?
MATT: Yeah.
I'll be an evil character
and murder them all,
you're going to regret it immediately,
make 'em just cry.
LIAM: "Listen, that's the game, suck it up!"
MATT: Yeah, turn it into Mazes and Monsters.
TALIESIN: Is that why you play so much War Machine,
is because for once you
don't have to be responsible?
MATT: Probably.
I occasionally,
I got to play a game of
Diaspora for a while,
with Philip Eisner, the guy
who wrote Event Horizon.
So playing a sci-fi kind
of horror-based universe
with him running, that was great.
That was very brief.
LIAM: Matt, can you give us any
teasers of things to come?
MATT: No.
See as they happen, man,
that's part of the fun,
the mystery of it all.
I know what's coming.
I got stuff planned for years.
It's gonna be fun.
LIAM: Do you have any advice
to get into voice acting?
Learn to act, study acting,
go to where the work is,
keep acting, in anything,
in fucking anything.
Go to where the work is.
Act.
MATT: What age did you play your first
tabletop RPG game?
For me it was Second
Edition Dungeons &amp; Dragons,
and it was freshman year of high school.
TALIESIN: GURPS, 13.
I was, yeah, 13 years old, GURPS.
ASHLEY: Favorite tabletop games, not D&amp;D?
LIAM: Get Hulk Hogan to play.
ORION: That's not D&amp;D?
TALIESIN: Mansions of Madness.
MARISHA: Mansions of Madness is great.
ORION: Is MTG, Magic the Gathering a tabletop?
Is that considered tabletop?
MARISHA: It's a card building game.
ORION: Magic.
MARISHA: War Machine.
MATT: War Machine is really fun.
MARISHA: I'm a Cryx player.
MATT: It's awesome.
ASHLEY: I'm just starting.
MATT: You're the awesome Retribution.
ORION: I'm Circle of Orboros.
TALIESIN: We played with Scanlan, of course we do.
TRAVIS: It said do you ever think about sexuality
while playing, besides Grog, of course.
Scanlan does, I'm sure other people have.
TALIESIN: It's hard not to think about it with Sam.
TRAVIS: We just pay for it.
LIAM: Are we gonna release more
background information
of your campaign?
MATT: Yes, actually.
LIAM: We are?
MATT: Time has been hard, but
I'm trudging through.
What I'm gonna make
essentially is a video recap
of the previous two and a
half years of the campaign.
I'm gonna narrate it,
it's gonna be very simple.
It's gonna be just information,
with the occasional slides
of stuff in the background.
But I'm working on a video,
kind of like your guys' intros,
that'll be a synopsis of the story
up until this stream stared.
TRAVIS: Claymation, that's awesome, man.
MATT: I will destroy you, I
will fucking stab you.
LIAM: If you want, it's not much,
but I have a Vine account
that's under the name
VoiceofOBrien, and I
took a lot of Vine videos
from our private game.
So it's not a ton,
but you'll see us acting like shitheads.
TRAVIS: That's seven seconds at a time.
MARISHA: Seven seconds at a time, yeah.
I think I still have the video
of you trying to woo the nymph lady.
TRAVIS: Try?
TALIESIN: That was a good video.
MARISHA: It's basically just you
flirting with my boyfriend.
TALIESIN: I have some videos of the tarot game,
and a couple of us
TRAVIS: Matt is now a nymph.
MATT: Yeah, we sat there, and, hey man,
I've had to flirt with
quite a few of these people
as characters, it's interesting.
LIAM: Who's your favorite NPC that
you brought to life for us?
MATT: Oh, that's a tough one.
There's been a lot of good ones.
I really enjoyed Grimthorn,
the dwarf that was--
LIAM: Clarota is pretty good.
MATT: Yeah, Clarota is great.
He was the one eyed dwarf with the shave,
that was taking you guys
to the fighting ring.
He was fun.
I'm enjoying Balgus as
well, he's a good one.
MARISHA: Ballsack.
LIAM: Ballsack.
MARISHA: Do we have nicknames for all of our NPCs?
MATT: You know, I really enjoy
Arcanist Allura Visoren.
ORION: So do I!
MATT: She's an awesome, powerful,
headstrong elven sorceress,
who is part of a, not a secret,
but a very powerful circle
of magic practitioners
around the world,
and also a member of
the council of Tal'Dorei.
She's one of the largest
allies that this group
has had through a lot
of the adventure arcs,
and I love playing her, she's great.
LIAM: Grog, have you even thrown
a gnome as an attack.
TRAVIS: The very first time we played,
I picked up Sam and
chucked him across a room.
That was full of a trap.
MARISHA: Fastball special.
TRAVIS: And it worked.
It was awesome.
MATT: What character type would I play
if I ever got a chance to play?
I would probably be a bard.
I wanna make a bard that
actually conducts the battle.
Meaning, sits there and watches the fight,
and he's conducting,
like music happens when
other people attack.
Cymbals go off, and drum beats,
and all of his abilities are tied to music,
so he's actually conducting
the battle like a symphony.
That's what I wanna make.
MARISHA: That's cool.
ASHLEY: That's badass.
MATT: One day.
LIAM: Would you ever play an evil character?
My contingency plan, if I get killed,
I don't know about evil,
but he won't be as nice as Vax.
MATT: Evil characters have to
be discussed with the DM.
I'm iffy on the evil character,
unless they have a good reason,
and a personality that isn't going to
completely derail the campaign.
Doing an evil campaign, that's fine.
But if you're building a character
that is going to inherently be a troll,
and basically diminish everybody else's
good time in the story,
it becomes a problem.
ZAC: It's the internet though, man.
MATT: I know.
If you make a cool,
interesting evil character,
that can be evil but still like,
like a good example would
be in Baldur's Gate, Edwin.
ZAC: What if one of your guests,
that came on for one night,
would they be allowed to be?
MATT: Yeah, they'd be allowed to.
They may not survive.
ORION: Tiberius might not--
MARISHA: Or kill them.
LIAM: I don't know about evil,
but if I have to come back,
I might be a lot more selfish.
MATT: In it cool news, tabletop columnist,
offering to DM a game for me.
I may have to hit you
up on that some time.
'Cause that'd be awesome.
TALIESIN: He deserves a break.
ZAC: How do you remember all the voices
that you've done of the
NPC's over the years?
MATT: I make notes and audio files.
TRAVIS: You do?
MATT: I do.
As a reminder in case I forget.
TRAVIS: Jarvis.
(all laugh)
MATT: I have notes written next to every NPC,
like an accent or dialect
that I chose for them,
a general texture.
Kind of like what you'd see for breakdowns
for a character you're auditioning for.
I basically make that for each NPC
to remind me of what I've done.
And if it's a particularly weird voice
that I don't know if I could
replicate in the future,
after the session I'll go
and do a little audio file
of me doing the voice so
I can go back to it later.
TRAVIS: You're a freak of nature, man.
TALIESIN: Seriously.
MATT: Good question.
MARISHA: There's a lot that goes into it.
I think Matt, just to
put it into perspective,
for everyone in the chat room,
I think Matt probably
spends close to eight hours,
at least, on each time before we play.
Or I guess at least we used to.
MATT: For our big session,
I'd spend as much time
preparing as we did playing.
I'll put it that way,
I spend as much time preparing as we play.
So for these sessions,
I'm spending about three hours a week,
preparing, what, three to four hours a week?
For old sessions that was bigger.
LIAM: Someone asked, what was the
reaction to discovering
you had a magic flying carpet?
Which you can see if you
go to Matt's YouTube channel.
There's a video that
Ashley made of us playing,
and you see our reactions to that.
MARISHA: Who was it, was it you, or Vex?
That tried to float down with the carpet,
and then we realized it was magic?
LIAM: Yeah, underneath.
MARISHA: But we tried to just
use it like a parachute.
MATT: It was a crumbling tower,
it was Allura's tower.
You guys went into,
realized she was missing,
because the tower had been attacked.
You set off essentially a defense system
of her arcane tower,
which caused it to
crumble into a tiny pearl.
ORION: Tiberius jumped out the window
and just cast Featherfall.
MATT: Yeah, and just kinda glided away.
You turned into an eagle
and grabbed the gnomes.
The rest of the party had to try
to rapidly escape a crumbling tower
that was compacting on to itself.
MARISHA: I think it was mainly
the twins in the tower.
LIAM: Hey, Grog almost died once.
He fell from a great--
MATT: You fall a lot, but when
you fall on to something,
that thing is fucked.
MATT: All right, we're winding down here,
'cause we gotta leave here shortly guys.
Two more questions.
LIAM: Three more questions.
ZAC: Closing messages
before you guys go, too.
MATT: Oh yeah, all right, so we'll
do a couple more questions,
then we'll go to closing messages.
Who wants to pick?
LIAM: Let's make it a magic three.
MARISHA: Let's do a good one.
MATT: Three, three questions, make 'em quick.
Let's see.
MARISHA: Waiting for a good one.
MATT: How much does Grog weigh?
Grog weighs approximately
600 pound we decided.
TRAVIS: Just under 700.
MATT: So he's kinda rough.
TRAVIS: It's all muscle, bitch.
MATT: Yeah it is.
Muscle and brains.
TRAVIS: Muscle and wang.
500 pounds and a hundred-pound wang.
MATT: Any of you consider running a game
for fans of the stream?
Actually, I've run a couple
games at conventions
for some groups.
I had a couple of sessions I ran,
actually in conjunction with Wizards,
they sent stuff out for us.
TALIESIN: And for charity.
MATT: Yeah, we've had some charity
D&amp;D games out here in L.A.
So we've done them before.
I'd consider it if there
was time available,
and a venue that allowed it.
So if it does happen,
we'll definitely announce it here.
TRAVIS: Best item in your inventory?
ORION: That's for a magic item?
TRAVIS: Oh, did we already say that?
I'm just blanking.
ORION: No.
TALIESIN: It's hard to read this quickly.
MATT: You guys have some good questions.
TRAVIS: My brain's turning into applesauce.
ASHLEY: I know, me too.
LIAM: Do you realize how lucky you all are
to have such a nice group of friends?
ALL: Yes.
MATT: Very much so.
TALIESIN: The world is cold and unfeeling.
LIAM: Let's close it on that.
I love these guys.
MATT: And I like to think that this is,
because there are so many good
people out there in the world,
and we were lucky enough
to find each other
through weird circumstances.
And there are so many good
people in the world out there,
don't close yourself off to it.
You'd be surprised how many awesome--
TRAVIS: How long does it usually take
the woman in the back
to tie her boot?
MARISHA: I'm multi-tasking.
MATT: No, that's the question we end it on.
That's the question.
MARISHA: I've just been tightening my laces
while I've been kicking it back here.
ZAC: I'm gonna squeeze in here really quick.
So I have some thank
you's I wanna call out
while you guys are here.
I figured they'd appreciate
me calling them out
the most while you guys were on screen.
'Cause they like you guys for some reason.
ALL: Aw.
ZAC: So these are all people
that have sent us stuff
off Amazon, to help
make the studio better.
So Danielle Denny.
ASHLEY: Thanks Danielle!
MATT: Danielle, thank you so much Danielle.
ZAC: Bradley Dealman?
MARISHA: Dalman.
MATT: Bradley Dalman.
LIAM: Do we know what they sent us?
Can you tell us some of
the things they sent?
ZAC: I have, I--
Well I mean they're like--
new microphones for
that station and lights.
MARISHA: That's amazing.
ZAC: Wii controllers.
MATT: Brad, thank you, that's amazing.
ZAC: And other stuff for tech we
needed that we didn't have.
Shane and Russell said thanks
for all your hard work,
and everything you are doing.
MATT: Aw.
Thank you Shane!
ZAC: Ty Odlinger.
ASHLEY: Ty!
ZAC: Timothy B. Hudson.
ASHLEY: Timothy!
ZAC: Timothy B. Hudson, he went nuts.
MATT: Timothy!
TALIESIN: Triple threat.
ZAC: Kathel T. Stockdale.
ASHLEY: Cool name, Kathel.
ZAC: Yeah, that's rad.
Luis Archuletta.
MATT: Luis Archeletta!
ASHLEY: Luis!
ZAC: Steve Chua.
MATT: Steve!
ZAC: Here's a little something
to help you guys out.
Another one from Chua,
here's a little something
to help you guys out.
And I know there's more coming in,
this is what we've got so far.
Thanks everybody.
MATT: That's so cool guys, thank you.
ZAC: And they also have asked
that a couple of you guys
come on Honesty Hour sometime.
LIAM: What is that?
ZAC: It's a show I do on Monday nights,
where it's 100% no-holds-barred.
I will answer any question that they ask.
TRAVIS: What?
ORION: I would love to do that.
TRAVIS: Sounds like a horrifying idea.
ZAC: Okay, they've asked
specifically for Ashley,
they've asked for Matt, and as for,
actually I think everyone has been asked
at one point in time.
So I'll say maybe I'll
have you guys once a month.
ASHLEY: When is Honesty Hour?
ZAC: It's usually Monday nights from nine to,
whenever the fuck.
Like it went to 1:30AM the other night.
CREW: Isn't it really an Honesty Time?
ZAC: Don't do it!
It's only for subscribers.
It's not that bad, because they
ask really great questions,
a lot of them have been about
how have you gotten through
certain aspects of depression,
or what kind of thing--
MARISHA: Oh that's good.
ZAC: It's pretty inspirational.
LIAM: How many times have you been
hit in the nuts in your life?
ZAC: I can say twice.
And would probably
explained how it happened,
and what I did.
It's just story time.
Sometimes the questions
get a little inappropriate.
MATT: That's okay.
ZAC: That's fine.
MATT: But like for the most part,
the audience here's been so awesome,
they're all super intelligent
with great questions.
I'd be down, I'd totally be down.
ASHLEY: Wait, is this Noncompliant?
ZAC: Yeah.
MATT: Oh, that's awesome.
Yeah, I got the Noncompliant
tattoo this week, actually.
MARISHA: Oh yeah, I saw your picture.
ASHLEY: That's amazing.
ZAC: We have a comic book show on Tuesday.
TRAVIS: (air-horn sound)
ZAC: Real talk with Zac.
But thank you guys so much for doing this.
The subscribers really wanted to do it,
so hopefully you guys enjoyed as well.
And we will
come back next week.
TRAVIS: Yeah!
ASHLEY: Yay!
ZAC: Tomorrow, if you guys are at Wonder Con,
are any of you guys
gonna be at Wonder Con?
TALIESIN: Saturday.
MARISHA: I don't know, maybe.
ORION: I'll be there Saturday.
MATT: I'm sadly not gonna be there.
ZAC: I will be there tomorrow
from 12:30 to one,
for a meet and greet,
which I'm going to pretend
is an autograph signing,
and I'm going to bring my own pictures.
MATT: Yeah!
ZAC: We're gonna have fun with it.
Going in costume.
Becca and I are going in costume,
and then Hector and Ify will be at four.
And then Hector and Ify are doing a Q and A,
or no, a trivia game
that night on the stage
for Geek &amp; Sundry and stuff like that.
So Geek &amp; Sundry will be there,
you guys should stop by.
LIAM: Thanks for all those
greater than three's, guys.
MATT: Less than three's.
TALIESIN: Greater than three, too.
ZAC: The computer, the story behind that,
is during the charity drive,
we had a robot read off
all the donation messages.
And the robot would say,
and when they made a heart,
it would say, "we less than three."
MATT: So beautiful.
ZAC: So we turned that into a thing.
LIAM: (robot voice) We less than three you.
MATT: It fucks me up every time you do that.
ZAC: Cool.
Thanks guys!
TALIESIN: Forgot you speak-and-spell.
ZAC: Thank you so much.
MARISHA: Bye.