(laughing)
MATT: Hello everyone, and welcome to tonight's
episode of Critical Role! Where a bunch of us
nerdy-ass voice actors sit around, play Dungeons
and Dragons, and shout obscenities a little late.
LAURA: Did it make it?
MATT: We'll find out, I'm sure.
LAURA: We'll find out.
MATT: Anyway, glad you guys could join us for
tonight. Tonight is not a typical episode, we are
missing two of our cast members, and since we're
in the throes of an interesting narrative, we
wanted to push that off for a week. Next week we
return with Vox Machina's normal narrative as well
as Jon Heder as a guest, which is going to be a
lot of fun!
(cheering)
MATT: However, this week, for the five members
that we do have, we are going to have a
fantastical Battle Royale. A Level 17 Battle
Royale. The power level has definitely jumped
since the last time we had one of these, I'm
curious to see how it pans out. Should be fun.
LAURA: By the way, I saw voting-- there was a poll
to see who they thought would win.
MATT: Don't say anything yet! Hold off on that.
Hold off on that.
LAURA: Okay.
MARISHA: I wonder how many people are going to
lose money on us tonight.
SAM: Travis, you have something-- yes, right,
right there.
TRAVIS: Where? Right here?
SAM: Yeah, right there. There's a little
something.
TRAVIS: Did I get it?
SAM: Yup.
MATT: Anyway. So yeah, so real fast, just to get
through our brief announcements for the day. Me,
Marisha, Taliesin, and Brian Foster will be flying
out tomorrow, early, to Atlanta to join you guys
at MomoCon. We've been talking about it for a few
weeks here. We have a Talks Machina panel on
Saturday. Signings. Other fun events, so please
come join us if you're going to be out in that
vicinity. Next week after that a bunch of us are
going to be at the Stream of Annihilation, a
stream up at Seattle with the D&D folks, along
with a bunch of other awesome D&D groups and
streamers, High Rollers guys. We've got Curse of Strahd
folk. A bunch of just really awesome people coming
up. We're going to be playing with some folks, I
might be running a game, it will be fun. But look
forward to seeing you guys there. Check us out.
We'll have more information to come out soon. Then
the week after that, I'm going to be at A-Kon in
Dallas.
Because I apparently don't like having
weekends.
TRAVIS: Are you allergic?
MATT: I need to work on that. Planning is a
problem, it catches up to you. But anyway, I'll be
out there for that in Dallas, Texas. Hope to see
you guys that weekend. What else? What else do
people want to talk about?
TALIESIN: I think we're going to have our
Wednesday Club this Wednesday. I think we're going
to do Wonder Woman. We were having a straw poll,
where I think we're going to be talking about
Wonder Woman.
TRAVIS: That's kind of irrelevant right now, right?
TALIESIN: Yeah, we don't normally veer relevant,
but we figure this is kind of a big deal so, you
know, and it's an interesting conversation.
SAM: Have you ever done an episode about Groo the
Wanderer?
TALIESIN: No, but I know of Groo. We don't know
Groo well enough to really delve in.
SAM: If you do an episode on Groo, that's the one
I'll watch.
TALIESIN: Not the one you'll be on?
SAM: No, no, no. I'll watch it, though.
TALIESIN: You'll watch it, then?
SAM: Yeah, yeah. I'm not going to go on your show.
TALIESIN: Okay.
(laughter)
SAM: I could bring my comic collection on your
show! And show it off!
TRAVIS: You have a comic collection?
SAM: Yeah, man!
TRAVIS: More than ten? More than ten comics?
SAM: Yeah, I've got some good books, man.
TALIESIN: You gave me that really good comic book
for-- was it Christmas last year? Or the year
before, because I read it in Colorado, it was
really nice.
MATT: Save your rolls, Laura.
LAURA: I had to test it!
MATT: I know. I know you do.
LAURA: That was the Joe-dice.
MATT: Oh! There you go!
LAURA: He's making it into the battle.
MATT: There you go. You need to know who's in your
corner, Laura.
LAURA: That's right.
MATT: All righty, guys. If we don't have anything
else to discuss, we're going to go ahead and dive
into tonight's episode of Critical Role.
[dramatic music]
MATT: All right, and welcome back, everybody! So
as part of tonight's Battle Royale, a couple of
things that I want to put out there. One: because
we're at higher power levels, it may go quickly.
If it goes quickly, we may do a second round.
Which, keep in mind, whatever alliances or
betrayals you endure that first round will
probably be remembered for the second.
LAURA: Wait, wait, wait! Were we supposed to make
alliances?!
SAM: Oh yeah, we all made alliances. We all made
alliances, Laura.
(laughter)
SAM: It's all four of us against you.
TRAVIS: Yeah, raise your hand if you're on Team
Right.
MARISHA: Table Right!
MATT: Laura, have you played Risk?
LAURA: Yes.
MATT: Risk is a game where you make alliances and
then double-cross people. It doesn't say it in the
rules, but that's how it always happens. That's
what I assume will probably happen. It may not!
You guys may surprise me! I'm just saying, be
prepared.
LAURA and TRAVIS: (singing) Be prepared!
MATT: (laughing) Okay, now I'm voting for that
table! All right, guys, the other thing I want to
mention is, whoever the victor is will get a minor
prize. A very, very minor prize.
LAURA: What is it?! Do we get to know what it is?
TALIESIN: A Nintendo Switch!
MATT: PlayStation 2. No. You will get a fate die
that you get to carry over
into the main campaign.
It's a single reroll.
SAM: That could come in handy.
MATT: It's like a Luck point.
TRAVIS: Well fuck! No! My lighthearted self is now
changed!
LAURA: You already have fate dice! You have a
fucking Deck of Many Things. You have an entire
plethora of fate dice.
TRAVIS: That is not the same. There's like a seven
percent chance I even pull
something even close to that.
TALIESIN: I'm with Travis on this one. It's just
not the same. No.
TRAVIS: That's a big prize!
LAURA: Enjoy the fate die, Keyleth or Grog.
TRAVIS: Yeah, like when you choose to become a
goldfish from a thousand feet.
MARISHA: Yeah, that would have been great. To have
then. Mm-hm. So clutch.
TALIESIN: Is this your first Battle Royale? So,
what happens though, is that the people who are
obviously the problem often get targeted first.
And then it'll be other people who somehow have
all their hit points in Round Four.
SAM: Oh, that's happening, guys. You're going to
forget I existed.
MARISHA: Mr. Loot-Drop over here.
TALIESIN: Mr. Loot-Drop may go down early.
TRAVIS: Mr. Care-Package.
MATT: As you all comfortably find yourself
resting, falling into sleep and darkness for the
evening, in the city of Whitestone, over some
point in the break of the year-long period. You
find yourself-- Your eyes opening; bleary,
blinking, towards what appears to be a grey
cloud-covered sky. You look about and find
yourselves somewhat scattered amongst an
unfamiliar battlefield. Travis, I want you to go
ahead and roll a d6 for me, please.
TRAVIS: Oh God. Okay!
LAURA: This is serious! This is serious!
TRAVIS: A two.
MATT: A two. Okay.
LAURA: Oh my God! I was just looking at the
top-view, I didn't realize that
those are fucking towers!
MATT: Yeah, so that's you there.
TRAVIS: Okay. Okay.
MATT: Laura. Go ahead and roll a d6.
LAURA: (panting) Okay! Six!
MATT: A six! With Trinket there.
LAURA: Oh God. Oh, with Trinket up there!
MARISHA: Exactly where the ranger should be.
MATT: All right, Marisha, roll a d6.
SAM: First roll of the night!
MARISHA: Four.
MATT: Four. All righty. Taliesin?
TALIESIN: Four.
MATT: Roll again.
TALIESIN: Three.
MATT: Okay. Go ahead and roll a d6.
SAM: One.
LAURA: Look at us, spreading out our numbers!
MATT: All righty, so as you take in the scenery
around you, seemingly no rhyme or reason. You
wonder how you transported to this space. Taryon
in particular, you find that you seem to be a
little more viable power than you were when you
went to bed that night. You watch as a singular
cloaked figure seems to emerge from the clouds
above you and slowly fall from the sky. As the
entity, you see arms out, hood up, the wind
blowing around causing the cloth to flap and curl
about them. The hood blows back, and you see
before you, a--
SAM: It's me, Vax.
(laughter)
SAM: Hey everybody, I can fly 200,000 feet in one
second.
MATT: So, if we ever do a live-action Vox Machina
film, we get Owen Wilson to play Vax. So, as the
figure descends to about this point in the center
of the battlefield, you watch as the wind blows the
hood back, and you see there a handsome man with
immaculate, somewhat ear-length brown hair, and a
magnificent beard. As he smiles and looks around
and goes: "Tonight, you fight for me and my
"pleasure. For I am the forgotten deity, known as
Colville!"
(laughter)
MATT: "And you will dance before me. And between
you all, one victor shall stand and gain my
"blessing." At which point, he raises his hand, and
you watch as a force field of energy suddenly
(whoosh) warps around and encapsulates around it,
also zeroing off the top about there. So there is
a height limit to this chamber. Right across
there. About 20 feet up
from the base of this tower.
SAM: Which are 30 feet tall, 20 feet tall?
MATT: These are 30 feet tall.
MARISHA: So about 50 feet up.
MATT: 50 feet up, yeah. You watch as he grins and
smiles. "I hope you all learn something. Now, you
"have six seconds to decide where to go and what to
prepare for. No fighting is to commence until
"these six seconds are up. And then... Show me what
you've got!"
(laughter)
LAURA: So wait, we can cast things in these six
seconds?
MATT: You can cast or prepare anything you want
to, an action or movement or bonus, that doesn't
attack or assault another person, for the first
round, but first! Let's roll initiative, guys.
LAURA: Oh my gosh!
TALIESIN: Yeah.
SAM: I'm feeling lucky? That's terrible.
MATT: All righty.
SAM: That's one Luck down.
MATT: So, 25 to 20?
TALIESIN: 29.
TRAVIS: What the fuck, man?
TALIESIN: Ain't gonna have a repeat of last
time.
MATT: All righty. (laughs) That's right, yeah.
TALIESIN: I was just low enough, if I had been
above Liam, that would have been the end of him,
but he hid.
MATT: All right. 20 to 15?
LAURA: 19.
TRAVIS: 16.
MARISHA: 16.
MATT: Okay. Vex, and then Keyleth and Grog.
Interesting.
SAM: You need a tie breaker?
MATT: I think so. I'll have you guys both roll
dexterity checks for me, please. Just roll a d20--
TRAVIS: Just normal dex rolls? Or just straight
up?
MATT: Just roll a d20, and add your dex modifier.
TRAVIS: Okay. 20.
MARISHA: Four.
MATT: So we have Vex, then Grog-Keyleth! All
righty, and then Tary!
SAM: Oh, sorry, nine.
MATT: All righty. Which, by the way, you also
have--
SAM: Doty!
MATT: Doty at your disposal at the top.
SAM: Yes.
MARISHA: Are you at the top of the tower too?
SAM: I'm on that tower. She's on the other tower.
LAURA: Wait a minute, here's my question. Did we
see where everybody landed? Could we see
everybody, when we came down? Or did we just see
the guy?
MATT: You guys just saw the guy, and you just got
your vision around, so this round is going to be
running and taking in your surroundings, and doing
what you're going to do to prepare. From where you
are right now, you can barely see somebody. We'll
say as part of this round,
you guys get a feel for it.
MARISHA: As part of this round we what?
MATT: You get a feel for where everyone else is,
as part of this first round.
TRAVIS: On the towers, on the far ends of the map,
is there a back entrance to the tower,
or just the door?
MATT: Just the doors there, or climbing upward, and
there appears to be a trapdoor on either side.
TRAVIS: Going up?
MATT: There's a ladder, ladder, and a chain.
LAURA: When he said you have six seconds, I
immediately duck down and cast Pass Without a
Trace on myself and Trinket.
MATT: Okay, so, we'll get to your turn; Percival,
you're up first.
TALIESIN: I'm going to activate the Boots of
Spider Climbing. Should knock that out. I'm going
to charge Diplomacy. And then I'm going to--
TRAVIS: Can't hide.
SAM: What, is that a rule?
TRAVIS: No, I'm just talking shit.
TALIESIN: I ain't hiding.
SAM: I'm hiding.
TALISIN: I'm going to climb up to the top of that
building that's right over there.
MATT: Which one? This one?
TALIESIN: That little hut.
MATT: Okay, so you climb up.
MARISHA: Is that a hut, is that what those are?
MATT: They're little stone bunker-like
structures. There's an entrance on this side and
on this side.
MARISHA: Shit.
TALIESIN: Actually, how far-- I have a--
(counting) six, one, two, three, four, five--
MARISHA: It's like a paintball arena.
MATT: So, it's half your movement, that's 15 feet,
you can move 15 more feet if you want to.
TALIESIN: Yeah, let me get just one step back or
so.
MATT: There?
TALIESIN: Still at the edge, on the other side,
though. To your right.
MATT: Okay, here? Okay. So there you are.
TALIESIN: Yeah, and boots are activated, Diplomacy
is activated.
MATT: Boots are activated, Diplomacy is activated.
Perfect. All right. Just after Percy goes, you
watch as all the flickering braziers, the flames
flicker bright. You see these two glowing towers
that are slowly spinning, the blue crystals
(crackling noises) little sparks. And each of
these pillars gives off a slight hum. Vex, it's
your turn.
LAURA: It's like a trapped thing? This is so
Hunger Games. Oh shit! Okay. I'm going to cast
Pass Without a Trace on me and Trinket. And I'm
going to send him down-- Is there a trapdoor or
like a stairway around? That he can go down?
MATT: There is a trapdoor that he can go down and
then make his way.
LAURA: He's going to make his way down. But I am
going to hide, at the top here,
behind one of those--
MATT: Behind one of those? Okay. Go ahead and make
a stealth check. And Trinket makes it-- We'll say
halfway down the tunnel with Trinket's full
movement, there. So down the stairs and he's
halfway through the tower there.
LAURA: So my stealth is 30.
MATT: Okay. Good to know. Nobody else has any idea
where you are right now.
LAURA: Solid.
MATT: At the moment. All right, that brings us to
Grog.
TRAVIS: (grunts) I would like to rage! Just, oh,
so angry! I don't like people putting me in
strange places and floating down from the clouds,
Colville. Can I equip-- yeah, fuck it. Fuck it.
I'm going to stick with the Bloodaxe. Not the
Dwarven Thrower.
MATT: Okay, Bloodaxe. Oof.
TRAVIS: I know. I know. That might be a poor
choice. Oh, you motherfuckers can fly!
TALIESIN: I can't.
TRAVIS: Bullshit, you're climbing up shit with
spider boots. You know what, no, Dwarven Thrower.
Dwarven Thrower, and can I start to climb the
little rope ladder that's next to me?
MATT: Yes, you can, make an athletics check.
TRAVIS: I just want to get a good lay of the land!
I don't even know anybody's up there! 15.
SAM: The glasses are clutch.
MATT: You rage, get up, and just crest over the
top.
LAURA: Oh shit, you're already there!
SAM: (screaming) He sleeps in war paint?! Why would
he sleep in war paint?!
MATT: He rage-climbs the ladder. One rung over the
other, and with the rest of his movement gets to
the very top of the tower.
TRAVIS: Do I have a bonus action?
MATT: Well, your bonus action was rage.
TRAVIS: Oh, that's right, never mind.
MATT: If you have an action you want to do that
doesn't involve attacking or hurting anybody--
TRAVIS: I blow a snot rocket when I get to the
top.
MATT: Okay. You watch as a large globule of
goliath snot slaps the ground in front of you, and
skids a bit, leaving a trail.
SAM: Oh, man.
TRAVIS: Dexterity check.
SAM: It's like a cicada.
(laughter)
MATT: All right. Is that your turn, Grog? Keyleth,
you're up.
MARISHA: Oh, god. It begins. Can I just run up,
and just check that water right in front of me?
And really fast, put my foot in it and see if I
can see how deep it goes?
LAURA: And you die.
TRAVIS: No, no, let her do it.
MARISHA: Let me take my staff. And just put my
staff down a little bit.
MATT: Okay. Your staff dips down and it goes
about-- It keeps going. It's pretty deep.
MARISHA: It's pretty deep?
MATT: To the point where you get, like, to the very
edge of your staff, holding it there, and it
manages to go all the way in.
MARISHA: Oh, I touch the bottom now, though?
MATT: Yeah. Well, you haven't felt the bottom yet,
any more and you're
going to submerge your hands.
MARISHA: Okay. I'm going to cast Freedom of
Movement on myself. And then can I move around to
this side, here-ish? This side here-ish. Over
here. And hide.
MATT: And move over this way? Well, you're not
hiding, you don't have anything left to do a hide
action, but you move there.
MARISHA: That's fine.
MATT: Okay. All right. So, Taryon.
SAM: Everyone else has gone?
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: I have a lot to do.
MATT: All right, what are you doing?
SAM: Number one, how much does Doty weigh?
MATT: At his size, I'd say he weighs somewhere in
the range of 700 pounds.
SAM: Fuck. That changes things.
MATT: He is somewhat hollow in places, though.
TRAVIS: Build him out of aluminium?
MATT: No. He's large and he's heavy, metallic
substances, but he is hollow in places, so I'd
actually say he's probably closer to 500 maybe.
400 to 500.
SAM: Still, anything over 400 bones my strategy so
it's okay. We're okay. Plan number two. Okay. I
say, Doty! I need you to carry me away from all
the bad people. Remember how we played keep-away
as children? We're playing that now. Keep me away
from everybody.
MATT: "Tary."
SAM: Yes. I cast Sanctuary on Doty. I think I can
do that. Yeah? Okay. And then for my action I will
throw down the Bead of Force on myself and enclose
myself in the bubble.
MARISHA: You're going to be a guy in a hamster
ball being carried around by robot?
SAM: I take 5d4 damage.
LAURA: That's pretty smart.
MARISHA: It's pretty awesome.
TRAVIS: You take 5d4 damage?
LAURA: Just putting yourself in the ball?
SAM: Uh-huh.
LAURA: That's smart, you know what? And then we
can't hurt you.
SAM: Not for a minute.
LAURA: Oh shit!
SAM: I got ten rounds, y'all. See ya!
MARISHA: Is it totally invulnerable type of shit?
SAM: Yes.
LAURA: Unless somebody can dispel it or
something?
MATT: Only breathable air can pass through the
sphere's wall. No attack or other effect can.
SAM: It says no magic can pass within or without
the space, it doesn't say that I can't do magic in
the sphere, it just says it can't leave the
sphere.
MATT: Correct. So you can cast things on yourself
within, but nothing can pass by. However, you are
at the mercy of whoever has control of the ball at
the moment. So yes.
MARISHA: So wait, but you can't cast spells out
either?
TRAVIS: You ever see those sporting events where
the beach ball's just going
around the fucking crowd?
LAURA: So wait. Only air can pass through it,
huh?
SAM: Breathable air. Not poison air.
MARISHA: If I was an air elemental, could I go
into the sphere? Just conjecturing.
MATT: I don't know if you're considered breathable
as an air elemental.
MARISHA: Yeah. But I'm a breath of fresh air.
MATT: Taryon, as you slam into the ground, how
much damage do you take?
SAM: I'll roll. Six, seven, eight. Nine points of
damage.
MATT: That's not too bad. You take nine points of
damage, and the sphere encapsulates you and you
begin to roll forward slightly as Doty walks over,
grabs you, and pulls you back about there to the
edge. Not sure what to do, he's just holding you
now in this ball.
SAM: Sure.
MATT: "Tary?" Confused. All right. At the end of
that turn, you watch over as Colville, floating in
the center, goes, "And now, my champions! Let the
fight begin!" Slams his hands together and you watch
him vanish in a burst of thunder as it cracks
around the landscape. And you feel this energy
pulse you all at once as the battle has begun.
Percival, you're up first.
TALIESIN: Who can I see?
SAM: Grog's head.
MATT: You can barely see part of Grog with
three-quarters cover. Barely.
TALIESIN: I can barely see Grog with
three-quarters cover.
MATT: Everyone else looks apparently at the moment
not really in your line of sight.
TALIESIN: That's fine. That's my first shot then.
Let's just take a couple shots at Grog.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: You know, if you hadn't made it all the way
up that tower you'd be in intense trouble right
now. Okay, just pointing that out.
MATT: You have Sharpshooter, so you ignore
three-quarters cover.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I ignore three-quarters-- Let's do
first shot with Animus. That's a 29 to hit.
TRAVIS: Oh yeah, that hits.
TALIESIN: That hits? All right. Let's just roll
all three first.
MATT: Go for it, yeah.
TALIESIN: Oh! No. And then the second one is a
misfire.
LAURA, MARISHA: Oh my God!
TRAVIS: Like, gun-break misfire?
TALIESIN: Gun-break misfire. It's gun-break
misfire. That's okay. Yeah, so I'll just take my
third shot with Bad News. Just for fun.
MATT: Okay, go for it.
TALIESIN: 20 to hit.
MATT: Yeah, that hits. All right, so-- One Animus
shot, and then one Bad News shot.
TALIESIN: One Animus shot, one Bad News shot. And
I also take, really quickly,
I take a little damage.
MATT: You take 2d6 psychic, right?
TALIESIN: 2d6 psychic damage. Five, six, seven.
Seven points of psychic damage. Did I-- No. It
doesn't matter anyway, because I was going to call
Hex, but I'll do it later. Fuck it. All right.
Let's roll. I'm also going to run some Cabal's
Ruin into this, just for fun.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: So, let's do the first one, is 1d10.
MATT: So, do Cabal's Ruin damage at the end
because that is not halved.
TALIESIN: Yeah. So, 1d10 plus 1d6. So, first shot
is ten points of piercing damage and four points
of psychic damage.
MATT: Ten points of piercing damage, so that's
reduced to five. And then how many points of
psychic? Four points of psychic. Seven points of
damage.
TALIESIN: Then, the Bad News is--
MATT: Wait. Ten points-- it's nine. It was ten
points piercing reduced to five and then four
psychic. So that's nine.
TRAVIS: Oh, and the psychic's not reduced,
that's right.
TALIESIN: So, that's cocked. That's seven, eight,
nine, ten, 11. 17 points of piercing damage.
MATT: Okay, so take that down to eight.
TALIESIN: And let's just-- three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine. This is not halved, is it?
MATT: Nope!
TRAVIS: The psychic?
MATT: No, this is Cabal's Ruin. He's pumping you
full of lightning damage.
TALIESIN: I'm going to empty Cabal's Ruin into
him.
MATT: Okay! That's how many d6s?
TALIESIN: 10d6.
MATT: 10d6 lightning damage to you, Grog!
TRAVIS: Ones!
SAM: Lot of ones.
(laughing)
TALIESIN: Six, 15, 20.
SAM: It's all threes and fours.
LAURA: I'm so nervous.
MARISHA: Me too.
TALIESIN: 33 points of lightning damage.
TRAVIS: 33.
MATT: There you go. All right, Percival, and you
have movement. And a bonus, if you want.
TALIESIN: I'm not going to blow my bonus for now,
but I am going to run down and across towards that
tower towards you.
MATT: Over here? That's 30 right there, right?
SAM: There's like six cameras in front of us.
TALIESIN: As far that way as I can go.
MATT: Fair enough. All right, so, end of
Percival's turn.
LAURA: Oh! Oh! Are there lair actions?
MATT: There are lair actions on this battlefield.
TALIESIN: Is there a door, by the way, in that
thing?
MATT: There's a door right there.
TALIESIN: Okay, I'll eventually be heading towards
that.
MATT: Okay. Well, as you're running by it,
Percival, you hear that low hum (humming) begins
to (humming intensifies). Spin up, you hear this
crackling noise. And you watch as each of these
four towers suddenly gives off this intense
vibration around it. As you're walking, you feel
this force pulling on you, like being within a
certain radius of this is forcing you to move
slower (grunting). That's all. Vex, your turn.
LAURA: Okay, I can see Grog as well, because I'm
assuming his head is above those parapets?
MATT: Yes. He does have half-cover from you
currently.
LAURA: I have Sharpshooter, so he does not.
MATT: All right!
LAURA: I'm going to send Trinket down.
MATT: So, Trinket does manage to get all the way
to the bottom and emerges from the front door
there, but that's as far as Trinket can get with
his movement.
LAURA: Trinket's like (confused bear sound).
TRAVIS: Aren't you concerned with the love of your
life running across the courtyard?
LAURA: I can't see him! He's hidden, like from my
field of view, I'm assuming I can't really see
him. Can I see Percy?
MATT: Percy? Yeah, you can see Percy from there.
LAURA: I'm going to still shoot Grog. Yeah, I'm
going to shoot Grog twice. Once with the Blazing
Bowstring, and we're just going to see how that
goes. Aww man! 17.
TRAVIS: That is my AC.
LAURA: So it hits! Yes! Oh, shit.
TRAVIS: It's not too hard to hit me!
MATT: You've just got a billion hit points.
LAURA: 15. 15 plus four lightning damage.
TRAVIS: Okay, halved.
LAURA: Wait, lightning damage is halved?
TRAVIS: Mm-hm, I have resistance to lightning
damage.
MATT: You do when you go into your large form.
TRAVIS: Oh, which I'm not, yet! So 15 halved is
eight, right?
LAURA: Okay, and then four lightning damage.
MATT: Which is why you didn't halve any of the
Cabal Ruin damage last round.
LAURA: And then five points of fire damage.
TRAVIS: Okay.
LAURA: Damn it, he gets half piercing damage?
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: Fuck! Okay, I'm going to try it again.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: And that's an 18!
MATT: That hits!
LAURA: 14 halved is seven. No, wait. Eight,
because it's 16 points of damage.
TRAVIS: Okay.
LAURA: Plus four lightning damage.
LAURA: Plus Blazing Bowstring. Seven points of
fire damage.
TRAVIS: Okay.
LAURA: And I'm going to use my bonus action. I'm
going to move down a couple parapets towards you
and I'm going to keep hiding as my bonus action.
MATT: Okay. Go for it. Roll a stealth check.
LAURA: Do I have to roll if I've got skirmisher
stealth? Or do I just continue to hide? I'm just
wondering how that works.
MATT: It's been a while since you used skirmisher
stealth.
LAURA: I know. I don't remember. Yeah, it's a
ranger thing.
TRAVIS: This fight started and I'm like (machine
gun fire). The fucking Godfather just
(screaming).
MATT: Basically. You're not wrong.
TALIESIN: I hit you with a ball of lightning, man,
like a Tesla coil.
TRAVIS: I climb up to the top of the tower like,
what's going on? (machine gun fire)
MATT: At the start of your turn, you pick a
creature to remain hidden from,
not a general hiding.
LAURA: Oh, so I could say, I'm keeping hidden from
Percy.
MATT: Yep. But everybody else can still see you.
LAURA: And then I would roll for stealth to hide
from everybody else?
MATT: If you wanted to make the hide action.
LAURA: I'm going to keep hidden from Percy for
skirmisher stealth, and then I'm going to roll for
stealth, and I got a 24 to hide from everybody
else.
MATT: Okay. Good to know. Now, you guys are aware
she's there, you just cannot shoot her or attack
her from this distance necessarily. All right,
that ends your turn?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: Grog. Mr. Pincushion. What are you doing?
TRAVIS: I take the Titanstone Knuckles and I smash
them together and I cast Enlarge on myself. Is
Doty up there with you?
SAM: Oh, sure. He's holding me in a ball.
MATT: Like a giant hamster ball.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Do it.
LAURA: Is this tee-time?
TRAVIS: Can I go into a frenzied rage?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: And can I try and shove Doty off of the
top of the tower?
MATT: Yes, you may.
SAM: You'll have to succeed a wisdom saving throw,
first.
MATT: Yes, you do.
TRAVIS: My wisdom ain't bad. My intelligence is
dick-all.
MATT: Make a wisdom saving throw.
TRAVIS: Okay. 14.
MATT: Nope. So you go to shove him, and you go
(groan).
TRAVIS: Oh, because he's got Sanctuary on
himself!
LAURA: That's what Earthbreaker Groon had!
MATT: Yep. That's what Earthbreaker Groon did to
you.
TRAVIS: Understood.
SAM: You can still make the attack, you just have
to point it at someone else.
TRAVIS: Interesting. I choose to urinate all
over-- no.
TALIESIN: Does the ball count as someone else, or
just Doty?
MATT: You can attack the ball, but it does
nothing.
SAM: Well, it'll throw me away.
TRAVIS: Interesting, interesting. I don't learn
lessons very well. I'm going to try again. One
more time. I get three attacks, so.
MATT: Okay. So you're going to do the second shove
attack.
TRAVIS: Yep.
MATT: Wisdom save.
TRAVIS: 17?
SAM: I mean, that's it. DC 17.
MATT: Okay, so now getting Doty's sheet out here.
For a shove attack, I believe it's a contested
athletics check, let me double-check real fast.
TRAVIS: Okay. Not strength, but athletics?
MATT: Pretty sure. I'm sure the Internet right now
is going, "No, it's this! God damn it, Mercer!"
No, it's athletics contested by athletics, so go
ahead and roll an athletics check, Grog. With
advantage, because you're raging.
TRAVIS: That's higher.
MATT: Roll a d20, add four. For Doty.
SAM: 14.
TRAVIS: 24.
SAM: (Goofy-style screaming)
MATT: You watch as Doty turns to Grog, goes,
"Tary?" (bang) and end over end gets shoved off
the parapet, slamming onto the ground, prone here
at the bottom of the chain. You, Taryon, fly off
(boing) harmlessly and roll into the middle of the
pool, and are currently now on your side.
SAM: Floating? Is it like at Ren Faire? I'm in one
of those balls!
MATT: For the 30-foot fall, Doty takes 11 points
of bludgeoning damage.
SAM: Still alive, he's fine.
MATT: And is prone. (chuckles)
TRAVIS: I have some movement left.
MATT: You do. You have 40 feet of movement left.
TRAVIS: Right. Is there a trap door at the top of
the tower?
MATT: There is, yes.
TRAVIS: Would I need an action or a bonus to be
able to open it? To go down into it?
MATT: It would be an action to lift it up.
TRAVIS: I have one-- well, I have an attack. Okay.
Can I move to the--
MATT: Actually, it's not that much, because it's
not locked or anything. You can probably just pull
it open.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'd like to go into the tower
stairs.
MATT: Okay. So, with the rest of your movement, 40
feet, you can get almost to the bottom, so you're
partway through that.
TRAVIS: And I'm still inside, right?
MATT: Yeah, you're still inside.
TRAVIS: Great. As long as no one can... yeah.
MATT: All right. That ends your turn, Grog.
Keyleth. Your turn.
TRAVIS: Fucking hamster ball piece of shit.
MATT: That's so awesome!
SAM: I might be alive for a long time after you're
all dead.
MARISHA: That's kind of true. Ten rounds, that's a
long fucking time. Okay, question. The radius of
the (energy field sound effect). I have Freedom of
Movement, do I seem to not be affected by that?
MATT: You seem to not be affected by it, actually.
You see it there, and as you push forward a little
bit with your hand, it doesn't seem to be-- the
gravitational shift isn't affecting you.
MARISHA: Cool. I'm going to move up and forward
this direction.
MATT: Up this way?
MARISHA: Yeah, one, two, three, stop right there!
MATT: Right there on the edge?
MARISHA: Do I see Doty?
MATT: You can just barely see the edge of Doty
right past these. You see his head on the ground.
You see Taryon in the middle, and you see Percival
right there.
LAURA: I like the idea of seeing Tary like...
MARISHA: I can move one more square, correct?
MATT: You can move three more squares if you want
to.
SAM: The inside of the ball is all puke smeared
everywhere.
MARISHA: Okay. Move me up to the doorway, up one
more.
MATT: Okay. You can look inside now. You see a
small chamber, and what appears to be a small
chest against the wall there, and this area is
just an open space.
LAURA: Oh, fuck, is there loot?
TRAVIS: You shut your damn mouth.
LAURA: And I'm up top?! Fuck.
MARISHA: That's good to know.
TALIESIN: You have a beacon. It's a very nice
beacon.
LAURA: I do have a beacon. I have a feeling that
beacon is going to attack us.
TALIESIN: It's probably going to attack us.
TRAVIS: No! It's so benignly designed.
MARISHA: I'm going to, on top of Doty, cast a
5th-level Flaming Sphere.
MATT: (laughing) Okay! (boom) So, you watch as,
suddenly, spiraling out of the air, this swirl of
fire forms into a large, burning ball of flame
that begins to collide and burn and singe into
Doty's (squealing metal) prone form on the ground,
still reeling from the impact of being knocked off
the tower. That's 5d6 damage. Go ahead and roll a
dexterity saving throw for Doty. I think it's
dexterity, right?
MARISHA: He's prone.
MATT: Prone doesn't change your dexterity saving
throw.
SAM: Oh, I rolled a 16, plus dexterity of zero. So
16.
MATT: That does not make her DC, unfortunately. So
that's 5d6 points of fire damage against Doty.
MARISHA: 18, 20, 21, 22! 22, and then--
MATT: 22 points of fire damage.
SAM: Sure, sure.
MARISHA: I don't get any other bonuses, okay. I'm
going to say, sorry, Tary! And then go (whoosh)
and go fire elemental form, and hope that this
isn't a mistake.
TRAVIS: Please be nothing but black powder in the
chest.
MARISHA: Wouldn't hurt me none.
MATT: Just, "Tary?" (explosion) Just a white flash
like Akira opening.
MARISHA: Can I do any more movement with my
elemental form?
MATT: You know what? You had ten feet of movement
left.
MARISHA: I'm going to pop into the room.
MATT: So I'll say, boom, boom. There you go. So
you flicker inside and you are currently contained
on the inside there.
LAURA: Ooh, with the roof on there and
everything.
MATT: Oh, yeah. It's all sorts of held up there
for you. So, that ends your turn, Keyleth. Taryon.
You are floating in a sphere over a pool of murky
green liquid.
SAM: End of round one. Okay. Action: Prep my
healing draught. Just pour it into a bottle and
get it ready to rock. Bonus: Click my Boots of
Speed.
MATT: Boots of Speed, clicked.
SAM: Movement: (rapid vibration sound effect)
TRAVIS: Like Sonic the Hedgehog?
SAM: With my Boots of Speed on, and the feat that
I took, I've got 80 feet of movement.
TRAVIS: Have you ever run in one of those balls on
the water? They don't go anywhere, man.
SAM: Shh. It's shooting water everywhere, it's
spraying it on Keyleth!
MATT: You have 80 feet of movement on the sphere.
However, the sphere is half your movement to push
it, so you get to push it 40 feet.
SAM: But I'm also in water, and I don't know if it
has any friction or anything.
MATT: Right now, on the water, you get about that
far.
SAM: Hey, I moved!
MATT: (straining sound) It's splashing behind, the
ball's coasting, and you're almost three, two feet
from the edge of the rock, and you're like, "Oh
God! Oh God!" The sweat's starting to pour from
your brow.
TRAVIS: You're vomiting inside the sphere.
TALIESIN: Like the worst spin art ever.
MARISHA: Throwing up the wine you drank earlier.
MATT: All right. And what's Doty going to do?
SAM: I can't communicate with him, I don't think.
I don't think sound can escape, so he's going to
keep doing what I told him to do. Get to me, and
keep me away from other people.
MATT: Trapped inside the sphere, it doesn't say
anything about it making silence or blocking
sound, so you can still communicate.
TRAVIS: Does Sanctuary stay on Doty now, or does
it go away when I hit him?
MATT: Sanctuary, once you get an attack--
SAM: It lasts a minute.
MATT: It lasts a minute until--
SAM: It doesn't say if he gets hit it ends.
MATT: I'm pretty sure it's until the creature
attacks. Yes, until the warded creature takes an
attack. So right now, it still has Sanctuary on.
SAM: Okay, but if he attacks he'll lose it.
MATT: Yes.
SAM: I'm going to tell him to do that. Get to me
and get me away from other people. This is a
suicide mission for Doty, guys, this is not going
to end well for him.
TALIESIN: Doty's not going to win this.
MATT: That's a valid point and reminder. It
probably will be fine, but Keyleth, I should've
remembered, because he did have Sanctuary.
SAM: No, it's okay, because hers was an area of
effect.
MATT: No, it wasn't. You target it to ram into
something. It wasn't a Fireball.
MARISHA: I have to make a wisdom saving throw?
MATT: Wisdom saving throw. Because it says "target
with a harmful spell." So, yes.
MARISHA: I've got crazy high wisdom. 22.
MATT: You're fine. I just wanted to double check
on that, because I totally forgot about the
Sanctuary. But still warded with Sanctuary,
getting up, half movement, so Doty has 20 more
feet to move, I think. Speed of 40. What do you
want Doty to do?
SAM: Get to me and push me away.
MATT: Okay, so Doty's going to move five--
MARISHA: Is he not affected by the gravity thing?
MATT: No, he is, and he gets about that far.
Doty's like (clanging metal) "Tary!" A ball of
flames just slamming into the back. All right. I
think that ends your turn, Taryon. Percival,
you're up.
TALIESIN: I'm going to dive into that room.
MATT: Okay. Five, ten, 15, 20. Your movement's
halved, it's like rough terrain, essentially, as
you're moving forward.
TALIESIN: So I've got two more movement? Two more
bits of movement?
MATT: Two more. But now as you get into the
doorway, it's not affecting you anymore. You do
see a small chest in the corner.
TALIESIN: I'm going to go over to the chest. I'm
going to try and fix my gun really quickly.
MATT: Okay, so make an action to try and repair it
real fast.
TALIESIN: That's fine. Had to roll a nine, I got a
12.
MATT: Okay, yeah. So you repair Animus.
TALIESIN: And then I can't open the chest as
well.
MATT: It's an action to do that, yeah.
TALIESIN: All right. I'm just going to hide and
wait.
MATT: Okay. So there you are. You are inside of
that chamber. Perfect.
SAM: Explosions.
MATT: All right. The large pillars that were
humming diminish. The slowly shifting blue,
crackling towers at the top of each large tower
begin to spin faster, and you hear (crackling) and
bursts of electrical energy just (static) out of
each side. Everyone on the tower, which would just
be you, I need you to make a dexterity saving
throw.
TALIESIN: Yeah!
LAURA: Are you celebrating that I'm getting hurt?
TALIESIN: Yes.
LAURA: You dick.
TALIESIN: I'm so excited that I don't have to be
the one to kill you. I don't want to be the one to
kill you. I'll never live that down.
LAURA: 24.
MATT: Okay, so you succeed. It would be 16 points
of lightning damage, it's reduced to eight. So you
take eight points of lightning damage.
LAURA: All right.
MATT: And then as the bolt subsides, the towers
slowly spin back down and appear to have gone
dormant once more.
TALIESIN: This is a great map.
MATT: This has been fun so far. You guys just
barely got into it.
TRAVIS: Call of Duty needs to copy this map.
MATT: All right. Laura.
LAURA: Yeah?
MATT: Your turn.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: What you got, Vex?
LAURA: Okay. Who can I see?
MATT: You can see Doty. You can see Taryon. You
watched Keyleth turn into the fire elemental and
disappear into this chamber. And you watched Percy
run into this chamber.
TRAVIS: And the roofs of the chambers are stone,
wood?
MATT: They're stone. Five feet of stone.
TALIESIN: We can't give suggestions, can we, over
the earpiece?
MATT: You can if you want to. You guys are welcome
to communicate between each other for this.
TRAVIS: On your turn!
TALIESIN: Oh, shit. Damn it. Fuck, I had such a
good thing to do!
LAURA: Okay. Trinket's going to run up to Tary and
push him back in the water.
(laughing)
MATT: Trinket runs up (heavy footsteps) (growl)
and shoves you, and you spin back.
LAURA: Just gentle enough to put him right in the
middle.
MATT: Roll a strength check, because this is
pushing against Taryon's wound-up, Sonic the
Hedgehog, gotta-go-fast speed.
LAURA: 16.
MATT: 16. Okay, make a strength check.
SAM: Oh, no. Eight.
MATT: Yeah, you get pushed back right into the
center of the water there.
TALIESIN: This is the Overwatch map I've been
waiting for.
LAURA: Well, then, I'll tell you what. Was that an
attack for Trinket?
MATT: Yeah, that was Trinket's attack. It was a
shove attack.
LAURA: Okay, then I'm going to save my action
until somebody outside of
Tary or Doty becomes visible.
MATT: Okay, so you're holding your attack action,
arrow ready, waiting for someone else to show up.
That ends your turn, Vex. Grog, you're up.
TRAVIS: I'll remedy that shit. Can I rage-tiptoe
up to the doorway at the bottom?
MATT: Okay, you (ferocious growling) (quieter
growling).
LAURA: The minute I see his head!
MATT: You glance through and you see a large,
burning ball of fire that's right there, just
chilling. You see Doty (heavy footsteps) running
away towards the water, where you see Taryon being
pushed back in the water by a large bear.
TRAVIS: And the fireball's around here?
MATT: And as soon as you glance up... a dual arrow
release.
LAURA: 17.
TRAVIS: That's my AC.
MATT: Yep. So you get two strikes on this.
TRAVIS: I mean, I'm literally doing this, so does
she get me in the fucking eyeball?
MATT: Yep.
TRAVIS: Oh, God.
LAURA: 11 halved. Plus three lightning damage.
MATT: So eight damage. Or, because lightning's
halved, too, right?
LAURA: Oh, because you're enlarged.
MATT: So six damage.
LAURA: All right.
TALIESIN: Whittle him down.
LAURA: Ooh, that next one is good. That definitely
hits. And then 16, 17, 19 halved.
TRAVIS: Nine?
LAURA: Because he's not by anybody, is he?
MATT: Currently, no.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: By the way, it is a tiny doorway, and you
are a big man. The hatch you went through was a
leap down, and you barely fit through. This
doorway is going to cost you some movement to get
through it.
TRAVIS: Oh, balls and ass. Okay, can I, after
getting shot in the face--
MATT: Yeah, it's like (whooshing arrow) (scream).
TALIESIN: You're not having a good day. You're
like an Ernest film right now.
Ernest goes to war.
TRAVIS: Ernest goes to camp. Can I break out
through the door and run down here to this corner
as far as I can? How far do you think I can get
with my movement?
MATT: You get out there, it'll take you ten
movement. To get to the doorway, it took you ten
movement, to move and get out of it, so you have
30 more feet from here.
TRAVIS: Okay. How far will that take me on those
squares?
MATT: Going this way?
TRAVIS: To that corner.
MATT: Five, ten, 15, 20, 25, 30. You can get
there.
TRAVIS: Yeah, actually, can I come towards you
instead of going back that way,
and can I lay down prone?
MATT: Sure.
LAURA: Down and dirty.
MATT: All righty. Grog is lying down prone. Is
that your turn?
TRAVIS: Can I use my Second Wind to roll a 1d10?
MATT: Yes, you can.
TRAVIS: Okay. Plus my fighter level. Fucking A.
Ten plus two. 12.
MATT: There you go. You gain 12 hit points. All
right. So, Grog, that's your turn?
TRAVIS: That's my turn.
MATT: Keyleth. You didn't use your action, so if
you wanted to, you could use your action to move
again if you wanted to dash. Don't forget you have
that option.
TRAVIS: Oh! Is that 50 more feet? Oh, really?
MATT: Yeah. If you're not using your action for
anything else, and your Second Wind is a bonus
action, if I recall, correct?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: So yeah.
TRAVIS: Yeah, let's just mad-dash tear ass towards
the tower that shot me in the eyeball. I might not
even get all the way, but we're going to see.
MATT: All right, so instead of falling prone, you
go.
TRAVIS: Yeah, just turn the corner and book it
like the T-1000 in Terminator 2, just chopping.
MATT: Do you want to go this way or this way to
get towards the tower?
Like, the perimeter or center?
TRAVIS: Perimeter. Perimeter.
MATT: Okay. You get there, and then you go prone?
TRAVIS: Yeah!
MATT: All righty. Say you're prone there.
LAURA: Can totally see your head outside of the--
TRAVIS: No you can't.
LAURA: Yeah, I can. From where I am, I can see
your head.
MATT: From where you are, you cannot see him. You
watched him run; he wasn't being stealthy about it
and he's 12 feet tall right now.
TRAVIS: Team Target Practice!
MATT: You're watching him (heavy footsteps) and
he's just out of view, but you know exactly where
he is. Ends Grog's turn. Keyleth, you're up. You
see a giant Grog just (heavy footsteps) loom past
the outside of the structure. You see this
flickering fire of Keyleth's elemental form in the
inside of this structure there.
MARISHA: I look to see if he's going to keep
going. Okay, know where Grog is. Is there any
windows in this little shack that we're in or--
MATT: No, there's just the doorway here and the
doorway here. Those are the only--
MARISHA: No bars or cracks or crevices?
MATT: Not from what you can tell. You can
investigate for it if you want to, but that'll be
your action.
MARISHA: No, fuck that. Okay, I'm going to move
out-- sorry.
I'm going to go up to Trinket over here.
LAURA: Aww. You terrible person.
MARISHA: Can I get into Trinket's space?
MATT: Yeah, it's 25 feet to get into Trinket's
space.
MARISHA: Well, let me do my attack first.
MATT: Okay, go for it. So 20 movement right next
to Trinket.
MARISHA: I'm going to be like, good job with the
ball, buddy! Shh, go to sleep! Go to sleep, we'll
make it less painful for you! We'll make this very
painless. Go to sleep. I'm sorry, I just can't
have you messing stuff up right now! That's true.
I'm trying to smoke him out first.
TALIESIN: Your nervous system knows to keep you
awake and conscious for that whole event.
SAM: Only you can prevent--
MARISHA: 15 for the first one.
MATT: I believe that misses on Trinket.
MARISHA: Natural 20 for the second.
MATT: Okay! So, the first one misses, the second
one definitely hits. Go ahead and roll double-die
damage on the second one.
TALIESIN: It's un-bear-able.
MARISHA: I get to reroll ones. I also get an extra
d6 for my fire hands.
And then I double die roll, right?
MATT: Yes, and then add the bonus.
MARISHA: 14, 15, so 30, plus 33 fire damage.
MATT: So Trinket takes 33 fire damage and is
currently on fire.
LAURA: Aww, buddy.
MATT: So, Trinket is like (very unhappy bear
groans) (roars).
SAM: There's water right there!
MARISHA: And then I'm going to use my bonus action
to turn over and take my flaming sphere and go
(whoosh) and ram Tary again.
MATT: Tary or Doty?
MARISHA: Doty, sorry.
MATT: Go ahead and make another wisdom saving
throw.
LAURA: Wait, how many damage was that?
TALIESIN: 35?
LAURA: 34? I'm going to say 34.
MARISHA: 19.
MATT: 19? Yeah. Go ahead and roll a dexterity
saving throw for Doty,
and roll another 5d6 fire damage.
SAM: Pretty good, this is plus his dex, which is
nothing. 18.
MATT: What's your spell DC?
MARISHA: 20.
MATT: Yeah, no. So, full 5d6 fire damage.
MARISHA: Those don't count, it's fine. That's not
great. I can reroll that one. Two, four, six,
eight, 11 points of fire damage.
SAM: We have our first victim.
LAURA: Oh, Doty!
MATT: As the ball slams into the back, you watch
as Doty's open chamber where the book is held goes
(cling) and flings open as fire bursts out from
the inside.
TRAVIS: Protect the book!
SAM: No!
MATT: He's now burnt and hollowed out from the
inside, and you watch as a cinder cluster of pages
hits the ground before burning away. Doty goes,
"Tar--" (clang) and falls to the ground.
MARISHA: Sorry! Sorry, guys!
SAM: Does the fire ignite his cannon hand?
TRAVIS: Look, he's rolling for it!
MATT: One arm detonates. It doesn't hit anybody,
but there's now curled pieces of broken and
sheared metal where the arm once was.
MARISHA: I'm going to take my other 25 feet of
movement that I have left to go back into the--
MATT: What's the speed of your fire elemental?
MARISHA: 50.
MATT: Yeah, so you have 25-- no, it was-- you have
30 more feet of movement.
MARISHA: I go back inside for cover.
SAM: It's like she was never there. This crazy
fireball came out, lit a bear on fire and went
back in the room!
TRAVIS: Do we have a certain amount of health
potions or anything like that? Like a set number
of them?
MATT: What's that, I'm sorry?
TRAVIS: Did we start with like a set number of
health potions or anything?
Like one each, or two each.
LAURA: Or is it just what we had on our body?
MATT: We'll say for the sake of fairness, because
I realize now if one of you guys was the keeper of
the health potions you'd be way too unfair.
TRAVIS: Right. I have a shitload.
LAURA: Yeah, we aren't, but yeah that's true, Grog
always has a bunch.
MATT: I'd say none of you have health potions on
you right now.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: You may have to search the battlefield to
discover things to help you.
TRAVIS: I'm way too ragey to search for shit.
MARISHA: I'm sorry for beating up Trinket.
MATT: All right. Keyleth, that's the end of your
turn?
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: Okay. Taryon.
MARISHA: Vex is mad at me.
SAM: As my action I tear off my patch of Healing
Potions. Now I have four healing potions.
(laughter)
MATT: Okay. (laughs)
TALIESIN: He's a lootdrop. We just have to-- Like
he's like such a lootdrop.
TRAVIS: Wait, wait. Ten rounds it lasts, right?
TALIESIN: Not anymore, it's now eight. It's nine
rounds or eight rounds.
LAURA: Don't, none of us do anything. If we don't
do anything for a minute, Tary's weak.
MARISHA: That would be so fucked up.
SAM: Don't believe them, Grog, they'll turn on
you.
TRAVIS: Why is there a tapping on this end of the
earpiece?
TALIESIN: This is such a Community episode: in
eight rounds he dies of exposure. I wait nine
rounds. (laughs)
MARISHA: (laughs) That's so true. It's so true.
MATT: So Tary, you have your four healing potions.
SAM: Can I take one of them?
MATT: As a bonus action you can, yeah.
SAM: I will take one. Yeah! Oh, that's cocked. Ooh!
Ten points, I am whole again.
MATT: There you go.
SAM: Great.
MATT: And you're going to attempt to move?
SAM: Oh yeah! I mean sure, when Trinket pushed me
do I have momentum that way?
MATT: The momentum is now going this way.
SAM: Okay, so I'll turn around and I'll go that
way.
MATT: You turn around, okay. I'll say you get just
to the edge and you can get ten more feet, that
direction. As the rest of it carries you onto the
land on the other side.
That's as far as you get. Okay.
SAM: Yeah, that's it.
MATT: That ends your turn. Percival.
TALIESIN: I'm going to check that chest.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: Is that a full action?
MATT: It is, yes.
TALIESIN: All right.
MATT: So you go (chest opening) throw the chest
open.
LAURA: It's a mimic!
MATT: Ha, shit. No, you do find a greater healing
potion.
TALIESIN: I take the greater healing potion. And
then I've got some movement, right, okay. And then
I go one, two, three, four-- Can I get to behind
that building? Behind the building towards you?
MATT: Over here?
TALIESIN: No, no like directly-- Yeah, like as far
over there as possible. I'll come out the door I
came in. Yeah, over there. And if I have anything
left I'll start walking up the wall. I know I
won't make it.
MATT: Okay, you can get to the very top if you
want to.
TALIESIN: Not quite, next round I'm going to pop
up.
MATT: Okay, so we'll say you're right there. But
this chest is opened, so I'll turn it to the side
as a reminder.
TALIESIN: Knock it prone.
MATT: Basically. You knocked the chest prone.
Okay! That's the end of your turn, Percival?
TALIESIN: Yep.
MATT: All righty. The fiery braziers around
suddenly begin to (explosion) and detonate, as the
flames inside burst out in a radius. Nobody is
quite in the radius to be affected by them. You
watch as the corners of the battlefield are
suddenly engulfed in flames briefly. Then the
flames retract back into just very gently burning
braziers.
TALIESIN: I love it. This is like Battlebots.
MATT: Vex, you're up.
LAURA: Okay, Grog's coming for me.
TRAVIS: No.
LAURA: First of all, Trinket's going to just wade
out into that water to get no longer on fire.
MATT: Okay, well, Trinket first takes three points
of fire damage at the top of the round. Trinket
wades into the water and does manage to put out
the fire. However, Trinket does take--
LAURA: Damn it, it's acid or something. What is
it?
MATT: -- does take six points of acid damage.
TRAVIS: Ooh, that shit's not water, it's acid!
MATT: Nope, it is not water.
TRAVIS: He called that shit poop.
MATT: As Trinket wades in he goes (acid sounds)
(hurt bear sounds).
LAURA: No, Trinket goes ow, ow, and then he comes
back out.
MATT: He gets back out of the water, and he's
like-- you see like the (sizzling) off of him.
LAURA: Trinket, I didn't even tell you to do that,
you just did that on your own! And then--
MATT: If a bear could shrug--
LAURA: Yeah, you know. And then I'm going to get
on my broom--
MATT: What is a whale?
LAURA: What's a whale? I get on my broom and I
want to fly up and over, above Grog.
MATT: Okay, so you (whoosh) over, and as you get
up, you almost bump into the ceiling
where that tower is.
LAURA: Actually, could I actually get to Grog if I
was flying?
MATT: If you were flying from here? You could get
right over there and see him on the ground, yeah.
LAURA: I couldn't get down to him, though?
MATT: You could get right down to him.
LAURA: Oh, this is going to be the worst move ever
if it doesn't work. I'm going to get down to where
Grog is. This is so stupid, though! No, because if
it doesn't work I can't get away! Because that's
all my movement, isn't it?
TRAVIS: Let's team up, you and me.
MATT: What are you doing?
LAURA: You want to team up? I go down to Grog and
I say, let's shake on it.
But I take my necklace
off and I put it into my hand.
TALIESIN and MARISHA: Oh!
MATT: Make a deception check.
TRAVIS: Which is not hard.
LAURA: Oh, it's a one. Whatever. I still try to
touch it to him. Whatever, he doesn't do it.
MATT: Right. So Grog, do you accept it?
TRAVIS: No.
MATT: Okay. She still touches it to you, but
you're not willing,
so what's the saving throw on that?
LAURA: It's a wisdom saving throw.
TRAVIS: You sneaky.
LAURA: It's only a ten.
TRAVIS: That's okay, it's not a high modifier.
That's a five.
MATT: (suction sound) Grog, you are absorbed into
a familiar dark stony throne room, staring out
through this small open space, almost like a
personalized movie theater of
the outside of the necklace.
TRAVIS: How do I get out?
LAURA: You can't unless I release you.
MATT: She has to release you. Mind you, Vex, the
battle cannot be won until all the other people
have been defeated. This is not considered
defeat.
TALIESIN: You could release him into the acid,
though.
LAURA: Hey, man. My mind's already there.
MATT: Remember, just be aware, if you're the last
one standing after everything else happens and you
release Grog, he's going to destroy you, so think
tactically.
LAURA: Yes, I plan on it, believe me. I'm going to
use my bonus action to stay hidden from... for my
skirmisher stealth, can I pick a target? I want to
stay hidden from Keyleth.
MATT: Okay. You cannot, because in order to get
there, your full movement leaves you right in the
doorway where she can see you. You literally
landed, did that to Grog, and turned over your
shoulder and see a giant fire elemental looking
right at you.
LAURA: Great. So I can't use my bonus action to
hide, because she's right there.
MATT: Yep, because you're not behind anything.
LAURA: Tight. I'm going to then use my skirmisher
to stay hidden from Percy,
and I've got nothing I can do.
TRAVIS: Fuck. Fuck! Like a rat in a cage.
MATT: You're just (groans).
TALIESIN: I imagine this as the interior of the
genie bottle from I Dream of Jeannie.
Pink and plush.
TRAVIS: Really? I was picturing something from
Saw, like the inside is just awful.
MATT: The inside is essentially a 20-by-20-foot
cold stone room with a central stone throne, and
the view you have is this ten-foot-by-five-foot
slit window that looks out from the necklace.
TRAVIS: Is it fish-eyed?
MATT: No, it's just a perspective. This is what
Galdrick, the wolf, had been looking through for
hundreds of years. And what Trinket looks through
whenever he's trapped. That's your turn, Vex.
Keyleth, you're up. What are you doing?
MARISHA: Oh shit.
SAM: It's like prison. You could do some
push-ups.
TRAVIS: I'm going to Rocky montage this shit.
Wait, are you skipping me?
MATT: Oh, that's right, you're up next. Grog, what
do you want to do?
TRAVIS: I'm going to flip the fuck out! I'm inside
of a goddamn box! I'm going to take my Dwarven
Thrower and throw it as hard as I can at the
window!
MATT: Okay. Go ahead and roll an attack.
TRAVIS: Yep. Reckless! Yep. Almost a natural 20.
26.
MATT: Go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: Awesome. I'm getting out of here in no
time. 25.
MATT: All right. Damage?
TRAVIS: Yeah, 25 damage.
MATT: Okay. Good. You are also technically sieged
because of your gauntlets.
TRAVIS: That's right, double damage.
MATT: All right. As you slam your axe into the
front of this, you watch as the stone (rumble)
quakes a little bit, and a little bit of dust
(hiss) settles from the ceiling.
TALIESIN: Oh my god.
TRAVIS: Oh, really?
LAURA: He could bust out of the necklace.
TRAVIS: Yeah, this is also Matt Mercer, who had us
fight an entire thing, taking down damage the
whole time while nothing was happening. I'll take
all three attacks at the window. Reckless.
MATT: Go ahead and roll attack.
TRAVIS: Natural 20.
LAURA: Does that mean if I put an actual monster
inside of it during the game
that they could break out?
SAM: You don't know.
TALIESIN: They'd have to think of it. I wouldn't
think of attacking the room, and he's designed to
hurt rooms.
LAURA: And he's designed to not think.
MATT: He's designed to make terrible choices.
TALIESIN: The room could collapse and squish him
like a bug, for all we know.
TRAVIS: That critical is 55.
MATT: So that's 110 points of damage with your
siege weaponry.
LAURA: I'm so dead, you guys. He's going to pop
out!
MATT: As you rear back for your second strike, you
bring your axe to go against this crystalline
field, this layer that defends you from that. As
you slam it, the axe hits and you watch as it
spider-cracks (cracking) all across, and the room
(rumbling) is now actively shaking. As you look
around, you can see that the walls are starting to
crumble, and rocks begin to tumble, and you see
what looks like a black void behind the cracks
that are opening.
LAURA: Oh no, that could be really bad.
MATT: You have a third attack, Grog. What are you
going to do, Mr. Raging?
TALIESIN: Oh god, I love watching his brain
strain.
MATT: What are you going to do?
TRAVIS: Fuck it!
LAURA: Oh shit!
TRAVIS: Natural 20.
MARISHA: No way. You are lying!
TRAVIS: No, it's true.
LAURA: What if you get sucked into a random void?
Then we can never defeat you.
MATT: Roll some damage.
MARISHA: If he gets sucked into a random void, I
imagine that would be considered defeat?
MATT: Oh, he would be fucking dead.
TRAVIS: 60 this time, so 120.
MATT: So 120 points of damage. So Grog. You rear
back once more, and that little bit of doubt in
the back of your brain, you quickly squash! As
your frenzied fury takes over, you see nothing but
red, anger, and blood, as you rear back a third
time and (whack). As you slam it, you hear what
sounds like a thousand windows shattering at once,
and all the walls suddenly collapse in towards
you, rocketing and spiraling inward. It crushes
into your body as you're thrust forward as the
crystalline structure ahead of you shatters and
pulls you through like a heavy vacuum.
LAURA: Oh god, he's out!
SAM: Or he's dead.
MATT: You suffer 26 points of piercing and
bludgeoning damage.
TRAVIS: Halved to 13?
MATT: Halved to 13.
SAM: That's not bad.
TRAVIS: And imploded from the inside?
MATT: And the necklace in front of you
(shattering) shatters off your chest, and you
watch as a giant Grog, right there into the
hallway, right in front of you.
MARISHA: Oh shit! So much just happened!
TRAVIS: Because I reference Terminator 2 later...
TALIESIN: You punched a hole through time and
space. Well done.
MATT: Your necklace is gone. It is not functional
for the rest of this battle. I was not expecting
you to attack the inside of the wall.
TRAVIS: I was just going to do it because he's an
idiot, but that really worked!
MATT: All righty! That ends your turn, Grog.
TRAVIS: Yeah!
MATT: Keyleth, you're up.
LAURA: I was going to release you!
SAM: In acid!
MARISHA: Okay. I'm going to turn around and be
like (screams, booming) on both of these guys. I'm
going to move into Vex's space and then attack
Grog. (bam, bam)
MATT: Go for it. You're technically occupying
Vex's space, right there.
MARISHA: Correct.
MATT: So you attack.
MARISHA: 15.
TRAVIS: Misses.
MARISHA: Second one, much better. That hits. 16
plus six is 22.
MATT: 22? That hits, yeah. So go ahead and roll
damage against Vex. Vex, you also catch fire.
MARISHA: Oh, I'm attacking Grog.
MATT: Oh, Grog! I misunderstood, sorry. So Grog,
you catch fire. Flames are just (whoosh).
SAM: You're having a weird six seconds of your
life right now.
TRAVIS: I know! (panting, warp sound effect,
screaming) Hulk angry!
MARISHA: That's 20 fire damage.
MATT: So you take 20 points of fire damage,
reduced to ten, and you're on fire. And you will
remain on fire, taking 1d10 fire damage every
round, until you spend an action to put it out.
SAM: But it looks cool.
MATT: But it looks cool. All right, and because
you moved into Vex's space, Vex, you also catch
fire automatically. Does she immediately take the
1d10 damage for occupying someone's space?
MARISHA: The first time it enters a creature's
space on a turn, that creature takes 1d10 fire
damage and catches fire.
MATT: Okay. So roll 1d10 damage for Vex.
Technically, both of them, because you had to move
into both of their spaces to do it, so you take
another 1d10 damage, Grog.
MARISHA: Five for Vex and four for Grog.
MATT: All right, so Grog, you take two points of
fire damage. Vex, you take five.
TRAVIS: Can I make my retaliation strike after her
melee on me?
MATT: Yes, you can.
TRAVIS: Okay. Reckless! Where's the crit now?
That's what I want to know.
MATT: Actually, that's a valid point. Go ahead and
roll, because he did reckless attack last turn.
TRAVIS: Oh yeah, you do get advantage.
MARISHA: Oh, on that first one again? Nope.
MATT: Okay. So what's your attack roll?
TRAVIS: It is a 22.
MATT: Yeah, that hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
MARISHA: This is going to hurt.
TRAVIS: Nah, you're fine. No, that's going to
hurt. I'm just kidding. Yeah, 25. That's it.
MATT: 25 points of damage to your fire elemental
form.
MARISHA: Okay. Is that halved because it's
bludgeoning? No, his weapon's magical.
MATT: You take full damage. However, doesn't he
take damage whenever he...
MARISHA: Yeah, when he attacks me, he takes
another 1d10 damage.
TRAVIS: Good to know.
MARISHA: Sorry, I'm an asshole. Eight.
MATT: So you take four points of fire damage. All
righty. Keyleth, so that's your action. You've
moved 15 feet to get into Vex's and Grog's space.
MARISHA: Okay. I'm going to back out and around
again, through the room.
MATT: Okay, so that's 15, 20, 25, 30. You're going
to stay in the room?
MARISHA: Do I have any more?
MATT: Yes, you have 20 more feet of movement from
here.
MARISHA: Yeah, let me go out one more and onto
this lip next to Trinket.
MATT: There?
MARISHA: And I'm going to take my bonus action to
take my Flaming Sphere, and I want to jump it over
this shallow end on this far side. I've got
cameras right in front of me. It can jump over a
ten-foot gap.
MATT: How much does it move?
MARISHA: 30. Can it get ten more feet over?
MATT: 25, 30. It'll get just about there.
MARISHA: To the edge? If it looks like it's not
going to land in the acid, and extinguish it or
something weird?
MATT: It looks like it'll probably land in the
acid.
MARISHA: Would it extinguish it?
MATT: Probably.
MARISHA: Then I'll keep it there on the edge.
MATT: Next round, it can. It doesn't have the
movement for the full jump, unfortunately. So it's
right there on the edge (fire noises) angrily
burning. I need you to make a concentration check,
by the way, with advantage, for the damage that
Grog hit you.
MARISHA: Yeah, I'll take that. 16. What do I have
to get over?
MATT: It's a constitution saving throw, and you
have to beat half his damage that he did to you.
MARISHA: So he did 25 damage.
MATT: So 12, half.
MARISHA: So yeah, I'm good.
MATT: That ends your turn, Keyleth. Taryon!
SAM: Oh, hi. I'm going to read my Scroll of Fire
Shield, setting it to a warm shield that will
protect me from all cold damage and last for ten
minutes.
TRAVIS: No one can hurt you in there anyway,
right?
SAM: Oh, but when I get out.
MATT: Wait, so your Scroll of Fire Shield, you
said?
SAM: Fire Shield.
MATT: Okay, yeah, that's ten minutes. Not
concentration. So you said warm shield, which
gives you resistance to cold damage?
SAM: Correct.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: That's what I want, because I'm already
resistant to fire damage.
And then I'll roll my ball.
MATT: All right, you've got 40 feet of movement.
SAM: I'm just going towards that corner.
MATT: Here?
SAM: No, top right. And I'll also pull out my rod
and I'll say, crossbow!
MATT: (clang) Turns into a nice crossbow.
SAM: And I'll load it with a bolt.
MATT: All right. (clicking) That's your turn? All
right! Top of the round.
Percy, what are you doing?
TALIESIN: Pulling around the corner.
MATT: Around here?
TALIESIN: Yep.
MATT: All right. You turn the corner.
TALIESIN: Casting Hex on Grog.
MATT: Grog is now hexed and on fire.
TALIESIN: And now I'm going to take a sharpshooter
shot and add a point of grit for an aimed shot to
the legs. Actually, does that make that harder for
me to shoot him later?
TRAVIS: I have pretty big legs.
TALIESIN: No, I mean if you're prone. I can still
shoot him just fine.
LAURA: Not with sharpshooter, I think. If they're
prone, we don't take disadvantage, right?
MATT: If they're prone, an attack roll against the
creature has advantage if they're within five
feet. Otherwise it's disadvantage. If the person
is prone, it's harder
for you to hit with ranged weapons.
TALIESIN: In that case, I'm going to hold on that
grit, and I'm instead going to use a piercing shot
with sharpshooter. So for shot number one, with
Animus, sharpshooter. Oh, for fuck's sake.
TRAVIS: Is that a misfire?
TALIESIN: It's another misfire.
MATT: This is not very Percy of you.
TALIESIN: No. So that needs to be picked up.
That's fine. Irritated, I pull out Bad News and
take another shot.
MATT: Okay. Is this also piercing?
TALIESIN: This is also piercing.
MATT: So that's another grit spent.
TALIESIN: Another grit spent. Oh, thank you.
God damn it... That's better. 22?
MATT: 22, Grog?
TRAVIS: Oh yeah, that hits. Sorry.
MATT: So you get to also roll an attack against
Vex, as well.
TALIESIN: Yes.
MATT: Basically, the shot goes through both of
you. It goes through Grog's shoulder (explosion)
and has enough weight to actually impact and hit
Vex in the same shot.
TALIESIN: Thankfully, it can't misfire when I do
this. 16.
LAURA: No.
MATT: So you watch as the muscle of the shoulder
explodes, and in that brief second you dodge your
head out of the way, and watch as the ball goes
(whoosh) and skims the edge of your cheek. A
little blood goes (flick) down the side.
LAURA: I glare at Percy, from under Grog's
armpit.
MATT: You glare at him through the hole in his
shoulder, Tombstone-style.
TRAVIS: Grog doesn't understand why you're so mad
at his shoulder.
TALIESIN: Aw, shit. So that's (counting). That's
33 points of piercing damage.
MATT: 33 points of piercing damage. That's 16.
TALIESIN: Plus four necrotic damage.
MATT: Four necrotic, not halved.
TALIESIN: And I'm going to take my last shot.
Actually, I'm going to take a Retort shot, because
this is the fucking day I'm having, and I'm going
to burn another grit, and I'm going to try and
knock him prone, because you're welcome.
TRAVIS: You just have a thing for me today.
TALIESIN: That, too. This is another sharpshooter
with Retort. Ugh, that's a 16.
MARISHA: Snitch is failing you tonight.
TALIESIN: 16 to hit.
TRAVIS: Misses.
TALIESIN: Goddamn it.
MATT: This time you turn around and see Percy
there. He pulls out the Retort shot, and you're
like (whoosh) and duck right out of the way.
TALIESIN: I'm diving back behind the bloody
doorway, goddamn it.
MATT: Okay. That's about the extent of your
movement, there.
TALIESIN: Yep. That did not go well.
MATT: All righty. That ends your turn.
TALIESIN: Yep. Oh, you have a disadvantage on
wisdom saving throws right now. Wisdom checks.
TRAVIS: Because of Hex? Wisdom saves?
MATT: Not saving throws, checks. So insight,
perception, things like that.
TRAVIS: Most things that I normally suck balls at
anyway.
TALIESIN: I want to make sure you really suck at
them right now.
MATT: All right. The pillars that you see in the
center here begin to (vibration) emit that weird,
vibrating hum again, and you feel, Keyleth, as the
gravitational pull warps around you but doesn't
affect your form, because of your Freedom of
Movement.
TALIESIN: Like the Matrix.
MATT: However, Trinket seems to (groans) be pulled
down by the gravity of it. You watch as Doty's
form on the ground across the way, (crack) gravity
crushes a little further in towards the stone.
TRAVIS: Is it anything inside of the four pillars
or in circles around each pillar?
MATT: It seems to be radial around each pillar.
All right. Vex, you're up.
TALIESIN: I take two psychic damage on top of
that. I forgot about that.
LAURA: I'm going to put myself out.
MATT: Okay. So you put yourself out as an action?
Okay. First thing, at the top of your round, you
take four points of fire damage. You spend the
action to put yourself out, so you are now no
longer on fire.
LAURA: I'm going to disengage.
MATT: That's a bonus action. From Grog?
LAURA: Yes. And I'm going to kick off the ground
and fly up as high as I can.
TRAVIS: You can disengage now? Son of a bitch.
MATT: Rogues, man. So you can get up about...
we'll say 40 feet. Yeah, you're up near the top,
straight up.
LAURA: I want to be over the roof of the building
below me.
MATT: Okay, so you get a little ways over. We'll
say about... there. Ends your turn?
Grog, you're up.
TRAVIS: How high is Vex?
MATT: She's about 40 feet up from you right now.
TRAVIS: Okay. I'm on fire.
MATT: Yeah. So you take three points of fire
damage, reduced to one.
TRAVIS: I am going to stay on fire, because fuck
it, and I am going to use my max speed to advance
towards Percy.
MATT: Okay. So you turn. All right, you're
advancing towards Percy. (counting)
TRAVIS: With my bonus action, can I use my Boots
of Feral Leaping to jump 20 feet horizontally in
the direction of Percy?
MATT: Yes, you can.
TALIESIN: All right.
MATT: Go ahead and roll your check to see if you
succeed or not.
TRAVIS: Yeah. 19.
MATT: You land right on the opposite side of
Percy. We'll push this open just a little bit to
get your placement as you slam into the ground
right next to him. (heavy impact). All of a
sudden, Percival, you're standing against the wall
and you hear (footsteps). Nothing. (explosion)
Right to the right of you, the sudden slam of
stone, as the behemoth goliath Grog lands next
to you, grinning, blood pouring out of the bullet
wound in his shoulder, big smile.
TRAVIS: Can I stick my finger in the bullet wound
hole and taste it and go, hi. And can I take all
three attacks, reckless, great weapon master, the
whole smash.
MATT: Yes, you may.
SAM: If that was the real Percy!
TRAVIS: I know! Some phantom bastard.
TALIESIN: I'm only nine hit points down.
TRAVIS: Oh, this is the hammer, so I don't have
great weapon master.
MATT: No, you took Blood Axe, didn't you?
TALIESIN: No, you went to hammer.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I've been using the hammer. 28.
TALIESIN: 28 hits.
TRAVIS: Good to hear. That's a 26 for the first
one.
MATT: 26 points of damage to you.
TALIESIN: 26 points of damage? Okay.
TRAVIS: That's a natural 20.
TALIESIN: Fuck.
TRAVIS: (giggling) I don't know what's happening.
That's not part of the plan. Hey, that's okay,
that's only a two, plus a lot.
MATT: So you rolled a what? What did you roll for
damage?
TRAVIS: Well, the dice landed on a two, plus my
modifier.
MATT: Well, hold on. What level fighter are you?
TRAVIS: Two?
MATT: Right, which means...
TRAVIS: Oh, I can re-roll a one or two for
damage.
MATT: Yep. That's the great weapon fighting.
TALIESIN: Fuck, dude. All right.
TRAVIS: Thank you, Matthew.
MATT: You haven't used that yet, really.
TRAVIS: That's cocked. That's an eight.
SAM: He likes to hit things.
TRAVIS: 72 points of damage.
TALIESIN: Is that everything so far? Is that
rolled into what you just did?
TRAVIS: That's just the second hit.
MATT: Wait, so how much is that?
TRAVIS: Well, it was a 24. 24 points of damage.
MATT: You double the dice, not the bonus.
TRAVIS: Double the dice. Okay. Not the modifier,
too?
MATT: No, just the dice. So you rolled an eight,
so it's 16, plus the modifier.
TRAVIS: 32.
MATT: Plus your brutal critical.
TRAVIS: Which is another damage dice.
MATT: Which is another three additional damage
dice at level 17, Grog. Well, no, because you're
not a level 17 barbarian, so it is two. You're
right.
TRAVIS: Right. Yeah. That's a ten. That's a nine.
MATT: So, that's two. An additional 19 to the 30.
SAM: 51.
TALIESIN: 51 points, so I'm at 26. 51.
TRAVIS: Third.
TALIESIN: I have a Hail Mary at the end of this.
We'll see how it goes.
TRAVIS: 27 to hit?
TALIESIN: Oh yeah.
TRAVIS: That's only 19 points of damage.
TALIESIN: Okay, I actually have to do the math to
see. I don't think I'm unconscious. No, I'm not,
but that hurt.
MARISHA: You're close, though.
SAM: That was 76 points of damage.
TALIESIN: I'm going to do the math with a
calculator--
MATT: 76 plus 19? Right? The last hit was 19
points of damage? So 76 total before that.
TALIESIN: 26, 51, and 19. I've taken 105 points of
damage. I have 35 points remaining.
SAM: He's fine!
TALIESIN: I'm at 35.
MATT: He did 96, wait.
TALIESIN: I'm at 140 points. I have 140 hit
points.
MATT: Right. Sorry, just doing the math here.
TALIESIN: I also had nine points of damage from
psychic damage from my own fucking gun.
MATT: Oh, total! I see. Okay. Grog, not a bad
round. You did 96 points of damage!
TRAVIS: (heavy footfalls, impact noise)
MATT: All right! So, that's Grog's turn. Keyleth,
you're up.
MARISHA: (heavy breathing) Okay, Vex is flying.
MATT: Vex is flying up on the top, on her broom.
SAM: You're all alone.
MARISHA: I'm going to take my bonus action, go
ahead and get this out of the way first, to get my
Flaming Sphere over that gap and ram it into
Trinket.
LAURA: You are so cruel.
MATT: Have Trinket roll a dexterity saving throw.
MARISHA: I'm a druid. I'm sorry! I feel bad about
this.
LAURA: 16!
MATT: Nope! 5d6 points of fire damage on Trinket.
LAURA: I have a feeling this going to kill him.
Oh, and I don't have the necklace anymore!
MATT: Nope!
SAM: Oh, so he'll just be dead?
LAURA: Or unconscious.
MARISHA: Six, 12, 18, 22 damage.
LAURA: 21 points is what he had. Trinket is
unconscious.
MATT: Unconscious and burning. Smoke (sizzling)
off the burnt fur. (sad bear sounds)
MARISHA: Okay, I still have my full movement,
right?
MATT: Full movement and action; that was just your
bonus action.
TRAVIS: Do I take any extra damage because I
didn't put the fire out at the end of the round?
MATT: No, it's at the top of your round that you
take the damage. Oh, and Percy? Roll concentration
checks for Hex.
TALIESIN: Oh, I took how many points of damage?
MARISHA: You could roll a natural 20 and save it.
TALIESIN: I could roll a natural 20.
MATT: So first attack, just roll higher than a 14,
we'll say.
TALIESIN: No.
MATT: Okay, Hex is gone.
TALIESIN: Hex gone.
MATT: Hex-a-gone! All right. Keyleth, what are you
doing?
MARISHA: I'm going to haul ass. Do I have enough
movement if I dash, or whatever,
to get into that building?
MATT: Over here?
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: Speed of 50, right? You can try, I don't
want to tell you if you can or not. You can try to
figure it out.
MARISHA: (counting) Yeah, I'll try it.
SAM: You're good at jumping over bodies of water.
MARISHA: I'm not going over water, man!
Can I peek in?
MATT: You get just there on the inside. You see,
it's largely empty and there is a chest that's
currently open and looks empty.
MARISHA: Cool!
MATT: You see, as you're running by, a large
hammer over the top of the wall on the opposite
side going (thuds). These heavy, wet thuds. All
right, so that's your movement. You have your
action, still.
MARISHA: Oh, right! Oh my god! Okay. I'm going to
use my action to expend a level-2 spell slot to
heal myself. With my spell slot to heal myself in
wild shape thing.
MATT: Right. It's a bonus action to do that, which
you already used to move your sphere.
MARISHA: I can't use my action? I'm basically
wasting an action to do it instead.
MATT: Sure.
MARISHA: Okay. Where are my d8s? Here they are.
That's not great.
I heal nine hit points in my form.
TRAVIS: That's great.
MARISHA: Thanks, man. I'm glad you're so
approving.
MATT: Taryon.
SAM: Me?
MATT: Yes. You're there in the corner with your
crossbow.
SAM: Yep. I'm going to-- crossbow in one hand, I'm
going to take my broom and stick it between my
legs. Ready to go.
LAURA: Is there room for that? How big is that
damn orb?
SAM: I don't know. Matt?
MATT: The broom isn't huge. You can fit it up
inside there. Take that quote out of context.
(laughter)
MATT and LAURA: You can fit it up inside there.
SAM: And then I will continue my movement. Where
am I? Am I that thing in the corner?
MATT: You're right here, way over in the corner.
SAM: I'm going to go around the wall so nobody can
see me.
MATT: Okay. Five, ten, 15.
SAM: Right next to the fireball of death, yeah.
I'll stay there, and then I'll try something. It's
not going to work.
MATT: What are you going to try?
SAM: I don't think it'll work.
MATT: What are you trying, Tary?
SAM: Secretly, I'm going to take a patch off my
robe, a window patch, and see if I can make a
window to climb through the sphere.
(laughter)
SAM: I don't think so. It says no effects can pass
through the sphere. I assume no effects can affect
the sphere, either.
MATT: I'm going to make a judgment call here,
based on the wording. Give me just one second.
TRAVIS: Can you drop it prematurely if you want
to, whenever you want?
SAM: No, I'm trapped in here. Trapped for a
minute.
TRAVIS: You're in the bomb shelter. You don't
know.
SAM: They'll let me out when they're ready.
MATT: Can pass through the sphere...
SAM: I don't think it's going to work.
TALIESIN: It's kind of brilliant.
MATT: I'm going to say sure. It's not passing
through it, it's creating
a passable window in the sphere.
TRAVIS: I like the ruling.
MATT: It makes sense.
SAM: I'm going to hover out a little.
MATT: So you go ahead and pull it off and slap it,
and you watch as a little two-foot-by-two-foot
window opens up.
SAM: I'm not going to leave yet. I'm staying
in the safety of the sphere for at least one more
round, ready to go.
LAURA: I really hope the fire pillar goes off.
SAM: I'm still in the sphere!
LAURA: Yeah, but you've got a hole in it.
SAM: Yeah, I realize that.
TRAVIS: (explosion, screams)
MARISHA: Come on, fire pillars, come on!
MATT: All righty. Yeah, technically... nah,
it's too late now to retcon that. My fault.
All right, so. That ends your turn, Tary?
Percival, you're up.
TALIESIN: Oh here's a hail Mary. First thing I'm
going to do is I'm going to use my bonus action to
down a potion of greater healing, which is how
many d4?
MATT: Greater healing is 4d4 plus four.
TALIESIN: 4d4 plus four. Let's make that happen.
That's okay.
MARISHA: Yeah, that's not a bad roll.
TALIESIN: 15 points of healing.
MARISHA: Yeah, not bad.
TALIESIN: That's one hit from Grog that I can now
take.
MARISHA: Yeah, might keep you alive.
TALIESIN: I'm going to try and hit him with
Diplomacy. Since I'm technically in grappling
distance, I can't shoot, and if I try to move,
he's going to hit me, so I'm going to attempt to hit
him with Diplomacy and see what happens.
MATT: Okay. All right.
TALIESIN: What is that, since I haven't used
it...
MATT: What does it say on the card?
TALIESIN: Where is the card? I have a lot of them
out. It's a dex-based unarmed melee attack. Just
dex modifier?
MATT: Yeah, just dex modifier. Well, no. I'd say
add your proficiency, as well, because you built
the thing.
TALIESIN: Add the proficiency bonus? Okay, thank
you. That's less of a hail Mary. Slightly. Oh my
god. 14.
MARISHA: Oh, buddy! No.
TALIESIN: I've rolled three ones and a two this
game.
TRAVIS: That's unreal.
MATT: So that's one attack.
TALIESIN: Another round with it?
MATT: Yeah. So Percy's (frustrated grunting)
trying to reach out towards you.
TALIESIN: 17?
TRAVIS: That's my AC.
TALIESIN: Okay! That's 2d12 electrical damage.
MATT: Lightning damage to you, so that's halved.
TALIESIN: That's 24 points of lightning damage.
MATT: So you take 12 points.
TALIESIN: Guess what. Make a constitution saving
throw.
TRAVIS: Which I have disadvantage on?
LAURA, MATT, and TALIESIN: No.
MATT: Constitution saving throw.
TALIESIN: You actually no longer have
disadvantage.
MATT: Yeah, Hex went away.
TRAVIS: Okay. That's a 27.
TALIESIN: You have a 27?
TRAVIS: My constitution is amazing. Fuck.
MARISHA: He's a fucking barbarian.
TALIESIN: Oh, I'm so fucked.
SAM: Does it do anything to him?
TALIESIN: Nope. It doesn't do what I was hoping it
was going to do.
That would've saved my goddamned life.
MATT: If he would've rolled low, that would've
saved you, probably.
TALIESIN: Yeah, if he had rolled low.
MARISHA: Does he take any damage?
TALIESIN: He takes 12 points of lightning damage.
What the fuck else am I going to do?
MARISHA: That's just Grog putting his finger in
the socket.
TALIESIN: I can run like a motherfucker. Let's
see.
TRAVIS: I had an action surge I forgot about last
time, so consider this borrowed time.
MATT: Technically, you had advantage on your
attacks against him because he used reckless.
TALIESIN: But I can't use my gun, can I? Oh wait,
I would've had advantage, but I didn't get
advantage on the--
MATT: You would've had advantage, so the two
attack rolls we'll say were one attack.
TALIESIN: I can't hit him with my gun, but I can
still hit him with my sword.
MATT: Well, you can hit him with the gun. You just
have disadvantage with the strikes, but you have
advantage, so it would be just a straight roll.
TALIESIN: Okay. So I have two more sword attacks,
and then I've got to figure out some shit. Let's
take two--
LAURA: Wait, you have four attacks?
TALIESIN: I have three attacks. But I had
advantage, so technically that was one attack.
LAURA: Oh!
TALIESIN: So I'm going to take two sword attacks.
TRAVIS: Come on, man. You got this.
TALIESIN: No, I don't. That's a 27 piercing.
MARISHA: Wait, are you rolling damage?
TALIESIN: No, I'm sorry. That's to hit. I'm sorry,
my brain is-- you're scaring me. 25 to hit and 21
to hit, so both hit?
MATT: Both hit, yeah.
SAM: Most of your war paint is gone, by the way,
Travis.
MARISHA: How did that happen?
TRAVIS: I absorb things that make me stronger.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: (counting) 22 points of piercing
damage.
MATT: Okay, so 11 points piercing damage, Grog.
TRAVIS: Thank you.
TALIESIN: And I'm going to burn an action surge.
You can't use an action to disengage unless you
have it. I'm just fucked, aren't I?
MATT: Correct. You can still run, but he gets to
swipe at you.
TALIESIN: I'm going to take my heal with that
action surge. I'm going to heal up.
MARISHA: Going to hold down the fort? You're
looking down the barrel, man.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I know. That's awful. 14 points of
healing, but it'll get me away.
TRAVIS: Can I take my retaliation strike?
MATT: Yes, you can.
SAM: Oh no.
TRAVIS: 26?
TALIESIN: 26 to hit? Hits.
MARISHA: So fucking nonchalant, like he doesn't
know.
TRAVIS: 24.
TALIESIN: 24. Okay. That's his reaction, so I can
run now.
TRAVIS: You may flee.
TALIESIN: Oh. Well, that's fine.
MATT: (laughs) You can flee.
TRAVIS: Or you can stand here and face it, like a
man.
TALIESIN: Yeah, you'll be laughing when I'm far
away from you. I've got to get some distance. I'm
going to start running straight up the tower.
MARISHA: He can still hit you if you run.
TRAVIS: I already did.
MATT: (counting) That's as far as you can get with
your movement.
TALIESIN: That'll do.
SAM: Is there an entrance to the tower there?
MATT: There's two doors and a ladder.
TALIESIN: I don't need a ladder, though.
MATT: No, you can run up the side.
TALIESIN: I don't want to go around that wall. I
want to go up that wall.
MATT: Up this wall?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: So you're right there.
SAM: Cat on a hot tin roof.
MATT: That's your turn, Percy?
TALIESIN: That's the end of my fucking turn.
MATT: The electrical towers at the top cycle
(electricity noises) and flash with a bolt of
energy. Nobody is in the radius to be affected; no
effect. That brings us to Vex. Up at the top, as
you flew up there on the broom, you felt your head
and shoulders bump and hit the ceiling, and you're
like, shit. Arrows ready.
LAURA: Welp. I can see Percy, so I'm going to
Hunter's Mark him.
TALIESIN: All right.
LAURA: And then I'm going to attack him.
SAM: The love of your life. Bathtub buddy.
LAURA: This first attack. Well, let's see. Oh
yeah, that hits. Yeah, that definitely hits, 31.
And it's a bramble shot.
MATT: Okay.
(laughter)
LAURA: So you have to roll a strength DC.
TALIESIN: I have to roll a strength check against
bramble?
MATT: First, roll damage for everything.
LAURA: For the regular?
MATT: For all of it.
LAURA: Oh right. Okay, wait. That's an additional
4d8.
TALIESIN: Shit. Yeah, no. I'm fucked, anyway.
SAM: Maybe not.
TRAVIS: Hey, man. Better to be done by your lover
than by me. I left that action surge out.
TALIESIN: Oh, I have another action surge that I
didn't-- I was hoping.
LAURA: (adding) 38, plus six lightning damage.
TALIESIN: 38 plus six lightning damage? And then
I'm going to take... ugh, this is the worst I've
ever rolled in my life. 38 plus six lightning. I'm
going to bring that down to 25 points of damage.
MATT: From?
TALIESIN: From the Gloves of Missile Snaring. So
38 down to 25. Plus six lightning damage?
Still alive.
MATT: As you're on the wall, you feel the sense,
this burning in your ears, and you glance up just
as you watch an arrow (arrow sound) come towards
you and as it bursts open, this series of tendrils
of vines, you reach over and grab and stop the
arrow, somewhat, before it pierces into you, but
you still manage to pull it back and the vines
begin to ensnare around you. Go ahead and roll a
strength saving throw, I believe?
TALIESIN: 16?
MATT: DC 17. They (whoosh) wrap around you and you
find yourself--
TALIESIN: Actually, this is better. I'm so sorry.
Strength saving throw, 22.
MATT: That does succeed. So as they wrap around
you, you (strained grunting) and burst off of them
and the arrow breaks out and they all turn gray
and wither into dust as they hit the ground.
LAURA: You're so strong, darling. I'm so
impressed.
Right as I throw another arrow at him.
(laughter)
LAURA: That's a 25 to hit.
MATT and TALIESIN: That hits.
LAURA: I'm going to do another... no, I'm not. I'm
not going to do a bramble shot on him. I'm just
going to do a regular shot.
TALIESIN: No, it's smart.
LAURA: Well, yeah, he's taking half damage.
TALIESIN: I'm bleeding out. I'm just blood.
LAURA: Oh wait, do you only get to use the catch
once?
TALIESIN: Once per turn. It's a reaction.
LAURA: 12, 14, 16 plus six lightning damage.
TALIESIN: I'm out.
MATT: You fall unconscious and off the wall,
hitting the ground. You take three points of
bludgeoning damage as you hit, which is an
immediate failed death save.
TALIESIN: Are we doing death saves?
MATT: Oh yeah, that's part of this.
MARISHA: So you could theoretically recover and
come back.
MATT: Yeah, if you roll a natural 20 on your death
save. It's happened before.
LAURA: Fuck, okay. Those are my two attacks, so
can I fly down to the ground behind the
building... actually, they're all over on the
other side. I'm going to drop down where I am.
MATT: Okay. Drop down to the roof?
LAURA: Yeah, to the roof. And I'm going to lay
down on the roof and use my bonus action to hide.
MATT: Okay, you lay down on the roof, using your
bonus action to hide.
Go ahead and roll a stealth check.
LAURA: 27.
MATT: 27. As far as you know, no one has any idea
where the hell you are. All right, that ends your
turn. Grog, you're up.
TRAVIS: I see Vex...
MATT: You watch her (descending noise).
TRAVIS: But she was shooting at my quarry. I turn
the corner towards where Percy is.
MATT: As you lumber around, you go and see his
unconscious body there, on the ground.
TRAVIS: (gasps) Percy von Fredrickstein de blah,
skittles and balls and ass. What happened?
TALIESIN: He burns an action doing this, I
assume.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Spin the hammer, right down on his head.
MATT: Okay, you move in. That's ten more feet. Go
ahead and roll, with advantage.
TRAVIS: (laughing) That's a 32.
MATT: All right. It's an auto-crit because it was
within five feet. How do you want to do this?
TRAVIS: I start to swing down. Did he get new
glasses? I take them. (heavy impact)
(laughter)
MATT: The whole face caves in as the hammer
scatters him like a Gallagher watermelon across
the stone floor.
TRAVIS: Oh, I can see very well.
(laughter)
MATT: Percival is no more. First to fall.
TRAVIS: How much speed did I use?
MATT: Five, ten, 15, 20.
TRAVIS: 20.
MARISHA: And the sound of the first cannon.
TRAVIS: Can I use my bonus action to leap, with
the feral leaping, 20 feet toward the tower?
MATT: Toward the tower this way?
TRAVIS: Entrance, down.
MATT: Yeah, if you want to. Go ahead and roll for
that.
TRAVIS: 21.
MATT: You land (grunt, impact noise) right toward
the base.
TRAVIS: Can I use the remainder of my speed to run
up the tower?
MARISHA: And he's still on fire, right?
TRAVIS: Yep. Oh, I need to take the fire damage.
MATT: That's true. Last round, or just this one?
TRAVIS: Just this one. I took it last time.
MATT: That's five fire damage, reduced to two.
TRAVIS: Two. On fire.
MATT: And you disappear into the center of the
tower.
TRAVIS: 20 feet in?
MATT: You get partway up the stairs.
TRAVIS: Is it a winding thing?
MATT: Yeah, it's a spiral staircase. All right,
that ends your turn, Grog. Keyleth?
MARISHA: Okay, I saw Vex shooting Percy?
MATT: No, you were inside the cusp of this
building the entire time. Glancing around there,
you saw her up there, and make a perception
check.
MARISHA: Okay. 20. No, 21.
MATT: 21. You got the gist. You watched her
descend, but you have no idea directly where she
is. You know she's somewhere in this area.
MARISHA: Okay. So I don't see anyone?
MATT: You know where she is. If you have an area
something you want to do, you could probably hit
her, but you can't aim a specific attack directly
at her because you can't see her.
MARISHA: Okay. I am going to start by moving my
fire ball. Jeez. There's not a lot I can do. I saw
Grog run by, as well, correct?
MATT: You saw Grog run by this way, and that's the
last you saw. And you know that Vex is somewhere
in this area. What do you want to do?
MARISHA: I'm going to move out and around on this
side, my movement over here.
MATT: You're there.
MARISHA: I'm going to go ahead and use my bonus
action to heal a little bit more. Actually, no,
can I use my action to heal like last time and use
my bonus action to move my sphere?
MATT: Sure. Yeah, okay, go for it. Technically...
yeah, it's fine.
MARISHA: I'm going to do 1st-level. Five. Okay.
And then I'm going to move my sphere right in
front of the doorway.
MATT: 30 feet for the sphere?
MARISHA: Yeah, however far it can go.
MATT: There, that's as far as it can get right
there. Okay, that ends your turn, Keyleth?
MARISHA: Do I have any more movement? I'll pop
back in the building a little bit, and that's it.
MATT: All righty. Taryon, your turn.
TRAVIS: How many rounds is this? Four? Five?
LAURA: This is the sixth round.
SAM: This is the fifth round.
LAURA: This is the fifth round. After this will be
the sixth.
SAM: Invisibility. And I want to fly out of the
sphere and to a vantage point of your choosing, so
no one knows where I am, somewhere between 20 and
40 feet high, maybe towards the center-ish of the
game field. Up to you where.
MATT: Okay, I know where you are. That's your
turn?
SAM: Yes.
MATT: Okay, Taryon.
TRAVIS: Do you know where?
SAM: No, I don't want to know where I am so you
don't know where I am.
LAURA: It's smart.
(laughter)
MATT: No longer Percy's turn. So with that, the
braziers--
SAM: And Matt. Away from the things that blow up.
Was that understood?
MATT: Right, yes. And all the braziers flare up.
Don't affect anybody. That brings us to Vex.
LAURA: I'm going to take off from the roof and try
to make it to the opposite tower.
MATT: The opposite tower, flying over here?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: You make your way there.
LAURA: Can I see anything?
MATT: Make a perception check.
LAURA: 20.
MATT: Yeah, you see the flickering flames of
Keyleth within the inside, in the very cusp of
this. She has three-quarters cover, but you have
sharpshooter, so you ignore that.
LAURA: Well, then I'll try to hit her. I'm going to
attack her! That's a 27.
MATT and MARISHA: That hits.
LAURA: Eight plus five is-- no, is it? No. 13? 15,
plus four lightning damage.
And then I'm going to do it again.
MATT: 17 points of damage.
LAURA: I'm going to do a bramble shot on her,
because I only did the one. 25 to hit.
MATT: 25 to hit? That hits. Damage?
LAURA: (counting) 32, plus three lightning
damage.
TRAVIS: 35, damn.
MATT: As the brambles wrap around her, the flames
burn them away. She's immune to being restrained.
LAURA: Yeah, I figured. I bet Tary's up here, but
I don't know that. I'm going to use my bonus
action to hide. I was hidden at the beginning of
the turn, but I'm assuming my movement took me out
of hiding. Can I use my skirmisher's stealth to
choose a quarry to stay hidden? Or I have to be
hidden at the top of the turn?
MATT: At this point, yeah. We're skirting a line,
here, of watching you go up and land. You aren't
amongst trees in a forest. It's easy to see where
you are, vaguely.
LAURA: Okay, I'm going to hide.
MATT: Roll a stealth check.
LAURA: Only 18.
MATT: Okay, good to know. That ends Vex's turn.
Grog!
TRAVIS: Right. I don't see any immediate chests in
this big tower, right? It's just a stairwell?
MATT: No, it's just stairwell. Like when you went
through the other one, it's empty, more of a
gaining of ground and/or protective space.
TRAVIS: All right. Live and let die,
motherfuckers! Can I run out of the tower,
straight towards the pool of acid?
MATT: You got ten feet in, so ten feet out. You still
have 40 at the doorway. There's a Flaming Sphere
there, which you're like, "oh, avoid!"
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'm aiming to try and make my way to
this structure.
MATT: 25, 30, 35, 40. You're just stepping over
the corpse of Trinket.
TRAVIS: Lovely.
LAURA: Oh, I forgot he's just unconscious. He's
not dead yet. I haven't been making saving throws
for him.
MATT: He's doing okay for now. Grog, that's your
movement.
TRAVIS: I raise my hammer as I get to Trinket. I
don't give a shit about Trinket.
What square am I on?
MATT: You're technically right here. You have your
action, still. You can dash if you want to get all
the way there, or you can attack something in the
vicinity. What do you want to do?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'll dash.
MATT: (counting) You get inside here and see a
small chest by the doorway there.
TRAVIS: Can I move to the chest?
MATT: You can move to the chest, but it'll take an
action to open it.
TRAVIS: Can I use my action surge, which I have
not used, to open the chest?
MATT: Yes, you can. You do. You open it up, and
there is a potion bottle within it. So you acquire
the potion. You open the chest and you grab the
potion.
TRAVIS: Right, and I can't do anything else? Can I
consume it?
MATT: You have your bonus action, still, right?
TRAVIS: Yeah! That's right. Chug-a-lug, bitches.
MATT: So 4d4 plus four.
TRAVIS: Gimme some squares. No, 4d4. I need some
triangles.
MATT: You also take six points of fire damage,
reduced to three.
Because you're doing this while on fire.
TRAVIS: Yeah. 4d4 plus four. 14 points. That's my
turn.
MAT: Okay, Grog's done. Keyleth?
MARISHA: Okay. (grunts) Going to go ahead and drop
my fire elemental form. It's looking pretty rough
now. Hope I don't fuck that up. And I'm going to
peek around the corner and I can see
Vex a little up on the tower.
MATT: Make a perception check.
MARISHA: Don't fuck me, Gil, don't fuck me! Oh,
that's good! 29.
MATT: You glance up the tower, and you see just
the edge of Vex trying to hide around the
stonework. You see her feather and the edge of her
hair, and you see her right up on the top.
MARISHA: I'll be like, (yelling) your blue feather
is very pretty against the stonework!
LAURA: We have earrings, dear.
(laughter)
MARISHA: I yell it through the earring, and it
deafens her a little bit. (yelps) Ow, feedback.
LAURA: Do I hear Tary go (yelps) anywhere?
MATT: No.
MARISHA: And I'm going to take my Spire of
Conflux, and just to be sure, I'm going to call a
Fire Storm down and blanket the tower, and I want
to go down a little bit. So here's what I want.
I want this.
MATT: The Fire Storm down the side? How many cubes
is it?
MARISHA: Rain fire down everywhere.
MATT: That's nasty. Okay, Fire Storm. Ten ten-foot
cubes.
MARISHA: Because I don't know where Tary is. I
haven't seen him in a while.
MATT: You could even get to Grog, if you wanted
to.
MARISHA: It's a fire waterfall.
MATT: Yeah, it is. It's very Minecraft. (fire
noises) All right, I need you to go ahead and make
a dexterity saving throw, Vex. And Marisha, roll
7d10.
LAURA: Oh my god.
TRAVIS: 7d10?!
MATT: Yeah, that's the damage of Fire Storm, man.
LAURA: 20.
MATT: What's your DC?
MARISHA: Well, my spell DC is 20.
MATT: So you succeed, so half damage. Just barely
succeeded.
MARISHA: I get to reroll ones. Do you have one
more?
TALIESIN: Yeah, in my bag.
MATT: The front doors, by the way, of this tower?
Are now on fire. The wooden doors at the bottom
have now caught flame from the Fire Storm, and
you can see elements of the inside the tower are
starting to catch fire, too.
TRAVIS: Shit, so the passage through them
would...
LAURA: How many? 10d10?
MATT and MARISHA: 7d10.
MATT: And you get to reroll ones once because of
your staff.
MARISHA: No ones, but it's a pretty good roll.
(counting) 26.
SAM: 27.
MARISHA: (continues counting) 52.
MATT: So you take 26 points of fire damage.
LAURA: All right.
MARISHA: Was Tary in there, at all?
MATT: No.
MARISHA: Fuck!
TRAVIS: He was?! Or he was not?
MATT: No.
SAM: I honestly have no idea.
TRAVIS: When you moved, you said, "I go to you
know where?"
SAM: No, I said, you pick me a place. I don't want
to know.
LAURA: He knows where, but nobody else does.
MATT: Based on your specifications and the movement
of the broom, yes. I know where you are.
MARISHA: And I'm going to take my bonus action. I
know Grog ran vaguely in this direction, so I'm
going to take my 30 feet of movement of my Flaming
Sphere and move it toward that tower that Grog is
towards. Yeah, is that 30 feet?
MATT: Yeah, it's 30 feet there.
MARISHA: And then I'm going to pop back into
cover, hug against the wall.
MATT: All righty, that brings us to Taryon!
SAM: Hi. I lose Invisibility if I cast a spell.
MATT: Yes, or attack something.
SAM: Or attack something. Does drinking something
count as casting a spell?
MATT: Nope.
SAM: I will drink a Swift-Step Draught, increasing
my walking speed now to 60, plus my Boots of
Speed, which makes it 120.
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: I'm the fastest motherfucker on the planet.
MATT: Well, next to Vax. Not on the broom, though.
It's your walking speed.
SAM: No, I know. Just for future rounds, would
dropping a Smoke Stick count as an attack? It
doesn't hurt anyone; it just makes some smoke.
MATT: No.
SAM: What about dropping a Tanglefoot Bag?
MATT: That's starting to borderline on an attack.
SAM: Okay! I just want to know my options here.
All right, cool. I think that's it.
MATT: You're not too sure. You can try it.
SAM: The speed thing. And oh, can you just tell
me, without telling me where I am, do I know the
location of Keyleth?
MATT: Yes.
SAM: Okay. And do I know the location of
everybody?
MATT: Yes. You watched Grog run past, you watched
Vex get set fire in a tower, and you watched
Keyleth cast the spell and then disappear inside
the room.
SAM: Okay.
TALIESIN: Is Vex on fire again?
MATT: She's not caught fire, but you watched
flames consume her briefly. (laughs) It seems to
be a theme.
SAM: All right, just move me around.
MATT: Okay. That's your turn, Taryon. All right,
top of the round. The arcane towers burst. I need
you to make a dexterity saving throw.
LAURA: Motherfuck. Oh, that's great; that
definitely saves. 30.
MATT: 30? Okay, that would be 11 points of
lightning damage, reduced to five.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: All right. Vex, your turn. As the flames
subside, you're like (pants). You glance over and
you can see Keyleth vanish back inside that room.
LAURA: (groans) But I can't see her? I can't see
anybody from where I am?
MATT: Currently, you have no view of her, but you
just watched her just barely step inside. You can
still get perspective if you were to move to get a
better angle.
TALIESIN: This board was designed to actually fuck
with the two of us, because we don't have any good
long-distance shots but they have nothing but
cover.
LAURA: There's nowhere for us to hide!
MATT: There's plenty of places for you guys to
hide. There's nothing but hiding places!
LAURA: No, I know. It's ground hiding. I'm going
to fly up towards you, Matthew.
MATT: Okay, over here?
LAURA: Yes.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: And I'm going to hover right there. Wait,
can I see Keyleth?
MATT: You can barely see Keyleth out of the side,
yeah.
LAURA: Okay, but three-quarters, and I can still
attack her?
MATT: Yes, because you have sharpshooter, so you
can attack her.
LAURA: Okay. I'm going to attack her. She's in
that building.
MATT: You get to about there. You can look down
and you see her poking out.
LAURA: I want to be low enough that at the end of
my movement I can drop down to the ground.
MATT: Okay, I see.
LAURA: I mean, drop down to the roof. Yeah.
MATT: Yeah, so we'll say you can be there. You can
get down to the roof and see her from there.
LAURA: (laughing) Yeah. That works, too! She's
still Hunter's Marked from before, isn't she?
MARISHA: Did you ever Hunter's Mark me?
MATT: You Hunter's Marked Grog, I thought.
LAURA: I Hunter's Marked Percy.
MATT: Percy. That's what it was. Yeah.
LAURA: Then I'm going to move my Hunter's Mark to
Keyleth.
MATT: Keyleth as a bonus action.
LAURA: Oh, wait. That's a bonus action, just to
move it?
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: Okay, then never mind. I'm not going to do
that.
MATT: I'm pretty sure it is.
LAURA: It probably is; I'm not going to do it.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: 26 to hit.
MATT: 26 hits.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: So you're not Hunter's Marking her?
LAURA: No.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: 16, plus five lightning damage. And I'm
going to hit her again.
MATT: 16 plus nine. Roll a concentration check.
With advantage.
MARISHA: Oh yeah. I'm good. I rolled a natural
19.
MATT: Yeah, you're fine.
LAURA: And the second attack is 30.
MATT: Hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
LAURA: 16 plus four lightning damage.
MATT: That's 20 points of damage. Go ahead and
roll another concentration check. Just roll higher
than a ten.
MARISHA: With my modifier, right? With my bonus?
MATT: Yeah, whatever your constitution saving
throw is.
MARISHA: Yeah, I'm good.
MATT: So maintains concentration.
LAURA: And then for my bonus action, I'm going to cast--
oh, wait, can I do that? No, it's not. Shitballs.
I was thinking I had a potion, but I don't, and I
can't cast a Cure Wounds. That's an action. And I
can't retrograde a Hex on her. So I'm going to try
to hide again, because that's the only bonus I can
do right now.
MATT: You don't really have any way to hide from
her right now.
LAURA: I'm going to drop down to the ground.
MATT: Okay, so you drop prone.
TRAVIS: Yeah, that's an angle you can hold.
MATT: There you go, we'll say.
LAURA: I don't have any movement. I used all my
movement just to get there.
MATT: Yep.
LAURA: Tight. Because there's no such thing as
Fire Storm, which just fucking destroyed me. No
such thing.
MARISHA: Nope. Don't have any more of those.
LAURA: Maybe I'll roll a natural 20 and then
she'll just not know that I dropped down. I rolled
a natural 20!
TRAVIS: Fucking right, she did.
LAURA: Does it matter at all that I rolled a
natural 20?
MATT: You watched her vanish. You know she's
somewhere on or near that roof, but you're not
specifically aware. So that ends your turn. Grog?
TRAVIS: Yeah. Can I step out of the room? Can I
use as my bonus action my Boots of Feral Leaping
to jump 20 feet horizontally towards the building
that Vex is on? Straight line towards the door.
Straight up.
MATT: Roll for that.
TRAVIS: That's a 22.
MATT: 22, yep. You actually land on Doty's head,
crushing it into the ground.
TRAVIS: Can I use the remainder of my 50 feet of
speed to run into the building that Vex is in?
TALIESIN: He is being so smart.
MATT: That's the rest of your movement, there.
TRAVIS: Right there?
MATT: Yeah. You can dash if you want to move all
the way in, but you won't have an action.
SAM: You can still touch the building.
TRAVIS: Damn, I thought that was going to be just
enough. I am going to dash inside.
MATT: Okay. So you head inside, and you get to the
appearance of this.
SAM: You're too big for the ceiling.
MATT: You get in there, and there is the chest
there, yeah.
TRAVIS: Great. That is my movement.
MATT: That's your turn?
TRAVIS: Yes.
SAM: Did you drink the potion that you found? What
was it?
TRAVIS: It was a greater.
SAM: Oh, cool.
MATT: All right. That ends your turn. Keyleth?
MARISHA: Oh god. I don't know what to do.
MATT: Yeah, you just got shot twice, and you're
(gasps). You pull back inside and you're (gasps).
You glance outside and you hear (heavy footfalls).
You have no idea where Vex is at the moment. The
last you saw her, she was on the roof, and you
watched Grog dart by without seeing you and then
run into the building right across the way.
MARISHA: Okay. All right. Fucking hell.
TALIESIN: I know. It's a horrifying piece of
paper.
LAURA: I have to pee so bad.
TRAVIS: Go now.
LAURA: No, what if I die?
MATT: What are you going to do, Keyleth?
MARISHA: Okay. Fuck. Fuck! What am I going to do?
MATT: What are you going to do?
TALIESIN: Do something crazy.
MARISHA: If I do a Fire Storm around there, can I
also call on the inside of the room, as well?
MATT: Yeah. It's just making them adjacent to each
other. That can be in height, too, yeah. As long
as they're against a surface.
MARISHA: Yeah, fuck it. Let's do that again. Pop
out once again from the spire,
(war cry) coming down.
MATT: Okay. So how many points has that spent on
the spire?
MARISHA: I only did it once, so that's seven, so
that brings me to another seven, so I have six
points left in the spire.
MATT: There you go. You're causing it to consume
the entire roof?
MARISHA: Yeah. And because I heard Grog run in
that area, too.
MATT: Yeah, so you can just fill the roof and then
down the side and then fill the inside.
MARISHA: I'm just lighting up that tower.
MATT: All right, so I need both Grog and Vex to
make dexterity saving throws.
TRAVIS: That might be all she wrote. We'll find
out. I have advantage on these. That's not
awesome. That's better.
LAURA: 25.
TRAVIS: 19?
MATT: 19 does not make it. So roll 7d10 fire
damage. You take half of it because you're
resistant.
LAURA: Well, that's good.
TRAVIS: I've also been hit a lot. I don't like
getting that close.
SAM: What just fell all over the floor?
MARISHA: That was one of my dice. I re-roll ones.
Okay.
LAURA: What did you just do?
TRAVIS: Acted like I pushed you off.
MARISHA: I rolled two tens, so that's 20. Two
eights, so that's 36. 41. 44. One, two, three,
four, five, six, 44 plus seven is 51. One, two,
three, four, five, six, seven. 7d10.
MATT: Yep. 51 points of fire damage to you Grog,
halve that to 25.
TRAVIS: 25.
MATT: Still conscious?
TRAVIS: Yes.
MATT: Good. Vex, you take the same thing. 25
points of fire damage.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: So that's your attack.
MARISHA: For my bonus action, I want to bring my
Flaming Sphill to block this doorway that I'm in
front of.
MATT: The Flaming Sphere?
MARISHA: Yep.
LAURA: Sphill. The Flaming Sphill is what she
said, and that is what it forever will be called.
MATT: The Flaming Sphere hits there.
MARISHA: Okay, and then I want to move back and...
fuck. Around here, on the outside, and hide. Did
you get where I said?
MATT: Yeah, you're right. So yes.
MARISHA: I want to go on this side of the building
to use for cover.
MATT: So you get there.
MARISHA: Perfect. And then I don't have anything
else I can do, do I?
SAM: Well, you did everything.
MARISHA: That's it.
LAURA: Oh, I only called a giant Fire Storm!
MARISHA: Can I also hide?
MATT: No, you spent all your actions. They're well
aware of where you are; they watched you
(footsteps) around the corner. You hear (heavy
breathing) around the wall.
MARISHA: Fuck, I hope that wasn't a mistake.
MATT: That finishes Keyleth's turn. Taryon.
SAM: I assume, because you know me, Matt, and
you're a skilled strategery man, that I am
somewhere near Doty?
MATT: You could, with your movement, reach him.
SAM: I'll hover near him, over him-- but not right
over him, everybody! And just chuck that Smoke
Stick right on him.
MATT: Okay. (hissing gas) What's the radius of
that?
SAM: It's only a ten-foot radius.
MATT: Yeah, so there's a 20-foot area here.
Keyleth's the only one that can see it out of the
corner of your eye. You watch as where Doty's body
is, suddenly smoke fills this area here, obscuring
Doty's currently not moving body. That's your
turn?
SAM: That's it.
TRAVIS: So wait, where did you go?
SAM: I don't know, actually. I'm in the air,
somewhere within a 30-foot circle of Doty.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: If this is going to continue, I want you to
tell me where you're going, just to come over and
whisper to me. Otherwise this is getting a little
weird. For the first round, it's fine, but...
TALIESIN: Start texting.
MATT: Yeah, you can text me if you want to, or
come by and whisper real fast. All right. That
brings us to top of the round...
MARISHA: Is anyone still on fire, like Grog?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I am.
MARISHA: Another ten.
MATT: You did take ten damage, reduced to five.
All righty. So the towers (vibration) begin to
extend that vibration again, and the gravity
begins to converge and condense around each of
these towers once more. All righty. Vex, you're
up. You're on your back right now, going (groans).
A little bit of smoke (coughs) out of the mouth.
LAURA: If I flew up to the top of the tower,
nobody would see me that I know, right?
Right now?
MATT: That you know of.
LAURA: Okay. Then I'm going to fly up to the top
of the tower by me. But I'm going to be at the
back. I'm going to step away from the edge so that
people on the ground can't see me.
MATT: Okay, about there.
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: That's as far as you can get with your full
movement.
LAURA: Okay, and I'm going to use my action to
cast Cure Wounds at 3rd level.
MATT: Okay, go for it.
LAURA: Which is 3d8. 15, plus my spellcasting
modifier, which is 18 points. So I heal 18 points
of health.
MATT: 18 points of health to you. All right, got
it.
LAURA: And then I'm going to use my bonus action.
MATT: Trinket's still doing okay. Succeeded two.
LAURA: Oh, okay. I can't go down there. Before I
moved, can I have cast Hunter's Mark on Keyleth,
for my bonus?
MATT: You didn't have visual on her at that time.
LAURA: I still don't have visual? Do I have visual
on her now?
MATT: Not since you moved away from the edge. You
moved out of the way to make sure
nobody could see you.
LAURA: Can I say I moved up, cast Hunter's Mark on
her, and then backed off?
MATT: Sure, yeah. She wasn't hidden. So she's
marked.
LAURA: Okay, and that's it.
MATT: Okay, that's the end of your turn. Grog?
TRAVIS: All right. Can I use my bonus action to
take the healing potion in that room?
MATT: You haven't opened the chest yet. So your
action (bang) open the chest. Grab the potion,
bonus action to drink it, yeah.
TRAVIS: 4d4?
MATT: 4d4 plus four.
LAURA: The chest wasn't on fire and the potion
wasn't destroyed?
MATT: The chest is burning, but you're already on
fire, so it doesn't affect you any more than it
would. But you do take two points of fire damage.
It was four, reduced to two,
because you're still burning.
LAURA: (laughing) You're still burning.
SAM: He's not wasting any actions to put himself
out?
LAURA: No. I love it.
MATT: It's very Grog.
TRAVIS: 15.
MARISHA: I know, I look fucking crazy.
MATT: You were Hunter's Marked, by the way,
Keyleth.
MARISHA: Fuck! Did I get hit?
MATT: No, just Hunter's Marked.
TRAVIS: Okay. And can I use my movement... to go
to this corner behind the wall?
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: He is loving that fire.
SAM: Oh shit! Does he see an empty ball sitting
there?
MATT: Yep!
SAM; The jig is up!
MATT: You run over and you see a giant, empty
hamster ball with a big window carved in it that's
empty and derelict.
TRAVIS: Empty?! That's my turn.
MATT: All righty. Keyleth.
MARISHA: Okay. Oh my god. This is so scary.
TALIESIN: You have that thing you can do.
MARISHA: I do have that thing I can do.
SAM: Oh, the Kill Everyone spell?
MARISHA: Yeah, that Kill Everyone spell... It's
time.
SAM: Oh god.
MARISHA: It's time.
TALIESIN: It's time. Yeah! I've been waiting for
it.
MARISHA: I am going to, thinking of the acidy
black pit in front of us, and remembering
Umbrasyl, I am going to turn into an adult black
dragon. (war cry) Full werewolf transformation.
TRAVIS: Are you serious right now?
MATT: So I don't have an adult black dragon mini.
We're going to use a red one,
but you are a black one.
MARISHA: And I burn my Shapechange.
MATT: Yeah. You are still Hunter's Marked, but
yeah.
MARISHA: I hope I don't die.
SAM: No, we got this. We got this.
TRAVIS: Do some shit!
SAM: I don't exist.
LAURA: Seriously! Just a bystander, this whole
fight.
MARISHA: I can move, right?
MATT: Yeah, you can still move.
MARISHA: So how deep is this watery pit? Does it
go pretty deep?
MATT: Only one way to find out.
MARISHA: I am going to, as a dragon, see how far I
can get. I'm going to go black dragon, who can
swim and is immune to acid. I'm going to go (heavy
footsteps) and see if I can lay underneath the
surface of the acid.
MATT: You delve into the pool with a splash as it
spills over the edges, and you submerge yourself
beneath the surface. It's just deep enough for you
to get entirely within the water.
LAURA: But all the acid pours up and out, doesn't
it? Displacement.
MATT: It displaces a bit, yeah. But while she's in
it, she's currently submerged.
TRAVIS: She's not hurt from it?
LAURA: Does Trinket get hit by the acid? But Doty
does, too.
MATT: Yep, both of them begin to just (sizzle).
Doty's done.
LAURA: Right. But just in case.
SAM: Oh. I thought he was immune, but he's not.
MATT: Nope. And Trinket begins to slowly dissolve
in his unconscious state. That is a second failed
death save on Trinket.
SAM: Doty's done?
MATT: Well, yeah.
LAURA: Keyleth doesn't care about animals,
apparently.
MARISHA: Nope.
LAURA: Only plants.
MARISHA: That's true. A little biased.
TRAVIS: At least finish him with dignity before
you go into the pool. You just passed right by
him. Just let him suffer, unconscious.
MARISHA: I mean, I could accidentally trip over
him and kick him into the pool with me, if you
really want me to.
MATT: Is that your turn, Keyleth?
MARISHA: That's it.
MATT: All right. Taryon.
SAM: Land in the smoke.
MATT: All right.
SAM: See that Doty is history.
MATT: Yes.
SAM: Fire Prismatic Spray at the dragon.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: You can't see me.
MATT: You're submerged in the water, but the spray
goes through water. It's a light effect. So you
grab one of your rubies, you run up to the edge of
the smoke, and release a Prismatic Spray in this
direction. Trinket's done. Trinket is turned to
dust and ash. We're talking Terminator 2 dream
sequence atomic bomb.
TRAVIS: It's all T2 tonight!
MARISHA: Question. Sorry, before we move too far.
Are people affected by my frightful presence
within 120 feet? Those who are aware of me once I
(heavy footsteps) and then go in.
MATT: That's an interesting point, actually.
MARISHA: 120 feet, wisdom saving throw.
MATT: Well, the only one who's seen you transform
is Taryon, so Taryon, I need you to go ahead and
make a wisdom saving throw, please.
SAM: Oh, that's not high for me. No, that's
terrible for me. Oh. I'm going to use Luck! I'm
going to use Luck.
TALIESIN: (cackles)
TRAVIS: They're both terrible?
SAM: One and a two.
TALIESIN: A two and a one, even better. He rolled
a two. He rolled again and rolled a one.
MATT: You are considered frightened. You watch as
Keyleth turns into this black dragon and you go
(screams) and watch her dive into the acid pool
and you go (screams).
SAM: So when I'm frightened, I just want to get
away, right?
MATT: Well, no. When you're frightened,
specifically, you have disadvantage on ability
checks and attack rolls, as long as you can see
them, and you cannot move willingly closer to it.
You can move away or adjacent, but you cannot move
closer to her. You make the saving throw at the
end of your turn.
SAM: I was not planning on it, anyway.
TALIESIN: But it does mean that you have
disadvantage on the attack.
SAM: But it's a spell.
MATT: It's a spell. It doesn't affect him at all.
So you still have to make a saving throw versus
Prismatic Spray.
MARISHA: Shit. What kind of a saving throw?
MATT: We'll find out here in a second.
TALIESIN: It could be anything. It could be
something you're downright immune to.
MARISHA: That's true. Come on, acid!
MATT: So I need you to roll a d8, please.
SAM: d8. Four.
MATT: Four. I need you to make a dexterity saving
throw as an adult black dragon.
SAM: They're probably pretty dexterous.
MARISHA: Well, they're big fatty dragons.
TRAVIS: Wow, that is really stereotypical.
MARISHA: Not great. Seven.
MATT: Nope. So you take 10d6 poison damage.
SAM: Poison! Poison for the win!
MARISHA: Poison.
SAM: I don't want to roll 10d6, so I'm going to
use one of those websites.
TALIESIN: Here's 10d6. One, two, three...
SAM: Then I have to do all the math.
TALIESIN: Here's ten. Here's ten right here.
TRAVIS: We've got calculators out, ready to help.
MATT: You earned this.
TALIESIN: All the ones that are not yours. Oh man.
Oh, that's bad.
SAM: 34. That's not that bad.
MARISHA: 34?
MATT: 34 points of poison damage to you. Make a
constitution saving throw.
TRAVIS: How many hit points does an adult dragon
have?
MARISHA: A lot.
TRAVIS: Like, triple digits?
MARISHA: Oh, that's a natural 19.
MATT: You rolled twice, though, didn't you?
MARISHA: I have advantage.
MATT: Oh, that's right, because you have that
feat. She has the Warcaster feat. So you're good.
TRAVIS: Why are we even in this fight?
SAM: I'm no longer invisible. But I am in a
protecty cloud.
MATT: You are. So Keyleth, while you're submerged
under the acid, all of a sudden there's a spray of
greenish light that coasts through the surface of
the water and beams across you, and you feel a
horrible poison take effect on your stomach and
internal system. You're like (groans). You saw it
burst forth from that cloud of smoke that had been
appearing on that side of the battlefield just
outside of the water.
MARISHA: Okay.
SAM: I used some movement to land. Do I have any
movement left?
MATT: With your walking movement, yes. You still
have 40 feet left.
SAM: Then I'd like to go...
MATT: You are currently here.
SAM: I'd like to go around to the back of this
wall back here. Yeah.
MATT: Okay. There you go.
SAM: And then I'll cast Sanctuary on myself.
MATT: As a bonus action? Okay. Sanctuary on you.
TRAVIS: God, really? Balls, wanker, ass.
MATT: All righty. That ends Taryon's turn.
SAM: I'm still in my sphere, everyone. Don't come
find me.
LAURA: I heard Grog yell "empty."
TRAVIS: Yeah, I did it loud.
MATT: You did, just in time for all the braziers
to go (puff, fiery explosion). I need you to make
a dexterity saving throw, Grog.
TRAVIS: I was like, it's the other ones before
the braziers. Shit, ass, nipples. 15.
MATT: 15? You take four points of fire damage,
reduced to two.
TRAVIS: Hey!
MATT: And you're set on fire, but you already
were.
(laughter)
MATT: All right. Vex, you're up.
LAURA: I know where Grog is. I'm going to step
over and attack him.
MATT: Okay, so you head over to the edge, glance
down, and you see the flames rescind from the
brazier, and there Grog is patting the side of his
arm. The flames are on his shoulders, but he's
putting it out on his elbow.
TRAVIS: Sounds right.
MATT: All right, go for it.
LAURA: Oh yeah. 30?
MATT: Yep.
LAURA: Okay.
TRAVIS: You're going to attack me over the giant
red dragon?
MARISHA: I'm under the acid, man.
LAURA: Yeah. 12 plus two lightning damage.
TRAVIS: So six and one. Seven.
LAURA: And then the second one definitely hits.
MATT: Okay. This is getting close.
LAURA: 16 plus one lightning damage.
MATT: So eight, plus one. Nine. Nine damage.
Okay.
LAURA: And for my bonus action, I'm going to-- oh
god. No.
TRAVIS: Stay.
LAURA: No, he can get up to me. I'm going to get
on my broom and I'm going to fly up! I'm going to
fly into the air for my movement.
MATT: You spent ten movement moving up to the side
there. You get on your broom, so you get up to
about... we'll say, for the purposes of this, you
can't get too high up here. You get about there.
LAURA: I don't want to fly up. I want to fly over.
I want to fly away from Grog. No, towards the
other brazier. Yeah.
MATT: You can get about there. A little bit over
to this side.
LAURA: Okay, I'm going to do that.
TRAVIS: About 15 feet up, you said?
LAURA: Oh god! You know what? Ooh, this could be
real bad.
MATT: That's what you're doing.
LAURA: Nope. I'm not. I'm thinking about it. I'm
going to fly. I'm going to be up, but I'm going to
stay over the roof. This is still stupid. I'm
going to die. Grog's going to kill me.
MATT: We'll say you're up there.
LAURA: But further over towards-- I want to hover
over the roof, but towards the other brazier.
MATT: Right. About here. I'm just putting you--
fine, I'll move it.
LAURA: Sorry. I got confused, Matt. I thought
that's where you were saying I was.
MATT: There you go. Roughly, that's where you
are.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: It's a lot to coordinate. That ends your
turn, Vex. Grog, you're up.
TRAVIS: I was going to leave you alone. I was
going to leave you alone! Fucking dragon sitting
in a big-ass pool of acid. Piece of shit! And then
the spiral's going to go off. Fuck it. I'm going
to-- yeehaw howdy. Can I go to the rope ladder?
How much does that take,
to get to the rope ladder?
MATT: The wood ladder here? That is five, ten,
15.
TRAVIS: 15. Can I use my Boots of Feral Leaping to
jump 15 feet vertically?
MATT: Yeah, go ahead and roll.
TRAVIS: That's all I need. 25.
MATT: You get halfway up.
TRAVIS: Can I use the rest of my movement
to climb up onto the turret
and move to the far end?
MATT: Yeah. You get up to right about there, and
you have ten more feet. This way? Okay.
TRAVIS: Can I see Vex?
MATT: Oh yeah.
TRAVIS: (whoosh)
LAURA: Hi, Grog.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Reckless, please.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: 25.
LAURA: Oh, it hits me.
TRAVIS: 19.
LAURA: Doesn't.
TRAVIS: No, that's the damage.
LAURA: Oh. Shit.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: That's a million. That's 34 to hit.
LAURA: Oh, 34 to hit.
MATT: Grog, you took another four points of fire
damage, reduced to two, from the fire.
TRAVIS: And the damage is 24.
LAURA: Oh god.
TRAVIS: Last one.
LAURA: Oh dear lord.
SAM: So the hammer keeps coming back, and he
throws it again? Oh, wow.
MATT: (throwing noises) It's nasty.
TRAVIS: That is a 25.
LAURA: Oh no! I think my math is wrong. Hold on.
TRAVIS: You did it right.
LAURA: Hold on, that doesn't make sense. 25, you
say?
TALIESIN: Points of damage.
LAURA: Oh no, I just dropped unconscious.
(laughter)
LAURA: I stayed over the roof.
MATT: You stayed over the roof. You fall prone.
You still take a point of bludgeoning damage,
which is an immediate failed save, so you've lost
one death save and you're unconscious there.
TRAVIS: And you're trapped up here with me.
SAM: He'll go easy on you.
LAURA: Yeah, I'm sure. Kill me quickly so I can go
pee, because I've had to for an hour now.
MATT: That end your turn, Grog?
TRAVIS: Yes, it does.
MATT: All righty. Keyleth. You don't know where
anybody is. You're in acid water.
MARISHA: I poke my head out. Do I see anything?
MATT: Perception check.
SAM: A bunch of smoke.
MARISHA: Okay. 21.
MATT: From this perspective? Not really. You do
see Vex go (thud).
MARISHA: Cool. I've got a good idea. I'm going to
fly up.
MATT: How far up are you going to fly?
MARISHA: How high is the tower? (stutters)
MATT: It's about 35 feet to the top. 35 feet to
the top edge.
MARISHA: I've got a flying speed of 80 feet, so
I'm going to go 40 feet up.
MATT: You see Vex unconscious on the ground there,
bleeding out of the side of the mouth, and you see
a giant Grog.
TALIESIN: On fire.
MATT: On fire, with the hammer pulling back. Grog,
you look over your shoulder and you see a big
black dragon (whoosh).
MARISHA: I look at him and I say in Draconic,
because I always forget. I go, Grog, check it out!
Grog, look!
MATT: The dragon goes (guttural growling speech).
MARISHA: I'm going to be like, sorry, but I've
always wanted to do this. (vomit noises) And do an
acid breath. 60-foot line, five-foot wide.
SAM: You're trashed.
TRAVIS: Fire elemental, back to Keyleth, into a
dragon?
LAURA: Come on.
MATT: To be fair, you guys focused on each other
for most of this fight.
TRAVIS: That's true.
MATT: I need you to make a dexterity saving throw,
Grog.
TRAVIS: Thank you. Thank you, sir. May I have
another? 17.
MATT: That does not succeed. Keyleth, I need you
to roll your 12d8 acid damage
that Grog's about to take.
LAURA: Oh, are you immune to acid damage?
TRAVIS: No.
MATT: Nor resistant.
MARISHA: I'll roll five and then I'll roll five
more. Actually, give me one more and I'll roll
twice. Get that out of there.
TALIESIN: And ones you reroll, right?
MARISHA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: (cackles)
MARISHA: 16, plus let's do these two twos, which
is four, which brings us to 20, plus another 12,
so that brings us to 32. And then I roll again.
32, plus another 14, which is going to be 46, plus
three, which is 49, plus another six, which is 55,
plus another eight and another seven. 55 plus--
TALIESIN: 70.
MARISHA: 70, total. Acid damage.
MATT: (guttural growling) There's a stream of acid
that sprays down the tower over you, Grog. Go
ahead and make your constitution saving throw.
SAM: Tary versus a dragon. This is Dragon Slayer.
TRAVIS: 21.
MATT: So as the acid sprays over Grog, Grog still
stands there, covered in acid and looks at you. It
puts out the fire.
MARISHA: Do you have one hit point left, or some
shit?
MATT: Barbarians have an ability where when they
go to zero hit points, they make a constitution
saving throw to resist going to zero.
LAURA: What is he at, then?
TRAVIS: One.
LAURA: Oh, okay.
MATT: But he's still standing as the acid is
(sizzling).
TRAVIS: But the fire's out!
MARISHA: The fire's out, which is ironic because
that means at the top of your turn you could have
theoretically died. With the remainder of my
movement--
MATT: Your Hunter's Mark is gone now. You have
your movement.
MARISHA: I still have more movement. Can I go, oh
fuck! in Draconic and go (boop) right back
underneath the acid?
LAURA: She basically pooped. That's what it
sounded like she did.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: How much movement do you have?
MARISHA: I have an 80 fly speed.
MATT: Into the water. You're mostly submerged
right now. Splashing in and out of the water, it's
displacing a lot of the acid. Your wings and your
back are still visible.
All right, that end your turn?
MARISHA: He doesn't have anything fighting against
three-quarters cover.
MATT: With that, Taryon.
SAM: Yeah. I'll be fine.
MATT: You watch this dragon fly up, spray acid
onto the tower,
and then disappear into the water below.
SAM: Out of curiosity, where and in what condition
is Percival's dead body?
MATT: You haven't seen him.
SAM: Great. Not even when I was in the sky?
MATT: When you were in the sky, you saw what
looked like a mess in really nice clothing, so you
saw Percival. The head was pumpkined. It was bad.
SAM: Okay, then.
TRAVIS: Are you checking on the state of Percy's
brain?
SAM: I might need to use it. Can I poke out this
corner?
TALIESIN: Is that getting closer to the dragon?
SAM: Is it?
MATT: Actually, here's the thing real fast. Let me
read this. Frightful presence. You repeat at the
end of its turn. Make another roll for the end of
your last turn I forgot to make you do.
SAM: That's a two again.
MATT: So in theory, you know the dragon's there.
You can't quite move closer to it, and that would
be considered closer, so you'd have to go around
this way.
SAM: Where's the door to the thing? It's right
there on the front, right? The door to the tower?
MATT: The door to the tower is right there, yeah.
SAM: That's away from the dragon.
MATT: It is, yeah.
SAM: I'll use my movement to go there.
MARISHA: Are you still invisible?
SAM: Nope.
MATT: You get there. You see the dragon as you
rush by. The smoke is still there.
SAM: I poke around the side of the smoke.
MARISHA: I'm like a Florida alligator right now.
MATT: You move past the smoke and the pillar.
SAM: And a quick little Prismatic Spray.
MATT: This Flaming Sphere is gone, by the way.
Forgot that. All right, so roll a d8.
TALIESIN: That's a d6.
SAM: Oh shit. Four again. It's the same.
MARISHA: Fuck!
MATT: All right, so go ahead and roll a dexterity
saving throw, Keyleth.
MARISHA: Nope. I think that's the exact same thing
I rolled last time.
MATT: So that's another 10d6 poison damage.
SAM: Should we call it the same?
MATT and TALIESIN: No.
SAM: I don't like to roll this many things!
TRAVIS: You're actually very fast.
TALIESIN: Two, four, six, eight, nine, and you
have one. There you go.
SAM: 35.
MATT: 35 points of fire damage to you.
TALIESIN: 35 points of poison.
MATT: Poison damage, yeah.
TALIESIN: I'm enjoying being the rules Nazi here.
MATT: Keyleth, make a constitution saving throw.
MARISHA: Don't fuck me, Gil. Don't fuck me. That's
good. That's even better. 24.
MATT: Yeah, you're fine. You maintain your
concentration. Okay, and?
SAM: Going into the tower. I have a bunch of
movement left, right?
MATT: You do, yeah.
SAM: I'll go into the tower.
MATT: You have your boots and the potion, so your
movement is 160?
SAM: 120.
MATT: 120. Yeah, you can go anywhere in that tower
if you wanted to. There's this floor, there's the
second floor, there's a third floor, and then
there's the hatch through the top.
SAM: Ooh, there's floors?
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: I'm going to go into the second floor, that
has those little...
TRAVIS: Yeah, the little slit windows?
SAM: Yeah. Is there any that can see the dragon,
or no?
MATT: This is a stairway, which blocks this.
Technically, that's just there, so you can fit up
into here, and you don't technically see the
dragon from that. You can glance over to the side
of here and poke your head through the stairs and
look and be like (whimpers).
SAM: I'll look, get a bead, and then just duck
back so no one knows where I am.
And also Sanctuary.
MATT: And also Sanctuary. One more. Sanctuary's
not there, since you used Prismatic Spray.
LAURA: I know, right?
MARISHA: Just hide.
LAURA: I mean, come on, that would've been the
absolute best thing to do.
TALIESIN: Just hide and be extremely inconvenient
to Matt.
TRAVIS: It is a strategy.
MARISHA: Yeah, you're called a dirty camper. A
camper! Like someone
who camps in first-person shooters.
SAM: That's me. That's exactly me.
MATT: All righty, so make a wisdom saving throw to
see if you can resist the frightened effect.
SAM: 15!
MATT: Plus?
SAM: Minus one.
MATT: Minus one? Nope. You're still frightened.
You're still like, "Oh god, dragon!"
LAURA: Damn, I wish my thing wasn't busted. I
would put him in the--
TRAVIS: I know.
MATT: All righty, top of the round. The pillars
once again (vibration) and begin to affect this
area around these pillars, beginning to call
gravity to the ground. All righty. That brings us
to... Vex, roll a death saving throw.
LAURA: Save.
MATT: Yeah, okay. Grog, your turn.
TRAVIS: Standing there, with one hit point, acid
melting my flesh, I would like to pull out the
Deck of Many Things.
MARISHA: Oh, you dick! You dick!
(laughter)
LAURA: He has the actual, Matt!
TRAVIS: I actually have this. It's blocked on the
back, and each card represents each one of them.
You can check it, if it's good.
MATT: Well, I'll have to pare down the deck, since
we don't have the full deck here. It's a half
deck. Where did you get this?
TRAVIS: I think that's... It was a gift from a
fan.
MATT: Oh man. I'm going to do this.
SAM: Thank you, Critters, for all the cool, useful
stuff.
TRAVIS: I also have to name a number of cards that
I would like to pull.
MATT: This is very true.
TALIESIN: I'm so sad I'm dead right now. This
would've been worth everything.
MATT: You may not be in a moment! Who knows?
TALIESIN: Good god.
MATT: Okay, so starting from here, we have...
TALIESIN: I'm so proud of you. This is the end of
Cabin in the Woods. I'm so impressed. Lighting a
cigarette at the end of the world.
TRAVIS: There's not a ton that could help me, but
fuck it.
MATT: Thanks for your patience, guys.
TRAVIS: No, take your sweet time.
SAM: What do we have in the store right now,
Laura?
LAURA: Oh, we have t-shirts...
SAM: What do they say on them?
LAURA: We have Gilmore's Glorious Goods, we have
Vox Machina t-shirts, we have How Do You Want to
Do This? t-shirts...
SAM: I feel like people should go to the store and get
stuff now, because when the 100th episode runs
around, some of those items might be dropped from
the store and replaced with new stuff.
LAURA: You never know.
SAM: I don't know, actually. I literally don't
know.
TALIESIN: He literally has no idea.
TRAVIS: It's not like we've been planning for a
100th episode or anything.
LAURA: No.
SAM: So if you want these items, you got to get
them now.
TALIESIN: We should totally do that. We should
plan something.
TRAVIS: We should. When is the 100th?
LAURA: It's in a couple weeks, right? Is that
enough time to plan anything? Two weeks from now?
We could throw something together, right?
MARISHA: I'll get a cake from Porto's.
SAM: That's it?
MATT: So Grog. How many cards do you want to
pull?
SAM: Five cards?!
MATT: (giggling) Five? Five cards?
TALIESIN: Yeah! Do it, I'm so proud of you!
SAM: It's chaos, and you're not even going to be
here to deal with it! I'm in a house with this
stuff! It's going to be me!
MARISHA: Tary versus many horrible things.
TALIESIN: No good, really bad day.
LAURA: Oh my god, it's going to be a grim reaper
that comes out and kills Grog immediately.
TRAVIS: Do you want to pick one for me?
LAURA: Can I? Okay!
TALIESIN: Oh my god. Choose the form of your
destroyer.
TRAVIS: Wait, keep it face-down when you pick it.
MATT: Okay. Five cards. Here, you guys got to
pick, all right.
TRAVIS: Okay, I get four, you get one.
LAURA: Okay!
TRAVIS: One, two...
MATT: Keep track of the order. The final one
there. Okay, so Vex is the last one.
SAM: We're never going to get that far.
TALIESIN: I'm so excited!
MATT: Okay. Grog, first card. What did you pull?
TRAVIS: Ruin.
SAM: End of game.
LAURA: What is Ruin?
TRAVIS: The picture is a cliff exploding and a
body flying off to his death.
SAM: That's literally what's about to happen.
MATT: Grog. Weirdly, not much happens to you that
you notice in the moment. At all.
TRAVIS: Great.
TALIESIN: Oh, I know how Ruin works.
MATT: Your Bag of Holding's fucking empty now, and
all of your non-magical items are gone.
SAM: Oh, you're just poor.
MATT: All of your personal wealth is gone.
MARISHA: What about his weapons and all of this
shit, too?
MATT: Magical items are not affected. It's
non-magical. You're no longer a Grand Poobah in
this temporary alternate universe. So that
probably was one of the better cards you could've
pulled. What's the second card, Grog?
TRAVIS: Rogue?
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: It looks terrible.
TRAVIS: An individual standing in front of a devil
with five swords going through his torso.
MATT: Okay, so no discernible effect at the
moment.
MARISHA: What?
LAURA: What does that one do?
MATT: But I'll say for the hell of it: Should you
survive this battle, it's going to be really rough
one day to have Wilhand stab you in your sleep.
TRAVIS: Oh, it turns somebody against you? All
right. Third card.
MATT: While you're sitting there, and you're
resting one night, Wilhand's like (growls).
TRAVIS: If I survive this, and I'm acid-melted and
laying there dying, and he walks up with a little
butter knife, I'll be like, do it! Just do it!
MATT: All right. Third card.
TRAVIS: Star.
LAURA: Oh, it looks good. It looks like a good
one.
TRAVIS: Which, it seems to be the opposite of
what's been happening, so maybe I'm fucked.
MATT: Increase one of your ability scores by two.
TRAVIS: Hey! Life score! Kill dragon score! Health
score?
LAURA: Intelligence!
MATT: You can increase your constitution by two.
TRAVIS: Let's do that.
MATT: Okay, so your hit points now go up by 17.
TRAVIS: That's important.
SAM: Does he have 18 hit points now?
MATT: Yes, he does.
MARISHA: Really?
MATT: Yeah, because it automatically increases his
modifier by one.
TRAVIS: I'm coming.
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: We'll see.
MATT: Fourth card?
TRAVIS: Key.
TALIESIN: Oh shit.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Is this a good one, too?
It looks good.
MATT: This is the one I thought you had pulled
originally. A rare or rarer magical item.
SAM: Oh, you get a cool thing!
LAURA: I hope I've cursed him! Please let me have
cursed him!
TRAVIS: I want the one that lets me succeed on my
next venture.
MATT: I'm going to roll randomly for this real
fast.
MARISHA: That one automatically succeeds at
something? Bring it, bitch.
TALIESIN: This is amazing.
TRAVIS: I should've just picked seven. I picked
five; that was good.
LAURA: Five is a lot. Five is as high as you can
count.
MARISHA: That's true. That's how many fingers you
have.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
TALIESIN: That's the highest number you really
know. Everything is just more fives.
MARISHA: Grog lives in intervals of fives.
MATT: A beautiful black and ivory-inlaid sword
shows up, a greatsword shows up in your hand. You
have to attune to it, unfortunately.
TRAVIS: Right. I got 30 minutes to waste. Just
sitting here melting.
MATT: And then, what's the next card?
LAURA: Oh no, this looks good, too.
TRAVIS: The Knight.
MATT: (giggles)
LAURA: Does he get a wish?
MARISHA: Did he get something stupid? He's going
to the bag.
SAM: You get a horse or something.
MARISHA: Grog becomes cavalry.
LAURA: Please be on top of the tower on a horse.
MATT: You look at the card for a second like,
"Huh, what does this do?" And you hear a voice go
(clears throat). You look to your side, and there
is a gentleman with armor and weapons who goes,
"Sir Grog! I am here to serve you! Whatever you
need, let me know! My life for Strongjaw!"
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Do you have any health potions on you?
MATT: "Oh, goodness, sir! Are you all right?"
TRAVIS: Things are very bad. It's dire stakes.
Kill the dragon.
MATT: "Dragon?"
TRAVIS: Yeah, dragon. Your courage is most
important at this dire hour!
MATT: Okay, you control this character. You tell
him whatever to do.
So you have a 4th-level fighter.
TRAVIS: 4th-level!
MATT: Yeah. However, he's the same race as you, so
he's a goliath in full armor.
TRAVIS: Hey! Sweet. Hold on, come here, I need to
draw some tattoos
on you to make you look like me.
MATT: All righty.
TRAVIS: Awesome.
SAM: The streak continues with Grog.
TRAVIS: Right. Okay. I have 18 hit points.
Everybody's alive. That's my turn.
LAURA: Can you move?
TRAVIS: Were any of those draw again cards?
MATT: Nope.
TRAVIS: Yeah, cool.
LAURA: Can you move?
TRAVIS: Oh, I can move, because I'm alive. I live.
At this moment.
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: I would like to go down the trapdoor.
MATT: Okay. What about your friend?
TRAVIS: Yes, with the friend. No! He's going to
stand up there. Just double birds. Out going like
this. And he has to go, "I am Grog!" The whole
time.
MATT: Okay, so you pull down the trap door once
again, and it's small in there.
How far down do you go?
TRAVIS: The second level.
MATT: You go down to the second level and as you
crawl down, you look and you see Taryon there,
looking out a window, looking very scared.
SAM: Where's your skin?
TRAVIS: (grunts)
SAM: (shrieks) No! It bounces off my Sanctuary!
MATT: You re-cast Sanctuary on yourself, right?
SAM: Yeah, I did.
MATT: All right, so that's your turn, Grog.
TRAVIS: That's it.
MATT: As your knight's double fingering towards
the... Gotcha. Whoa, this got weird. Okay.
Keyleth, it's your turn.
MARISHA: Okay, I'm going to come back out of the
acid. (war cry) What do I see? I look towards
where Grog was.
MATT: You look up and you see a goliath in full
armor just going...
MARISHA: (war cry) I'm going to fly over, and I'm
going to land on top of the tower, and I'm going
to do a multiattack against him. (heavy impacts)
And frightful presence. I don't know if that
affects an imaginary knight from a deck of cards.
MATT: It does! Go ahead and roll a wisdom saving
throw for the knight.
LAURA: Is that a 20?
TRAVIS: It's a three.
MATT: Jeez. He's like, "Dragon! Where--" (screams)
As you land next to him,
he's like (weak chuckle)
TRAVIS: Poor bastard. Into creation for, what, 30
seconds?
MATT: So full multiattack on this guy, you said,
right?
MARISHA: Yep, bite and two claws.
MATT: All right, go for it. Roll some attacks
here.
MARISHA: That's a natural 19 on the first one.
MATT: Okay, that'll hit.
MARISHA: So that's 30. Not so good on the second
one. That's 15.
MATT: Okay, 15 does not hit.
MARISHA: Okay, and then on the third, that's a
seven plus 11, so 18.
MATT: 18 does hit.
MARISHA: So two attacks.
MATT: Yep, two attacks hit.
MARISHA: So one bite and one claw, I guess.
MATT: Sure, go ahead and roll damage.
MARISHA: 2d10 plus six, plus 1d8 for acid damage.
Oh man, why does this keep happening to me? Okay,
11 plus seven is 18. Wait, let me make sure I'm
doing this right. No, plus six. 11 plus six, so
17, and then 1d8. Four. Okay, so he takes 18--
wait, what did I just say? 17 piercing damage, and
then four acid damage from the bite.
MATT: Okay, so 21 total. And then your next
strike, the claw?
MARISHA: Eight plus six is 12. 12 damage.
MATT: 12 damage. As you strike him (heavy
impacts), he's like (whimpers)
and he's still alive.
MARISHA: Okay, can I take the rest of my movement
to fly and hover above?
TRAVIS: Attack of opportunity.
MATT: Yes, you do get an attack of opportunity.
MARISHA: That's fine.
MATT: All right, so you hover above, we'll say
with your full movement, you don't get too far,
unfortunately, because you took, to get into that
space up there, would've been 70.
MARISHA: Would I get out of the sphere of the
electrical attack? Then no, I'll just stay there.
MATT: Okay. You stay there. Go ahead and roll an
attack for him.
TRAVIS: What do you think?
MARISHA: Does he get a retaliation attack?
MATT: No, if you're not moving, he doesn't. You're
right. Never mind. All right, so bringing it back
to Taryon.
SAM: Never thought it would come to this. I hold
up a diamond, and I point it at your face, and I
say, I will heal you if you swear you will not
stab me in the back.
TRAVIS: I swear. I want this dragon dead.
SAM: Insight check!
MATT: All right, roll an insight check.
SAM: That's pretty lousy. 11.
TRAVIS: I swear. Yes. Giant dragon.
SAM: Healing draught. 9d8.
MATT: Go ahead. You have to drink it on your turn,
but he hands it to you.
SAM: I can't use my action to pour it down his
throat?
MATT: Yeah, you can. You walk up to Grog, and
(cork pop).
TRAVIS: Give me these things.
LAURA: What do you want?
TRAVIS: 9d8! And who rolls them?
TALIESIN: Here's another question, when was the
last time you hit something?
TRAVIS: I have persistent rage.
MATT: He can maintain his rage as long as he
wants. High-level barbarians, man.
SAM: I will live... to regret this.
TRAVIS: No! No.
MATT: Well, there can be only one.
TRAVIS: 46. 46 plus 18.
SAM: That's pretty good.
MATT: So 54? No, 64. 64 health, I think you're
at.
TRAVIS: I'm at 64, yeah.
MATT: That's your turn. You can move, Taryon, if
you want to, or do you want to stay put?
SAM: I don't know what our plan of action is,
so... I can't go up, because I would be scared.
Do I have to roll for fear again?
MATT: Yes, at the end of your turn, you do. At the
end of your turn, though. If you're going to move,
move first.
SAM: I will move down to the bottom floor.
MATT: Okay, you get down to the bottom floor, and
you're right by the doors, which are now burned
down entirely. The wood has caught fire and
crumbled in.
SAM: I still have some movement, right?
MATT: Yeah, you have a shit-ton of movement.
SAM: I look up to see if I can see the dragon.
MATT: You see the edge of a wing going (whoosh).
SAM: A wing. I'm going to go to the north bunker.
MATT: Over here? Okay. With that, Taryon, you head
down through here and into this north bunker over
here. All right. Grog, you're technically in that
room there.
SAM: All right. And now I roll my fear?
MATT: Yes, now you roll your fear.
SAM: 16? 15. What do I have to roll to beat this
thing?
MARISHA: Yeah, you didn't roll high enough.
MATT: 18, I think it is?
SAM: Jesus, I'm never going to do it.
MATT: Only lasts a minute.
SAM: Oh, okay.
MATT: All right, that ends your turn, Taryon?
SAM: Yep.
MATT: The arcane towers (crackling) send out a
burst of energy. Roll a dexterity saving throw for
your knight friend, and you roll, as well.
LAURA: He's not dead?
TRAVIS: No. 18?
MARISHA: Oh, that's not that great. I thought that
was better. 15.
MATT: 18? He succeeds.
MARISHA: Goddamn it.
MATT: It would be 16 lightning damage. Instead, he
takes eight. I'll mark that here. He's hurt pretty
bad, but he's still hanging in there. What did you
roll?
MARISHA: 15.
MATT: 15. So you take 16 points of lightning
damage. Go ahead and roll a constitution check.
MARISHA: A lot. I'm good.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: That's a failed death save for me.
MATT: And... yeah. How many have you lost now?
LAURA: That's two fails.
TRAVIS: What is the point?
MATT: Now it's your turn. Go ahead and roll
again.
LAURA: Well, all right. One!
MATT: And with that, we'll say from a narrative
standpoint, as the lightning sparks out and it
hits Keyleth in her dragon form, she falls back
and her back foot (squelch)
accidentally smears Vex.
TALIESIN: That's going to be hard to clean up.
LAURA: No fate dice for us, Percy.
MATT: All right, so that's the end of Vex's turn.
Grog, you're up.
TRAVIS: I pull out the rest of the-- no, I run up
to the top of the tower.
TALIESIN: Fear?
MARISHA: He's immune to fear because barbarian and
raging.
TRAVIS: I ain't scared.
MARISHA: He ain't scared.
TRAVIS: It's absurd. And then she has all of her
hit points left.
MATT: So Grog, you get up to the top of the hatch
and you come out and you're right there next to
your goliath friend, in the face of this big
dragon. What are you going to do?
TRAVIS: I'm going to rush up to the giant red
dragon and go: Yo, Wilfred. This is how it's done,
lad. And I do all three attacks, reckless, at the
fucking dragon.
MATT: Okay. Go for it.
SAM: Reckless? You could kill the dragon in one
move.
TRAVIS: I don't think so. That's a 32?
MARISHA: To hit? Yeah. He could take me down.
TRAVIS: 24 on the first one.
MARISHA: Damage?
MATT: Before you roll damage on the next one, roll
another constitution saving throw for
concentration. Beat a 12.
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: Natural 20.
TALIESIN: You've had a few of those tonight.
TRAVIS: Okay, so that was a nine, so 25. That was
nine on the die.
MATT: You rolled a nine on the die. This is the
damage.
MARISHA: Oh, right.
MATT: So 18, plus your modifier.
TRAVIS: So that's 34.
MATT: Plus two additional dice for the weapon.
TRAVIS: That's right, yeah. Ten, plus a three.
47.
MARISHA: Total?
MATT: 47 points of damage to you. Roll another
constitution saving throw. You have to beat a 23.
MARISHA: As long as I roll over--
MATT: Constitution.
MARISHA: Oh, constitution?
MATT: It's not wisdom. It's constitution for
these.
LAURA: Have you been adding your wisdom modifier
this whole time?
MARISHA: My constitution's all right. I've been
rolling over the minimum, anyway. No. Nope.
MATT: Keyleth's form drops.
SAM: Oh shit!
MATT: The spell drops, losing concentration. Her
form reverts into regular Keyleth again. It wasn't
damage over. There's Keyleth in front of you. You
still have your third attack.
TRAVIS: I definitely think about kicking her off
the top of the tower.
SAM: Of course you do.
TRAVIS: I think the attack is better. Yep.
Reckless.
SAM: So many menu options.
TRAVIS: That hits. 33.
MATT: Okay. Go ahead and roll damage.
MARISHA: Why were you like, ugh?
You wanted a critical?
TALIESIN: Don't be greedy.
TRAVIS: I know. 27.
MARISHA: Damage total?
MATT: 27 damage to you, and your friend next to
you, who's no longer frightened because you're no
longer a dragon.
MARISHA: He doesn't get to attack, does he?
MATT: Yeah, he does. He attacks on your turn. He
gets two attacks with his greatsword. Go ahead and
attack twice for him. Plus five to hit.
TRAVIS: Plus five to hit. That's a 23.
MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: 24?
MATT: All right, so 2d6 plus three to each hit.
SAM: For the honor of Strongjaw!
MATT: I'll protect you, my lord!
TRAVIS: Ten, one. You said 2d6 plus one?
MATT: 2d6 plus three.
TRAVIS: Right, so that's 13 for the first one.
MATT: 13 damage.
TRAVIS: Six, seven. Ten.
MARISHA: So 23 total.
MATT and TRAVIS: 23 total.
MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: I thought he was going to be in and out in
a quick Pop Tart flash.
MATT: Ends your turn, Grog?
TRAVIS: Three attacks, bonus action. Can't do
anything. Yep.
MATT: Keyleth, you're up. Form has dropped. Grog
is looking healthier than you remember him.
MARISHA: Grog. We're friends, right? Remember me?
Come here. I'm going to grab him real quick and
I'm going to do Plane Shift.
TALIESIN: Whoa!
MARISHA: It's me, Keyleth! (grunts)
MATT: Roll a charisma saving throw. I think it's
charisma, right? Plane Shift is a charisma saving
throw. Grog, roll a charisma saving throw.
SAM: He's going to break this plane of existence,
too, and come back.
TRAVIS: It's a 19.
MATT: What's your charisma?
TRAVIS: Plus one.
MATT: So you rolled a 19?
TRAVIS: It's a 20 with a plus one, but I need a
natural 20, I know.
MATT: What did you roll on the dice?
TRAVIS: 19.
LAURA: Plus one.
MATT: That's a 20.
MARISHA: The 20 is what I had.
MATT: Yeah, so he saves.
MARISHA: You are lying to me. You are fucking
lying!
MATT: It's what he rolled!
TALIESIN: This is what's been happening all
night.
SAM: The plane of existence. You break it!
MATT: You resist the effect as Keyleth is holding
onto you, and she slowly lets go,
shaking a little bit.
TALIESIN: You have your bonus and your movement.
MARISHA: I have a bonus and a movement.
MATT: Yes, you do.
MARISHA: Okay. Oh god.
LAURA: Run away!
MATT: That's your 7th-level spell, gone.
LAURA: Plane Shift was her 7th-level spell?
MARISHA: Yeah, it was bad. I'm still all right. I
have a bonus and a movement. Okay. I'm going to...
take my bonus action to go oh, Grog! And cast a
Grasping Vine.
MATT: Grasping Vine is 4th-level. You can't cast
it.
MARISHA: Fuck! Okay. I will do... options are
dwindling very quickly.
LAURA: Tary will be the survivor because he's
hiding.
SAM: Why, because I haven't taken a single hit
yet?
MARISHA: I have Freedom of Movement still on me,
though. Does that aid me escaping?
MATT: Nope. Still gets a swing at you. Both of
them.
MARISHA: Okay. I'm going to do a bonus action to
heal myself. Healing Word. Let's do a 3rd-level
Healing Word.
MATT: 2nd-level Healing Word. You can't do more
than 2nd-level.
MARISHA: Sorry. You're right. 2nd-level Healing
Word. So it's 2d4. Oh my god.
TALIESIN: You are the luckiest motherfucker. This
has all been just--
LAURA: Why couldn't he have rolled like he did on
the one-shot, where
it was one after one after one?
MATT: I can't believe you made that fucking roll!
TRAVIS: I was like, aw, it has to be a 20. Yeah.
My charisma's plus one.
MATT: It's the hat. It's the feathered hat. It
pushes it just over.
MARISHA: 53. Okay. And then I'm going to-- fucking
hell, I'm really tapped out. Okay, my mantle
allows me to jump. My jump distance is tripled.
Does that mean I could successfully back up and
jump off the tower and potentially land safely?
MATT: Land safely?
MARISHA: How about this? I'm going to go, sorry,
Grog! And turn and run, and I'm going to do a
full-on ninja-style jump and see if I can land on
top of this roof?
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: Parkour.
MATT: Both you and your buddy get an attack of
opportunity on her.
TRAVIS: Reckless, for me. Buddy, first. That's a
23 to hit.
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: 2d6 plus three.
TRAVIS: Six.
MATT: Six points of damage to you.
MARISHA: Just six? Six from the knight. Okay, that
puts me at 46.
TRAVIS: 28 to hit from me.
SAM: That hits.
TRAVIS: 21 points of damage.
SAM: She's okay.
MATT: Keyleth, you turn, you run. Make an
athletics check, please.
MARISHA: Do I have advantage on this?
MATT: No.
MARISHA: I'm so bad at my athletics. I'm always
so bad! 12.
MATT: It's okay. You didn't have to roll high.
You'll get a decent distance, but your jump
distance is tripled because of your mantle, so you
do manage to make it and land on that roof. You
take four points of bludgeoning damage. I rolled
one, one, two.
MARISHA: Ugh, I fucking twisted my ankle.
MATT: Yeah, it hurt. It pops a little bit, but
you're there.
MARISHA: How much? Four points?
MATT: Four points, yeah. All right. That's your
turn, Keyleth? Taryon. You're way over here.
SAM: Fly out, fly up. Halfway up.
MATT: Halfway up? About there.
SAM: How does a cone work?
MATT: Cone? It's a cone outward.
SAM: We're dealing with three dimensions, here.
MATT: You could hit both of them. All three of
them with it.
SAM: I will aim that way.
MATT: You have to pull back a lot, like over
here.
MARISHA: What the fuck kind of cone are you
using?
SAM: I have many Prismatic Sprays.
MARISHA: Even though I'm down from them?
SAM: It's a 60-feet distance, 60-foot cone. I
don't know if the math is going to work. If not, I
have a backup plan.
MATT: Yeah, they're all within 60 feet.
TALIESIN: Oh my god.
MARISHA: Tary wins.
SAM: d8 again?
MATT: Prismatic Spray. Yeah, d8.
SAM: This is a different one. This is a five.
MATT: Five. That's cold damage. I need Grog,
Keyleth. Your knight friend is (ice cracking)
frozen into place and is now a frozen statue of
ice, there, up in the tower.
MARISHA: Dexterity saves?
MATT: Dexterity saving throw, yeah.
MARISHA: Oh, that's good!
TRAVIS: Six, but I have resistance to cold.
MARISHA: I am at 20.
MATT: Yeah, you succeed. So half damage to both of
you. Roll that now. It's 10d6 cold damage.
TRAVIS: Ten cubes.
MARISHA: That saving throw may be the only thing
that saves me. Maybe. Depends on how he rolls.
MATT: Yeah, we'll see how the roll goes. This is
close.
TALIESIN: Ooh. Oh. Yeah.
SAM: 36, halved. 18.
MARISHA: I'm good!
TRAVIS: She says, before she dies.
MARISHA: Shut your dirty mouth.
SAM: Yeah. I'm flying. That negated my Sanctuary.
I'll do one more Sanctuary, and I'm going to stay
up. Can I fly back down? That probably took all my
speed. Yeah, I'll hover in place.
MATT: Top of the round. The towers surge,
bursting with energy up here and up here. Grog, I
need you to roll another dexterity saving throw.
TRAVIS: 18.
MATT: 18? Okay, that just succeeds. You take half
damage.
TRAVIS: And I have resistance.
MATT: Right. I rolled pretty good, so it was 21
points of lightning damage, reduced to ten, and
then halved because you have resistance, so five.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: And Grog, it's your turn. You have Keyleth
over here.
TRAVIS: Oh, I only have one target. I stride
confidently to the edge of the tower, and I'd like
to use my Boots of Feral Leaping to jump and bring
my hammer down on top of Keyleth,
on top of the tower.
MATT: Go ahead and roll your athletics check.
Don't be a one.
TRAVIS: Oh yeah, don't be a one. That's pretty
good. That's a 22.
MATT: Okay. You leap and land. You do take three
points of bludgeoning damage.
Six, reduced to three.
MARISHA: Goddamn it, he was so close. I had him.
Twice!
MATT: I know.
MARISHA: I had you twice!
TRAVIS: Reckless, I smash.
MATT: Okay, go for it.
MARISHA: Time for a beautiful and glorious death.
LAURA: He got another 20!
MATT: On the first hit? Go ahead and roll damage.
TALIESIN: Oh my god.
TRAVIS: That's a nine, so 18.
MARISHA: I almost teleported his fucking ass.
MATT: I know.
TALIESIN: There's six places he should have died.
TRAVIS: 34.
MARISHA: I'm unconscious.
TRAVIS: Let's not rush it. 43. 51.
MATT: So Keyleth-- you take the three damage not
from the stone breaking your fall, but from her
breaking your fall as you land on her. She (thud)
onto the stone, flat on the ground, the hammer
placed squarely between the back of her
shoulderblades, in the middle of the neck. As you
bring the hammer back up, pulling it back,
she's twitching a little on the stonework, but
she's still alive.
TRAVIS: I reach down. I grab one of those
jacked-up antlers, hold her up in the air. I look
at Tary, and I lob it and smack her towards the
acid pool. I want to hit her in the air towards
the acid pool.
MATT: Roll an attack.
MARISHA: (laughing) So cold!
TRAVIS: Jesus. Yeah, 36?
MATT: Yeah. It's an auto-crit, so it's two
automatic fails of your death saving throw.
(splash) Make a strength check.
MARISHA: Look.
TALIESIN: Oh, that's depressing.
MARISHA: Strength check.
MATT: He's making it, not you. You're making it.
What did you get?
TRAVIS: That is 12 plus eight. 20.
MATT: 20. You arc her, (whoosh, sizzle) taking the
final death saving throw as you slowly dissolve in
the acid. Keyleth eliminated from the battle.
MARISHA: I got to use the tattoo.
TRAVIS: One last attack. I look up at Tary and I'm
like, you did save me. What do you want to do?
SAM: I crack my knuckles. Come on, little man.
Let's rumble.
TRAVIS: I like your style. I have a throwing
distance. It is ranged, so I think it's at
disadvantage, which is 70 feet.
MATT: 70 feet? You can hit him at 70 feet, yeah.
It's disadvantage on the attack, though.
TRAVIS: So a regular roll, reckless.
MATT: Right. Well, first make a wisdom saving
throw, because he has Sanctuary.
TRAVIS: That's right.
LAURA: What did you get?
TRAVIS: An eight.
MATT: You go--
TRAVIS: Nah. I'll let you go first. With my speed,
can I run on this side
of the structure to get cover?
MATT: Here?
TRAVIS: Yep. Down. Whatever blocks his line of
sight from me.
MATT: Okay. Your turn, Taryon.
SAM: I'm flying, so I will fly where I saw him
hide.
MATT: You see him. He's not really hiding.
(laughs)
SAM: He's immune to everything, right?
LAURA: No, he's just resistant.
SAM: But he's resistant to everything.
MATT: He's resistant to slashing, bludgeoning,
piercing, fire, cold, and lightning right now.
LAURA: So poison, acid he's not resistant to.
TRAVIS: I'm resistant to poison.
LAURA: Oh, he's not resistant to acid.
MATT: Yeah, because of your belt.
SAM: I'll fly over there and I guess I've got to
get within 30 feet above him. Or 30 feet of him.
MATT: You can get about there. A little closer,
actually. You'd have to get to about there and you
can throw to him.
SAM: I'll chuck acid at him.
MATT: This vial (splash) hits the ground and
splashes acid all around you. He has to make a
dexterity saving throw, I think?
SAM: I'll look.
TRAVIS: Really? Already?
SAM: Dexterity saving throw.
TRAVIS: 18 is the first one. 18 on the second
one.
MATT: The DC, I'm pretty sure 18 makes it.
SAM: Yeah, so that's halved?
TRAVIS: Danger sense.
SAM: It's 9d6.
TALIESIN: Four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
MARISHA: If Tary wins, I'm going to be so happy,
even though dirty fucking camper. Dirty camper.
MATT: No, that's a tactic.
SAM: 16. Wow, lousy. It was all ones and twos.
TRAVIS: 16 reduced to eight?
MATT: You take eight points of acid damage, Grog.
SAM: Oh, I attacked again, didn't I? Shit. I will
do another Sanctuary at level two.
MATT: All righty. Grog, it's your turn.
SAM: (singing) I'm like a bird.
TRAVIS: I climb back up on the roof. I walk over
to Tary. How did I break the Sanctuary with Groon?
I just booped him, right? Can I reach him with my
fingertip?
MATT: Nope. He's about 15 feet ahead of you.
TRAVIS: I'm going to try and hit him.
SAM: Jump and hit or throw and hit?
TRAVIS: Throw and hit.
MATT: So wisdom.
TRAVIS: No. 13.
MATT: So you go (frustrated noise).
TRAVIS: Stubborn as a mule. 11.
SAM: I'm doing that pec thing that you always do,
but I can't do it, so it looks like this.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: One more. Ooh! 19?
SAM: Sure, yeah. That means it breaks my
Sanctuary, yeah. Does he roll again to attack?
MATT: You have to roll to attack.
TRAVIS: Reckless. I got through, ma! 31.
SAM: Oh yeah.
MATT: Roll damage on that.
TRAVIS: 26.
SAM: Okay.
MATT: You're like, (laughs, gong sound). You taste
the blood for the
first time in your mouth, really.
TALIESIN: Does he stay on the broom?
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: Had to bring him back, didn't you?
MARISHA: This is your fault.
SAM: Sorry.
TRAVIS: With the rest of my movement, can I run
back down off the roof and into the room?
MATT: Going off the roof there and then get
inside. So you'll be about there. You're low.
You're hunched in there. Melee attacks inside that
room for you right now are going to be at
disadvantage because the space is so crowded.
Taryon, your turn.
SAM: I'm going to actually fly away further and
pull out another gem from my helmet and cast what
modern-day people would call napalm. Straight into
the door. A Wall of Fire, straight in the door, in
the room.
TRAVIS: I ain't winning any beauty contests.
MATT: A straight wall of flame engulfs the room.
TRAVIS: (screams)
SAM: It's 5d8 fire damage.
TRAVIS: Ones and twos. Here we go!
SAM: But you're resistant, right?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
SAM: Okay.
TRAVIS: I've been burned, melted, burned, melted,
and burned.
MATT: Dexterity save from you, Grog.
TRAVIS: Dexterity? 21. Plus two on a 19.
SAM: 26.
MATT: 26, so you take half that, which is 13,
because you succeeded on your save, and then half
that. You take six points of fire damage.
SAM: That's it? Weak.
MATT: He's resistant to fire, man.
SAM: Okay.
MATT: That's your turn? You still have your bonus
action.
SAM: I'll Sanctuary myself again.
MATT: (laughs) All right.
TRAVIS: Damn it. Sanctuary!
MATT: Grog, it's your turn.
TRAVIS: How far above the roof of that building is
he?
MATT: He's 30 feet above it.
TRAVIS: Okay, never mind. I will leap horizontally
towards the building that
he is close to. 20 feet.
MATT: You have to move out of the room first. So
you have ten feet out.
TRAVIS: I might not have made that. 17. I made it
by one.
MARISHA: Oh, you almost tripped in the acid? That
would have been awesome.
MATT: That would have been great.
TRAVIS: Yeah, because I fall prone.
MARISHA: Damn. It would have been so cool.
TRAVIS: So 20 feet horizontally, and then the rest
of my speed to run to the building, climb up on
the roof, and get right underneath him. I'd like
to try and get through this fucking Sanctuary.
MATT: Wisdom save.
LAURA: I like that we thought this might go fast.
MARISHA: I know. I'm still laughing at him saying
that at the top.
TRAVIS: 14.
MATT: Second attack lost.
TRAVIS: 19.
SAM: Oh yeah. That gets through.
MATT: Third and final strike. (grunts)
TRAVIS: 31.
MATT: 31 points of damage.
TRAVIS: No, just to hit.
MATT: Oh, to hit? Okay.
TRAVIS: Ten, 26.
MATT: 26 points of damage.
SAM: Okay. Still kicking.
TALIESIN: Quite well, I might add.
LAURA: He's got a lot. He had a lot of hit
points.
TRAVIS: Who?
LAURA: Tary.
TRAVIS: Oh, really? He ate half of his cloak or
whatever.
SAM: This guy is impossible to kill.
LAURA: Not impossible, Tary. It's not impossible.
MATT: All right. Tary, it's your turn.
SAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: 19. That 19 will haunt me for forever.
SAM: Is pulling a patch an action? I'll fly right
over the acid pit, right over the center, and I've
got to do one more Prismatic Spray.
MATT: All righty. Dexterity check, Grog. Roll a
d8.
TRAVIS: A d8?
MATT: He rolls a d8. What did you roll?
TRAVIS: 19?
SAM: It's four. It's poison, right?
MATT: Four is poison, yeah.
TRAVIS: Which I have resistance to.
MATT: Yeah, so roll 10d6. And he saved, so he
takes a quarter of the poison damage.
SAM: Wait, a quarter?! Goddamn it! This guy!
TRAVIS: Tary, at any time, you can just plop into
the acid and it will all be over. You can drop in,
listen to the bubbles consume your flesh. Be like
soggy Cracklin' Oat Bran. That milk looks weird.
SAM: 42 halved and quartered. So it's 11? Wait, is
that right?
TRAVIS: 21.
MATT: 21, ten. Ten points of poison damage.
SAM: Ten? Ten?!
MATT: He can't have that much more. Don't give
up.
TRAVIS: Let me guess. Sanctuary?
SAM: Oh yeah. That's a good idea!
(laughter)
SAM: I don't have many more of those.
MATT: All righty. Grog, it's your turn.
SAM: 3rd-level Sanctuary.
TRAVIS: I fucking walk off the roof and toward the
edge of the acid and I'm like, okay,
in range, and I'll--
LAURA: Wait, you can't cast 3rd-level spells after
you've already done a spell. You can only do
2nd-level.
SAM: Is the Prismatic Spray a spell?
MATT: It's not casting it at a higher level. He's
sacrificing a higher-level spell slot to cast a
lower-level. It doesn't change anything about it.
SAM: No, but because I used Prismatic Spray. Oh, I
see. It's still a low-level spell. I'm just using
a slot.
MATT: You're just using a higher-level slot. It's
not casting at a higher level.
MARISHA: Wait, what? All right. I just thought if
you cast it as a higher-level spell, you couldn't
do it as a lower-level spell?
SAM: Shenanigans.
MATT: He's basically sacrificing a high-level
spell to cast a lower-level spell that doesn't get
any benefit from being sacrificed.
TRAVIS: First wisdom save. Goddamn, the fucking--
17?
SAM: That's my DC.
MATT: First attack, you get through.
SAM: Where are you?
MATT: He moved right under here.
TALIESIN: He's right under you.
SAM: But I'm over the acid!
MARISHA: If you land in the acid, dude--
LAURA: If he knocks you off your broom?
TRAVIS: It's a 37 to hit.
LAURA: Did he get knocked off his broom? He
doesn't have the same things that I have.
TRAVIS: 24 on the first hit, for damage.
TALIESIN: I don't think we ever built a safety net
into his broom.
MATT: No, but he's not being knocked-- if it was
an attack that pushed or did anything to affect
his movement or yank him, then it would become an
issue. Just doing damage won't do anything.
TRAVIS: Oh, 26?
MATT: The same things that would knock him off the
broom would knock you off the broom. It would just
mean the broom stays attached to you.
TRAVIS: 22. Natural 19. Son of a bitch. A
million.
SAM: Sure.
MARISHA: I love that he's getting so cranky about
rolling natural 19s.
TRAVIS: 19 points of damage. I mean, after six
rolls, you'd hope so.
MATT: You made a save on each of those rolls?
TRAVIS: I am so sorry. I thought after I got
through the first one it just dispelled it.
MATT: Nope!
TRAVIS: The first one was a 24, I think?
MATT: Yes.
TRAVIS: So you need to erase--
MATT: Well, you have to roll saves for the next
two.
TRAVIS: Oh, okay. I probably won't get through
him, though. 15?
SAM: Nope.
TRAVIS: 15.
MATT: All right, so the last two attacks do no
damage.
SAM: I live to see another day.
TRAVIS: I'm sorry. I thought it dispelled it.
MARISHA: Or 15 more seconds.
SAM: Jesus Christ. I know that he takes acid
damage, right?
MATT: Yes. He doesn't appear to be resistant to
acid damage.
SAM: Okay, then I will throw acid at him. In
the face!
MATT: Two-Face style.
SAM: Yeah, the acid drop. It's a dex save.
MATT: It's a dex save on you, Grog, to try and
avoid it.
TRAVIS: 15?
MATT: What's your DC?
SAM: 17.
MATT: No. Full damage on this.
LAURA: Oh shit!
SAM: This could be it. Oh, this is it. Well,
maybe. 29.
TRAVIS: Oh, 29 points of damage?
MATT: Acid damage, yeah. Roll a constitution.
TRAVIS: With the plus two to constitution from the
card.
MATT: Well, plus one. The modifier gives you a
plus one. The DC is 15 this time.
TRAVIS: 24.
MATT: Okay. He stays up at one hit point.
SAM: (screams) He's insane!
MARISHA: He's undead!
MATT: The DC's going to be 20, next time that
happens. You still have your movement.
SAM: I'm going to go 50 feet anywhere. To the top
of that tower over there, I guess.
MATT: Over here?
SAM: Yeah. Can I get there? Or as far away from
him as I can get.
MATT: You can get... all the way over here.
SAM: I'm going to get lightninged, but that's
okay. I'll take it.
MATT: It's better than a Grogning. All right, that
ends your turn.
TRAVIS: You're on top of the fucking tower?
MATT: Top of the round, the braziers all
(explosion noise) in the distance. No effect.
Grog, your turn.
TRAVIS: May I leap over the acid pit with the
Boots of Feral Leaping, knowing I might fall in.
No, I'm in there. 23. Where are you going,
chicken? With my 50 feet of speed-- is there a
chain hanging from the front of it?
MATT: Yeah, right there.
TRAVIS: Can I climb that with 50 feet of speed?
Probably not.
MATT: You can climb it. We'll see how far you can
get.
TRAVIS: No. I'm going to run into the tower and
start running up the stairs.
MATT: You'll get partway into the first floor on
your 50. Are you going to dash
to try and do the rest?
TRAVIS: Yes, if it will get me to the top.
MATT: It won't get you all the way to the top,
no.
TRAVIS: Okay, that's fine. I'll dash.
MATT: Okay, you'll get-- with your dash, into the
third floor, almost to the hatch. So you're up in
the third floor right now. Tary?
SAM: (giggles) I casually walk down the stairs.
MATT: You come to the hatch, and Grog rushes up
into the third floor there. As you come down in
the hatch.
TRAVIS: I have a request. With your hands.
Please.
SAM: With my hands?
TRAVIS: Yes.
LAURA: Don't.
TRAVIS: I'm a simple man.
SAM: All right. I can do that. (laughing) I can't
do that. You're so powerful. I'll probably miss!
TRAVIS: You got it, man.
SAM: If I miss, then I'm trapped in a room with
him!
TRAVIS: I've got one hit point.
SAM: But I could miss.
LAURA: Kill him, Tary!
TRAVIS: This is your chance to claim your bravery
for your house.
SAM: Greatsword!
MARISHA: You're getting him with a greatsword?
SAM: That's what I've got. Greatsword.
MATT: Your rod turns into a greatsword.
TRAVIS: (laughing) The fucking thing.
SAM: I'll do this crazy around and around thing
and try to do that with the greatsword. Oh, and
can I set it on fire, first?
MATT: Yes, you can.
TRAVIS: Oh, good. Yeah.
SAM: What am I rolling? What was that? 12 plus
eight plus two magic. That's 22.
MATT: Hits. Roll damage.
SAM: Three.
MATT: Grog, make a constitution--
SAM: Oh, it's 2d6. Four.
(laughter)
MATT: Roll a constitution saving throw. DC 20.
TRAVIS: That's a natural 19.
MARISHA: Oh my god, he's still fucking alive!
SAM: What happened?!
TRAVIS: Natural 19.
SAM: (screams)
TRAVIS: And I'd like to take my retaliation
strike.
TALIESIN: Yeah!
SAM: I still have movement.
MATT: You do, after this. Retaliation is an
immediate reaction.
SAM: I get a disengage. Didn't we go over this? I
did a melee weapon attack. Don't I get a disengage
for free?
MATT: As your feat, you mean?
SAM: Yes! My Mobile feat.
MATT: Right, but this isn't him getting a free
attack from you moving away. One of his barbarian
abilities is if someone hits him with a melee
attack, he can immediately attack.
SAM: Okay.
MATT: He goaded you right into doing what he
wanted.
TALIESIN: Oh my god.
TRAVIS: How many hit points do you have?
SAM: Enough.
TRAVIS: Oh, okay.
MATT: Make your attack, Grog.
TRAVIS: Reckless. Come on, natural 20. No. 27.
SAM: To hit? Sure.
TRAVIS: 25 points of damage.
SAM: That hurts.
TRAVIS: But not enough.
SAM: It hurts you, because I have a Shield of Fire
that burns anybody who attacks me with a melee
attack. With 2d8 cold damage.
TRAVIS: This fucking magic is too much for this
barbarian. I mean, goddamn. People are turning
into flames, dragons, running around in a fucking
hamster ball,
setting me on fucking cold damage...
MATT: Roll some cold damage.
SAM: Two. Nine.
MATT: Make another constitution check with a DC
25, Grog.
MARISHA: DC 25!
LAURA: He has to roll a natural 20 in order to get
this. No. He has to roll a 19.
SAM: He gets two rolls.
TRAVIS: I have plus 12 as the modifier to the
roll. My constitution is plus 12.
LAURA: Oh, a saving throw? Oh shit.
TRAVIS: So I have to roll-- what's the math on
that?
MATT: It's a 25.
TRAVIS: 17 or higher?
LAURA: It's not even that much. It's a 13 or
higher.
MARISHA: He's going to make it.
TRAVIS: Seven.
MATT: Taryon, how do you want to do this?
SAM: I want him to hit the blazing TD on my chest
and have the might of my name ricochet back with
the power of energy. The Darrington name strikes
him down.
MATT: The cold shatters you, and you feel the
ribcage break like brittle glass on the inside of
your chest from the blast backward. You fall to
your knees, unable to move a muscle. You can feel
the life barely beating through. Your body is
heaving with each heartbeat pulse. He's prostrate
before you, Taryon, as you approach.
SAM: I say, Doty, take this down. I win. And I
kick him over.
MATT: As you hit the ground, as the last of the
cold damage has curled over your body and freezes
you solid, you (shattering) shatter into thousands
of small, frozen pieces. The last T2 reference of
the night, yep. As Taryon Darrington stands victor
of this round. As you stand there, breathing
heavily, suddenly the stone top of the tower
cracks open, like it's being pulled apart by giant,
invisible hands. And there you see, descending
from above, a gentleman in a large, dark cloak and
a magnificent beard, and a glorious, well-kept
mane of hair. He lands. "Let this blessing of
"Colville carry you into any dimension." He touches
your forehead and you feel the fates reach into
you and plant you with a seed of possibility. And
then with that, a flash is gone. You awaken in
your bed. Cold sweat. The next morning after you
went to sleep. You're not as powerful as you felt
before. That was a crazy dream. But you look down
and you see this slight glow of white light across
your sternum from underneath your silk pajamas,
and then it fades, and you feel like something
from that dream is holding on. And that's where
we're going to end our game tonight.
(cheering)
TRAVIS: You got your fate dice.
LAURA: Oh my god. And your parents are named after
Tony Stark's parents. How crazy is that?
SAM: Oh, wait. They are?
TRAVIS: How many hit points did you have left?
SAM: I still had 30 or something.
TALIESIN: He had 25.
MATT: I'm curious. Where were you going to try and
Plane Shift Grog?
MARISHA: Water Plane. Water dimension. You would
have just drowned.
TALIESIN: Solid.
MARISHA: I didn't know your charisma was-- I
thought you had zero.
TRAVIS: It's plus one.
MARISHA: All he had to roll was an 18 or lower.
Anything else.
TRAVIS: That's why I was like, ugh, it's a 19.
LAURA: Oh man. That was awesome.
MATT: That was a great battle, guys.
TRAVIS: That was a great map! That map was
amazing.
MATT: I'm glad you guys had fun. I was hoping it
would be fun.
TRAVIS: The three different varying--
SAM: It was like a paintball field.
MATT: That's what I wanted to make it feel like.
Little bunker areas.
LAURA: You did have places that people that were
flying could hide.
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: If we had tried to hit one of the spires
that created electricity,
would that have ended that?
MATT: Here? You could have destroyed it. Hitting
it would have done damage to it, but it would have
prevented that from going off in that area.
SAM: Were all the trunks the same thing?
MATT: Yeah, each trunk had one healing potion. It
was whoever got there first.
TALIESIN: And there was one trunk left?
MATT: One trunk left that nobody went to.
TRAVIS: Which one?
MARISHA: The one that I was in for a lot of the
time.
TALIESIN: I kept thinking about telling you.
TRAVIS: Oh, really? The one down here in the lower
left?
TALIESIN: Yeah, bottom left.
MARISHA: It was the one I was camping out in.
TALIESIN: But it wasn't my turn, so I didn't say
anything.
MARISHA: I almost thought about taking it just so
no one else could have it, but never got to it.
MATT: Well done, guys.
TALIESIN: (giggles) That was nuts.
MATT: Oh man. Well, when this campaign arc's over
and we have everybody available, hopefully, we'll
probably have one final battle royale with
everyone max level, with Vax, with Pike, and see
who comes through on that one. And whatever gift
boon I decide for that one, if it's similar or the
same, will probably carry over to the next
campaign for their first new characters.
Should be fun.
MARISHA: Level 20 Keyleth is nasty. I get
unlimited Shapechange.
TRAVIS: What do you mean, is nasty? You are nasty!
You were like the fucking Conclave. Jesus. The
only thing you didn't turn into was a giant.
MARISHA: I thought I was going to take the light
down.
MATT: You had a 90% chance of just disappearing
and drowning.
MARISHA: Yeah. I thought that's what he was going
to fucking do. I can't believe that.
TRAVIS: That's true, yeah.
MARISHA: You would have bamfed, and then it would
have been down to Tary and I.
LAURA: I had no idea you could break out of my
fucking necklace!
MATT: Nobody tried.
TALIESIN: There's so many ways that you could have
died tonight.
MARISHA: Yeah, you could have died 80 times.
TALIESIN: If that glove had worked, I would have
had an action surge and five shots to the head.
MATT: It's the balance to the necklace so you
can't just imprison the main big bad guy of
something and be like, "Oh, that's over because he
rolled poor." It will help for a while, but if he
stays in there for a long time and he's
intelligent, he'll eventually find a way out. It's
an imperfect prison.
TALIESIN: It's a wicker basket.
TRAVIS: And the Deck, yet again, didn't harm me.
LAURA: Well, you don't know that because it was
all a dream in Tary's fucking head.
MARISHA: You pulling that knight probably changed
things because he did just enough damage to me to
make it a pain in the ass.
TALIESIN: That plus two to modifier? There's a
lot.
SAM: The cards were amazing!
MATT: I'm going to hold onto those, if that's
okay. I want to use those from now on. Oh, that
was so much fun.
TALIESIN: Came in the mail a little while ago.
TRAVIS: Taryon Darrington, champion of the battle
royale.
MATT: Two clerics and an artificer are our
reigning champions in the battles, guys.
MARISHA: Two clerics?
TRAVIS: Kashaw won the first.
MATT: Then Pike.
MARISHA: That's right, Kash. And I was the
runner-up with Pike, too! Goddamn it.
MATT: And then Pike pushed your face into lava.
MARISHA: I wasn't the runner-up tonight.
TALIESIN: I went down hard, man.
LAURA: You did go down hard.
MATT: Oh, Percy.
SAM: You got hammered to death so soon.
TALIESIN: Again, if the glove had worked, it would
have been amazing. That would have been an ugly,
terrible death for Grog.
MATT: You had some bad rolls. You, more so than
anybody in this party-- maybe Grog, but Grog had
to still get there-- you, with an action surge and
some good rolls, you can pretty much take down
almost any member in one round.
TALIESIN: With good rolls.
MATT: With good rolls.
MARISHA: You jammed all of your guns. I can't
believe you jammed all of your guns.
TALIESIN: Not only that, but the gun that does
damage when it jams jammed twice.
LAURA: All of your war paint is gone.
MARISHA: How did you do that?
SAM: Oh my god, it's gone. Did you go wash your
face?
LAURA: No, he's just been wiping his face the
whole night. It's all over his hands, probably.
TALIESIN: Show us your hands.
LAURA: No, don't.
SAM: Your sheets tonight are going to be nasty.
TALIESIN: You're going to be hard to see in the
forest.
MATT: Well done, guys. Thank you guys for playing.
Hope you guys enjoyed watching. We'll see you guys
next week to pick up the next leg of the
adventure, as we left off right as you were
exiting the platinum mines with the swarm of
ankhegs below you. We'll pick up from there next
week. We'll have Jon Heder as a guest, which I
got to coordinate with him to get his story stuff
figured out. We'll talk. And the week after that
will be our 100th episode. That's fucking crazy!
LAURA: I mean, how?
SAM: Well, some of them weren't that good. So
really only 60.
TALIESIN: I think 20th episode, really.
MATT: There's a lot of people who went, "yeah."
And I don't blame you! But we're having fun.
That's what matters. So looking forward to
that. We should have some fun surprises on the
100th episode. We're excited about that. Anyway,
much love to you guys. Have a wonderful night, and
is it Thursday yet? See you soon.