MATT: Hello, everyone, and welcome
to tonight’s episode of Critical Role,
where a bunch
of us nerdy-ass voice actors
sit around and play Dungeons & Dragons
and occasionally
get shivved by a rakshasa.
LAURA AND ASHLEY: No!
MATT: Occasionally.
ASHLEY: Go away.
MATT: So! Before we go ahead
and jump into the game tonight,
let’s go ahead and do
a couple quick announcements.
First and foremost,
returning again this week,
our sponsor Loot Crate
for bringing this episode to you guys.
For those who are familiar with it,
and most of you are at this point,
but Loot Crate is
a monthly subscription box service.
They have awesome geek-related gear
and merchandise and clothing,
a lot of them exclusive to the box.
You get $20 a month to get 6-8 items
that include licensed gear, apparel,
collectible, all that fun-ness,
but you also get a $3 discount
if you go ahead and sign up
at lootcrate.com/criticalrole
and enter the key phrase
criticalrole - one word -
into that new subscription code box.
They also have a DX box, which is bigger,
awesome for the super-collector out there.
Which has a bunch
(indistinct music in background)
of really awesome exclusive content.
Plays awesome music
from Ashley’s phone.
ASHLEY: That’s true,
you all get my phone if you get it.
MATT: This month’s Dystopia boxes
will be shipping out soon
to those of you guys who subscribed,
and Loot Crate will be announcing
their next box tomorrow, 6/24.
TRAVIS: Yeah, they will!
MATT: So look forward to that -
MATT: - and you’ll see what
their next theme is, which will be nice.
LAURA: How - you were already here!
MATT: Sam! Come on in, sir.
MARISHA: You’re here,
you’re still coming in.
MATT: You were on time
and you’re still somehow late.
SAM: Nobody told me
that the show was starting.
MATT: It’s 7:00! It’s crazy.
SAM: Oh, that's right.
LAURA: Oh, that’s how it works.
MATT: So yeah. The links are in the chat.
Check it out if you’re interested
in signing up for Loot Crate.
We hope to make it
a little bit cheaper for you.
So, there. We got that.
The Critical Role t-shirt design contest
has been live for a while.
LAURA: There are so many good pieces.
MARISHA: Oh man, so many good ones.
MATT: It’s going to be ridiculous.
I’m not looking forward
to having to choose.
MARISHA: Yes, I know,
it’s going to be tough.
TRAVIS: Stick figures for the win.
MATT: But yeah, it closes June 24th, guys.
This Friday at midnight.
So go ahead and get them in;
you got one more day for the most part,
a little over a day
to get those last entries in
and we’ll announce those winners soon.
Remember, you have to be
18 or older to enter,
or you can have a guardian enter -
LAURA: We choose the top three, right?
And then the Critters get to -
MATT: The Critters choose the last one.
SAM: But you can already vote.
LAURA: Yeah, I don’t understand
how that’s working,
because we’re choosing the top three,
and then the Critters get to choose
between the ones that we choose.
MARISHA: I think it’s supposed to be
like how our Congress is supposed to work,
SAM: They’re choosing representatives?
MARISHA: Yeah, exactly.
LAURA: I understand.
MARISHA: We’ll see what you want -
LAURA: And disregard it completely.
MARISHA: We’ll disregard it completely
and just make our own choice.
MATT: We’re just all not
in the room where it happens.
ALL: (singing) I wanna be
in the room where it happens,
the room where it happens,
the room where it happens.
MATT: Oh god, we’re those people. Sorry.
Anyway, that ends tomorrow.
You have to be 18 or older to enter,
but you can have a guardian enter
on your behalf if you’re a young artist.
Fantastic news.
Next up, our posters
that we put up last week.
ALL: Oh!
MATT: Really excited about those,
done by the awesome Joe Mad.
Those are still on sale.
We have one more week only
for the exclusive cast-signed posters,
and then two weeks for the pre-order
for the regular poster.
Go check it out
at the Geek & Sundry shop
if you’re interested.
The artwork is amazing.
TRAVIS: They’re so pretty!
ASHLEY: They're just so pretty!
MATT: Pretty sick, movie poster-sized.
TRAVIS: I want it in a frame.
ASHLEY: They’re so pretty in person.
LIAM: In person, they look about
ten times more vibrant -
LIAM: - than the images I saw.
SAM: Just like us!
MATT: Mostly Sam, though.
You can’t help but be so vibrant.
(funny voice)
I just spilled on my groin.
I don’t know why I felt like
saying that out loud.
So those are the posters.
Check them out at
shop.geekandsundry.com/
collections/criticalrole.
Starting tomorrow,
we have the MDA stream.
Geek & Sundry’s doing
a fantastic 24-hour charity stream.
They’ve partnered with
Amy Poehler’s Smart Girls and Nerdist.
There’s going to be a variety:
game-show, livestream, everything,
benefiting
the Muscular Dystrophy Association.
You guys are welcome
to come in at any time
for as much of it as you can,
check out the great programming
we have set up for you guys.
It starts tomorrow at 7pm.
There will be
no regular programming tomorrow
because the crew is going to have to
be setting up and preparing
for this actual livestream,
but starting at 7pm,
it goes on for the next 24 hours.
So look forward to us all
being sleepless and crazy.
We are going to be finishing out
the charity drive Saturday evening,
starting at 5pm PT here.
I’m going to be running a one-shot
Deadlands Savage Worlds game
for a few of our cast
who are going to be here for that,
and I’m excited for that
because it’s one of my favorite settings.
It’s going to be great!
The shirts are available now
if you want to check them out.
MATT: We have our own -
TALIESIN: Right here. Critical Role.
MATT: - charity shirts right there.
LAURA: Ooh, it’s beautiful!
TALIESIN: Lovely vibrant blue
with a thing on the -
LAURA: All of it,
all of it goes to the charity.
MARISHA: Yeah, 100%
of the proceeds go to -
MATT: All the proceeds go to MDA.
ASHLEY: Beautiful “turquaz.”
TALIESIN: “Turquaz.”
MATT: We got that set up.
Next up, we have tomorrow,
we have the next issue,
release would we call it,
of Dear Vox Machina.
However, it is not necessarily
a member of Vox Machina.
This is one that I put together
that I think you guys should enjoy.
What character could it possibly be?
I guess you’ll just have
to check in tomorrow to find out.
But that’ll be on geekandsundry.com
tomorrow, I think around noon?
Maybe earlier. I’ll tweet it out.
You’ll find out
on Geek & Sundry’s Twitter page, but -
SAM: Is it Jarrett?
MATT: You’ll have to check it out,
you’ll have to come find out,
but I had a lot of fun writing it.
ASHLEY: Someone
keeps forgetting to do it.
LAURA: (gasps)
You haven’t done it yet?
ASHLEY: I keep forgetting.
I keep forgetting to do it.
And then it comes around,
and then...
MATT: I got you covered.
Trinket had you covered.
MATT: You got five more days.
ASHLEY: All right, guys, we’ll get there.
MATT: So yeah, that’s coming up tomorrow.
Check that out.
We have a new Signal Boost host.
Marisha, you want to take that?
MARISHA: A new host!
MATT: Yeah, what you got?
MARISHA: Stay tuned for the break
to see who it is,
or if you happened to watch it
you already know,
but stay tuned for the break
for the surprise.
SAM: Best kind of surprise.
MARISHA: Best kind of surprise.
That you’ve already heard about.
MATT: Yeah. And last on my end
as far as announcements go,
there will be no Critical Role
official episode next Thursday
because me and Marisha
will be in Australia at the Haven Expo,
so all you Aussies
that want to come see us then,
we’ll be out there
doing panels and talks
and meeting a bunch of you guys.
It’ll be a lot of fun.
However, while we will not be here,
there will still be other members
of our fantastic group here
that are able to be here next week
to put on whatever you decide to,
that’s up to you guys.
LAURA: We’re just going
to hula-hoop for three hours.
TRAVIS: It’ll be a surprise.
It’s going to be great.
We're going to draw on each others' faces
with toothpaste.
LAURA: They’re going to do other things.
I’m going to hula-hoop
for three hours straight.
MATT: Laura’s going to hula-hoop
You heard it here. Hold her to it.
ASHLEY: She’s really good.
TRAVIS: Yeah, Liam’s going
to hold the plank position for 2 hours.
LIAM: Oh, that’s easy.
TALIESIN: It’s the one
where you lie on your back, right?
TRAVIS: Yep. Roll like a turtle.
MATT: Hashtag flat on your back.
TALIESIN: I can do that one.
MATT: The reverse plank? Yeah.
MATT: So yeah, check it out on Twitter
as these yahoos figure out
what their content
is going to be next week.
I’m sure it’s going to be fantastic.
We’re going to be watching it
from Australia.
I’m excited to see
what you guys pull together.
Anyway. That’s all I got.
Has anyone else got something
they want me to mention?
Or shall we dive on in?
TRAVIS: Let’s get it! Let’s get it!
LAURA: No no no! Keep stalling!
MATT: All righty, then.
LIAM: Wait wait wait.
LIAM: I would like to say that I was into
breaking my friends’ hearts
before it was cool.
(all laugh)
MATT: Sorry about that.
Without further ado,
let’s go ahead and dive into
this week’s episode of Critical Role.
(spooky ethereal music)
(heavy breathing)
(roaring)
(dramatic music)
(gun firing)
(crackling flames)
MATT: Welcome back!
So. Last we left off, Vox Machina,
having returned to Vasselheim,
in which Vax
and to a lesser extent Percy
had their own encounters
with the Raven Queen.
Vax found seemingly
some catharsis and purpose
to his currently-deemed champion position
with the Raven Queen.
Percy discovered
he’s been broken all along
and left slightly slapped in the nuts.
But such is the nature of your journey.
But you also crafted
a metal claw hand for an ally.
But as you guys finish up
your business in Vasselheim,
you made your way
back to Whitestone.
While in Whitestone,
you met up with some old friends,
had dinner with Allura, Kima,
the Realmseer, Gilmore.
You guys discussed all the things
that you needed to do in the future,
some information had been acquired
from some of the Vestiges,
as well as the nature
of some of the dragons of the Conclave
and some discussion was had
on the overall purpose
of this recent incursion
of dragon destruction.
After which, you all went to bed.
While resting, midnight,
a visit from Gilmore to Vax's room
after some oil prankery
was beset upon each other
via Grog and Vax.
Gilmore gifted a fine silk robe to Vax
and requested his presence
to discuss time that has passed.
Upon changing into the robe,
you guys made your way
down the hallway, up the stairs
to one of the high balconies
of the west tower of Whitestone.
Upon which Gilmore turned,
seemingly in some serious displeasure,
and stabbed you with a dagger
you had not seen was there.
As the pain set in, you realized
perhaps this is not
the Gilmore you recall,
but a shapeshifting,
tiger-like devil entity
that you may have pissed off
some time in the past.
LIAM: Is it a sports mascot?
It's a sports mascot.
MARISHA AND TALIESIN: They're grrreat!
MATT: That's not sports.
TRAVIS: Wow.
(all laugh)
MATT: Not that I'd know.
Anyway, let's go ahead
and jump in this moment.
As the rest of the party
is sleeping soundly,
I would like you, Vax'ildan -
SAM: I am not sleeping.
MATT: You're not sleeping?
SAM: Remember, I said
I was staying up to read my book.
MATT: To read your book,
you're right, you are totally right.
Well, I'm going to have you
roll initiative, if you don't mind.
LIAM: I have a lot of interesting ideas
that will go out the window
depending on this roll, possibly.
TRAVIS: We're all watching.
LIAM: I don't like his reaction.
I'm going to use luck.
I have two lucks left,
I'm going to use one of them.
(groans) It was on 18
and went down. No, 16.
MATT: 16. All righty.
LIAM: Oh, well.
It was going to be really interesting.
MATT: I can only imagine.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: Shit.
MATT: Sorry.
TRAVIS: Thug Life glasses come down,
joint comes up.
MATT: I didn't mean
for it to come off that way, it just -
TRAVIS: Bu-bu-bu-bu-blam, gutshot!
(all laugh)
SAM: Play ding dong...
LIAM: It went 18,
it hung like a half second... 4.
MATT: As the surprise round has faded,
the Gilmore-like entity draws the blade
out of your abdomen,
snarls towards you,
and the round begins
with the initiative on the rakshasa.
MARISHA: (groans)
TRAVIS: You got this, you're fine.
SAM: Wait, refresh us all.
Is Liam - I'm sorry - is Vax naked?
MATT: No, Vax is wearing
a long silk robe -
MATT: - and his boots.
SAM: And what underneath?
MATT: And that's it.
SAM: So, he's naked.
LIAM: I'm wearing my boots,
because it's cold.
I wouldn't go walking barefoot.
MATT: Boots are a given.
Everything else left behind.
SAM: No armor. No weapons.
LAURA: Remember, he was in his pajamas
and Gilmore was like,
"put this on, I made this for you."
LIAM: Why wouldn't any of us
trust Gilmore? Or Matthew?
MATT: I'm just telling a story, yo.
Speaking of stories -
SAM: But wait!
The robe has like a rope tie to tie.
SAM: You can use that for something!
LIAM: Shush!
MATT: You’re reading your book.
So as it draws the blade back,
it goes in for a claw towards the face,
LIAM: Uncanny Dodge?
MATT: Hold on to see if I hit you first.
LIAM: Oh, okay.
MATT: (chuckles) Because
that is going to be a...
MATT: 13 to hit. Your AC is 15.
LIAM: Misses.
MATT: The claw (whoosh).
You duck underneath
as it spins around with the dagger
and hits you from the other side
as you come up from that.
MATT: That will be a 19 and does hit you.
LIAM: (funny voice) Uncanny Dodge?
MATT: You suffer 5 points
of piercing damage
as the dagger just barely (sssh)
cuts across your face.
You can feel the little line of blood
begin to spill down your chin
as you hear the growl
under the breath again,
"I will send you to a place
you'll never return from." (growls)
and is actually going to
stay right there. You're up.
LIAM: Now I can do my crazy-ass shit.
So, out of instinct,
the heels click together, the boots go on,
the world slows down as I speed up
and in that split second,
in a millisecond, I think,
"he's gone to all this trouble
to get me here,
"the door behind me
could very well be locked.
"Also, he knows everything.
He knows about Whitestone.
"If he leaves, he can tell the Conclave
"and if I run, he's gone."
So instead...
he's right in front of me, yeah?
Okay. I would like to grapple him.
MATT: Okay. All right.
Go ahead and make an athletics check.
LIAM: Okay.
Last luck of the day. 14.
MATT: 16
You attempt to grapple
and as soon as your arms
reach around the rakshasa,
Hotis breaks away.
LIAM: Okay.
That's action number 1.
Action number 2,
I'd like to grapple him.
(all laugh)
LIAM: No good.
LAURA: Well, say it, he might roll less.
LIAM: Huh? Say what?
LAURA: Isn't it a roll against a roll?
MATT: Yes, it's a roll against a roll.
LIAM: It's a 7.
MATT: 17. Sorry.
LIAM: Okay,
I will cast Lay on Hands on myself.
MATT: That is an action to do so.
LIAM: That's an action?
Okay, then...
I'll stay where I am.
MATT: Okay. All right.
LIAM: No, sorry! Sorry, sorry (mutters).
At the top of my lungs I scream,
not just in my earring
but loud enough for every guard
and person in the castle. I scream,
"Assassins, western tower
and the courtyard!
"Jenga!"
MATT: All right.
Can I have all of you guys
roll a perception check?
MARISHA: What about
those of us with earrings?
LAURA: To wake us up?
SAM: I'm awake.
MATT: You're awake. You hear it.
TRAVIS: 16.
ASHLEY: 17.
LAURA: 26.
MARISHA: 16.
TALIESIN: 15.
MATT: All right.
Many of you jostle awake
at the sound of the shouting
into your ear.
You hear a few words come through
in the middle of your consciousness.
You hear “tower, west, jenga.”
That's as much as you make out.
The first word was enough
to just shake you awake
and you're not quite sure
what that word was,
but you hear “west tower, jenga,”
and you get the gist of that.
You, however,
did hear the full phrase.
As you look around you,
Percy, Keyleth, and Pike.
SAM: Oh, shit.
MATT: You aren't alone in your room.
TRAVIS: (laughing gasp)
MATT: As climbing through the window,
or in Percy's -
SAM: Ninjas!
MATT: - had come in
through the hallway, you see -
TALIESIN AND MARISHA: Ninjas.
MATT: - cloaked individuals,
blades drawn up in the air,
about to come down
onto your asleep forms,
as you suddenly look up
and see the figure there before you -
MARISHA: Motherfucking ninjas!
MATT: - they look surprised
to see you suddenly move.
I need all of you guys to roll initiative
to add to this initiative order.
TRAVIS: All 3 or everybody else?
LAURA: Everybody?
MATT: Everybody.
MARISHA: Oh my god.
Ooh! That's not bad.
TRAVIS: Have advantage.
TALIESIN: That'll do.
TRAVIS: 18.
ASHLEY: 8!
TRAVIS, LAURA, AND MATT: (chuckle)
LAURA: (southern drawl) 11.
MARISHA: 17.
TALIESIN: 23.
LAURA: Nice.
SAM: Is initiative an ability check?
(all laugh)
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: Then I will inspire myself
on my initiative roll.
MARISHA: Yes!
MATT: You just got that ability
at level 14.
SAM: Yes.
MATT: So.
SAM: So I will just say,
"Come on Scanlan.
Wake up! Wake up, man!"
(all laugh)
SAM: Oh, it's a 1.
SAM: No, it's a 7. It's a 7.
That brings my initiative to 19.
MATT: 19.
(all laugh)
ASHLEY: "Come on, man!"
MATT: All righty.
Well, as you all wake up,
the initiative round finishes
as the attempted assassins
do get their round
on the three of you guys.
So there is the one
that is up against Keyleth right now
is going to make
two short sword attacks on you.
MARISHA: Aw, he beat me?
MATT: Yep. Well this is -
as you guys wake up,
you see them there,
and they're finishing their combat round.
So that's going to be a 19 to hit.
MARISHA: Hits.
MATT: That hits.
Okay. You take 9 points
of piercing damage
and make a constitution saving throw.
ASHLEY AND LAURA: Oh, god.
TRAVIS: Shit.
MARISHA: That can't be good. Okay...
TALIESIN: (wordless noise of approval)
MARISHA: 20, total.
MATT: Okay. You take 12 points
of poison damage.
ASHLEY: With?
MARISHA: On top of I had 9 originally?
MATT: Mm-hm.
MARISHA: Right?
MATT: Yep.
MARISHA: Okay. So that's...
MATT: The second strike is going to
be another 19. Rolled 12 again.
You take another 9 points
of piercing damage,
and I need you to make
another constitution saving throw.
LAURA: This is so much worse
than I thought it was.
TALIESIN: Goddamn it.
MARISHA: I rolled a natural 19, so 24.
MATT: You take another 12 points
of poison damage.
SAM: How many points?
TALIESIN: Wow, that's the good reaction,
apparently.
MARISHA: Jesus, fuck.
He just did 42 points of damage.
ASHLEY: What?
MARISHA: In one round. Yeah.
TRAVIS: Four-two? Four?!
MARISHA: 42!
MATT: So, the one
that's there before you, Percy,
as you're just sitting up out of your bed.
That's going to be an -
oh, that's a natural 17.
24 to hit.
TALIESIN: If I have an AC of 24,
Am I fine or no?
I mean an AC of 24 -
never mind, it hits.
MATT: It still hits you
and and this is assuming also
the fact that that you guys were sleeping
and not in your full armor, either.
TALIESIN: No, no that hits.
No, actually - yeah,
I can't do that, can I? Fuck.
MATT: That's 8 points
of piercing damage to you.
TALIESIN: (sighing) Yeah...
MATT: I need you to make
a constitution saving throw
TALIESIN: All right. Don't be stupid.
Oh, stupid.
That's a natural 1, that's what it is.
MATT: You suffer 24 points
of poison damage.
As whereas you manage
to shrug off the effects,
Percy, you feel as the short sword
strikes across your flesh
the wound that's left open
in the front of your long johns
suddenly begins to burn
and feels like it's singeing,
white-hot fire,
like an iron just out of the forge
has been pressed into your chest.
The second strike rolls a natural 2.
It's going to be a 9.
TALIESIN: Nope, that does not hit.
MATT: This time, you actually
duck out of the bed
as it slams down on the wood,
cutting into the side of the bed frame,
ending that guy's round.
That's going to bring us
to the one that is against you, Pike.
ASHLEY: Okay.
MATT: So, Pike.
ASHLEY: Yes?
MATT: First strike on you.
That's going to be a 20 to hit.
ASHLEY: (chuckles) Just hits.
MATT: Though, not wearing your armor
at this point in time.
LAURA: How do we know
what our AC is?
ASHLEY: So what are we, then?
MATT: Your AC would be
just 10 plus your dexterity modifier.
ASHLEY: So it's 11, so that hits.
MATT: 11. Yeah. You suffer 5 points
of piercing damage
and I need you to make
a constitution saving throw.
ASHLEY: Okay.
20?
MATT: All right, yeah.
So you take 12 points
of poison damage
and that is going to be 10,
so that misses you.
ASHLEY: Great.
MATT: Yeah. So you take
an additional 12 points
of poison damage from the last strike.
ASHLEY: So 5 plus 12?
MATT: Correct. 17 total,
and the second strike goes to hit you
and you actually reach over,
grab your shield which is sitting
on the table by your bed
and just (ping)
knock the blade nearly out of his hand
but deflecting the blow.
That brings us to the top
of the initiative round now.
You guys are all conscious.
Some of you are aware
of the danger you're currently in.
Percy you're up first.
What are you doing?
TALIESIN: I do keep my small pistol
under my pillow.
MATT: Of course you do. (laughs)
Yes, you would, Percy.
TALIESIN: I don't have access, in theory,
to the big gun, the sword,
which are under the bed
and that would require a thing,
and I also don't have access
to any of the things
I could use to reload it,
but I do have four shots.
MATT: You do.
TALIESIN: Okay. Where's my room?
MATT: Your room is right here.
TALIESIN: I don't have a window, do I?
MATT: No, you do not have a window.
Your room is on the inside
TRAVIS: What floor are we on?
MATT: You guys are
on the second major floor of the castle.
The west tower, as you know,
is up this way.
The staircase leads up
and then spirals up to the west tower.
SAM: Do we know how far?
MATT: You haven't -
you've maybe explored there a few times.
It's between 60 to 70 feet up.
SAM: We've not been there,
we're not familiar with it.
MATT: Percy would be
pretty familiar with it.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I would.
MATT: You guys may have gone there
here and there.
TALIESIN: You've seen it.
It's not that big a castle, to be honest.
MARISHA: So there are windows
that they came through?
They came in the windows?
MATT: These two came in the windows,
this one you're not sure,
may have come in through other means
or through another window.
MARISHA: Who are you pointing at? Percy's?
MATT: The one that's in Percy's room.
MARISHA: But we have windows.
MATT: Right.
MARISHA: That are open to the outside.
MATT: Yes.
TALIESIN: Is mine
standing against the door?
MATT: Currently, yes.
TALIESIN: I'm going to try
and shoot him through the door
to see if I can blow him out of my room.
TALIESIN: With trick shot. So.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: Trick shot
to blow him out of the room,
Let's... Let's... Yeah, no,
I'm not adding a sharpshooter
for that, fuck that. First shot.
Oh god, I'm nervous.
(high pitched voice) That'll do.
It's 22.
MATT: Yeah, that'll hit.
They're only wearing studded leather.
TALIESIN: Okay. Good enough.
MATT: And they're caught off guard
at how suddenly everyone,
or at least you,
were suddenly conscious.
He was so quiet,
he was so quiet
and yet you still got there
before he could stab you.
TALIESIN: Okay and that's got
an auto push, I think,
or do I have to roll for push?
MATT: I believe -
TALIESIN: Strength saving throw.
MATT: Yeah. That is going to be
a 5 plus 0, none. No.
So. how much damage is that total?
TALIESIN: That does... sorry.
I was not prepared.
I thought I was going to watch a fight.
MATT: (chuckles)
TALIESIN: I was really prepared for that.
That's 11 points of piercing damage.
MATT: All right.
And pushes him how far back?
TALIESIN: Once... how many squares?
That's a good question.
That's 10 feet directly away.
MATT: (thwoosh) It pushes him
out through the door.
You guys hear this muffled (pshew)
gunshot in the distance
and this slamming sound
of a heavy wooden door hitting stone.
Percy, as you watch, as (boof)
he's blown through the doorway,
landing into the hallway on his back,
and jumps back to his feet just in time
with his blade still out in front of him.
TALIESIN: I'm going to take
two more shots on him.
The next shot is a Sharpshooter shot.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: -5 to hit.
Yeah, no that's a 13.
MATT: 13. As you aim this time
and fire for a second time (pshew)
he does see it coming
and ducks out of the way
as it just scoots under his hood,
avoiding his head
and leaving a hole in the fabric
and then (kssh) taking a chunk
out of the stone in the wall behind him.
TALIESIN: Okay, final shot is -
I'm using the head shot
to try and blind him for a round, so...
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: That's no sharpshooter
because that sucked.
That's better! 28 to hit.
MATT: That'll do.
Go ahead and roll damage.
TALIESIN: He needs to roll
a constitution saving throw.
MATT: He rolls a 20 total.
TALIESIN: And that's against -
I just rolled so terribly...
20. It's a 19 DC,
so unless that changes
with my new intelligence?
MATT: Yeah so it doesn't -
it isn't affected by -
TALIESIN: He just takes 7 points of damage
MATT: It was sharpshooter, wasn't it?
It's a +10?
TALIESIN: What?
No, that wasn't sharpshooter.
I just did the middle one sharpshooter.
MATT: Gotcha. Okay.
7 points piercing damage on that.
(pshew) While the first hit
managed to miss his face,
this one does (whoosh)
scrape across his chin
and cracks a bit of his cheekbone,
but not too much of an impact on him
to actually affect his eyesight.
TALIESIN: I'm going to use
my movement and bonus
to grab at least some of the stuff
that's under my bed.
Some of my things
and start to put myself together
and steady myself
and I’ll start yelling bloody murder.
MATT: Okay. You guys, at this point,
start hearing the distant echo
of Percy's voice
screaming in the distance.
TALIESIN: Intruders! Intruders!
MATT: At the end of Percy's turn,
that now brings us back
to the rakshasa,
which is narrowed down.
Takes the dagger and as a bonus
dips it back into the sheath,
pulling it out
with the liquid trailing off of it.
It's going to go in
and attempt to claw and strike.
ASHLEY: No...
MATT: That's going to be
a 23 with the claw.
LIAM: Yep.
MATT: You take 10 points
of slashing damage.
LIAM: Where did my thing go?
LAURA: Here take it, I'm sorry.
LIAM: Okay.
MATT: And then the dagger
is also going to be thrust back at you
as it moves this way,
getting between you and the door.
That strike is going to be a 21 to hit.
LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: All right.
This time with the dagger.
That's going to be 4 plus...
that's going to be...
LIAM: Uncanny Dodge on it.
MATT: 7 points of piercing damage
and then I need you to make
a constitution saving throw.
LIAM: 20, natural 20.
LAURA: (happy grunting noise)
EVERYONE BUT MATT AND LIAM:
(groans in relief)
LIAM: There was some damage, though.
It was what?
MATT: An additional 7 points
of poison damage.
You used Uncanny Dodge on this.
That all gets reduced to just 7 total.
LIAM: I did use Uncanny Dodge.
MATT: So it would've been 14 total.
You take it down to 7.
LIAM: I lost track of what was what.
MATT: Sorry. 7 points of piercing
and 7 points of poison
together would be 14.
Your Uncanny Dodge brings it down to 7.
So you just take 7 points of damage
that round.
LIAM: Okay.
MATT: All right.
That will end Hotis's turn.
That brings us to Scanlan.
SAM: Okay. I'll use, I guess,
some movement
to gather my belongings
and anything that I don't still have on.
MATT: I mean, everything that you have
would also include your armor,
which you can't really put on right now.
It would take you
about a minute to put it on,
as it is leather armor,
but you can grab everything else
if you wanted to.
Or you could carry your armor
awkwardly with you.
SAM: I'll just grab
a couple of instruments.
MATT: Okay. (grabbing sound)
You gather some things.
SAM: And go. I'll grab
the shawm and the Mythcarver.
MATT: Okay. (grabbing noises)
SAM: And if I've ever been up there,
I'm going to try to Dimension Door
to the west tower.
MATT: Okay. All righty.
SAM: I don't know
if I'm familiar enough with it,
but I'll give it a shot.
MATT: All right.
You would've walked
through the castle
at some point in the past.
You grab your things.
ASHLEY: I've been there with you.
SAM: What did we do up there?
TRAVIS: Made out.
ASHLEY: Like just so much stuff there,
so we've totally been there.
TRAVIS: Under the moonlight.
SAM: Did you have hickies afterward,
or something?
SAM AND TRAVIS: (laugh)
SAM: Oh, it worked!
MATT: At the distance it is at that point
and plus the fact
that you have been there before,
you concentrate,
you remember a few nights
you walked up there
to look over the grounds
because it's a beautiful view
and it's close to where you guys
usually stay here in the castle.
(zoopf) You come out
of the Dimension Door
and looking before you,
you can see Gilmore
holding a dagger out to one side
and Vax bleeding,
holding and clutching
the front of his abdomen,
eyes darting around wildly,
trying to think of some sort of plan
for survival.
So that's your action,
that's most of your movement...
SAM: That's - I mean,
that's pretty much all I've got.
I imagine
I would be pretty confused, so -
MATT: Yeah, you're taking
in the circumstances.
SAM: I will probably just,
if I have any time left, I'll just say,
"What the fuck is going on, Gilmore?"
And that's it.
MATT: The Gilmore looks over his shoulder
and sneers at you. (hissing growl)
SAM: Oh, shit.
(all laugh)
MATT: Grog, you're up.
TRAVIS: I spring out of my bed
because I don't sleep with any armor on,
I got all me bits on me,
and I grab my axe
and I kick the door open!
MATT: (boof)
TRAVIS: Because I know jenga.
It's one of my favorite words. I'm like,
(wordless aggressive sounds)
Is there anybody in the hallway?
MATT: There's nobody in the hallway.
LAURA: No no no.
I thought the gunman was in the hallway?
MATT: Hmm?
LAURA: Percy's gunman was in the hallway.
MATT: Grog is sleeping
in this side of the hallway.
LAURA: Oh, shit!
TALIESIN: Oh.
TRAVIS: Where are the stairs?
MATT: Around that way.
TRAVIS: Fucking shit!
So I start tearing down the hallway
as far as me little legs can carry me.
MATT: About there
if you want to take a dash.
TRAVIS: I'll dash.
MATT: That's your movement
and your dash, your action.
You get to there as you come around
and see a guy in full black cloak
and some bullets (tssh) flying by,
shattering the stonework behind.
And then you see this humanoid character
holding a short sword at his side,
growling.
He sees you looming down the hallway
and his eyes go wide for a moment,
unexpected to see this giant train
of a muscled entity charging down.
TRAVIS: And the dash
was my bonus action right?
MATT: No, the dash is your action.
TRAVIS: So I have a bonus?
MATT: You have a bonus, yes.
TRAVIS: Can I look down and say,
"Hello, muppet."
And I would like to rage.
(all laugh)
MATT: All righty.
LIAM: Golf clap.
LAURA: Golf clap.
MARISHA: Good play, good play.
TRAVIS: Polite as fuck.
MATT: Keyleth, you're up.
MARISHA: Okay.
So this guy is by the door, yeah?
Or by the window?
MATT: Mm-hm.
MARISHA: How far away from the window?
Like, is his back up against the window?
MATT: Like - like basically just
stepped out of the window
and you were immediately next to it,
so the window is right to his left
as he's staring down at you
with a blade in the air.
MARISHA: It's an open window.
MATT: Yes.
MARISHA: Bars on it or something?
LAURA: He came in.
MATT: It looks like the window
is easy enough
for somebody to slip through.
It's an open window.
MARISHA: Okay.
TALIESIN: It's a nice neighborhood.
There's no bars on the windows.
MARISHA: I'm trying to think
which way I want to go with this.
MATT: Make it quick.
MARISHA: I'm going to towards him
do a Thunderwave push (boof)
and try and push him out the window.
Thunderwave.
MATT: So you're going
to move around him first?
MARISHA: Oh, does he have me
up against the window?
MATT: You're up against the wall.
If you want to Thunderwave him,
you'd have to get
on the other side of him
to knock him away from you.
MARISHA: And he'll get
an attack of opportunity, I'm assuming?
MATT: No, because you
don't leave his combat.
MARISHA: Oh. Okay, yeah,
I'll just shoulder around him.
MATT: You dart off the edge of the bed,
catching yourself on the ground,
turn around the other side and (boof).
What's the DC on that?
MARISHA: Jesus, I don't know.
I don't do this very often.
MATT: (singsong) DC of Thunderwave.
Vax, you're up next, prepare.
MARISHA: It is
a constitution saving throw.
MATT: And what's your spell DC?
MARISHA: 19.
MATT: That is a 9 + 2, 11.
That's not enough.
How much damage does he take?
MARISHA: He takes 2d8 damage
and he is pushed 10 feet.
MATT: All righty.
MARISHA: Hopefully out the window
because that's what I was going for.
TALIESIN: It's a small room.
MARISHA: That was cocked. 4 damage.
MATT: 4 points of thunder damage.
However, (boomf) it slams him back.
His feet hit the edge
of the the lip of the window.
He goes flipping backwards
out the side.
He's going to attempt
to reach out and grab it.
TRAVIS: Please fail.
MATT: That is a natural 2.
(all cheer)
MATT: (thwoop) You hear,
"Nooo!"
ASHLEY: Yes!
MATT: As he's flung out the window.
You don't even hear the landing,
he's just out of the room now.
TALIESIN: Full on Wilhelm scream.
TRAVIS: Nice. Nice job.
TALIESIN: (imitates Wilhelm scream)
LIAM: How about a Howard Dean?
MARISHA: And then I'm going to take just -
MATT: You have a few more...
15 more feet you can run, if you want to.
MARISHA: Okay.
I'm going to throw open the door
and just peek out the door
and see what's up.
MATT: Okay, you throw the door open.
Immediately out,
you see Grog standing in the hallway
clutching the axe,
kind of sleepy-eyed, but filled
with hatred and intent to kill,
while grinning
in the center of the hallway.
MARISHA: And then I’m going
to come over my comm and just say,
"Status report, where is everybody?"
And that’s it.
MATT: Okay, after Keyleth's turn,
that brings us to Vax.
LIAM: I can’t see
through the corner of the wall there.
Is Scanlan like 10 feet away?
5 feet away?
MATT: Scanlan is 10 feet from you.
LIAM: All right.
I’m going to skirt along on his side,
the rakshasa’s side, and shout out,
"It’s not Gilmore,
it’s a fucking demon!"
at Scanlan, and then
I’m going to use my first action
to try to disarm kitty-cat.
MARISHA: Meow.
MATT: Okay. All right.
LIAM: What is that?
TRAVIS: Disarm him?
MATT: Go ahead and make...
go ahead and make an attack roll -
or no, for this one,
let’s make an athletics check to try.
It’s essentially a type of grapple.
LIAM: All right.
Uh, 16.
MATT: 16.
Okay, you reach out
and manage to grab the Gilmore’s wrist,
holding the dagger.
His arm goes up
and starts clawing these fingernails,
these currently
not-even-visible fingernails
that all of a sudden
turn into these large hooks
that start tearing into your skin.
Go ahead and make a strength check
to see if you can
wrestle the blade from his grasp.
LIAM: And this is the next action?
MATT: This would be the next action, yeah.
Since you don’t have
any disarm-based abilities,
this is a more involved -
LIAM: 15. That’s still acrobatics, right?
MATT: No no no, this -
LIAM: What’d you say?
MATT: This is all athletics.
LIAM: This is athletics.
Same thing, sorry, yeah. 15.
MATT: Yeah, 15?
LIAM: 15.
MATT: You still have the grip on him,
but unfortunately his fingers
are too tight on the blade
and you can’t quite pull it out.
LIAM: Okay, then,
for the rest of my turn,
I whip my head to Scanlan, say,
"Follow me down. I’m going down."
And I want to drag him
off the balcony, and go with him.
MATT: Okay,
you can drag him at half-speed -
LIAM: Half-speed. I’m hasted.
MATT: Hasted.
LIAM: 12 squares, full.
MATT: (fwwsh)
(all shout)
MATT: You watch, Sam,
as he grabs
this apparently Gilmore character,
looks at you, tells you this,
and then they both just hit the edge
and tumble over the side of the balcony
and go falling off.
LIAM: This takes two seconds to go down.
I looked it up. 80 feet is two seconds.
MATT: Yep. (whoosh whoosh boomf)
You hear two impacts.
SAM: But I just got here!
Don’t leave!
MATT: Both you and Hotis...
36 points of damage
as you both (boomf)
hit the bottom, this stone surface,
essentially the ceiling
and the beginnings
of the entire castle here on the top,
both prone on the ground,
dazed from the impact.
LIAM: Really hoping the guards are awake.
LAURA: Really hoping.
MATT: All righty. Ending your turn,
that brings us to the assassins. So -
ASHLEY: But we didn’t -
LAURA: But we didn’t get to go.
LAURA: Do assassins get to go twice?
MATT: No, you guys go after them
because that
was how the initiative order happened.
LAURA: (biting noise)
TRAVIS: Yep.
LIAM: That was 3 points of damage.
MATT: Him yelling and waking you guys up
avoided them getting an auto-crit
on their first attack.
LAURA: Oh, shit.
TRAVIS: Oh, god.
MATT: So be happy that
at least you woke up for the last round.
LAURA: That’s good, that’s good.
ASHLEY: I’m happy, I’m happy.
TALIESIN: Thank you, Matt.
LIAM: So happy! Happy.
MATT: Happy.
TRAVIS: Thanks, Matt.
MATT: So that’s two strikes
against you, Pike,
and then this one here
looks over the shoulder
and sees you, Grog,
and is going to start darting this way...
and currently is out of sight.
MARISHA: The assassin doucher?
MATT: Yep.
MATT: The one that’s attacking you, Pike -
LIAM: I assume what I said to Scanlan
was heard over earring as well.
MATT: Most likely, yeah.
That’ll be a 22.
ASHLEY: Well, yes.
(all laugh)
MATT: You take 7 points
of piercing damage,
and roll
another constitution saving throw.
ASHLEY: 7 points?
MATT: Yep.
ASHLEY: Okay. That’s fine. 7 points.
MATT: And roll
a constitution saving throw when you can.
The second strike, this time,
you slam his hand with the shield
and you can see
he actually drops the blade
and has to rush over to pick it up.
ASHLEY: 13?
MATT: 13. You suffer 24 points
of poison damage
as the first strike this time
cuts you right across the clavicle
and down to the front of your chest,
and it’s just, that sharp burning pain
for a second
and as you knock the other hit away,
all of a sudden you feel the (oomf oomf).
Your ears fill with bright,
burning-hot warmth
and all of sudden
the pain from your wound
begins to pulse with every heartbeat
as the poison hits your system.
ASHLEY: Nice. Okay.
MATT: And he’s going to move this way
to start getting between you
and the doorway.
That’s going to end their turns.
Vex, you’re up.
LAURA: Okay. I’m going to get up,
I’m going to yell at Trinket
to run out the door,
and I’m going to grab my arrows
and my quiver and my broom.
MATT: Trinket’s going into a full -
we’ll say he can do a full dash.
LAURA: Can he get to the guy?
MATT: He’s gotten that far
up the hallway.
He doesn’t see anybody yet.
You grab your stuff. All right.
That’ll be an action to
get all of your things together.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: Your quiver, your arrows…
LAURA: The broom.
MATT: The broom.
LAURA: And I take off running
to the west tower.
So we don’t see the guy
outside of Percy’s room?
MATT: Nope.
That’s as far as you get, there.
Cool. That ends Vex’s turn.
Pike, you’re up.
ASHLEY: Okay. So, I’m going to
take out my hand,
and I’m going to Guiding Bolt him.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Take out your hand?
TRAVIS: I’m going to take out my hand!
ASHLEY: My trusty old hand.
MATT: The wound across your chest
with the pulsing poison,
suddenly the area that was once dark
begins to light up
as the holy symbol that forever hangs
around your neck
begins to glow
with vibrant divine energy,
this whitish-yellow pulse of light.
The assassin, standing there grinning,
seeing that he’s getting the upper hand,
all of a sudden realizes
that you aren’t as disarmed
as he thought you were.
Go ahead and roll for the attack on this.
TRAVIS: Smoke him!
ASHLEY: 28.
MATT: That’ll hit.
Go ahead and roll damage on that.
What level were you casting it at?
ASHLEY: I’m going to do it at 4.
MATT: Usually you decide that
before you roll the attack, but yeah.
ASHLEY: Okay.
TRAVIS: Puddins, Pike.
ASHLEY: I was going to.
That’s what I was going to do.
MATT: I assumed you were.
That’s fine.
ASHLEY: But I didn’t tell you that.
How many do I roll?
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
MATT: Let me look it up for you.
Guiding Bolt is 4d6 -
ASHLEY: 7, right?
MATT: - and then it would be
an additional 3d6
for 7d6 radiant damage against him.
ASHLEY: Yeah, 7, okay.
Okay, so.
TRAVIS: Yep, 8.
ASHLEY: 8.
TRAVIS: 11, 19.
TRAVIS: 7, 26.
LAURA: One more.
ASHLEY: What was it?
TRAVIS: 27.
ASHLEY: 27 points.
MATT: 27 points, nice.
You see his eyes widen
as suddenly you blast him in the face
with this Guiding Bolt.
The impact just (boof)
bursting across him,
leaving this trail of divine fire
that’s burning around the seams
of his leather armor.
He’s trying to pat it out,
but it won’t go out.
While it’s not burning him,
it’s lighting him up
like a Christmas tree,
and Grog, you see -
from underneath Pike’s door,
you see a little bit
of a bright divine glow
flash out from under the door
and you hear a couple thumps
against the wood from inside the room.
TRAVIS: And that’s her,
the one to the right of me?
LAURA: Yeah, which ones
are everybody’s rooms?
MATT: This is Vex’s room,
Keyleth’s, Pike’s, Percy -
SAM: The one that smells like patchouli
is mine.
MATT: Yeah. Scanlan’s and Grog’s
and Vax’s were over here.
LAURA: Okay.
ASHLEY: So can I move
out of the room?
MATT: You can try to, yeah.
ASHLEY: I grabbed all my stuff
and then I’m going to make my way out.
MATT: Okay, all your stuff would be -
You have your shield already
that you pulled off the side.
You can grab maybe one weapon and go.
You’re not going to get armor, though.
ASHLEY: I’ll grab my mace.
MATT: So you grab your mace, all right.
LIAM: You’re in a slip or nothing, so.
ASHLEY: I sleep naked.
TRAVIS: Thatta girl!
SAM: So you’re naked
with a shield and a mace.
TRAVIS: That’s a bad bitch.
LAURA: Hell yeah, she is.
LIAM: Monster!
MATT: Shield, mace, holy symbol -
ASHLEY: Do I have my gauntlets on or no?
MATT: Nothing else.
Yeah, your gauntlets are on.
ASHLEY: Okay.
MATT: We’ll say the gauntlets were there,
you slip them on real fast.
As he’s pulled back
and trying to pat out the flames,
you grab your things and rush through.
He does get
an attack of opportunity on you
as you run out of his combat range,
so he’s going to swing at you.
MATT: That is going to be a 16.
ASHLEY: Yeah.
MATT: That does hit.
With your shield, what’s your AC?
It would be 11-13, so yeah, it still hits.
So you take 5 points
of piercing damage.
I need you to roll
another constitution saving throw.
SAM: Man. Pikey.
ASHLEY: That is a 5?
MATT: You take another 24
of poison damage.
SAM: Oh my gosh, she going to die.
LAURA: Oh, no!
ASHLEY: No no no, I don’t think
I’m uncon - wait, 24 points?
ASHLEY: I got one hit point left.
SAM: How did that happen so fast?
LAURA: She took 24 twice!
TRAVIS: Poison sucks.
MATT: Assassins, man.
SAM: What are these assassins?
MARISHA: Bullshit.
LIAM: Heal and run, heal and run,
heal and run.
ASHLEY: Okay.
MATT: All righty.
TRAVIS: Does she burst out in the hallway
naked with a mace and a shield?
MATT: Naked with a mace and shield,
glowing holy symbol,
and just gash across her chest,
blood pouring from the wound.
LAURA: Oh, Pike!
MATT: Sweat on her brow,
one eye’s half-closed.
MATT: She’s barely standing.
SAM: And weirdly hairy shoulders.
(all laugh)
LIAM: That’s why
I never take the armor off, guys.
MARISHA: No!
ASHLEY: And hairy chest.
Just full hairy chest.
MATT: Ending Pike’s turn.
SAM: Oh, god. I never knew.
MATT: Percy, you’re up.
LIAM: Still love me, Scanlan?
TALIESIN: I’m going to run out of my -
I’m grabbing just the basics.
Gloves and the gunbelt
and my gun stuff. No armor.
SAM: Gun stuff.
TALIESIN: No amulet.
Running out in the front, what do I -
MATT: Amulet, you would probably -
you don’t need to take that off to sleep,
so I’ll let you have that.
TALIESIN: Okay, so fine,
I’ll just have that.
All right, so no armor, so.
TALIESIN: Which direction is the west?
MATT: This way.
TALIESIN: It’s this way,
and do I see any, I don’t see what -
MATT: You don’t see anyone,
you just see Pike burst out
of her room suddenly, bloodied.
TALIESIN: Okay, I’m going to
run past her room towards the west,
and do I have a view right there?
MATT: You now have a view of a guy
beaming with divine light,
trying to pat out divine flames
after swinging
and getting a nice heavy wound on Pike,
who looks like she’s barely standing.
TALIESIN: Okay,
I’m going to take a couple -
LIAM: Fuck him up. Fuck him up.
TRAVIS: If he takes care of you, though...
TALIESIN: I get one foot, stop,
turn around.
I draw my sword and I’m just going to
go stabby on the bastard
because I haven’t reloaded my gun yet.
TRAVIS: That was in Pike’s room?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Good, okay.
TALIESIN: I can get there.
MATT: This is the end
of your movement.
TALIESIN: Oh, right there? Okay.
Then fine, I’ll just unload the gun.
That’ll be fun.
MATT: So you have a fourth shot.
TALIESIN: I have a fourth shot
and then another one, yeah.
MATT: Okay. Regular shot?
TALIESIN: No, sharpshooter.
MATT: Sharpshooter, okay.
You have advantage on this shot,
by the way,
because of the Guiding Bolt
that she did to him.
SAM: Ooh!
TALIESIN: Oh, I do?
MATT: Yeah, because the divine fire
that’s surrounding him
is lighting him up
like a giant birthday candle.
TALIESIN: All right, that’ll be 28 to hit.
MATT: That’ll hit.
MATT: Go ahead
and roll damage on that one.
SAM: Hashtag gun stuff.
LIAM: Quentin Tarantino joined.
TALIESIN: 22 points of damage.
LIAM AND MARISHA: Gun stuff.
MATT: (gunshot sound)
The Guiding Bolt flares off.
The impact hits him
and sends him on his back foot.
He looks over and sees
the smoke pouring out of the barrel
as you’re aiming down for another shot.
You reload real fast.
TALIESIN: Taking another shot at him.
MATT: Go for it.
TALIESIN: Advantage?
MATT: No, that was just the first one.
TALIESIN: That’s okay,
I still rolled really great.
(all laugh)
ASHLEY: That’s okay, I still rolled well.
TALIESIN: I was hoping for a critical,
but whatever.
LAURA: Yeah, I’m not going to need it.
ASHLEY: Fucking nailed it.
MATT: Just wanted to check.
TALIESIN: 25 to hit.
MATT: The dungeon master
will remember this.
No, it’s fine.
So go ahead and roll damage.
Sharpshooter as well?
TALIESIN: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It was...
24 points of damage.
MATT: 24 points of damage...
(gunshot) The second shot.
You reload, fire again.
This time this one hits him
right square in what looks like
the side of his jaw,
shattered his cheekbone and his jaw
and there’s now blood and teeth
pouring out
and he’s clutching the side of it,
shaking his head.
He’s in a really bad place right now
and is looking over the back window,
realizing he’s probably going to -
TALIESIN: Fuck it, let’s burn
an Action Surge. This’ll be funny.
LAURA: Percy tastes blood.
TALIESIN: That’s, 16, 17, 18, 19... 25?
MATT: That hits.
ASHLEY: Get him!
TALIESIN: That’s 19 points of damage?
MATT: With that, as he’s turning around,
about to dart towards the window,
as he spins around in his space,
you take aim a second,
or now a third time on him, fire...
You watch. It’s obscured to see;
all you see is the moonlight
from the outside sky coming through
and the silhouette of his head,
and now the missing silhouette
of his head -
as you scatter the top half of his skull
across the stone
surrounding the window in Pike’s room.
ASHLEY: Thanks, Percy.
TALIESIN: I reload.
ASHLEY: I had him, but thanks.
TALIESIN: I drop a health potion
and then steady to take care of that
and reload my guns
with the rest of my turn.
MATT: Okay. Good to know.
All right. Ending Percy’s turn,
you’re currently on the ground now,
you’re both prone.
Hotis stands up,
using half of his movement,
looks down at you,
"You’re clever."
Which, for the record,
the illusion has faded.
The Gilmore visage is no more.
Now you see before you the angry,
curled bare-teeth face
of the familiar rakshasa.
"The feeling’s mutual."
As you are currently
prone on the ground,
it has advantage on you.
It's going to go ahead and...
make two strikes
with the dagger against you.
With advantage,
yeah, that’ll be 25?
LIAM: He didn’t redip, though.
I don’t remember you saying
he redipped, right?
He used his poison last time
and I made the save?
MATT: Correct.
LIAM: Right? Okay.
LIAM: So that hits. Uncanny Dodge?
MATT: Right. So the first one hits.
MATT: You take...
10 points of piercing damage. No poison.
ASHLEY: I’m sorry, I’m sorry.
Sorry, I’m nervously playing with it.
LIAM: Sorry. One more time?
MATT: 10 points of piercing damage.
LIAM: Yes.
MATT: He’s going to dip the blade,
remembering that he forgot that
after the first strike.
Then with the second strike
he’s going to stab down once more.
LIAM: That’s just a bonus to do that?
MATT: Yeah. That’s going to be a 21.
You suffer 11 points
of piercing damage.
Plus 10 points of poison damage.
LAURA: No more!
LIAM: I’m unconscious.
MATT: Unconscious.
So as you get up,
he just stabs and stabs again,
and this time as your finger’s extended
the pain hits you
and you just watch your vision
fade to darkness.
LAURA: No.
MATT: That’s the end of his turn.
He has no more attacks,
so he just watches you go limp.
LIAM: For my turn, I’ll be dead.
LAURA: No.
MATT: All right.
Well, Scanlan, you’re up first.
SAM: I go to the ledge and look over.
MATT: Yeah, you look over the ledge,
down about 70 feet,
80 feet on the stonework,
you see and watch as the rakshasa,
now fully visible, Gilmore visage gone,
jams the blade twice
into the currently laid-out back of Vax,
as the back's body goes limp,
unconscious.
Drawing the blade, chuckling,
throwing it up in the air, catching it,
and is preparing to go down
for some finishing blows.
SAM: Okay, shit.
My stuff doesn’t go that far, does it?
Any of my vocal spells, only goes 60 -
MATT: Only about 60 feet, yeah.
SAM: Yeah, fuck. All right.
Well then, for my action-slash-attack,
I, overcome with fury
seeing my friend on the ground,
pull out Mythcarver
and just fucking jump and plunge.
LAURA: Oh my god!
TALIESIN: Yes!
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: Yes yes yes.
MATT: So you leap, (shhh) -
SAM: And I have advantage
because I’ve inspired myself.
(all laugh)
MATT: I’ll say for the purposes
of this action,
you will have advantage
on the strike, as -
SAM: But I’m also exhausted.
MATT: Right, but that doesn’t affect
your actual attack roll.
That’s more your ability check.
Actually, you should have
had disadvantage earlier for that.
SAM: I rolled twice for that.
MATT: Oh, you did? Okay, good.
MATT: So as you come down, quiet.
Currently overcome with the now
possibility of vengeance before it,
the rakshasa does not seem
to notice you
as you fall off silently, blade down,
(whoosh) wind rushing past your face,
the tunnel-vision before you
as you can see
this whole scene play out before you.
The blade comes down, slamming.
Go ahead and roll with advantage
your attack against the rakshasa.
SAM: 14. 15. Plus I don’t know what!
I don’t do these things!
TRAVIS: I’ve never hit!
SAM: Strength? Is that strength?
MATT: It should be written on your attack.
It would be
your proficiency bonus plus your -
SAM: Oh, it’s +8.
MATT: Yeah, so.
SAM: That’s a 23.
TALIESIN: 23.
MATT: 23 definitely hits.
TRAVIS: Nice.
SAM: Okay.
ASHLEY: Nicely done!
SAM: I don’t know what to do now.
I roll a d8?
MATT: Go ahead and roll your d8
plus damage.
SAM: Okay. 8 + 3, so that’s 11.
Plus 1d6 force damage. 6! Holy shit!
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: This is happening.
This is happening.
SAM: So that’s 11, that’s 17. Right?
MATT: 17?
SAM: Okay.
MATT: I’m adding to that attack
half of the damage you take from the fall.
Because of the force
of yourself and the blade.
So the damage
you take from the fall...
TRAVIS: I don’t know
what that expression was.
LAURA: Yeah, I know,
is that good or bad? Both?
TALIESIN: It’s either a lot or a little.
MATT: 29 points of damage you suffer,
slamming into the ground
and falling prone from the attack.
But he does suffer
an additional 14 points of damage
as the blade (sssh) just sinks
into the shoulder and the torso
and he tenses in pain
as the blade is still jammed
into his form.
You let go of it
as you slam into the ground
and he draws it out with a spurt of blood
and throws it to the ground angrily,
spinning around towards you,
still holding the dagger aloft,
looking over.
SAM: Do I still get my bonus action?
MATT: You do, technically, yeah.
SAM: Okay, so I, on the ground,
turn over to Vax
and I’ll bonus Healing Word him.
LAURA: Oh, thank god.
SAM: And I will sing with whatever wind
I have left in my body,
"(singing) Vax’ildan,
you’re going to put up a good fight,
"Vax’ildan,
I need you to put up a good fight.
"Put up a good fight!
Put up a good fight!"
TRAVIS: (laughing) Is that "Roxanne?"
SAM: That’s "Roxanne."
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: I couldn’t even join in
because it was so good.
LIAM: So in love with you right now.
So in love with you.
SAM: 4! I’m rolling great!
Plus 5. So you have 9 hit points!
MATT: So you come back to consciousness
face-down on the ground,
scattered out on the stonework
and the last thing,
as your eyes come open,
you hear the gentle tunes
of Scanlan’s voice
calling you back from the darkness.
You glance out the corner of your eye
and see that Hotis is still standing
with the dagger up on top.
LIAM: It was just my turn
in the initiative. Can I go?
MATT: No, your turn’s not yet.
We have Grog, Keyleth, and then you.
They actually got initiative
higher than you, so.
LIAM: Oh, okay, okay.
MATT: We’re coming to you, don’t worry.
So your turn hasn’t happened yet.
LIAM: Okay. I totally -
I trust in you, Matt.
MATT: All righty.
LIAM: And fear you.
MATT: Good.
All right, that brings us to...
Grog, you’re up.
TRAVIS: So I heard him say,
"I’m going down," right?
We all heard him say
he’s going down as he was falling?
MATT: Roll an intelligence check.
SAM: Oh, boy.
TRAVIS: This’ll be great. Ah! 18 minus...
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: Minus 2. 16.
MATT: 16. It takes you a moment,
and you have to bite your tongue
for a moment
as you’re running down the hallway,
but you ascertain that probably means...
It’s a tower,
Probably jumped off the tower!
TRAVIS: Yeah, probably.
I look out and I say,
"Oh, Pike,
you’re in your birthday suit!
"Are you all right?"
ASHLEY: Yeah, I’m fine,
I’m fine, I’m fine.
SAM: She’s bleeding all over.
ASHLEY: Wait, did I take -
I took a potion on the -
MATT: Well, he had the potion
on the ground.
TALIESIN: I threw you a minor.
It’s not much.
ASHLEY: I’m going to be fine,
I’m going to be fine.
TRAVIS: Okay.
Is there a window in the hallway?
My question is,
is the courtyard through those windows?
MATT: The courtyard
would be over here, actually.
TRAVIS: Right. Is there -
MARISHA: In relation to where we are?
MATT: This is no longer
really part of the deal,
so in relation to where you guys are,
they’re about here.
TRAVIS: Do all of the rooms have windows,
or is there a window in the hallway?
MATT: All of the rooms that have windows
are the ones on that side,
so currently the only way to get here
would be to travel
back where you came from
and find an exit out to the top of the -
TRAVIS: Fucking ass.
MARISHA: I was going to
try and handle that.
TALIESIN: Do those stairs go
to the west tower, by the way?
MATT: These stairs go
to the west tower, yes.
TALIESIN: Cool, just checking.
TRAVIS: Can I hold my...
turn until Keyleth goes?
MATT: All right.
You can still move, though,
if you want to.
TRAVIS: I will - where are you?
MARISHA: I’m right behind you.
In the room, in the door behind you.
TRAVIS: Yeah, but I can go back in.
LAURA: Okay.
TRAVIS: I should just stay there
if you’re going to make a door.
MARISHA: Hey, Grog!
TRAVIS: What?
MARISHA: You want to jump
from really high?
TRAVIS: Yeah. I just want out.
MARISHA: All right.
TRAVIS: So I’ll hold until Keyleth goes,
and I won’t move.
I’ll stay there,
because she’s right beside -
MATT: What action are you holding?
TRAVIS: I will hold my... movement.
MATT: Well, no, I mean, the movement
gets used in your turn regardless.
You just choose what action
you want to hold as a trigger,
so if something’s going to happen,
you would then use
whatever your action is.
Your movement you have to use now,
or it’s lost.
TRAVIS: I have to choose
what she’s going to do? I'm so confused.
LAURA: Well, you won’t be able to move
once she goes.
You won’t be able to do an action
because you’re trapping yourself.
TALIESIN: It's like,
"I’m holding everything
"until she makes a door."
MATT: Your impulse hit now
and if you decide not to move,
then the impulse
loses the movement, so.
TRAVIS: I don’t know.
I don’t know what to say, I -
SAM: Yeah, you can’t really do anything.
TRAVIS: Yeah. I don’t move.
MARISHA: He’s just holding his action -
TRAVIS: I decide to stand still.
SAM: Yeah, but just to get
through this portal,
he’s going to have to move.
It’s a whole other turn.
TRAVIS: Otherwise,
I’m running down a hallway for no reason.
I just don’t move.
I just stand there dumbfounded
that Pike is naked and cut to shit.
MATT: Okay. That ends Grog’s turn.
You’re up.
MARISHA: Okay. I’m going to reach over,
put on my circlet in my nightgown.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: And I’m going to step out,
look left and right.
Okay. And then,
going off what Grog was saying,
I’m going to walk behind Grog
and I’m going to do Stone Shape.
I’m going to blast a door into that wall,
blast a giant hole. Yeah.
MATT: All right. (boof)
As you tear this wall open there -
MARISHA: Yeah, dude. Yeah.
LAURA: Awesome.
MATT: - it opens up before you
and you can see a little bit of it
gets pushed to the side,
because it’s a little bit elevated
from the the roof area,
but you force it upward
to where it bursts open
and creates a slight ramp
that leads up
to what would be the roof
of this part of Whitestone Castle.
MARISHA: Okay. Cool. And then I’ll -
Can I see Pike from where I am?
MATT: You can, yes.
MARISHA: I’m going to look at her
and give her a Healing Word,
just a level 1 Healing Word.
MATT: All right.
MARISHA: You are going to heal -
ASHLEY: Thanks, pal.
MARISHA: Oh, it’s not great.
Sorry.
MARISHA: So 7 points.
ASHLEY: I’ll take it.
MATT: All right.
You still have a little bit of movement
if you want to use it.
MARISHA: I’ll step back a little bit
out of Grog’s way.
MATT: Okay. There you go.
MARISHA: Not that, back towards you.
MATT: Okay, got you.
So it’d be there, probably,
far as you can get.
MARISHA: Sure, yeah.
So he can get by.
MATT: All right, cool.
That brings us to Vax. Your turn.
MARISHA: Oh, Grog.
TRAVIS: No, but I can’t do anything.
MARISHA: You can’t do anything?
MARISHA: Oh, I thought he held -
MATT: You didn’t say
you were holding an action for anything.
TRAVIS: I wanted to move through the door
once she made it.
MATT: I’ll let you do it.
You’re generally not supposed to do -
TRAVIS: What do I say, I hold a dash?
Or a hold a movement?
MATT: Say you hold a dash.
You could do that, yeah.
TRAVIS: Oh, okay.
I would like to hold a dash.
MATT: Okay. So yeah,
then you just go ahead and -
TRAVIS: We’re still learning.
TALIESIN: You can hold a dash
for Keyleth’s turn.
TALIESIN AND TRAVIS:
Hold a dash for Keyleth’s turn.
TALIESIN: And then she moves
and then you go.
TRAVIS: I didn’t do my homework.
MATT: So as Keyleth opens the window,
you dash up and rush onto the rooftop,
and there you can see
across the way...
MARISHA: I give him a good-game
smack on the ass as he runs by.
SAM: Naked ass.
LAURA: He’s got his normal clothes on.
LIAM: Always naked.
TALIESIN: He’s naked.
LAURA: We’re all naked.
TRAVIS: Well, I only sleep naked
in the lady-favors house.
LIAM: Question.
Grabbing a weapon off the ground,
that’s a freebie, right?
Is that a bonus action?
I feel like that’s - I think that’s free?
MATT: As part of an action,
you can pick it -
LIAM: Part of an action?
All right, great.
I’m going to thank the Raven Queen
for my family
and cast Lay on Hands on myself,
take back 5 hit points.
I see Mythcarver on the ground.
I’m going to grab it
and use my movement to stand,
and I also noticed
that we’re flanking Hotis,
so I’m going to sneak-attack
the motherfucker up the back.
MATT: All right. Just as a note,
the way that the bonus attack works -
well, this is with your haste ability.
LIAM: Yeah, I’m hasted.
The bonus action was -
Oh, no, the action, right.
The action was the spell.
MATT: The haste would’ve faded
once you went unconscious.
LIAM: Oh, okay. That’s okay.
I have one action still.
MATT: Well, you have an action,
and then you have your offhand strike.
Offhand strike works
as part of the attack action.
If you use your action for anything else,
you don’t get the bonus attack.
MARISHA: So is picking something up
not a free action?
I thought picking up a weapon
was a free action.
MATT: It’s part of an action.
Don’t worry about it.
It’s fine, let’s do it.
LIAM: I didn’t even -
no no no, do it the real way, man.
I don’t want any mulligans.
MATT: No, the idea would be,
you don’t get a free bonus attack
with any other action.
It’s whatever you’re attacking,
you then get to throw this in this way.
LIAM: Well, let me ask you this
because if I understood that
I wouldn’t have cast the spell,
so I’m happy to skip the spell
and then cut the -
MATT: Okay, that’s fine. We’ll do that.
As part of the action economy,
the idea is
that because you’re attacking with one,
you can give yourself an opening
to get a quick strike with the other.
LIAM: So it has to go with another attack.
Now I understand.
So if I had understood -
thank you, thank you.
I’ll take that mulligan for understanding.
So now I’m going to stab him
with Mythcarver through the back.
LIAM: Flanked.
MATT: Yes.
LIAM: And flanked is at advantage, yeah?
MATT: No.
LIAM: An ally nearby, was it not?
MATT: Technically, he’s not flanked
because the other ally is prone
and is not currently
threatening his face -
LIAM: All right, that misses, then.
MARISHA: Fucking fuck.
LIAM: So I’ve used an action
but not the bonus action,
so I’m going to disengage.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: And I’m going to dart back,
as far away from him as I can get.
ASHLEY, LAURA, AND TALIESIN:
(silly voices) D&D!
LIAM: 12 speed - the boots are off.
6, got it. Yeah, got it.
MATT: All right, there you go.
That brings us to...
At this point,
waiting around this way.
As you guys are all distracted
at this point,
turns around, takes a dagger.
MARISHA: Who?
LAURA: There’s another guy?
MARISHA: Where did he come from?
TALIESIN: That’s the one
that ran that way. He’s mine.
MARISHA: That yours? The little shit.
LIAM: By the way,
the Whitestone guards are shit.
MARISHA: Yeah, no shit.
LAURA: This is all happening so fast!
LIAM: Don’t they stand on the wall?
Don’t they stand on places?
SAM: It’s movie night.
They’re all watching The Sound of Music
in the rec room.
TRAVIS: Vasselheim, yeah,
they’re on the lax.
LIAM: Whitestone, Whitestone.
TRAVIS: I mean Whitestone.
MATT: This is all, like, 3 a.m.
at Whitestone Castle right now.
That being the case,
the guard makes two dagger attacks.
One at you, Percy,
and one at you, Pike.
That’s natural 20 against you, Percy.
TALIESIN: Natural 20 against me?
MATT: Yes.
TALIESIN: Goddamn it.
Where’s my goddamn - ah, shit.
SAM: What do you need?
What? What’s wrong?
MATT: No, it’s okay. He rolled a 1.
So you take
6 points of piercing damage.
TALIESIN: I was going to try and grab it.
I’m just trying to find my -
my dagger seems to have vanished.
Yeah, I can’t find my dagger
for some reason. My gloves.
MATT: That would be 18 against you, Pike?
That does hit you.
ASHLEY: Does hit.
MATT: You take 4 points
of piercing damage.
ASHLEY: Okay okay okay okay okay.
TRAVIS: Okay okay okay.
TALIESIN: I think the snare glove is 1d8.
MATT: 1d10, actually.
TALIESIN: 1d10. That’s even better.
MATT: Because he hit you first -
ASHLEY: I’m still alive.
MATT: - it’s sneak attack
on top of that. He was hidden.
So that was 6, plus...
34 points of piercing damage, all together.
TALIESIN: Dropped to 23.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: Yeah. so. That’s right.
MARISHA: Yeah, don’t do that.
TALIESIN: No, I’m not thinking.
There we go.
MATT: All righty.
MARISHA: All right.
MATT: That finishes their turn.
Vex, you’re up.
LAURA: Me?
MATT: Yes.
LAURA: Okay, the wall just opened up,
so I’m going to shout for Trinket
to run after the assassin
throwing the knives.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: And I’m going to run
out the doorway.
If I go up on my broom,
will I be able to see them
down in the courtyard?
MATT: From this perspective? No.
LAURA: I mean, if I run out the door -
right, right.
MATT: If you run out the door...
is this all on the broom?
LAURA: Well, if I’m in the air,
can I see down at...
MATT: You’d be able to from -
MARISHA: Jazz hands?
TALIESIN: (singing) You’ll be swell.
TALIESIN, ASHLEY, AND LAURA:
(singing) You’ll be great.
TRAVIS: (singing)
You’ve got the world on...
TRAVIS AND ASHLEY: (singing) a plate.
MATT: Yeah, so from up there
as you (shhh) shoot out above,
looking down, you can see
where they lie on the battlefield there.
LAURA: I want to shoot the rakshasa!
(all laugh)
MATT: Go for it.
LAURA: Yes! I’m going to use
my Longbow of the Sky Sentinel.
MATT: All righty.
SAM: You were born for this stuff.
ASHLEY: I want to shoot the rakshasa!
LAURA: Okay.
I make an attack roll for three arrows.
Okay, that’s a good one. That is 31.
MATT: 31? Hits.
LAURA: Yes. As the first hit.
LAURA: 19 is the second?
MATT: That does hit.
TRAVIS: Nice.
LAURA: And 22 is the third.
MATT: Okay. Just as a note,
what’s your alignment?
LAURA: No, I’m neutral.
Chaotic neutral.
MATT: Okay, cool, just checking.
All right, so go ahead and roll damage.
LAURA: Why?!
ASHLEY: What does that mean?
LIAM: I know what it means.
SAM: I don’t know what it means.
TRAVIS: You do know what it means?
LIAM: I do.
LAURA: Does that mean
I do not as good damage to him
or something?
LIAM: Sort of.
LAURA: God darn it. Okay, wait.
TRAVIS: That fucking smirk.
LIAM: Sort of.
LAURA: Hold on. I’m just
going to roll the first attack,
because I’m stupid.
Great. 12 for the first
because I forgot
to Hunter’s Mark him
because I’m a genius
because I’m just so worked up
because my brother’s in trouble.
TRAVIS: As per uzh.
LAURA: Gosh darn it.
LIAM: This shit ain’t my fault.
MATT: As a note,
your rage would have faded
because you had gotten no damage,
but you also could have used
your bonus action last turn
for your rage.
TRAVIS: Which I totally whispered,
but just not loud enough.
MATT: That's what I figured.
SAM: We’re on point today.
TRAVIS: You are omnipotent, my man.
LAURA: 9 for the second attack.
MATT: All righty.
LAURA: Oh, I haven’t been adding
for the bracers.
Add 4 extra to what I told you.
MATT: All righty.
LAURA: 18 for the last.
MATT: Nice.
LAURA: No, 20 for the last.
I’m sorry, Matt.
I’m freaking out.
LIAM: So cruel, so cruel, so cruel.
MATT: You rush up in the air,
and these were with disadvantage
on all the attack rolls
because you’re on your broom?
TALIESIN: I swear
I’ll finish it eventually.
I swear, I swear.
MATT: Roll three more dice
and we’ll see if I negate any of these.
First one is?
LIAM: (laughs) 1.
MATT: First attack, nope,
and I need you to roll a dexterity check.
LAURA: Natural 20.
SAM: Whoa!
MATT: Okay, so you stay on the broom,
you don’t fall off.
LIAM: Yeah.
SAM: She’s surfing on the broom.
LIAM: No pressure.
MATT: Roll -
LAURA: The second one I already rolled.
It's a 25 for the second.
MATT: Okay.
Roll again for the third one.
LAURA: (fake-cries)
LAURA: What is that? 20.
ASHLEY: 21.
LAURA: 21 for the last.
MATT: Okay, so the last two still hit.
LAURA: Okay, do I have to roll...
oh no, do I have to roll again for -
TRAVIS: No, you stayed on.
MATT: No, you stayed on. You’re fine.
MATT: Essentially, as you rushed up,
you saw him, you took aim,
but you almost fell off the side.
The first arrow goes far.
The other two that split off
do manage to make their hit,
but the first one
does streak off into the sky.
You right yourself back up on the broom,
but that’s the end of your turn.
LAURA: Wait, I get another attack.
MATT: You do,
because that was the first one.
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: All right. Go ahead and roll.
LAURA: My second one -
can I use my bonus action? Sorry.
MATT: No.
LAURA: Not in between my two attacks?
MATT: What are you going to use it for?
LAURA: Hunter’s Mark!
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: It’s really just a stink-eye.
ASHLEY: I want to shoot the rakshasa!
MATT: You watch as your mark...
has no effect.
TRAVIS: It has no effect?
LAURA: Oh, that’s right.
He’s a rakshasa. He’s an asshole.
TRAVIS: Why does it have no effect?
TRAVIS: Tigers resist Hunter’s Mark?
LAURA: I don’t know why.
MATT: You’ve never actually
fought one before, Laura.
LAURA: No, I don’t know why, but -
ASHLEY: Tiger’s resistance?
LAURA: - he didn’t seem to be affected.
ASHLEY: Tiger bomb?
TALIESIN: It’s the eye of the tiger.
MARISHA: Tiger bomb.
MATT: You try and focus
your intent on attacking him
and yet it doesn’t seem to find its form.
LAURA: 19 for the last, with disadvantage.
MATT: That does hit. Roll the last attack.
LAURA: Okay. Okay okay okay.
LIAM: Okay okay okay.
MATT: Pike, you’re up next.
LAURA: Oh, no,
I don’t get any additional -
MATT: Nope.
LAURA: - so that’s just 14.
TRAVIS: Why don’t you get any additional?
LAURA: Because I don’t get
any storm damage.
MATT: So you pull -
LAURA: Oh, but -
MATT: B-b-b!
LAURA: No, I didn’t say that was true.
LAURA: I didn’t say that was
through the flaming bowstring, did I?
Because I was so distracted
by the Hunter’s Mark.
MATT: All right. That finishes your turn.
Pike, you’re up.
ASHLEY: Okay, so I’m going to
cast Cure Wounds on myself.
MATT: Go for it.
ASHLEY: Okay.
MATT: What level?
ASHLEY: 5.
SAM: Yeah!
MATT: (laughs) 5th. Go for it.
So 5d8.
ASHLEY AND TRAVIS: (count quietly)
SAM: 5d8?
MATT: Yeah, 5d8 + 5.
TRAVIS: 21.
ASHLEY: That’s the last one?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
ASHLEY: Okay, 21 points.
MATT: You heal yourself 21 points.
ASHLEY: Okay.
MATT: What else you doing now?
MATT: You see Trinket
run around the corner
and is now currently in the face
of the assassin
that just threw a blade at you.
And the rest of the party’s
running through this hole.
ASHLEY: How close can I get to the hole?
MATT: You can get about there.
ASHLEY: Okay.
So I’m going to go to there.
MATT: Okay, so you run around
to that area there.
ASHLEY: And then I’m going to
create a Spiritual Weapon.
MATT: Okay.
ASHLEY: Can I send it
down to the rakshasa?
MATT: You don’t know
where the rakshasa is.
ASHLEY: I don’t know
MATT: You have no idea, no visual cue.
You just see a hole in the stone wall
that everyone’s rushing through
and that’s the most that you know.
ASHLEY: Okay, so you know what?
Can I nix that?
MATT: Yep, you can do that.
ASHLEY: I’m going to
cast Shield of Faith on myself.
MATT: Okay.
ASHLEY: So that will bring me up to -
because I’m 13 right now with the shield?
MATT: Yes, that’ll bring you to 15.
So you have that
on your concentration.
Good call. Percy, you’re up.
TALIESIN: Can I see that jerk
who just threw the knife at me?
MATT: No, he ducked around the corner
and Trinket gave chase.
TALIESIN: Okay, I’m going to
roll towards that corner as well.
MATT: This corner?
TALIESIN: Yeah, I’m going that way.
MATT: Come around the corner that way
and you see Trinket harrying the guy.
LIAM: Run, Steve Martin, run.
TALIESIN: (laughs)
I’m taking some shots at him.
MATT: Go for it.
TALIESIN: Sharpshooter.
LAURA: Trinket instinctually ducks.
TALIESIN: I will not hit Trinket. 24?
MATT: Hits.
TALIESIN: Yeah, that’ll do it.
25 points of damage.
MATT: Hoo.
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: (gunshot) Giant blast
as one of his shoulders is blown back.
You see a spatter of blood
across the stairs behind him
and he almost stumbles
back into the stairs.
Trinket’s using this position
to move even closer and snarl.
He’s feeling closed off.
TALIESIN: Taking another shot.
MATT: Go for it.
TALIESIN: Sharpshooter.
That’s 19?
MATT: Hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
TALIESIN: Hee! 24.
ASHLEY: Dang.
MATT: All righty.
TALIESIN: Another shot.
LIAM: Consistent.
MATT: (tssh) This one
actually hits him
right above the pectoral muscle
and blows him back,
now almost leaning against the stairs,
these two big wounds
right in the middle of his chest.
SAM: I think you’ll
probably have mercy on him, right?
TALIESIN: Yeah, no,
I’m actually going to hire him.
He’s been great.
MARISHA: Could be an intern.
TALIESIN: (laughs) I can’t count
when you do that. 24.
MATT: 24?
TALIESIN: 24.
MATT: All right, that hits.
TALIESIN: Come on. 18.
SAM: Jesus.
MARISHA: Kill him. Kill him.
TALIESIN: 6 + 10.
But I get a -5 to my attack.
MATT: Yeah, with this one,
as you pull back, final shot,
you fire and it (fwoomp),
right through the forehead.
Eyes roll back as Trinket lunges
and tears the throat out.
TALIESIN: I keep running by them
right up the hill.
LAURA: Midnight snack!
LIAM: Take it, DiCaprio!
MATT: That’s as far as you make it,
full movement.
LAURA: He does the paw thing.
ASHLEY: Wait,
are all the assassins gone now?
MATT: You only saw two.
ASHLEY: And you just killed one.
TALIESIN: Mine’s dead and yours is dead.
ASHLEY: Or two. Okay.
TALIESIN: We don’t know about any others.
TRAVIS: He smoked both of them, yeah.
MATT: All right.
That ends your turn, Percy.
TALIESIN: Yep.
MATT: All right.
SAM: Trinket’s the best
at killing dead guys.
LAURA: He is so good at it.
MATT: Everyone rushes in,
the rakshasa glares around.
LAURA: No!
MARISHA: Oh, this motherfucker.
ASHLEY: Don’t you leave!
LIAM: He's going for spells!
TRAVIS: We’re still on the roof.
It’s just Scanlan and Vax down there.
TRAVIS: He’s not intimidated yet.
LAURA: I shot him, though.
TRAVIS: He doesn’t see us.
MARISHA: I hope he’s got a Counterspell...
TRAVIS: He doesn’t know where it’s coming.
Right? (high-pitched) Right?
TALIESIN: (singing)
Sam has got a Counterspell.
LAURA: What are you - what’s happening?
MARISHA: (singing) When you’re a Jet,
you’re a Jet all the way.
LAURA: Oh.
MARISHA: I don't know.
LIAM: Rakshasa.
SAM: He’s doing math.
MATT: All righty.
SAM: It’s a Beautiful Mind moment
right now.
LIAM: He does want to join Vox Monica.
TALIESIN: This is what it's like
on this end,
going, "what the fuck do I do?"
Thank you.
MARISHA: You know, there’s
a mathematical equation for your stripes?
LIAM: Well, he reads thoughts
but he gets them backwards, sometimes.
SAM: He’s thinking
about that great Loot Crate deal.
LIAM: Vox Merkernerkerk.
LAURA: Verks Merkernerk.
ASHLEY: Vox Monica.
TRAVIS: Oh, shit.
ASHLEY: Vox Phoebe.
TRAVIS: He’s really thinking about this.
ASHLEY: Vox Ross. Vox Chandler.
SAM: How many people will die instantly
SAM: - if I set off
a thermonuclear bomb in my pocket?
MATT: All right. So.
LAURA: Vox Joey.
TRAVIS: Joey.
MATT: So. Hotis, first, is going to...
reach back and pull out -
no actually, no.
Hotis is going to look up
at the creature that just
flew in on the broom.
ASHLEY: Look away.
MATT: Looks at you and says,
"You’ll do."
MATT: Right as the eye contact hits you -
MARISHA: Oh my god.
MARISHA: He’s going to fucking
Finger of Death.
MATT: - you feel a presence
begin to push into your head.
I need you to roll
a wisdom saving throw.
LIAM: At advantage, being a half-elf.
LAURA: Is it a charm?
MARISHA: Yeah, he’s trying to charm.
LAURA: Okay okay okay!
LIAM: Okay okay okay.
LAURA: Sheesh! Okay.
LIAM: Ah, we’re good.
LAURA: And what is it, wisdom?
MATT: Wisdom.
LAURA: 18 plus 3 is 21?
MATT: 21, all right.
You resist the effect.
TRAVIS: What was he doing?
What was the effect?
MARISHA: Trying to charm you, man.
LIAM: It was what he did to me
the last time we faced him.
TRAVIS: Oh, really?
LIAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: Only half of us
know how this fucker works.
LIAM: Now he does nothing at all.
LAURA: I don’t know what he is.
MARISHA: Wait...
TALIESIN: I wasn’t there.
MARISHA: It was just -
was it just me and you?
LIAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: Oh my god,
it was just me and you.
TALIESIN: Yeah, we’ve never, we have no...
LIAM: (sings) We’ve only just met.
ASHLEY: (sings) We’ve only just begun.
MATT: Yeah, he’s going to get
quite a way aways from you guys.
ASHLEY: Where’s he going?
MATT: I’d say because you’re prone,
you do get
one attack of opportunity on him -
no, you dropped the blade.
The blade is not at your feet,
so you can punch him if you want
as he runs by.
SAM: Oh, if he runs away
I can cast a spell on him.
MARISHA: Yeah. Warcaster.
MATT: From prone.
I’ll let it happen, sure.
MARISHA: You can cast
when you’re on your back.
MATT: 5 feet of you. I’ll let you do it.
What do you want to do?
SAM: Well, it’s not the rule, though,
I don’t want any preferential -
MATT: No, it’s not against the rules.
It's a weird in-between.
You’re on the ground
after falling from the top.
SAM: Yeah, I’m hurt,
so maybe it wouldn’t work.
MATT: Yeah, but you see him running away
and you can still cast from the ground,
so go for it.
What do you want to cast?
SAM: Okay. Well,
what I was going to cast
before he ran away
was Bigby’s Hand
and try to grapple him.
MATT: Okay,
so you create Bigby’s Hand.
SAM: (singing) Bigby's Hand!
MATT: And what level is Bigby’s Hand?
SAM: 5.
LAURA: Oh, no!
MATT: Bigby’s Hand (whoosh) appears
and rushes out,
and the fingers
pass through the rakshasa.
It has no effect.
LAURA: I know, I know.
ASHLEY: No!
MATT: It twice more tries to reach out,
And the rakshasa shrugs it off
like it’s nothing.
SAM: What? Bigby...
But the hand is still there?
SAM: He didn’t Counterspell it.
MATT: Correct.
SAM: He’s somehow immune
to hand-based attacks.
What if it were a foot?
Would that have the same effect?
MATT: One could only conjecture.
SAM: Shit!
TALIESIN: It’s just
the number of fingers, man.
SAM: Well, then I flip him off with it,
but the British way.
(all laugh)
MATT: Perfect.
All right, that’s going to end his turn.
MATT: Scanlan, you’re up
LIAM: Rakshasa cannot be jerked.
SAM: All right, I’m up.
Well, that didn’t work.
So I guess I’ll drop that.
And instead -
Jesus, what else can he resist?
Fucking shit.
How far is he from me?
MATT: Currently? He’s about...
40 feet from you?
SAM: Okay.
MATT: You can get up.
You’re still prone on the ground.
SAM: I’ll use half of my movement
to get up,
and I will stare daggers at him
and cast Eyebite against him.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: Yeah, I’ll just do one of these
and I'll sing at him.
I'll sing,
"(singing) I hate rakasha,
so put another arrow in his body, baby!
(others join in singing):
"I hate rakasha,
"so come and take the time
and fight with me!"
(all laugh)
MATT: As he looks back at you
as you’re singing out loud
and chuckles to himself -
SAM: Fucking -
MATT: - as it has no effect.
LIAM: Ah! Haha.
SAM: Fuck! But it was a good song!
TRAVIS: It was!
MATT: It was a very good song.
LIAM: Petition to Chris Perkins
to rename it “rakasha.”
MARISHA: Rakasha!
LAURA: (whispers) Rakasha!
SAM: But what, he’s impervious to spells?
How did that happen?
ASHLEY: What level was it?
SAM: That’s a 6th-level spell!
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: You have two more squares,
if you want.
SAM: I don’t have a sword anymore.
He picked it up, right?
LIAM: Yep.
MATT: Yep.
SAM: So, I guess I will…
LIAM: Hey, I’m in a lot of pain.
SAM: Oh, yeah. That guy.
(all laugh)
SAM: Okay. I’ll, uh -
LIAM: 6 big hit points.
SAM: I’ll heal you again with a -
I can only do a level 1 bonus action
with a Healing Word, right?
MATT: Up to level 2.
SAM: Oh, then I’ll do
a level 2 Healing Word.
MATT: So 2d4 + 5.
SAM: Ooh. 2d4 + 5 and 5?
Or 2d4 + 5?
MATT: Just 5.
SAM: Well, this is shitty.
It’s 9 points again.
LIAM: I’ll take it.
MATT: It’s better than nothing.
LIAM: Yep.
MATT: Better than nothing. All righty.
That ends Scanlan’s turn. Grog, you’re up.
TRAVIS: Can I see them at all
from the roof?
MATT: Yeah. You’ve gotten up
and you can see them all there.
Whatever this creature is,
is now in the distance,
trying to run back.
TRAVIS: Sweet anus! Reason to jump!
TRAVIS: And I jump off the roof
into the courtyard.
MATT: Okay, (landing thud) you leap
and it’s a very small step down (footstep)
TRAVIS: But I make it look
like I landed really hard!
MARISHA: Three-point landing!
TRAVIS: Can I continue my movement
in his direction
as far as I can go? 50 feet.
MATT: 50. That’s as far as you can get.
TRAVIS: Is he another 20 feet away?
MATT: About 20 feet from you, yeah.
TRAVIS: Can I take my...
Can I attach the Blood Axe
to my Chain of Returning
and hurl it at the rakshasa?
MATT: I’ll say yeah. You, being Grog,
for the most part,
you don’t take your equipment
too far from you
because you’ve been
in uncomfortable situations.
TRAVIS: Only in the house of lady favors
do I let my beans hang out when I sleep.
MATT: Right. Fair enough.
You would have the chain on you, still.
ASHLEY: Franks and beans!
LIAM: How do you get the beans
above the franks?
MATT: You attach it, swish it,
and throw the axe. Go ahead.
TRAVIS: Reckless attack.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: Thank god.
Not much better. 17.
MATT: 17. 17 does hit.
TRAVIS: Oh, yay!
MATT: Go ahead and roll damage on that.
TRAVIS: 6! That’s 26
with 6 points of necrotic damage.
MATT: Nice!
(throwing sounds)
The axe slams
into the tiger creature’s chest.
"(growls, breathes heavily)
I’ll come back for all of you!"
Do you want to pull the blade back?
TRAVIS: Nope.
MATT: All right.
It’s on the ground next to him,
it’s not jammed into him -
TRAVIS: Oh, then yeah, I’ll pull it back.
MATT: Yeah, it’s not hard to pull back.
TRAVIS: Just (whoosh).
MATT: Go ahead
and roll your athletics check.
TRAVIS: What is it?
MATT: You’re raging,
so you have advantage.
TRAVIS: Oh, thank you.
TRAVIS: Same number.
LAURA: (laughs)
MATT: Athletics.
TRAVIS: 11.
MATT: You pull it back (vwoof)
and it streaks past you (shhh),
scatters across the ground
in the other direction.
You haven’t quite picked it up yet;
you’re going to have to try again.
TRAVIS: Meant to do that.
MATT: Yep.
ASHLEY: It’s 15.
SAM: Cool move.
TRAVIS: Oh, it’s 15, sorry.
MATT: 15?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: Then as you (shhh) pull it back -
No, not this day, Blood Axe.
You’re mine.
(all laugh)
MATT: All right.
That finishes your turn, Grog.
Keyleth, you’re up.
MARISHA: I am going to...
move up, I guess.
My full movement.
MATT: About there.
MARISHA: Okay, roughly how far away
is he from me now? The rakshasa?
MATT: Eyeballing it right now,
from best you can tell,
he’s about 60-70 feet from you.
MARISHA: All right. Okay. 60-70 feet.
First things first,
I’m going to cast Wall of Stone,
and what I want to do
is make it a semi-circle,
and wall him in with us.
MATT: A semi-circle and wall you guys in?
MARISHA: Yeah, wall him in with us.
I don’t want us to lose sight on him,
but I want to make it like a -
TALIESIN: A cup.
MARISHA: A cup. Yeah.
MATT: All righty. So like around there?
MARISHA: Yep. All the way...
MATT: How long can you make the wall?
MARISHA: How long can I make the wall?
I can make the wall...
MATT: Vax, you’re on deck by the way.
MARISHA: I can do 10 by... sorry.
If it’s 3 inches thick,
I can do 10 foot by -
TALIESIN: 10 by 20?
MARISHA: 20-foot panels...
It doesn’t really specify right now.
Is it supposed to be 10...
Okay, right. Right.
So I think that’s about right.
MATT: I will pull this up.
MARISHA: I don’t want it
to be super thick.
TALIESIN: It’s not a very descriptive -
MARISHA: It’s not very descriptive.
MATT: Okay, 6-inch thick,
composed of 10 foot by 10 foot panels -
MARISHA: And when I do 3 inches thick,
I can create 10 foot by 20 foot panels -
it says the same damn thing in the book.
You create a span of 20-foot length...
MATT: We’ll say that that’s fine.
You do a 3-inch wall there, 10 feet high?
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: All righty.
MARISHA: And now I’m going to
do a bonus action - see if this works.
Okay, I have a 60-foot range here,
so I want to cast a Grasping Vine -
MATT: Grasping Vine is a 4th-level spell.
You can’t do it as a bonus action
the same turn you did another spell.
MARISHA: Fuck, that’s right.
Never mind.
Then I’m going to
take a bonus action
and Healing Word Vax.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: 8 points.
How far away am I from Vax?
MATT: You’re about 25-30 feet.
MARISHA: Okay, can I shout at him?
MATT: You may.
MARISHA: Vax! Is that Hotis?
LIAM: Yeah!
MARISHA: Uh, holy shit!
LIAM: That’s what I said!
MARISHA: That’s my turn.
MATT: And it’s your turn, Vax.
LIAM: Okay, and the first thing I do
is shout out,
"Blades! I think blades
are the best way to go here, folks!"
And I’m going to run at him.
MATT: All righty.
LIAM: I think I should get there
with 12, no?
LAURA: No boots.
LIAM: Oh! No boots!
LIAM: All right, I’ll use - fuck a duck.
I’ll use the bonus action to dash.
MATT: Okay, dash. (swoosh)
You’ll get right there.
Unless you want to hold back -
LIAM: And I’m going to try
to grapple that fucking dick.
MATT: Go for it.
LAURA: Mmm, that’s good.
LIAM: 19.
LAURA: I’m going to grapple that dick
so good.
ASHLEY: I’m going to grapple that dick!
TALIESIN: I’m going to grapple that dick.
SAM: Grapple that dick.
MATT: He is grappled.
LIAM: Okay.
LAURA: Grapple him, yeah!
(all laugh)
LIAM: And before my turn ends,
I’m going to pull him in and say,
"Fool me once, motherfucker."
And whoever steps in steps in.
MATT: Okay. Good to know.
This assassin is done -
no turns for them.
He is being slowly torn apart by Trinket
against the stairs. Vex, you’re up.
LAURA: Okay, I’m going to...
jeez, Louise.
I’m going to... fly down
and land on the ground as my move.
MATT: All righty.
LAURA: And I’m going to shoot him
with my Blazing Bowstring.
MATT: Go for it.
SAM: (singing) Blazing Bowstring!
LAURA: 22!
MATT: That hits.
LAURA: All right. (mumbling) ...13…
LIAM: (sighs) Girl…
LAURA: (mumbling) ...plus 8…
ASHLEY: Nice.
LAURA: Is 21! On the first attack.
MATT: 21 damage. All righty.
LAURA: And I get to use
the Blazing Bowstring again
because I get it twice.
MATT: You do. Roll for the next attack.
LAURA: That is a 26.
MATT: That hits, yeah.
LAURA: 15 on the second.
ASHLEY: Bracers?
MATT: All righty...
LAURA: Ah! Shit, add 4 to that.
I’m sorry. I’m an asshole.
MATT: No, it’s all good.
TRAVIS: You said it.
MATT: All righty, so (whoosh whoosh)
both arrows slam
(sound of flame catching)
burst of flame -
"(growls)"
MATT: He’s now starting to look
even more rough and ragged.
The fire’s curling
up the side of the robe.
LAURA: And I yell,
"What’s a hotis?!"
MATT: All right. Pike, you’re up.
ASHLEY: Okay. I would like
to get to the window and jump out.
MATT: The hole in the wall you mean?
ASHLEY: The hole in the wall.
I have my Celestial Shield.
I’m going to cast Featherfall on myself.
MATT: Okay, this actually is a climb up.
This isn’t a window.
This is an opening in the wall
that Keyleth made with Stone Shape.
MARISHA: I made a ramp with the rubble.
MATT: You’re actually stepping up.
ASHLEY: She made a ramp,
so we don’t need to do it.
MATT: So you get up,
and the farthest you can get this turn,
unless you want to go full movement -
you’ll not be able to make it
all the way up the ramp
and still do something, so…
ASHLEY: Can I use my Sprinter’s Boots?
MATT: You can, actually. Yes, you can.
ASHLEY: I’m still up on the ramp.
Can I still be hidden, then?
I’ll stay right there.
MATT: Okay,
so you come out onto the roof
and you jump down about 5 feet,
and you’re on the roof, now,
the moonlight coming down,
a somewhat clouded, spotted sky.
In the distance, you see everyone
rushing towards some sort of entity
that’s walled in by a stone wall.
He’s currently up in the face of Vax.
You still have your action right now.
ASHLEY: Okay. Do I have a clear shot
to use - where did it go?
ASHLEY: Flame Strike at 7th level.
MATT: You do, actually.
MATT: You do. On 7th level?
ASHLEY: Da.
SAM: Our music, it’s gone.
LAURA: Oh no.
MATT: Oh, it’s coming, don’t worry.
LIAM: (singing "Whistle Stop")
(all join in on different parts)
SAM: That’s also Bluegrass, folks.
MATT: And with that,
we’re putting box music up.
(all chuckle)
MATT: Or we should be.
LAURA: Oh no!
TALIESIN: (radio announcer voice)
That’s called "The Rakshasa Blues."
TALIESIN: Coming up next -
LIAM: (starts singing Mortal Kombat theme)
MATT: We’ve got a boombox right here -
LAURA, MARISHA, AND ASHLEY:
Mortal Kombat!
TRAVIS: Doo-doo-doo. Fight!
MATT: I don’t know why -
input’s functional,
but we’ll just make up the music as we go.
So, at a 7th-level Flame Strike.
That’ll be putting... 10d6 damage.
Going to attempt a saving throw.
That’s a natural 1,
but does have advantage
on saving throws against spells.
LAURA: I can hear music,
it’s just really quiet!
MARISHA: Yeah, I can hear it.
LIAM: I liked ours better.
MARISHA: Oh, there we go!
Oh, you were doing something to it.
SAM: This is exciting.
MATT: It’s coming, isn’t it?
MARISHA: It’s coming.
LIAM: (record scratching noise)
MATT: What’s the DC of your spell?
That’ll be an 18.
MATT: Spell DC?
ASHLEY: 18.
MATT: Yeah, it does save,
so it takes half damage.
Go ahead and roll 10d6.
LAURA: Damn.
LIAM: Damn.
ASHLEY: Okay, 6, 8, 9.
MARISHA: Kill that motherfucker!
ASHLEY: 14.
LAURA: 18.
ASHLEY: 18.
TRAVIS: (whispers) 19.
ASHLEY: 19, 22 -
TRAVIS: But that’s it -
ASHLEY: I roll 10.
TRAVIS: Oh!
LAURA: 22, 28, 29.
LIAM: It’s like watching the Olympics.
ASHLEY: 29.
LIAM: 5-9, 5-8, 6-1.
LAURA: Ooh!
MARISHA: I don’t even know
what that means!
ASHLEY: Okay, so 45.
MATT: So, 45 halved is 22 points
of fire and bludgeoning damage.
MARISHA: What did you cast?
MATT: So how do you want to do this?
ASHLEY: (gasps) Wha -
LAURA AND TRAVIS: Oh!
TRAVIS: Shit!
LAURA: Oh my god!
ASHLEY: Are you serious? (gasps) What?
LAURA: Pikey-Pike killed a rakshasa!
MATT: How do you want to do this?
LIAM: Do it, girl.
ASHLEY: I’m so shocked! I don’t know!
Okay, okay. Oh, man.
Can the Flame Strike go through his body
and (explosion noise)
burst him like a (foof)?
(all laugh)
MATT: Burst him like a foof.
So, as you turn the corner,
seeing all your friends
charging toward this creature,
knowing the fear that you heard
in Vax’s voice earlier,
the burning rage of vengeance -
ASHLEY: I’m mad.
MATT: - burns beneath your skin -
SAM: Exposed skin.
MATT: - your mostly exposed skin.
ASHLEY: My non-hairy skin.
(all laugh)
MATT: You grab your holy symbol,
drop the shield,
and bring your arm up like this.
As you do, the rakshasa before you
all of a sudden goes like (grunts) -
LIAM: I’m going to let go of him now.
MATT: You see the skin cracking -
LIAM: Just back up a few.
MATT: - these breaks to his exterior,
these strange, glowing,
internal cracks on his body.
"(hissing, raspy breaths)
I will return!"
LIAM: Yeah, we’ll see you next time,
shitface.
MATT: (explosion sound)
And he detonates with a column of fire
that comes bursting out of the ground
from the body.
You can see the shattering,
burned bits of rakshasa flesh
go flying across
the entire exterior of the castle
as this column, 20, 30, 40 feet up,
streaks up out of the top of the castle,
lighting up
the vicinity of Whitestone.
And as it slowly subsides,
there is nothing but a pile of ash
left where Hotis was.
(cheers)
TRAVIS: That was sweet!
LAURA: What the fuck was that?
ASHLEY: Thanks, Grog!
SAM: So, I think I understand.
You have to be naked
to cast spells on it. Is that it?
ASHLEY: I think that’s what it is!
LIAM: That’s how we did it last time.
LAURA: What was that? What is this?
TALIESIN: I’m going to
finish running up to the West Tower.
LAURA: Trinket is slowly realizing
nobody’s around him.
TALIESIN: He could have joined me.
ASHLEY: I hold my shield over my body.
LIAM: I think we might need to have
a discussion with Vanessa at some point
for not alerting us
to the fact that this is a -
MARISHA: That those things come back.
LIAM: - an ongoing -
MARISHA: - problem.
LIAM: - contract.
TRAVIS: I run over
and I give Pike a fancy robe.
MARISHA: We watched him die.
LAURA: Who, Hotis?
LIAM: I stuck a knife through his throat
and slit the front of it.
TRAVIS: You killed him before?
ASHLEY: So he comes back?
MARISHA: Remember when we split up
for the Slayer’s Take?
He was our contract.
TRAVIS: Oh.
LAURA: Right.
TRAVIS: Didn’t finish him off, did you?
MARISHA: Nope,
Vax and I watched him die.
TRAVIS: Like, die, or like he “ah” fell?
LAURA: And then you walked away.
LIAM: I slit his throat.
MARISHA: He slit his throat.
LIAM: And it exploded blood
all over the ground
underneath his big smile -
MARISHA: Yes, it got blood
all over the place.
TRAVIS: That’s pretty dead.
MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: So he’s a vampire.
MARISHA: I think we need
to talk to Vanessa, like he said.
TALIESIN: I am alerting the guards
and I am yelling through the hallways
to lock down the city.
MATT: Which, at this point,
guards start coming up from below -
LAURA: Good job, guys! Totally on it.
TALIESIN: We don’t know we got everybody -
lock down, keep looking!
MARISHA: Yes, be that there are
assassins running around,
which was not part of the contract before.
LAURA: I fly up on the broom
and try to spot anybody on the ground
that looks dangerous.
TRAVIS: Can I look at Vax
and ask him what he’s wearing?
LAURA: (laughs)
LIAM: Oh, this is a -
SAM: A bloody robe.
LIAM: A beautiful, bloodied...
LIAM: It’s a robe.
It’s a beautiful brown.
MARISHA: The beading on it is gorgeous.
LAURA: I thought it was silver.
ASHLEY: Can I check the robe?
LIAM: No, no look at it - it’s brown.
It’s brown, it’s earthy.
LAURA: Matt said it was silver
the last game.
LIAM: Yeah, but look at it.
Can’t you see with your eyes? It's brown.
MATT: Well, portions of it are brown now,
due to the blood that has seeped into it
from the various stab wounds
that he’s suffered.
LIAM: I don’t really want to wear this.
I’m a little confused right now.
I think I need to -
SAM: What happened?
TRAVIS: Yeah, how did that happen?
ASHLEY: Can I take a look at the robe?
MATT: As you attempt to take the robe off,
you feel like the strength
is sapped from your body
and you’re like (raspy groan).
And the more you try to pull it off,
the more and more you start to feel
like it’s pulling the breath
out of your lungs.
ASHLEY: Can I try to rip it off of him?
LIAM: Ah, wait wait wait wait wait -
let’s figure out what’s going on!
LAURA: Do I see anything? Can I land?
MATT: Yeah, make a perception check -
LIAM: Wait, stop, everyone stop.
(breathes heavily)
That thing came to me
disguised as Gilmore.
He told me he wanted to talk,
we went for a walk, he gave me this -
Full disclosure,
we all know he’s fucking sweet on me.
We went for a stroll
and then he turned into whatever he is
and then
he fucking stabbed me in the gut.
ASHLEY: Wait, but -
MATT: You see guards
scattered around the castle.
ASHLEY: Gilmore gave you the robe?
LIAM: No, he was disguised as Gilmore.
MARISHA: The rakshasa can disguise -
LIAM: He’s a skinchanger.
MARISHA: He can shape-shift -
MARISHA: - and he can teleport,
and he can do all sorts of shifty things.
LIAM: Which means we need to find Gilmore
and we need to find Allura now.
TALIESIN: Everyone get -
MARISHA: Hang on, hang on!
MARISHA: I go up to Vax
and I cast Dispel Magic
as I try and pull off the robe.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: Ahh. Ahh?
It stings? I think.
MATT: Go ahead and roll a d20
and add 6 for your wisdom.
MARISHA: Add 6 to my wisdom?
MATT: Add 6 to the roll from your wisdom.
MARISHA: Oh, add 6 to the roll
from my wisdom.
Oh, adding my modifier, right. 14.
MATT: 14. As you cast Dispel Magic
and start pulling the robe back,
you feel like someone’s
pulling the skin off your body.
SAM: Oh, god.
LIAM: Fuck me!
MATT: You suffer 12 points of damage
as it feels like someone’s
peeling the flesh off your body.
SAM AND MARISHA: Wait, does it come off?
MATT: No.
TALIESIN: I've got a plan.
MARISHA: It doesn't come off.
TRAVIS: I pull it off.
TALIESIN: No no no no no! No.
I’m grabbing Vex.
Vax, Vex, with me.
Everyone start searching.
Tell them that we’re going to need
a healer downstairs.
And I’m going to take him.
We’re going to head towards -
LAURA: Wait, did you say me or him?
TALIESIN: I’m taking both of you -
TALIESIN: - because I’m not
carrying him alone, because he’s heavy.
LAURA: He’s actually quite light.
LIAM: I’m lighter than my sister.
TALIESIN: I have a strength of 12.
There’s not a lot I can do.
LAURA: Ow, no, I'm serious. Don't!
I'm really not strong.
TALIESIN: I’m going to try and drag him
down towards the pit
with the orb of death.
MARISHA: Oh, that’s a good idea.
TRAVIS: Are there any pieces
of the rakshasa left?
MATT: Burned, tiny chunks and ash.
It was a full - it was -
We’re talking end-of-Matrix-style
Agent Smith scattering.
LIAM: Scanlan!
SAM: What?
LIAM: Will you grab
that dagger off the ground for me?
SAM: What dagger? You had a -
LIAM: His dagger, the dagger -
no, I’ve got your sword.
And I toss it as we get dragged off.
The dagger. Get the dagger for me!
SAM: I’ll grab the dagger.
I’m coming with.
LIAM: I like them.
MARISHA: I go and I look
for Allura and Gilmore.
TALIESIN: Yes, let them know
what’s going on.
MARISHA: While they do that.
MATT: Okay. So you take Vax and Vex
down towards the ziggurat.
LAURA: Come on.
LIAM: (groans)
TALIESIN: Just make sure
if you start to feel strange
as we go down there, let us know.
And we slowly inch
towards the effects of it.
LIAM: This is why
I didn’t even bother to take it off.
LAURA: You know what? At least
it doesn’t smell as bad as your feathers.
TALIESIN: That’s so true.
ASHLEY: I’d like to follow.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: Life’s not that bad.
Life’s not that bad.
TALIESIN: Yes, but your smell is.
TRAVIS: I’ll go, too, just as security.
SAM: I’m with.
MATT: You’re with them?
SAM: Yes.
MATT: All right, so you guys
all make your way down.
As you’re going through the castle,
it’s in utter chaos now.
All the guards who, in what was
about 20 to 30 seconds of action
since the moment of actual shouting
at the top of the tower,
the reaction time would be great
if it wasn’t such a short window
they had to get up there
and you guys
were right in the thick of it,
and more trained than these soldiers.
MARISHA: As I’m looking
for Gilmore and Allura,
I’m alerting the guards
of the visuals of the assailants.
MATT: Okay. And the guards
begin to continue pushing around.
You can see now,
lights are starting to come on
in the town.
You guys make your way down
into the subterranean tunnels
under Whitestone, where the Ziggurat is.
You can see it, once again,
the large, pyramid-like structure.
TALIESIN: I cast - no, no, never mind.
I’ll hold off. Keep walking.
MATT: Okay. You make your way
into the central chamber.
It has a number of fire-based braziers
that are set in there now for light
that are just general fire,
but a lot of them
are burned down to embers.
It’s very, very low light in this area.
You can barely see anything in here.
You guys make your way inside the room.
It’s cold, it’s dank,
it’s not a very comfortable atmosphere.
TALIESIN: Okay. Very gently.
LIAM: I’ll do it! I’ll do it.
TALIESIN: If this doesn’t work,
we can try something else.
TRAVIS: What are you doing?
LAURA: I’ve got it.
SAM: Hold on, we’re close enough
that magic has no effect, yeah?
LAURA: Potentially.
LIAM: Potentially.
SAM: I’ll cast Mage Hand
to slap Percy in the face.
MATT: No effect.
SAM: No effect.
SAM: Okay, we’re good.
LIAM: All right.
LIAM: I’m going to just peel it, slowly.
I’m not going to rip it off
like these assholes.
MATT: Okay.
It pulls back with no issue.
LAURA: Hey! Get that shit off.
SAM: Throw it in the orb!
TALIESIN: Don’t throw it in the orb!
LAURA: Somebody give him
something to put on.
Grog, do you have
any more fancy robes?
TRAVIS: Nope, all out.
TALIESIN: Put it on the ground.
We’ll deal with it.
We’re not leaving it here.
LAURA: Well, just cover up your bits
with it, maybe.
LIAM: We look
almost exactly the same -
LAURA: I don’t have any dangly bits,
I’m sorry to tell you.
LIAM: Minus that one thing,
we are so close.
TALIESIN: Three things. Three things.
MARISHA: Three things. There’s a few.
LAURA: A couple other things.
LIAM: Yeah, but still.
TRAVIS: I do have one other fancy robe.
LAURA: Give him a fancy robe, Grog.
TRAVIS: Mmm.
LAURA: Grog!
TRAVIS: Yes?
LAURA: For my sake?
TRAVIS: All right.
Last fancy robe to Vax.
SAM: Will the Bag of Holding
work down here?
TALIESIN: No.
LIAM: Shush, you fucker.
LAURA: Oh, shit.
MATT: You reach into the Bag of Holding,
and it’s just an empty satchel.
TALIESIN: Yeah,
there’s no Bag of Holding in here.
So why don’t we go upstairs
now that it’s off
and we’ll leave it here,
and I’ll be the last to leave with it.
LAURA: Wait.
Why are you keeping it, Percy?
TALIESIN: Because I'm not sure
destroying it in here is the best idea,
and I'm not sure if destroying it
is going to damage him.
TALIESIN: So we're going to be careful.
LAURA: All right.
TRAVIS: Aren't there acid pools down here?
LAURA: No.
TALIESIN: It's not a terrible idea,
but we should -
TRAVIS: Yeah, there are.
LAURA: Oh. That's right,
that's where your gun went.
LIAM: But not near here, not here.
TALIESIN: Let's just very gently -
we don't know what that is yet,
so let's very gently
get you out of the orb's influence,
and then we'll remove it
out of the orb's influence,
and we'll see if there's a problem.
LIAM: I walk proudly and naked
out of the fucking ziggurat.
TRAVIS: That's what I was going to ask.
MATT: All right.
TALIESIN: I pick up the cloak
and move it outside the orb's influence
to see if it has any effect.
MATT: Okay.
As you pull it beyond the perimeter
of what you've come to mark,
and it is marked, by the way.
Through the research of Allura
and the folks
that have been here for a while,
there is a specific mark in the hallway
where that barrier begins.
TALIESIN: I just gingerly
start to put it forward, watching him.
MATT: No noticeable effect.
TALIESIN: All right.
LAURA: Nothing?
TALIESIN: Seems all right.
TALIESIN: I'm going to slowly walk
away from the -
slowly bring it
out of the influence of the sphere.
MATT: No effect.
LAURA: Does that mean
we should take it back in and chop it up
so nobody ever puts it on?
TALIESIN: I think we should
have someone look at it first.
SAM: No, we can use it as a weapon.
TALIESIN: Or we could destroy it properly.
One or the other.
TRAVIS: Probably a good idea.
Should I check the Bag of Holding now?
LAURA: Yeah, look in it.
TRAVIS: Can I reach in for a fancy robe?
MATT: Yeah, you pull out a fancy robe.
TRAVIS: Awesome. I wind it up like a towel
and I smack Vax on the ass super hard.
LIAM: What's - fucking hell.
And I don't even roll for it.
(screams)
TRAVIS: Bare ass. Bare ass
I get it really good, like (whack)!
LIAM: Grog. Grog.
TRAVIS: Yeah?
LIAM: Brother,
I am so happy to be alive.
TRAVIS: Yeah, me, too.
Here you go. (whssht)
LIAM: Whoo.
Wait, is this the one? Ugh.
LAURA: No, no, it's a fancy robe.
It's just a regular robe.
LIAM: Are you sure?
LAURA AND ASHLEY: Yes.
TRAVIS: Yeah, put it on, fucker.
MATT: (laughs)
MATT: The fear of robes has now set in.
MARISHA: (laughs) In robes?
TALIESIN: I am carrying the robe
on Bad News
like a stank rag, at this point,
through the hallway.
MATT: Okay. While this is happening,
you make your way down.
Allura and Gilmore weren't staying
in the castle.
They were staying
on the north side of the town.
MARISHA: As I walk towards them,
I want to throw up a Skywrite, once again.
The de Rolo crest, just alerting people.
MATT: Okay. And you do see,
there are lights coming on in the town
and guards are now going out
through the streets,
going through buildings,
searching for individuals
that match the description you're at.
As you make your way
towards Gilmore's home,
you hear what sounds like
a loud, heavy thud.
(boof) (boof boof) Another one,
and suddenly a crash of glass.
LAURA: I take off run -
oh, she's by herself.
MATT: She's there by herself.
MARISHA: Okay.
I'm going to cast Polymorph on myself.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: And I'm going to go as a mouse.
MATT: Wild Shape or Polymorph?
MARISHA: Polymorph.
MATT: Okay. (fft)
You turn into a tiny little mouse.
MARISHA: Can I fit through the door?
MATT: Yep. You (fft) skirt under the door.
The first thing you notice now
is there is a bookcase that is shattered
and there is a figure slumped
in the corner where the table is broken.
There's a little bit of light
from a lantern that's been knocked over
that's starting to catch fire
on the curtains,
and as the light (whoosh)
from the flames begin to pick up,
you can see the figure
that was off to the side
suddenly lifts up in the air.
And you now see there, held aloft,
what looks to be a humanoid,
wearing dark leathers, a cloak,
and a hood (groans)
being held about four feet in the air,
tense up.
Walking out of the next room,
you see Gilmore in disarray,
a little bit of blood
streaking down the forehead there,
sweaty in the face, with his arm out.
SAM: Ooh.
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: "What did you say?
That's what I thought!"
And he closes his hand
and you watch as the figure is just -
(squelching noise)
ALL: (shocked and impressed exclamations)
MATT: - squashed in this ball of flesh,
and you can see as it slowly twists,
it's like squeezing water out of a towel,
just blood pours out.
ALL: (noises of disgust)
TRAVIS: (gleeful laughter) Yes!
MATT: And then he releases his fingers,
and the figure (thud)
falls limp on the ground
like a crushed doll.
"(sighs)"
MARISHA: I drop Polymorph.
MATT: "(startled shout)"
MARISHA: It's okay! It's okay!
It's me, Keyleth. Sorry.
MATT: "It's not the night
to be doing that to me!"
MARISHA: (shouting) I know, I know!
(all laugh)
MATT: "(sighs) I need a drink."
MARISHA: Gilmore.
Rakshasa. In the town.
Pretending to be you.
Trying to kill Vax.
MATT: "Right now?"
MARISHA: Yes!
Also, a bunch of fucking assassins.
MATT: He grabs you by the arm -
MARISHA: (scared) Yeah.
MATT: - and just (shfff).
There's a rush of air
and a sparkle of purplish-blue energy.
As you guys
are walking through the tunnel,
all of a sudden (boof),
with a flash of light,
you see,
standing before you in the tunnel,
Keyleth and a very harried Gilmore,
who is -
MARISHA: (breathless) I found Gilmore.
MATT: "(pants)"
LAURA: I pull out my weapons.
TRAVIS: Are we killing this one?
MARISHA: No! This is real Gilmore!
Real Gilmore.
MATT: "Hi. (chuckles)
I'm glad to see you're all right."
LAURA: (laughs)
TALIESIN: (cracks up)
MATT: "Wasn't expecting it
to be my birthday, as well. (chuckles)"
LIAM: Oh, I'm still here?
Oh, I'm still here!
SAM: Vax, Vax, quick!
LAURA: (singing) And naked!
LIAM: Let's look at the backside instead.
This is a little awkward.
SAM: Vax, ask him a question
that only Gilmore
would know the answer to.
LIAM: Oh, sh -
What did I tell you in that tavern
the other night?
A couple of months ago, I guess.
What did I tell you?
LAURA: (laughs) Do you remember?
LIAM: Yeah, I do.
MATT: And you can see now,
he's breathing heavy.
He's been a little winded.
And his eyes are excited to see -
excited to see you for multiple reasons,
but excited to see that you're alive.
But as you ask him this question,
you see his demeanor darkens a little.
"That you... had interests elsewhere."
LIAM: Yeah, that's Gilmore.
MARISHA: As he says this,
I do a little cantrip Fog Cloud
around Vax's... privies.
Just a little floating fog cloud.
LIAM: Oh, not in my hair.
LAURA: A little floating cloud of -
MARISHA: Right around your waistline.
ASHLEY: A little tutu.
MARISHA: The old tutu.
LAURA: A little smoky tutu?
MARISHA: A little censor bar.
TRAVIS: Should I throw him the robe?
TALIESIN: Anime bathhouses.
TRAVIS: I thought I threw him the robe.
LAURA: He let it go.
He wanted to walk naked.
LIAM: It's been a shit night.
Who wants to get a drink?
MARISHA: Well, wait.
MATT: "I, for one,
could really go for some heavy alcohol."
MARISHA: Gilmore. Where's Allura?
Where's Allura?
MATT: "I don't know."
MARISHA: Gilmore, if they were after us
and they were after you,
they were probably also after Allura.
We need to make sure
that everyone on the Council is okay.
LAURA: Zahra. Kashaw.
MARISHA: All of them.
MATT: "Then let us go search.
And then we shall drink.
"Nevertheless."
And Gilmore steps into the fog cloud -
(all laugh)
MATT: - and puts his arms
around your neck
and pulls you in,
deep into his shoulder,
and as he holds you really close,
he whispers,
"I'm glad you're all right."
LIAM: (quietly) I don't say anything.
MATT: He lets you go.
LIAM: I pick the dialogue choice
in the Telltale Game, where I say -
LAURA: You say "dot dot dot"?
ASHLEY: Ellipses.
MARISHA: Say nothing?
SAM: Dot dot dot?
MATT: He pulls back with a smile
and kind of reads you.
TRAVIS: Gilmore will remember that.
LAURA: (laughs)
MATT: He gives a nod of understanding
and takes a step back.
"I'm sorry."
LIAM: Oh, no no no.
MATT: "Let's go make sure
that everyone else is all right.
"Come! Follow me."
He turns around
and goes into a jovial jog.
You guys make your way up
back up to the castle.
Kashaw and Zahra are both fine.
You come to them and find
that their rooms were not disturbed,
as neither of them were in the -
actually, no, Kashaw was.
SAM: Where was Kashaw?
LAURA: He fought
the rakshasa to begin with.
MATT: (laughs) Yeah, no.
You do come to the point
where there are now a bunch of guards
swarmed around the outside
of Kashaw's room.
As you push past,
there is blood everywhere.
Everywhere.
On the walls, the ceiling,
the floor, across the bed.
TRAVIS: Awesome.
MATT: And you see,
sitting on the edge of the bed,
spear in hand, shield tossed to the side,
also covered in bits of viscera,
Kashaw,
who's currently leaning against the edge.
LIAM: What's up, Stink-Eye?
MATT: "They knew better, right?
What else was going to happen?"
TRAVIS: How many were there?
MATT: "Oh, just one."
TRAVIS: Whoa.
ALL: (impressed laughter)
TRAVIS: Cool. Cool. Respect.
LAURA: We're grabbing a drink, Kashaw.
MATT: "I'll take a shower first.
But then a drink."
MARISHA: I grab him real fast and say,
"It was Hotis, the rakshasa.
Remember? From the Slayer's Take."
MATT: "I always hated cats."
ASHLEY: I put out my hand and say,
"I've heard a lot about you.
It's nice to meet you."
MATT: "Oh. Nice to meet you, too."
ASHLEY: I have a robe! I have on a robe!
TRAVIS: “I have on a robe,
I have on a robe!”
ASHLEY: I'm dressed! I'm dressed!
MATT: We'll say
he closes the front a little bit.
LIAM: It's probably way too large for you.
ASHLEY: A deep V?
MATT: Right, right.
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: "It's nice to meet you, too.
"I... don't normally dress like this,
either, so don't worry."
ASHLEY: I'm dressed like this all the time.
MATT: "Huh.
"I like you."
And he walks out.
"I'll meet you guys in a minute."
And he goes off to clean himself up.
Zahra's fine.
There's been no attack on Zahra.
LAURA: Cassandra?
TRAVIS: Allura?
MARISHA: Yeah.
Let's split up, I guess?
TALIESIN: Let's all meet in the sitting room
in ten minutes.
So let's have anybody on the Council
meet there in ten minutes.
I'll send word to the guards
to get everybody where they need to be.
If anything's out of sort,
it will instantly reported to us.
ASHLEY: Good plan.
LIAM: I'm going to get my shit.
LAURA: I want to put on my armor.
TALIESIN: I'm also getting my shit.
ASHLEY: Yeah.
LAURA: And then go find Zahra.
MARISHA: I'm going to go look for Allura.
TRAVIS: I'll go for Cassandra with you
because I don't trust that bitch.
LIAM: (laughs)
TALIESIN: Oh.
MATT: All right.
You guys gather your stuff.
At this time, Cassandra's awake,
and she's actually in the process
of dealing with the guards
that are coming back with information.
They've been sweeping parts of the town.
Haven't found anyone else.
There's been no real follow-up
to any other figures that have been found,
beyond the few select individuals.
And it's at this time,
as you guys gather your stuff
and begin to head back out,
that Allura comes
into the front of the castle.
She comes in, hair tossed,
and she looks a little frazzled.
"Is everyone all right?"
LAURA: Yes. Kima? Is she all right?
MATT: She looks over her shoulder,
and you see Kima come walking in,
wearing what looks
like a long nightshirt.
Her maul in her hand
and dragging behind by the foot
what looks to be a mostly-mashed face
of one of the assassins
that tried to find its way
into their home.
MATT: Dragging a long trail.
MARISHA: Still alive?
MATT: No, not alive at all.
The head is caved in,
and there's a long trail of crimson
that leads all the way
down the walkway,
down the footpath of the castle,
and disappears
towards the base of the walkway
at the north side of Whitestone.
"(grunts)"
And throws him. (repeated thuds)
Tumbles onto the ground,
smears across a bit of the stonework.
LAURA: Good work.
MATT: "You, too.
"I can see the rest of you guys,
at least, seem to be okay."
TRAVIS: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Who did get attacked,
out of curiosity?
What happened to yours?
MARISHA: This assassin
came through my window.
TALIESIN: Did you kill him?
MARISHA: Yeah. Well, I...
actually, I don't know.
I chucked him out the window.
He might still be alive.
TALIESIN: I'm going to
turn to a guard and say,
"Search underneath the window
of that bedroom.
"Anything you find -
"look carefully, find a body.
If you don't find a body, find a trail."
Good work. Windows are good.
SAM: Do "ra-kasha-kashas"
typically hire people?
Where do they come from?
Do they come with a band of merry men?
I don't know anything about them.
LAURA: They're just tigers. Do tigers -
MATT: Allura goes like,
"What did you say?"
SAM: Oh, there was
a "raka-sha-sha."
TALIESIN: A rakshasa.
MARISHA: A rakshasa.
SAM: No, I think you're saying it wrong.
LAURA: A hotis. A hotis?
MARISHA: His NAME was Hotis.
Rakshasas are devils from the Nine Hells.
MATT: "I'm quite familiar with them, yes."
SAM: Do they travel
with assassin friends all the time?
Where do they come from?
MATT: "Well, they come
from the hells,
"but they make allies
all throughout the realm.
"They're manipulators.
They masquerade as anyone
"that they think would help
their current intent and goal.
"They lie, they deceive, they convert."
LIAM: Keyleth and I encountered him last.
MARISHA: And Kashaw, wherever he is.
LIAM: And Kash.
And I took his last blood,
and I heard a threat,
but I didn't make anything of it.
MARISHA: We watched him die.
LIAM: And here he is again,
so I suspect this will happen again?
MATT: "So you slew this rakshasa tonight."
TRAVIS: Well, this one did.
MATT: "Well, that will be vengeance
on two, then. It will be back."
SAM: Is there a way
to prevent the "sha-ka-kan"
from coming back?
LIAM: Is there a way
to finish it off for good?
MARISHA: Permanently.
MATT: "There are a couple of ways.
All of them involve
"going to its home plane
and destroying it there.
"So unless you marvel
a trip to the Nine Hells,
"it's going to be a bit of paranoia
for a while.
"It does take weeks, months for them
to regain their form,
"but the process is very painful for them
"and, as far as what I've read,
at least,
"they only really care about getting back
at the ones that took it from them."
LAURA: So still him and you?
SAM: And now Pike.
MARISHA: Is it one of those things
where it passes off down the line,
or is this rakshasa going to be pissed
at both of them?
MATT: "Since you're alive,
its vengeance was not sated.
"I think that's two of you
on its shit list."
LIAM: Allura,
would you be able to...
give us guidance
on how to get to it?
I mean, this is a group decision,
and I'm not going to be fooled
in the same way again.
I'm going to be sleeping
with my fucking knives for a while.
But this will just repeat.
How do we get to it?
MATT: "Well, for right now,
"it's screaming its way back
to the pit of its own creation.
"It will take weeks, months
before it reforms.
"It will be very vulnerable
during that time.
"Mind you, it's not
the most welcoming place, either.
"But (sighs) if we make a journey there
in a few weeks' time,
"we could probably find
where it's currently recouping,
"and slay it for good."
LAURA: How long will that take?
MATT: "How long will what take,
the journey?
"Instantaneous.
To find it, longer.
"To survive that journey,
that is no easy task,
"as it is a place of great danger
and great evil."
LIAM: Are you able to locate it
once it's reformed?
MATT: "It's possible.
"It depends on what sort of magic wards
it may have.
"I don't know where it is.
We could certainly try."
MARISHA: I believe it's immune
to certain magics, correct?
MATT: "That is the issue."
ASHLEY: Do they get any stronger
when they come back,
or are they always the same?
MATT: "All creatures don't like to make
the same mistake twice,
"thence the why
it seems it brought friends."
MARISHA: Speaking of those friends.
You said these rakshasas
are master manipulators.
Is there a group or an organization here
that has it out for us?
MARISHA: I mean, I'm sure many, but -
MATT: "I am certain there are many."
MATT: "As there are a few
that have it out for me, I'm certain."
LIAM: Were there any survivors
from our assailants?
TALIESIN: We're looking, but none of ours.
LIAM: (sighs) Well, if there are any,
we follow it back to the source.
TALIESIN: Yes.
MARISHA: In the meantime,
I guess it's time to drink.
LIAM: (quietly) Also ale.
TRAVIS: (quietly) Also ale.
MATT: "It will be hard
to find this rakshasa
"now or any time
in the very near future,
"as it's still finding its seed
of corporeal form.
"(sighs) But I agree,
this has to be rectified."
MARISHA: I still feel
like we need to reach out to Vanessa.
Let her know what's going on.
LIAM: Maybe up the -
MARISHA: Cost of the contract?
LIAM: - asking price on that?
LAURA: (scoffs) Yeah, good luck.
LIAM: (laughs)
MATT: "I'm a bit confused,
but do what you need to do. Regardless,"
and she looks to Gilmore,
who has taken a breath now
and has pulled an evening flask
out of his night robe.
He takes a swig off of it, goes,
"I think we need to quicken
"our reinforcements
of the city.
"I think we need to make certain
that not only are we scry-proof,
"but I believe we need to find a way
to alert ourselves
"of any sort
of celestial or fiend intrusion."
LAUAR: So it's a fiend.
LIAM: A fiend? Also -
MATT: "The very definition."
LIAM: This is not just a vendetta.
It knows about Whitestone.
It knows about our base of operations.
LAURA: How do you know that?
TALIESIN: Because it came here.
LIAM: It looked us in the face.
It knows we're here.
It knows where we are.
It knows all of us.
It knows him. It knows all of us.
TALIESIN: It may not know its value,
but it does -
MATT: The rakshasa -
at this point, Gilmore is like,
"That's actually a very valid point.
"How would it - did it meet us?
How would it know what I look like?"
MARISHA: Good point. Did it meet us?
LIAM: When was the last time you saw us
before Kiki found you?
MATT: "You mean last night?"
LIAM: The last conversation we had.
LAURA: Okay, dinner?
MATT: "Dinner would have been
the last time, yes."
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: At this point,
Allura thinks for a second. She goes,
"I'm fairly certain
"that they can peer into the minds
of those nearby
"and can read surface thoughts.
"It may know more secrets
than you think it does,
"which makes it
that much more important
"that we eliminate it."
LIAM: Yeah, good.
That guy is a liability.
SAM: We'll put it on the list.
LAURA: I know.
Right next to the dragons?
MARISHA: He could be following us
for a while.
LIAM: He could rat us out to the dragons.
LAURA: (sighs)
LIAM: He's fucking pissed off.
He wants to hurt me, and now her,
as badly as possible.
All of you matter to us.
I think the rakshasa
comes before the dragons.
Maybe not before the Vestiges,
but on the list.
TALIESIN: If we can put some manpower
towards discovering where he is
and where he lies
while we continue our search
for the Vestiges,
and then once we have a solid lead,
we can follow it through.
MATT: "I can work on that."
ASHLEY: Can I go over to the dead body
that Kima threw
into the middle of the room
and cast Speak With Dead?
SAM: Ooh.
LIAM: (whispering) Yeah, girl.
TALIESIN: That's a way to go.
TRAVIS: Is his face super crushed?
TRAVIS: Is it like (krsch)
Halloween mask inside-out?
MATT: Yeah, it's just smashed inward.
TRAVIS: Well hold on,
let me reach into his mouth.
And I reach up under his nasal cavity
and I pop his face back out
just a little bit.
SAM: Ugh.
LIAM: (zombie groans)
TRAVIS: It's like
a deflated soccer ball, right?
MATT: Yeah, it's horrifying.
Straight-up horrifying.
ASHLEY: Five questions.
SAM: Five questions?
LIAM: I thought it was three.
Five? That's good.
MATT: Okay. All right.
So you have five questions
you can ask the creature.
As it sits there and you guys watch
as Pike comes over in her robe
and sits down next to it.
You touch your symbol
and reach out and touch the body.
And all of a sudden,
you watch as the chest rises again.
"(rasping inhale)"
You hear this horrible sucking sound
as air is brought into the chest cavity.
He doesn't breathe out,
he just holds the air in,
and the deformed, wrecked,
bone shard-pierced face
that once was this assassin,
which you can see now,
it looks to be
loosely elvish in appearance,
or at least there's
some essence of elvish to its form,
but the eyes are gone,
the eyes are just mush.
It slowly sits up
and turns towards you, Pike, going,
"(rasping groans)"
ASHLEY: Who sent you?
MATT: "(slowly) Hotis..."
ASHLEY: Hotis.
MATT: "...hired us."
ASHLEY: What was -
LAURA, LIAM, AND TRAVIS:
(overlapping) Hotis hired us.
ASHLEY: Hotis hired us.
What is your organization?
MATT: "We run The Clasp in Stillben."
SAM: Stillben.
TRAVIS: The Clasp in Stillben.
LAURA: Sheesh.
ASHLEY: Three more questions.
TRAVIS: How did the rakshasa
know to find us here?
How did Hotis know.
ASHLEY: How did Hotis know
to find us here?
MATT: "I don't know.
"He had information.
"He led us here.
Instructed our strikes."
SAM: How many men?
TALIESIN: How many of them were there?
ASHLEY: How many of you were there?
MATT: "We were 6 in total."
LIAM: You've got one more question.
TALIESIN: Where were they all
supposed to meet
when everything was finished?
TRAVIS: Or who would know
more than him?
LIAM: Who would know more?
LAURA: Who is his boss or something?
ASHLEY: Who his boss was?
TRAVIS: Or who does he report to?
LAURA: Within The Clasp.
Who does he report to in The Clasp?
LIAM: Who gives you your orders?
ASHLEY: Who gives you your orders?
LAURA: (whispering) Within The Clasp.
ASHLEY: Within The Clasp?
MATT: (chuckling) That's a fine -
LAURA: I have one job on this ship.
ASHLEY: I have one job -
LAURA AND TRAVIS: It's stupid -
ASHLEY AND TRAVIS:
(shouting) - but I'm going to do it!
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: So good.
ASHLEY: Yes.
MATT: "Spireling Veekar. (groans)"
MARISHA: Veekar.
MATT: And with that,
the last bit of air
that had been trapped
in the chest cavity
has been utilized
and the body (rasping groan)
goes back to its still rest,
no longer moving,
no longer puppeteered
by your divine energies.
TRAVIS: I'll take care of this.
MARISHA: Veekar.
LAURA: Spireling Veekar.
TALIESIN: So I think we have 4 dead bodies.
We're missing 2, then?
LAURA: Wait, 4 dead bodies? Wait -
SAM: Wait, there's Kashaw's.
TALIESIN: Kashaw's? Oh.
LAURA: Plus Kima's.
TALIESIN: Mine, yours -
LAURA AND TALIESIN: Gilmore's.
MATT: And Gilmore's like,
"(weak chuckle)
I actually have one that's pretty rough
"in my place right now."
LIAM: He got Akira'd.
MATT: "I got a little angry."
LAURA: Did you kill one or two?
MATT: "Oh, just one."
MARISHA: So the only one
that's missing in action
is the one
that I shoved out the window?
TALIESIN: And we're waiting for news
on whether that one -
MATT: "Is there one that was left alive?"
MARISHA: Well, there was one
that was shoved out a window,
so hopefully he died.
MATT: "We'll find out."
TRAVIS: Hm. Sloppy.
LIAM: Broke his legs
and his heart never woke.
MARISHA: I heard that, Grog.
TRAVIS: Oh. (ahem) I said. Super.
LAURA: (laughs) Good save.
MATT: "All right. Drinks? Please?"
TRAVIS: Yeah.
SAM: At some point, Percy,
ask Gilmore about that robe.
TALIESIN: Oh, yeah.
I still actually have it,
it occurs to me.
I haven't put it down yet.
MATT: (laughs) He's holding it
like a pair of soiled underpants, all -
TALIESIN: I've actually
been using Bad News like a -
MARISHA: Like a surrender flag?
TALIESIN: Like spindle. Like a bindle.
MARISHA: There you go.
TALIESIN: Hobo.
MARISHA: Hobo bindle.
TALIESIN: This was given to Vax.
It was mystical.
It was attached to your skin.
LIAM: Peeling the skin off my flesh.
MATT: "(shudders)"
He takes it for a second.
He puts his hand over
and his eyes flicker for a second
with a spark of arcane energy
and he sits back.
"No, this is indeed
a cursed robe.
"It's a Robe of Flaying."
LAURA: A Robe of Flaying?!
TRAVIS: Flaying?
SAM AND LAURA: Gross.
ASHLEY: Yikes.
TRAVIS: Awesome.
SAM: Is it worth anything?
MATT: "(chuckles)
To the right people, maybe."
LIAM: The Clasp, yeah.
SAM: Well, why don't you take it?
MATT: "Oh, I don't want to have
any hand in this type of business.
"I'm sorry. I deal
with above-the-board magical items.
"You've gone creative with me,
but even that was relatively harmless.
"This slowly takes the skin
off of its wearer.
"I don't wish to have this
part of my repertoire."
ASHLEY: If we destroy it, though,
would that hurt Vax?
MATT: "Well,
if you've removed it from him,
"then the enchantment's been broken."
SAM: So does it - do you have to -
anyone you put it on, it curses them?
LIAM: It sticks.
It's like fucking flypaper.
SAM: Keep that robe. (laughs)
TRAVIS: Yeah.
TRAVIS: I'll keep it.
LAURA: In the Bag of Holding?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: Yeah, it's not a bad idea.
LAURA: Don't play with it, Grog.
TRAVIS: Why?
LAURA: Just don't put it on
because you think it will be fun.
LIAM: You look way better mostly naked,
so don't -
TRAVIS: I'm not putting my bits
where Vax's were.
I'll just keep it in the Bag.
LIAM: Ow, that hurts my feelings.
LAURA: Percy?
TALIESIN: Yes?
LAURA: Are your guards
very well-trained in tracking?
TALIESIN: I honestly don't know.
I haven't been here.
But we hunt. We are...
everybody here hunts.
LAURA: Trinket has their scent.
I mean, I can send him to help.
TALIESIN: That's a great idea.
That's a brilliant idea. Yes, please.
We also, I might add, in theory,
have a wolf patrolling the area.
TRAVIS: Yes, Baldrick's somewhere.
TALIESIN: And I'm sure he's aware
that there's a commotion.
LIAM: I walk over to Gilmore for a second.
LIAM: Shaun, you know - sorry.
MATT: "Ah. Yes?"
LIAM: Wait, wait, wait.
Hey, hand that over, big guy.
MATT: "But of course."
LIAM: Yeah, thank you.
MATT: "You've certainly earned it."
LIAM: You know everything
about everything.
MATT: "(stuttering) I wouldn't say
I know everything about everything."
LIAM: It's close.
MATT: "Between the two of us,"
MATT: And he motions toward Allura.
"Pretty sure we know everything,
but she more than I."
LIAM: I can agree with that.
We found this in a tomb.
LAURA: What are you pointing at?
SAM: His pec.
MARISHA: Your heart?
LAURA: Your boob?
LIAM: My fucking rock-hard pec.
The ARMOR. I tap the armor,
as you fucking very well knew,
Laura Bailey.
I kind of understand it.
Can you tell anything about it?
LAURA: Other than the fact
that it smells really bad?
LIAM: Shush, yeah,
it does smell bad.
Scanlan gave me some patchouli
to rub on it,
but it only does half the job.
What can you tell me about it?
It belonged to a god.
MATT: He takes a minute
and walks around you,
looking at the armor up and down.
Looking at you up and down a little bit.
But mostly at the armor.
His eyes flare a few times
with arcane sparks.
"This is a powerful Vestige,
my friend.
"This has existed for quite some time,
and you've -
"well, there's certainly
a bit of dark divine energy around it.
"It looks like it has the capability
"to resist most elements
when given the instruction,
"and it safeguards
the life of the bearer
"and it looks like
there's some sort of a -
"Tell you what. Follow me."
LIAM: Yeah?
MATT: And he stops and he goes,
"It's really me this time!
Follow me."
LIAM: I know it is.
MATT: "All right."
And he walks outside
of the front of the castle to the walkway,
stepping over the crimson smear
that once was the one assassin.
And he walks up to the edge
of the sheer cliffs
that are on each side of that walkway
and the elevated, cleaved mountain
the castle was built on.
He walks up
to the very edge with you and goes,
"Do you trust me?"
LIAM: (quietly) I do.
MATT: As soon as you look down,
you feel a thrust
as he pushes you off the cliff.
At that moment, you suddenly,
instinctively, look up
and from outside
the back of the armor, (fwwsh) -
TRAVIS: What?!
MARISHA: Oh.
MATT: - these giant black raven wings
spill out from the sides.
LAURA: Wait, so you could have flown
when you came out of the dragon?
LIAM: Only if I know how to work it.
LAURA: (gasps)
MATT: You get the sense
that this feature to the armor
was only recently -
LAURA: Oh, shit.
TRAVIS: Oh, fucking shit.
TRAVIS: Get it, archangel.
MATT: You go from falling
to swooping over the forest
on the outside of Whitestone.
SAM: Oh, he's The Crow! He's The Crow!
LAURA: What the fuck?
LAURA: He can fly?
HE can fucking fly?!
LIAM: After doing that, I double back
and I fly up that same cliff
and I lift Gilmore up in the sky.
MATT: "(startled noise)"
LIAM: (shouting) You fucking
brilliant bastard!
Thank you. Thank you.
(sighs) This is embarrassing.
I float us back down.
MATT: You can see he's a little nervous,
but he's smiling.
"(nervous laughter)"
LIAM: Sorry.
MATT: "Thank you. No, it's all right.
I would have been fine."
LIAM: You are a dear, dear friend.
You are a dear friend.
And I give him a big diagonal hug.
A long, strong hug.
MATT: He freezes for a moment,
still figuring out his boundaries
with the dynamic being what it is,
but eventually he gives in
and you feel his arms take you in as well,
and you guys have this long, honest,
connecting hug.
And as this happens,
the wings also wrap around
and envelop the both of you.
TRAVIS: Good moment.
LAURA: (frustrated) It's so ridiculous.
TRAVIS: He's alive. Let it go.
MATT: And then time seems to pass
for a minute
and as you release him,
the wings (fluttering sound)
scatter into black feathers in the wind
and disappear.
SAM: (whispering) Wow.
LAURA: (frustrated noise)
MATT: He steps away from you
and you can see
there's just a little streak
down the side of his face.
And he reaches up
and smacks you on the cheek a little bit.
"Glad you're all right."
LIAM: I am a great ally to you.
And if you need any favors,
I am your friend.
MATT: "That goes both ways.
Don't forget that."
LAURA: I walk up and I -
LIAM: Ow! Where were you,
what the fuck - oh, you're -
LAURA: You flying fuck. You flying fuck!
LIAM: I forgot you were a rogue. Yeah...
LAURA: (angry noise) I mean,
congratulations, it's really cool!
LIAM: That broom is really cool.
That you stole.
LAURA: If I didn't fall off of it.
You have fucking wings! Jesus.
I walk away.
LIAM: Vex'ahlia.
MATT: (laughs)
LIAM: I follow her and I stop her
and I give her a hug and I say,
LIAM: "I love you."
LAURA: (angry groan)
LIAM: I love you. I love you. I love you.
(whispering) And I'll be
less of a fuckwit lately, I promise.
LAURA: Really?
LIAM: (whispering) Yeah.
LAURA: All right.
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: I love you, too.
I'm glad you're not dead.
MARISHA: Keyleth has been
in the door frame,
watching all this happen.
I'm in the door frame.
TALIESIN: I'm slowly -
I'm going to walk in
and have a moment
and look Vax over.
LIAM: Hey, Shaun?
Once in a while? All the time?
MATT: "Oh, that's once every dawn,
that can return to you."
LAURA: Oh. I'm glad
I didn't push you off the cliff!
I almost did.
Wow, good to know.
MATT: (laughing)
That would have been really funny.
LIAM: That would have been hilarious.
TRAVIS: Holy shit. Holy shit.
ASHLEY: (laughs) You dick. (gasps)
MATT: It's for up to an hour,
it can last, just so you're aware.
But once per day,
you give yourself a fly speed of 60.
LIAM: 60. Same speed as my sister.
LAURA: No, I'm less, aren't I?
LIAM: Thank you, Shaun-slash-Matt.
TALIESIN: There's one last thing.
And I walk up and I look you over
and I pull out
the raven head cloak clasp
and I pin it to hold the cloak together.
And it's very deep, pitted silver
with a slight ruby tinge to it.
And it smells FABULOUS.
And it smells better
the more you sweat.
And it smells
of the Raven Queen's temple.
Now talk to Keyleth.
I'm counting on you. Good luck.
And I walk away.
LIAM: (yelling after him)
You're hard to read, man!
TALIESIN: I know!
TRAVIS: Cask of ale is out
and the ale is flowing.
LAURA: Oh, shit! Shit.
Tracking the guy.
SAM: Have the guards reported yet?
MATT: By this time,
some of the guards have come back,
reporting that they haven't
seen anything yet.
There are folks that were following
the tracks into the forest,
but the tracks have mostly gone cold.
Whoever it is knows how to not be found.
It's part of their job.
SAM: You could spend the night
tracking him.
LAURA: I could.
SAM: Or we could just drink.
MARISHA: Or we could just drink.
We know who the fucker was.
We know who he's going back to.
TRAVIS: Yep.
LAURA: We know he's going
back to Stillben.
MARISHA: To Spireling Veekar.
We know where he's headed.
TALIESIN: You guys
are going to drink for a bit?
LIAM: I'll do whatever you do.
TALIESIN: I'm going to go out
past the wall
and see if I can yell for the wolf.
MARISHA: Galdrick.
TALIESIN: Galdrick.
MATT: Galdrick. All right.
TALIESIN: I’m bringing a swath
from one of the -
MATT: Okay. You shout out
for about 10, 15 minutes or so
before you hear a distant howl. (howl)
TALIESIN: Galdrick!
MATT: A few more moments pass
before you hear (panting).
Coming up
from the outside of the forest,
the large gray dark wolf.
(padding footfalls)
TALIESIN: I show the blood-soaked chunk.
MATT: "(sniffs)"
TALIESIN: There were six.
Now there’s one.
If you find him,
we would be forever grateful.
MATT: "(licks chops)"
Licks his deep,
pearly-white bladed incisors
and turns around and -
"(grunts)" -
takes off into the forest
at triple-speed.
TALIESIN: Now I’m going to go up
and have a drink.
TRAVIS: Triple-speed, damn.
That’s a fast-ass wolf.
MATT: All right.
You all at these twilight hours
find yourselves gathering
your friends and allies
for a long-needed drink
until the sun begins to rise.
You all appreciate the friendship
that you’ve maintained,
the survival of those
that were endangered,
and eventually find yourself,
rather tipsy,
finding your way back to bed,
this time with quadruple the guards
at the door -
LAURA: Fully armored.
MATT: - of each of your rooms, resting.
MATT: We’ll take a quick break.
We’ll be back here
to get to the next bit of this episode.
See you guys here in a few minutes.
[Critical Role resumes at 2:34:15]
MATT: Welcome back! So.
As you guys find yourself
having a good night’s sleep,
waking up restfully around midday
to the early afternoon here in Whitestone.
Everyone except for you, Vax.
You, as you went to sleep, found,
as opposed to a restful night,
especially given the circumstance,
a perpetual onslaught
of terrible nightmares
recapping the events of the night before
with alternate possibilities,
looking and seeing Gilmore
plunging the blade into your stomach,
seeing your friends and family
torn apart by demons
called forth by this rakshasa
returning for vengeance.
You were tossing and turning
and woke up sweaty.
Unfortunately, you do not
get the benefits of a full rest.
So you're still at the hit point value
that you had before.
LIAM: And I can't use hit dice, right?
ASHLEY: What?
MATT: You can use hit dice.
LIAM: I can use hit dice?
MATT: Yeah.
ASHLEY: I can also heal you.
LIAM: I think it might be more than that.
I feel weird. I feel really weird.
I'm going to have some -
I'm going to have -
What's the D&D term for Bloody Mary?
I need a mimosa or a Bloody Mary
and I'm going to take a rest.
MARISHA: A little hair of the dog?
LIAM: And use some hit dice.
TRAVIS: Technically, hair of the dog
would be poisoning him again this morning.
MARISHA: Oh, yeah. Yeah.
TRAVIS: Which we can do.
MARISHA: Which we could do.
You never know.
MATT: You actually take the time
to go ahead and rest up,
and even then,
your body's just restless.
LIAM: Hit dice does nothing?
MATT: You find yourself
unable to spend those, either.
You're basically rocking in place
and playing over the imagery in your mind
over and over again,
and there's a perpetual cold sweat
across your brow.
LAURA: Can I go knock on his door
in the morning?
LAURA: Can I knock?
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: Brother?
LIAM: What?
LAURA: Sorry. I don't mean to disturb you.
I just feel really guilty.
I just wanted to say sorry
for being mad at you
for being able to fly,
because I'm actually
really impressed and proud of you,
and I'm glad you're not dead.
LAURA: Is all I wanted to say.
LIAM: I open the door, scratching my arm.
LAURA: What the fuck is wrong with you?
LIAM: I don't feel very well.
LAURA: You smell better.
LIAM: (sighs) I'm just
going to ignore that.
Could you do me a favor,
if you really feel so special to me.
Could you get Allura for me, maybe?
Send Allura to my room.
LAURA: I mean, yeah,
she's not in the castle, but I can find -
LIAM: Where does she - where is -
yeah, you've got a broom.
LIAM: Could you go fly over there?
LAURA: Yeah, no fucking -
LIAM: You can fly
as much as you want, all day.
LIAM: All day long, right?
LAURA: This is true.
LAURA: I will go find Allura for you
as an apology
for being a dick last night.
And I fly off
and I go try to find Allura.
MATT: You come to Allura's home -
LIAM: I go have diarrhea
in the chamber pot in my room.
MATT: Okay. Ugh.
TRAVIS: Talk to your daggers
while you do it.
MARISHA: (laughs) Yeah.
MATT: You make your way back to the house
where Allura's been staying
and knock on the door.
Door opens. Kima's there.
LAURA: Oh. Hi, dear.
MATT: "Hi. You guys rest okay?
Everything all right?"
LAURA: Oh, yes -
MATT: "Any problems?"
MATT: She grabs her maul
from the side of the door.
LAURA: No, no, everything's great.
Is Allura in here, as well?
MATT: "Yeah, she's -
would you like some coffee?"
LAURA: I would love some.
MATT: As you come inside,
you can smell coffee brewing.
MARISHA: I've got time.
MATT: You see Allura
comes out of the kitchen area
of this home that she's staying in.
"Oh, hi!"
LAURA: Hi!
MATT: "I'll get another cup."
LAURA: Thank you.
MATT: And she leaves.
LIAM: Does she have
that beautiful but messy morning hair
that takes two hours to prep for a movie?
MATT: Actually, no. Her hair is perfect.
MARISHA: Oh, yeah. I'm sure.
LAURA: Of course it is.
LIAM: Fucking wizards.
LAURA: Prestidigitation.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: Fucking blow-outs
every morning.
MATT: No, she - yeah.
Way too well put together
for being this early
in the conscious day.
LAURA: I look at Kima.
How the fuck does she do it?
MATT: "I know, you're telling me, right?"
LAURA: Right?
MATT: "It's obnoxious. (sighs)"
LIAM: (singing) I say bitch...
MARISHA: (cracks up)
MATT: She brings coffee back
and sets it in the center
of this serving table for guests.
You start drinking the coffee.
It's very well put on, nice and sweet.
"So, what -"
LAURA: Oh! I forgot.
I came here for a reason.
My brother is shaken up from last night,
and I think he might be
a little worried about -
I don't know, he sent me to find you.
I'm not exactly sure what's going on,
but he looked terrible,
and he thought
maybe you would be able to help?
MATT: "It was a very rough night."
LIAM: I mean, you're not a cleric, but -
I don't know,
he seemed to think
he could use your help.
MATT: "Let's go have a look, then."
And so they go ahead
and they walk back with you.
LAURA: I'm going to catch up.
You get a head start.
I'm just going to get some more coffee.
MATT: (laughs) It's good coffee.
TRAVIS: You hear a whisper
from the coffee mug saying, "I own you."
(all laugh)
LAURA: I know you do, darling.
I know you do.
ASHLEY: You didn't perception check
the cup!
LIAM: Find my dominoes. They’re here.
ASHLEY: What's he looking up?
LAURA: I don't know.
MATT: Eventually,
you've found your way
wandering through the hall
to get some food, sunken sockets.
Grog passes by you in the hallway,
and you see Vax,
hand against the wall,
walking by,
looking dazed and a little weary.
TRAVIS: You all right, mate?
LIAM: I've got the shits.
TRAVIS: Oh. Like, the shits or the twirls?
LIAM: Bad - what's the difference?
TRAVIS: The shits it's just one end,
the other, both.
North, south, all at the same time.
It's like a relay race.
LIAM: I know what you mean now. Yes.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: Well, I was just - you know,
I might be crossing that threshold.
And I jump into a side door -
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: - and send it out both sides.
Two exits, no waiting.
MATT: Oh.
TRAVIS: (laughing) Oh, shit. Amazing.
ASHLEY: (dryly) Wow,
I've never heard of that.
MATT: You proudly hear,
through the doorway.
LIAM: This happened to me
when I was six, by the way.
I'm talking about Liam, not Vax.
TRAVIS: If you've had the twirls,
you never forget them.
MATT: All right. As time passes,
eventually your sister, Allura, and Kima
make their way towards you
to go ahead and check in.
LAURA: Is he still in the toilet
or did he get out yet?
MATT: He's made his way out.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: Allura takes a look at you.
"You certainly don't look well."
LIAM: (hoarsely) I'm having really bad -
I had bad dreams all night long.
I relived the moment from last night
and I've got really bad...
bathroom etiquette.
MATT: "It might be
lingering enchantment from the robe.
"Let me try something."
And she pulls back
and thumbs mentally
through some sort of index in her head
and brings her hand up.
"Eras to no est."
And begins drawing
this strange glyph in the air,
that where her finger traces,
you can see a slight sparkle falls behind
before it forges some sort of a letter
that you don't recognize,
and it passes through you (foomf),
and as it gets through, you can't help
but to get pushed back for a second.
"Do you feel any different?"
LIAM: (fart noise)
MATT: No change,
from what you can tell.
Still just... bad place.
LIAM: Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
(sighs) I'm new to this, but -
Can I cast Lay on Hands on myself?
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: Pray to my god.
It's the worst. Can you help?
MATT: The effect hits
and intends to remove any poison,
disease circumstance.
No change in physical presence.
LIAM: (whispering) Fuck.
ASHLEY: (whispering) What the fuck?
MATT: "Kima, have you any ideas?"
"Here! Let me have a look at you."
She pulls you down to her position,
just pushing your eyelids open.
TRAVIS: Yeah, be very thorough.
MATT: "Grog, do you
want to help me with this?"
TRAVIS: Yep, absolutely.
Open your mouth, stick out your tongue.
LIAM: You're not
going to slip me the digit, are you?
TRAVIS: Stick out your tongue!
MATT: "I'm not going to."
TRAVIS: I grab his tongue.
LIAM: Aaah!
TRAVIS: Kima, you see anything in there?
Any bumps? Mumps?
LIAM: (groans)
MATT: "Just seems tired to me."
TRAVIS: Pull his tongue a little bit more.
LIAM: Aaah! (garbled) Grog!
TRAVIS: I release, I release.
LIAM: Ohhh, fuck.
ASHLEY: Can I wake up
and come out into the hallway?
MARISHA: I'll join Pike.
MATT: You guys walk out
and see as Allura sits back
with a slight chuckle next to Vex,
as you see both Grog and Kima
manhandling a very exhausted-looking Vax
in the center of the hallway.
LIAM: Oh, it's funny to you, eh?
ASHLEY: What are you guys looking for?
TRAVIS: Oh, Vax doesn't feel well.
He shit and puked
all over the area in the back.
MARISHA: Oh no!
ASHLEY: Can I check him?
MARISHA: Was it the crab cakes?
LIAM: I didn't have those.
MATT: You want to make a Medicine check?
ASHLEY: Yeah.
TALIESIN: I ate them, and I was fine.
MARISHA: Really?
The crab cakes messed with me a little.
SAM: I'm reading this whole time.
Just reading and reading.
MATT: You hear this echo in the distance
of him shitting himself.
And you're like, "eh."
ASHLEY: 23.
MATT: 23. You push Kima aside
and take a very intense look at his body.
ASHLEY: Move aside, move aside, move aside.
MATT: "Oh."
Very intense look over.
Physically, there does not appear
to be any ailment to him, whatsoever.
There are traces of exhaustion in him,
and you do have a point of exhaustion,
by the way, for a lack of evening's rest.
But there's no signs
of onset of splotchiness or diseases.
There's no pulsing
or darkened vein marks.
Nothing physical.
ASHLEY: No poison?
MARISHA: What did you try on him, Pike?
ASHLEY: Medicine check.
LAURA: Are you cursed? Is he cursed?
MARISHA: I go up to Vax.
Does he still have the brooch on?
MATT: The brooch
that was given to him by Percy.
MARISHA: I look at it.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: I can tell you what is in there.
It's nothing fancy.
TRAVIS: You're killing him.
MARISHA: Is this the skull I gave you?
TALIESIN: Well, it's a cast of -
the skull you gave me is still in my bag.
MARISHA: You cast it? Wow.
TALIESIN: I did.
MARISHA: That's impressive.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
LAURA: My brother, puking his guts out.
MARISHA: Sorry.
LIAM: Not right now (retch).
TALIESIN: Oh, god.
MARISHA: Ooh. Allura, what did you try?
TALIESIN: Did he just throw up everywhere?
LIAM: No, I stopped it.
LIAM: (moans)
TALIESIN: Let it out. Let it out.
MATT: "I attempted to dispel,
"in case there was any spell
that was still sustained on him."
MARISHA: Kima, did you try Restoration?
MATT: Kima goes,
"Not really my specialty
at the moment. My apologies."
ASHLEY: I'll do it. I'll do it.
MARISHA: I've got
Greater Restoration learned.
ASHLEY: We could try.
MARISHA: Pike and I will tag-team
a Greater Restoration.
MATT: All righty.
LIAM: (groans)
TRAVIS: Percy, if you're feeling gross,
you can imagine -
go examine the leftovers over there.
TALIESIN: Is there some vomit
in the corner?
TRAVIS: Yep, yep. Just make sure
you crawl in on your hands and knees.
TALIESIN: I'm going to go poke at it
just to see if there's anything in there
that looks funny.
LIAM: Only some of it is vomit.
TALIESIN: I'm well-aware.
I have siblings, I've seen this before.
LIAM: (laughs)
MATT: And so as Percy has wandered off
at this time,
you guys both hold hands and channel,
through both of your abilities,
the Greater Restoration spell.
Suddenly,
you feel like this dark hook
that was in the center of your being
is lifted.
And as it dissipates,
you're still exhausted,
and still lost
an entire evening's worth of rest,
but whatever was keeping you
in that nightmarish realm of stasis
seems to have been dispelled.
LIAM: How's my intestines?
MATT: Better. Tired.
Your midsection is very sore
from the constant flexing.
MARISHA: Did Pike and I notice anything
when we ripped out this darkness
from his chest?
MATT: You gather
that there was some curse
that had taken hold of his body.
LAURA: Ah! He was cursed.
ASHLEY: Yeah, he was cursed.
MARISHA: Like, by the rakshasa, probably?
MATT: You gather,
probably something to do
with the rakshasa, yeah.
LAURA: Grog, can I have your jug
for a moment?
TRAVIS: Why?
LAURA: I just want to get some water.
TRAVIS: What kind of water?
LAURA: Regular-ass water.
TRAVIS: I'll do it.
LAURA: Not ass-water. Just regular water.
TRAVIS: Could I have
some ass-water, please?
LAURA: No, no. Just regular water, Grog.
ASHLEY: No, Grog.
TRAVIS: Regular water, please?
MATT: Jug fills up with clear, cool water.
LAURA: Drink this.
LIAM: All of it?!
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: Are you sure
that won't make me throw up, as well?
LAURA: You're very dehydrated, seriously.
ASHLEY: As much as you can.
TALIESIN: There's no signs of poisoning
in any of the remains, is there?
LIAM: (gulping sounds)
MATT: No. In fact,
you spend probably a good 3 to 4 minutes
pushing through Vax refuse
while nobody else has thought
to actually come and stop you
when they've already figured out
what the problem was.
TALIESIN: That's fine.
MARISHA: Hey, Percy!
TRAVIS: He still feels bad, keep looking!
MARISHA: Hey, Percy, you find anything?
MARISHA: Sorry, haven't found
anything yet, Percy.
Keep going. It might be clues.
TALIESIN: It will take -
if I don't see anything in 3 minutes -
MATT: Roll a medicine check.
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: Awful people.
That's a 14.
TRAVIS: Find a toy car...
MATT: It seems
fairly standard bile and excrement.
TALIESIN: Nothing, nothing, no poison.
MARISHA: Find anything, Percy?
TALIESIN: (annoyed) No.
MARISHA: Oh.
Maybe you should keep looking.
MATT: No signs of parasites, nothing.
LIAM: Are there any feathers?
LAURA: Percival!
MATT: There is one feather.
MARISHA: Do a litmus test.
Is it basic or acid? We don't know.
LAURA: Percival, stop. He was cursed.
TALIESIN: I can actually have everybody
killed in their sleep.
This is actually one of the perks
of sleeping here.
I don't even have to do it myself.
I come out and I'm -
TRAVIS: Are you done with the jug?
Can I have that back, please?
TALIESIN: (shudders)
TRAVIS: Thank you.
LIAM: Grog, does that thing make mimosas?
LAURA: Oh!
MARISHA: Ooh!
TRAVIS: Mimosas?
LAURA: Or Bloody Marys?
TALIESIN: Mimosas.
TRAVIS: Well, there's one way
to find out. Mimosas, please.
MATT: No effect.
TRAVIS: Shit.
LAURA: Ask for Bloody Marys. Bloody Marys.
TRAVIS: Bloody Marys, please.
MATT: No effect.
TRAVIS: Fuck!
LAURA: Does it not work anymore?
Ask for mayonnaise.
TRAVIS: Look, you put
a lot of stress on it, all right?
It made your ass-water just fine.
ASHLEY: Can you ask for some ale?
TRAVIS: No, I think it only works
for a little bit every day.
LAURA: Aw.
TRAVIS: You could try it.
ASHLEY: Ale?
LAURA: Please.
MATT: (fwssh) Fills with dark ale.
TRAVIS: Holy shit, you're magic!
MARISHA: Oh, we just found a loophole!
LAURA: Good job!
TRAVIS: (laughing) Monster magic!
ASHLEY: I drink some
and then pass it over.
SAM: Does it make mixed drinks?
TALIESIN: We hardly can make cocktails.
LAURA: Oh, that's probably bad for you
right now, but that's all right.
TALIESIN: No, this breakfast beer
is perfectly reasonable.
MARISHA: It needs to go
to a bartending class.
ASHLEY: Hair of the wolf.
TALIESIN: His face touched that.
I'm just dipping in.
LIAM: So studious.
TRAVIS: Oh, you're reading.
MATT: At this point,
you hear a guard's voice shout,
"Hail, Vox Machina!
Downstairs, please."
TALIESIN: Oh, god.
TRAVIS: We did your - give me the jug.
Don't you fucking hold onto that, Percy,
you give it back right now.
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: I take one more big sip
and toss it at him.
LIAM: Oh, catch it!
TRAVIS: I catch it.
MATT: Scanlan,
are you still reading this morning?
SAM: I mean, I'd tell everyone,
"Call me if it's important.
I've got to do this."
MATT: Okay.
Did you get a full night's rest, though?
SAM: I did.
MATT: Okay, yeah,
so your exhaustion point is gone.
All right. So you guys head downstairs.
TRAVIS: Yep.
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: As you get there,
the front gates to Whitestone castle -
no, the front doors
to the main entranceway
are partially open
and the guards are waiting there
as you see a shadow step in
from the outside daylight.
LAURA: It's a guy?
MARISHA: I light up my hands in defense.
MATT: You see step inside
to the center of the castle,
a very large, dark-furred wolf
carrying something within his jaws.
TRAVIS: Good boy.
MATT: Drops down on the ground
another dark-cloaked figure.
MARISHA: Is he still alive?
MATT: He is not alive.
There is a snapped neck
on this individual.
LAURA: Good job!
MATT: You can see a series of scrapes
across the face.
This person, as you go and inspect,
had been rushing quickly
through the forest
and had taken a number of small injuries
in the haste to escape.
However, could not escape
the ever-watching vigil.
ASHLEY: Ah!
LAURA: Fuck, yeah.
TRAVIS: I mean, we might as well
let him keep his prize.
TALIESIN: Oh, it's all his.
Check the body for bits
and then the rest is his.
LAURA: I want to check the body
to see if I can find anything useful.
MATT: Okay, yeah.
You actually find about 320 gold pieces
on the body.
SAM: Did we inspect
any of the other bodies?
MARISHA: No, we didn't.
LAURA: There was a lot going on.
MATT: You find 6 vials of poison.
LAURA: Whoa.
LIAM: Give that shit to me.
SAM: What kind? Just poison?
MARISHA: Fuck yeah.
MATT: You're not too familiar
with poisons.
Vax would be.
He could have a look at it.
LAURA: And you said 300 gold?
TRAVIS: 320.
MATT: 300 gold.
MATT: And you find what looks to be
a fist-sized glass sphere.
LAURA: A what-sized glass sphere?
MARISHA: Glass sphere?
MATT: Fist-sized glass sphere,
about that big.
TALIESIN: It might be a gazing sphere.
Be careful. Keep it under cover.
Keep it wrapped in something.
LIAM: I want to walk out
towards our beast here
and hold out my hand.
MATT: He walks up to you. (sniffs)
Smells your hand, and steps into it.
He head-butts the palm of your hand
and then runs his head under it.
ASHLEY: Oh. Percy, can I touch him?
MATT: There's a familiar scent.
You can see
there's an immediate familiarity with you
that wasn't there before.
LAURA: Oh, it's the Raven Queen.
Her champion.
LIAM: I just scrooch under his giant neck.
You want to be friends with me?
MATT: You can see the eyes,
dark and piercing into you.
"(grunts)"
LIAM: You be strong, I'll be fast.
You be strong and fast.
I'll be fast.
(shooka shooka shooka)
TRAVIS: Go give him a pet, Pike.
ASHLEY: Can I put my hand out to him?
MATT: He glances towards you.
LIAM: She's all right. She's all right.
MATT: You put your hand out?
ASHLEY: Yeah.
MATT: "(sniff sniff)"
He sniffs your hand.
MATT: "(snorts)"
ASHLEY: Oh!
ASHLEY: Can I try scratching at his ear?
MATT: You do,
and he seems to begrudgingly give into it.
ASHLEY: (laughs) I go,
"Ohhh."
(all laugh)
ASHLEY: I love him.
TRAVIS: Sourpuss.
LAURA: Can I check out the sphere
that I'm looking at?
TRAVIS: Baldrick, thank you.
You are free to do with this as you will.
MATT: "(grunt, chomp)"
He picks it up in his jaws again
and starts walking outside.
Spits it on the outside of the grounds,
rolling off the edge.
It doesn't go completely off,
but one of the legs
is dangling off the side,
and the guards wait there,
then take it and pull it away.
The wolf's not going to eat
the dead body.
But it's done. He's done his job.
He takes it out of the castle,
gets it out of your way,
and then begins to step back down
the walkway path south of the castle,
making his way back towards Whitestone
and the surrounding forest.
TALIESIN: Good boy. Good boy.
LAURA: I shake it.
MATT: You shake it.
You actually look inside.
There's a cloudy liquid
at the center of it.
When it was at rest,
it had no real motion,
but as you shake it,
it swirls on the inside.
LAURA: Oh, shit!
I made something happen.
LIAM: Bloop. Outlook shady.
MATT: (laughs)
MARISHA: You found a magic 8-ball!
TRAVIS: Signs point to yes.
LIAM: (laughs)
TALIESIN: We'll stop by Gilmore's
on our way back up to the front hall.
LAURA: Allura, do you know what this is?
MATT: She takes a look at it.
There's a little sparkle
of arcane energy in her eyes again.
You're starting to get the theme here.
There is a specific spell that she's using
to identify these objects.
You've seen it done before.
She takes a look at it and goes,
"Well, I can see
why this would be very useful
"for a member of the Clasp.
"It's a Scrying Eye."
MATT: And she throws it back to you.
LAURA: (gasps)
MARISHA: It's a scry - what?
LIAM AND SAM: A Scrying Eye.
LAURA: A Scrying Eye?
MARISHA: Oh, yeah. Sure.
MATT: When you take, essentially,
10 minutes to focus on the eye,
you can scry as per the spell.
But it can only be used for 10 minutes
and it cannot be used until the next dawn.
MARISHA: Can it be used by anybody?
MATT: Well, in theory.
You'll have to find out.
TALIESIN: And what can it see, precisely?
LAURA: This fist-sized glass sphere -
MATT: Anything a scrying spell could.
MARISHA: It works like scrying.
LAURA: You can scry...
Oh, you can scry for anything.
MATT: As per the spell. Once per day.
LIAM: What she does to waste a spell,
you can do as a freebie.
And you're so nosy,
so it's perfect for you.
LAURA: It actually is really perfect.
TALIESIN: That's disquieting. Excellent.
LAURA: I really, really like this thing.
MATT: You can see Allura.
Her face gets a little stern at this.
"This is precisely the issue
we have here.
"If they could scry information,
anyone can.
"Which is why
I'm going to get with Gilmore
"and go and get together with the rest
of the arcane minds here in Whitestone,
"and we're going to try to ward this place
from any sort of intrusion.
"If possible, I'd like to blanket
this entire area with illusion.
"I'd like it so those who should not know
that Whitestone even exists do not."
LIAM: Is there anything we can do to help?
MATT: "Honestly, do what you're doing.
"Although, I may need some aid
from you, there."
And she looks towards you, Pike,
and says,
"If we're going to find out
where this rakshasa is
"and how to head it off at the pass
in the coming weeks,
"I think your divine nature
would be of great aid.
"You and Keeper Yennan.
Between the two of you,
"I think we could map out
a plot to head it off at the pass,
"and when you return and are ready,
head into the hells ourselves
"and take it down
while there's still time."
ASHLEY: I would be glad to help.
MATT: "All right."
ASHLEY: It's okay.
I can come back to you guys at any time.
LIAM: What do you mean?
MARISHA: But you're so important, Pike.
ASHLEY: Well, I don't know.
MARISHA: We tend to need you a lot.
LAURA: We can give her one of the stones.
MARISHA: Yeah.
ASHLEY: Any time you need me.
(laughs) Ish. I will try to be there.
LAURA: (laughs)
LIAM: Here. You take this.
ASHLEY: A sending stone?
LIAM: Should you need us.
LAURA: Yeah, should you need us.
ASHLEY: Oh.
MARISHA: I have the other one, currently.
ASHLEY: Okay. I'll keep this with me.
MARISHA: Okay.
ASHLEY: Okay.
TRAVIS: Yeah,
you keep practicing to be a monster.
ASHLEY: Okay, I will, Grog.
TRAVIS: Okay.
ASHLEY: I'm a monster!
TRAVIS: Yeah!
MATT: So you write down "gate stone"
on your inventory.
TALIESIN: (quietly) She's staying
in Whitestone while we do our work.
(louder) Thank you
for keeping my home safe.
ASHLEY: You're welcome.
TALIESIN: Thank you. (sighs)
MARISHA: Well,
at least it's not as far as Vasselheim.
TRAVIS: No.
LAURA: That's true.
ASHLEY: No, it's not.
TALIESIN: We won't be gone long.
ASHLEY: No. And maybe
I'll meet you very soon.
LAURA: Yeah.
ASHLEY: I'll just help out where I can.
We got him once. I can get him again.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: (cackles)
ASHLEY: (laughs)
MATT: "As you can."
TRAVIS: Dragon-slayer
and Rakshasa-slayer.
ASHLEY: I'm a monster.
MATT: "All right.
Where are you off to, then?"
TALIESIN: I'd say one more
proper night's sleep,
then into the Feywild.
LAURA: The Feywild.
TRAVIS: Feywild?
TALIESIN: We've seen
what the Vestiges can be.
I think they're...
terribly important.
And we can return
from the Feywild immediately
and in theory,
be right back here when we're finished,
and perhaps by then
we'll have an avenue of attack
to this rakshasa.
LAURA: And we can just pop on in there
because of you, Keyleth.
MARISHA: Yes.
LIAM: We're going to make you a beast.
LAURA: Oh. Sure.
MARISHA: Beefing up the twins.
LIAM: Yeah.
ASHLEY: Yeah.
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: Beast.
LAURA: Let's find it.
MARISHA: I go up to Pike.
MARISHA: Can we take a quick walk?
ASHLEY: Of course.
MARISHA: Before we take off?
TALIESIN: I figure we would take
one full night's sleep -
MARISHA: Before I take us in? Okay.
TALIESIN: We leave at dawn?
ASHLEY: We plan at dawn?
MARISHA: Plan at dawn? (laughs)
TALIESIN: We plan at dawn.
MARISHA: We plan to leave at dawn.
TALIESIN: We plan to leave at dawn.
TRAVIS: You thought it was stupid
when I said it, but what?
ASHLEY: They learned.
TRAVIS: (laughs)
TALIESIN: Right on thirty is fine,
if you say 9:00, 9:30.
MARISHA: Yeah. 9:00, 9:30.
We plan ahead.
TALIESIN: Barring traffic.
MARISHA: Okay,
I'm going to take a walk with Pike.
LAURA: You just have a Trapper-Keeper
full of appointments?
MATT: You just walk down the path
from Whitestone castle?
MARISHA: Yeah, whatever.
We take a nice stroll around the Sun Tree.
MATT: All right, so you guys
start making your way
down towards Whitestone proper.
As you walk along the way...
MARISHA: I don't know, really,
how to start this conversation. (sighs)
I guess I just wanted to talk to you,
and maybe you can give
a little bit of insight
and help clear my head.
ASHLEY: Okay.
MARISHA: And I didn't think about it
until we were in Scanlan's spa the other day,
and you said you were really confused,
and I'm really confused,
and I didn't know you were confused
because I feel like
if I knew you were confused,
then I wouldn't feel so bad
about being confused
because we're confused together.
ASHLEY: I feel confused... all the time.
MARISHA: Do you? I do, too!
ASHLEY: Yes!
ASHLEY: Just in a perpetual state
of confusion.
MARISHA: The world is so big.
ASHLEY: I think that's just what life is.
MARISHA: (sighs) Right.
The world's really big.
ASHLEY: Yeah.
MARISHA: Very confusing.
LAURA AND LIAM: (laugh)
MARISHA: I guess I just -
I've always respected you
and looked up to you, and...
you're a cleric of Sarenrae,
but you still seem to be
very much in control
of your life and your destiny,
and you seem to know
where you're going.
(boxes fall offscreen)
MARISHA: Fucking...
(shouts) Assassin!
MATT: You look around and you see
a boy holding a wheelbarrow nearby
is picking up a bunch of fruit
that had fallen out.
"I'm terribly sorry.
Didn't mean to bother you."
He puts them back in
and keeps wheeling on.
ASHLEY: It's all right. It's okay.
MARISHA: I've always loved,
"My cabbages!"
MATT: "My cabbages!" Yes.
MARISHA: Anyway,
Sorry, it was distract - loud noises.
ASHLEY: It's okay.
I feel like maybe I just look that way,
because I don't feel like
I have much of anything together,
or know where I'm going.
MARISHA: (laughs) I guess
that's probably all of us.
ASHLEY: Yeah.
MARISHA: I guess I just -
I'm a little curious
on how your relationship
with Sarenrae works,
because it doesn't necessarily
seem like she... is in control of you.
ASHLEY: No.
MARISHA: Or has dominion over you.
ASHLEY: It's an interesting thing.
I think...
She just helps when we need her,
or when I need her,
and I think for the rest of the time,
She just -
MARISHA: Does her own thing?
ASHLEY: - does her own thing.
MARISHA: Yeah.
ASHLEY: It was interesting
going to the Temple
of the Raven Queen.
She seems... very interesting to me.
MARISHA: How do you mean?
ASHLEY: I don't know.
MARISHA: Like more...
ASHLEY: She's just very involved.
MARISHA: Involved? Yeah.
ASHLEY: But maybe that's -
maybe that's because Vax
has fully given himself to Her.
MARISHA: Would you say
you haven't fully given yourself
to Sarenrae?
ASHLEY: (hesitantly) I think I try to,
but there's always
that little part of me that thinks...
or has doubt?
So I don't know.
MARISHA: Growing up in the Ashari tribe,
we were taught
that the gods mind their own business
and we mind our own.
I don't have any disrespect for them,
but also want to... tread lightly.
ASHLEY: Yeah. I think that's
a very good way to handle it.
MARISHA: Okay. I don't know.
I guess I don't know
what I really wanted to find.
I guess misery loves company.
ASHLEY: Yeah.
MARISHA: It feels better
knowing I'm not the only one confused.
ASHLEY: Yes, there are two confused souls
in the world.
I'm sure there are so many more.
MARISHA: I confuse you?
ASHLEY: Yeah. (laughs) Hugs.
MARISHA: Hugs. Well.
I'm beginning to get the idea
that we're going to be
intermingling with gods
a little bit more, so.
ASHLEY: I think we will.
MARISHA: I guess it's something
I'm going to have to
start getting comfortable with.
ASHLEY: I think you should.
And I think...
you should
get comfortable with Vax.
LAURA: (laughs)
MARISHA: (embarrassed) Oh!
ASHLEY: I think he really fancies you.
MARISHA: (weakly) Uh-huh?
ASHLEY: But don't be scared.
MARISHA: I'm so terrified.
ASHLEY: Just know
that things are not forever...
MARISHA: (sighs) I think that's my fear.
ASHLEY: And just have fun, you know?
MARISHA: (weak laughter)
I haven't had fun in a long time.
ASHLEY: Well, you should.
MARISHA: I should.
ASHLEY: We all need a little fun.
(chuckles)
Well, I'll see you very soon.
MARISHA: You're always with us,
wherever we go.
ASHLEY: Okay.
MARISHA: (sighs)
ASHLEY: I love you.
MARISHA: I love you.
SAM: When I heard she was leaving,
I went out looking for Pike,
and I've come up to where they are.
MATT: They're both standing
at the northern base of the Sun Tree
in the center of the town square.
You see them hugging
and give each other a kiss on the cheek.
SAM: (out of breath) Oh, sorry.
MARISHA: (shouting) Assassin!
SAM: No, no, it's me.
It's me. It's me. Sorry. Sorry.
ASHLEY: Oh.
MARISHA: Haa - sure.
SAM: There was
a very frightened child over there
with a bunch of fruit.
(all laugh)
ASHLEY: Oh, he just -
MARISHA: I might have
screamed in his face.
ASHLEY: Yeah, we thought
he was an assassin.
MARISHA: Assassin, yeah.
SAM: He was crying.
SAM: Maybe you should go -
here, take a gold piece.
Why don't you go
buy something from him?
MARISHA: Okay, yeah.
What do you want?
You want some limes?
Some grapefruit?
SAM: I love a good lime.
MARISHA: You love a good lime?
I'll go to him and get some limes.
ASHLEY: See if he has a Choco Taco or -
MARISHA: Yeah, sure, yeah!
Yeah, yeah, okay.
I'm going to go to the kid.
MATT: Choco Taco, by the way,
is Draconic
for a fine cheese sandwich
in Wildmount.
It's a delicacy.
MARISHA: It's like
one of those traveling food carts?
You've got to track them on social media
to see where he's going to be?
MATT: Keyleth skips off in the direction -
ASHLEY: Love you, Kiki!
SAM: Pike, sorry.
I didn't know we were parting ways.
ASHLEY: I know. Maybe it won't be for long,
but I think I should stay.
SAM: Well, I respect that.
I just wanted to -
before we bid adieu, I wanted -
I can't believe we're leaving you again.
SAM: It's so sad.
ASHLEY: I know.
SAM: But I just wanted
to clear the air a bit.
You know, a short while ago,
I proposed marriage.
I've been thinking about it a lot -
ASHLEY: I know. I did not forget.
SAM: - and I hope you have been, too.
ASHLEY: Yes. I have been
thinking about it so much.
MARISHA: About this time,
I take the limes and I go,
"(shouting) Hey, Pike! Look! Fun!"
As I juggle them.
MARISHA: I'm having fun! (forced laughter)
ASHLEY: I'm proud of you!
TALIESIN: I feel
that this is a skill check.
No. I spent too long in high school
learning how to juggle.
Skill check.
MATT: Make an acrobatics check.
MARISHA: (laughs)
TALIESIN: No!
That's not how it works.
MARISHA: Fuck you, Percy,
you're not here!
TALIESIN: (laughs)
TRAVIS: It's off the table.
It's an automatic fail.
MARISHA: It landed on a -
LIAM: It's a fudge.
It landed on a blanket on an angle.
MARISHA: (laughs) What is it,
just a straight dex?
MATT: Acrobatics.
MARISHA: Acrobatics?
TALIESIN: Sorry. Sorry. I have -
MARISHA: 10!
MATT: 10. The limes (thud)
all over the ground.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
MARISHA: (forced laughter)
This is fun! I'll just keep going.
MATT: Keyleth slowly backs away,
realizing the moment.
MARISHA: Sorry!
MATT: Goes to get less-bruised limes.
SAM: Anyway, listen,
before you do what you're going to do
and we're going to go off on our way,
I just wanted to say
that I am here to officially
absolve you of that proposal,
and I rescind it.
I was foolish to do so,
and I don't want there to be
any strings attached when we leave,
and I think, really,
with you on the cusp of parting ways
and me seeing my daughter
and everything,
everything's come into
a bit of a clearer focus, and...
I think I've always been in love
with the idea of you.
You know, you're so perfect
and beautiful and smart and -
ASHLEY: It was the hairy shoulders,
wasn't it.
(all laugh)
SAM: But I don't want
to love an idea. I want to love a girl.
And I think in all of this time
of pining after you,
I forgot to just hang out with you
and know you as a person,
and I'm sorry for that.
ASHLEY: That's okay, Scanlan.
SAM: So I'm sorry
for objectifying you or whatever.
LAURA AND LIAM: (giggle)
MARISHA: (laughing) "Or whatever."
ASHLEY: It's okay.
These things happen.
And maybe it wasn't the best time,
and maybe someday in the future,
we can just reconnoiter
and see if we want to make a -
just talk about it again, I guess.
SAM: We'll be friends.
ASHLEY: We'll be friends.
Listen, I will always love you,
but I don't want this to be
a barrier in our friendship anymore,
so I'm taking it off the table.
And besides, all I really want
is to matter to someone,
and I do now,
and that's very new for me,
and confusing, and exhilarating,
and I've got to figure out
how to do it
and, well, I'll work on that,
and you work
on whatever you're working on,
and I will say this before we leave.
I'm a little older than you,
so I can give you some advice.
ASHLEY: Oh, I - okay.
(all laugh)
SAM: I will say,
speaking as someone
who has lost out
on years of a relationship
with someone I care deeply about,
if you have someone out there
that you love,
you should tell that person,
or, at least, tell someone about it.
It's a weight
that you're going to continue to bear,
and you're going to miss out
on months and years
of either knowing or not knowing.
ASHLEY: That's very true.
SAM: You don't have to tell me,
but you're the bravest woman I know,
and you should be brave enough
to just admit your feelings.
ASHLEY: (sighs) Well, maybe -
(all laugh)
ASHLEY: (stuttering) I'll think on it more.
And just, yeah. I have to get -
maybe I'll get more courage
just by staying here and, you know...
But thank you for the advice,
wise old man.
(all laugh)
LIAM: Bulletproof to peer pressure.
SAM: Anyway, I just wanted to say -
ASHLEY: But you are very charming.
I just wanted to tell you that.
SAM: Ah. It's not happening, sorry.
ASHLEY: Okay, okay.
(extended laughter)
SAM: Just so I'm clear.
ASHLEY: Nothing.
SAM: Off the table now.
ASHLEY: Off the table. Nothing.
(others continue to laugh)
ASHLEY: All right. Well.
SAM: I'm sorry.
I just have to let you down.
ASHLEY: It's really okay.
(laughs) All right.
SAM: All right, well.
Oh! Hugs?
ASHLEY: Just a friend hug.
SAM: Of course. Of course.
LIAM: Careful you don't get
velcroed to her shoulders.
MATT: Make another acrobatics check.
MARISHA: (laughs) Worse. 8.
I'm trying, Pike!
(crying) I'm having so much fun!
ASHLEY: It's okay! It's okay!
We'll talk later.
MARISHA: (crying) Huh?
ASHLEY: Can I - I'll just say bye
to the rest of the group.
LAURA: (unhappy noise) Oh, oh.
ASHLEY: It's okay.
ASHLEY: You don't need to cry yet.
LAURA: It’s all going so fast.
ASHLEY: Maybe we'll see you very soon.
LAURA: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
LIAM: Are we going already?
LAURA: I’m just so proud.
ASHLEY: Wait, are we going already
or do we have the night?
TALIESIN: We have the night to sleep
and we leave at dawn.
ASHLEY: Sorry, I just wanted
to give you a hug.
LAURA: I just really wanted to hug you, too.
ASHLEY: Yeah, because
you're one of my best friends
and I needed to give you a hug.
ASHLEY: It's going to be fine.
LAURA: Yeah.
ASHLEY: I may be here next week.
LAURA: You might.
LIAM: I mean, do your work tomorrow.
Can't we get shitfaced one last time?
ASHLEY: Let's go get shitfaced.
Come on!
LAURA: Can I just -
LAURA: (whispers) Percy.
TALIESIN: What? Yes?
LAURA: One quick question -
TALIESIN: Yes?
LAURA: I don't want to bother you
because I know there's a lot going on,
but we're going into the Feywild.
TALIESIN: Yes.
LAURA: And... I'm really nervous
about this broom.
TALIESIN: (irritably) Do you see
the giant mess in front of me right now?
LAURA: Yeah?
TALIESIN: This is the thing for your broom.
I'm sitting here while you were drinking,
working on this.
LAURA: (gasps) You were?
TALIESIN: You will
put a drink aside for me.
LAURA: Okay.
TALIESIN: I will see you
either later tonight, if this goes very -
Actually, give me the broom.
Just give me the broom.
LAURA: Okay. Well, all right, but -
TALIESIN: I will either see you
later tonight,
or I will see you in the morning.
LAURA: Don't lose sleep over it.
Unless you really want to.
But I don't want
to force you into anything.
TALIESIN: This pains me.
This pains me,
and it must be put down.
This must be put down and finished!
LAURA: Thank you, dear.
TALIESIN: Good night.
TALIESIN: I'm going
to roll a tinker check, at some point.
MATT: Yeah, yeah.
As you guys spend the rest
of the afternoon -
which, you woke up late,
for the most part,
so the afternoon's pretty short.
But as the sun sets here in Whitestone,
the cloud cover takes in once more,
and a very light drizzle
begins to hit the rooftops,
and you hear in the distance
people finishing rebuilding the roofs
that were destroyed in the battle.
Some buildings
that are starting to be put back up again.
The city is definitely, over time,
coming back to life.
You also know
that throughout the day,
you can see Allura and Gilmore
and the Farseer Eskil
are beginning
to mark areas in the town.
You're not sure what for,
but you gather
it's probably preparation for their wards
they're going to start putting up
throughout Whitestone.
During this time,
you make your first tinker check.
LIAM: Roll to attach a Baby Bjorn?
LAURA: (quietly) Come on, come on.
TALIESIN: That's a 21.
MATT: 21? Okay.
Working a good portion of the evening -
TALIESIN: It's not my first roll at it,
so, yeah.
MATT: Yeah, you start making
some decent headway.
You get the stirrups
well-bolted into the side,
making sure not to interrupt
any of the enchantment.
You also begin to work
on the finer elements
of the seat portion of it,
which in itself will have
a gimbal hinge
to adjust based on positioning,
which will allow her
to actually functionally sit on the seat.
We'll get to that in a minute.
The rest of you guys,
anything else you're doing
other than just drinking
in the time you have left?
SAM: Yeah, I go to see Vex real quick.
LAURA: Me?
SAM: Yeah. Oi, you. Oi.
LAURA: Hey, what's going on?
SAM: Remember when I did you a favor,
and you came to my room,
and I taught you how to fly the broom?
LAURA: I very much remember that, Scanlan.
SAM: And you said you owed me one?
LAURA: I owe you so much.
SAM: Here's the payback.
LAURA: Oh, no.
SAM: You have to wear
this fucking hat every time you fly.
(all laugh)
LAURA: This pointy motherfucker?
LIAM: Oh my gods.
TALIESIN: That was a long walk!
MARISHA: Such a long walk!
TALIESIN: Wow.
LIAM: Playing a long game.
LAURA: How's it look?
SAM: It looks really cool.
LAURA: Well, there you go.
(all laugh)
LAURA: I will gladly
do this for you, Scanlan.
SAM: Thank you.
LAURA: Does this mean we're even?
This hat makes us even?
SAM: That would make me so happy.
TALIESIN: (snorts)
LIAM: (giggling) Wow.
SAM: The debt is paid.
MATT: As she cackles loudly,
the hat atop her head
is everything you hoped for.
(all crack up)
SAM: Yes!
ASHLEY: Oh, Vex, that hat is amazing!
LAURA: (cackles)
TRAVIS: She's actually cackling.
LIAM: Oh, you devious motherfucker.
TALIESIN: Wow.
LAURA: I fucking like it. I appreciate it.
ASHLEY: I think it looks amazing.
SAM: The silhouette
is beautiful on you.
LIAM: It's very aerodynamic.
LAURA: Yeah.
ASHLEY: (laughs) Oh my god.
LIAM: If you're going straight up.
LAURA: I would try it out,
but I don't have the broom on me
right now, so.
MATT: Another tinker check.
TALIESIN: (whispering) Oh, bastard.
MARISHA: (chanting) Go, go, go!
MATT: You guys are drinking,
carousing in a local tavern,
laughing at her new hat.
TALIESIN: That's a 25.
MATT: 25?
TALIESIN: Proficiency, dex, and roll.
MATT: As the wee hours begin to click by,
the rest of you have finished
your evening of drinking -
LAURA: I turn the hat at an angle
and make it look a little more dashing.
MATT: There you go.
Yeah, it's more stylistic.
It's more Vex'ahlia.
LAURA: I like it.
TRAVIS: "Vex'ahlia."
LIAM: Can I squeeze in
one mini-conversation
before the end of it all?
MATT: Yes. I'm going to start up here.
As the evening progresses,
up to that point in time,
you're battling and battling
with this gimbal,
and making sure that everything itself
can sustain the necessary weight
without putting too much pressure
on a single point within the broom
to actually splinter the wood
or damage the actual object.
You're not even paying attention
to the fact
that there's very little airflow
and the sweat's
been dripping off of your face,
as you just need
to get this project done.
And in the moment, it finally hits you,
not knowing what time it is,
but you lift it up in your hands,
and you can see the completed work.
Hoping it will function.
We shall see.
But for now, your project is done.
TALIESIN: I've got a wonderful
little Elven signature on the bottom,
which I will tell you what it says
in just a little special signature,
and I put it aside.
I write down quick little notes
for some stuff that's to be taken care of
while we're away,
and I go find the bloody bar
that they have crashed.
MATT: All right.
TALIESIN: I'll take the broom.
LAURA: I hand him his drink
as soon as he comes in.
TALIESIN: I hand you a broom.
ASHLEY: Percy!
LAURA: (excited shout)
TALIESIN: At the very bottom in Elven,
scribed very gently with a twig,
it says in Elven,
"Death From Above."
SAM: Ooh.
ASHLEY: (laughing) Oh, yes.
TRAVIS: Oh.
LAURA: Percy, you've outdone yourself.
MARISHA: You and the names.
ASHLEY: (gasps) That's amazing.
SAM: Give it a try.
LAURA: I just sit on it,
raise up a little,
take my hands off the broom -
MARISHA: I reach over
and I grab the chicken
that I'm sure is on the table,
and I say,
"Vex, pull!"
TALIESIN: (yelps)
MATT: Roll an attack.
LAURA: Oh, god.
Do I have to roll disadvantage?
MATT: Nope.
LAURA: Ha ha!
That's right, and it's a 30!
(excited cheers)
MATT: The arrow smashes
into the side of the half-eaten chicken,
which, in your drunken state,
was not on your plate,
and you hear a voice go,
"Hey, that was my meal!"
(arrow impact)
TALIESIN: It's a 214-year-old pub.
Oh, god.
MARISHA: (weakly) Sorry!
MATT: The chicken,
now stapled to the wall by the arrow,
and the somewhat
frustrated-looking gentleman
who is on the other side of the table,
who has just been eating on his own,
is like -
"How are you going to pay for that?"
LAURA: I'm sorry, sir. No, it's all right.
MARISHA: (stuttering)
LAURA: I fly up
and I grab it off the wall
and I bring it back down.
MATT: He hasn't really noticed
the flight thing at this point,
so he's just like,
"(awed) Oh."
MARISHA: I take my fire hands
and I blacken it
and make it like a nice shish kebab.
LAURA: You burned it. Thank you.
MARISHA: Just a little -
I'm getting the dirt off of it.
I'm getting the hair off of it.
LAURA: Sorry it's burned now,
but there you go.
MARISHA: There's a little hair on it.
MATT: "It's okay."
ASHLEY: A little extra cooked.
TALIESIN: A round for the gentleman.
MATT: "It's burned."
LAURA: Yes. Charred. It's nice and charred.
MAN WITH CHICKEN: (weakly) Thanks.
MARISHA: I'm not a cook.
MATT: "I can tell."
MARISHA: It's arcane fire.
What do you want from me?
MATT: "I want my chicken untouched."
And he starts cutting into it,
trying to find pieces that are edible.
LAURA: I land next to my brother.
You wanted to talk to me. Why?
LIAM: What, you?
I don't want to talk to you.
LAURA: Oh, well fuck it.
I get up and start flying again.
TALIESIN: I was going to
go take a seat next to Pike,
at some point.
I've got a letter for you.
LIAM: I think we all
want to say goodbye to Pike.
That's what I was going to do.
MATT: As this is happening,
while the flying display is happening
and you're really intent
on watching all the mechanisms work
and watching how it adjusts to her weight,
and you want to be damn sure
that everything
that's supposed to move is.
While this is happening...
LIAM: All right.
And I sit down next to her
and I scootch her a little bit.
Thank you, Pickle.
ASHLEY: Thanks, Vaxy.
LIAM: I'm starting to gather
that you don't have
as many answers as I thought,
but be that as it may,
you're still a great inspiration to me.
I still feel
like I'm following in your footsteps.
ASHLEY: Well...
LIAM: Take that for what it's worth.
ASHLEY: Or flying in my footsteps, rather.
LIAM: Yeah.
ASHLEY: Because that's pretty cool.
LIAM: It is. It is pretty cool.
Fuck, we're going to miss you.
ASHLEY: I'm going to miss you.
I'm going to miss you guys very much.
But maybe I'll see you more often?
LIAM: If you need us, blink of an eye.
Blink of an eye, we'll come back.
ASHLEY: Okay. (sighs) Okay.
And I'll just be there when I can.
LIAM: We know.
ASHLEY: Okay.
LIAM: It's going to hurt, but we know.
ASHLEY: Yeah?
LIAM: And you know that we all - all of us.
That big asshole over there.
ASHLEY: That big asshole.
LIAM: My twin, with the -
LAURA: I float down behind him -
LIAM: She's behind me, isn't she?
ASHLEY: Yes.
LAURA: - and give him bunny ears
behind his head.
LIAM: That one.
ASHLEY: (laughs) Hi, Vex.
LIAM: Red, Whitey, Shorty.
We're all going to miss you.
ASHLEY: (sighs)
I'm going to miss you guys a lot.
LIAM: Cheers.
ASHLEY: Cheers.
LIAM: (toonk)
ASHLEY: (drinking noises)
LAURA: Gulp, gulp, glub, glub, glub.
LIAM: (sighs) All right.
ASHLEY: All right.
LIAM: I'm going to tie one on. Thanks.
ASHLEY: All right. Bye, Vax.
MATT: As you continue to drink, Percy -
MARISHA: Keyleth just hollers,
"Vax! Come sit by me."
LAURA: (loudly) Oooh!
I mean, go for her...
MARISHA: (yelling) Shut the fuck up, Vex!
LIAM: Or say nothing!
LAURA: Say nothing.
I won't say anything.
I'm just going to keep flying around.
MARISHA: That's it.
MATT: All right. As Percy,
you see the opportunity now
as Vax moves
to take that same spot next to Pike.
TALIESIN: Oh, bloody hell,
about fucking time.
LIAM: (giggles)
TALIESIN: (sighs)
ASHLEY: Hi.
TALIESIN: You're intimidating as fuck,
you know that?
ASHLEY: Me?
TALIESIN: Yes.
ASHLEY: How?!
TALIESIN: Everyone's always worried
about impressing you.
ASHLEY: Impressing me?
TALIESIN: Yes, it's why we're rubbish
when you're not around.
Everybody's trying to impress you.
ASHLEY: You know, I'm just rubbish.
I'm just all the time rubbish. (laughs)
TALIESIN: I know. Believe me, I'm aware.
I hand her a letter, and say,
"Here's a list
"of every terrible thing
I've got going on in this city right now."
ASHLEY: Okay.
TALIESIN: "So you'll know
what I've got cooking.
"Plus some people
that if you need particular things,
"you can talk to in the city,
who are friends of the family.
"10 things to see in the city
that might be nice,
"and my 10 favorite books in the library,
in case you get bored."
ASHLEY: Oh, Percy.
SAM: What to Do in Whitestone
for 48 Hours.
TALIESIN: Exactly.
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: You're going to
have to kill some time, I'm sure.
MARISHA: Whitestone Atlas Obscura.
ASHLEY: I will make sure
to visit all of these places
and read all these things.
TALIESIN: I'll try
and keep the kids safe,
and I will try not to be
the thing that kills them, either.
ASHLEY: Well - oh.
I have something for you.
TALIESIN: Hm? All right.
SAM: Is it a profession of love?
(laughs) Damn it!
LIAM: (laughs)
ASHLEY: When we went to my house,
or, well, where I lived with Wilhand...
TALIESIN: I remember.
ASHLEY: I got something
from underneath the bed, and -
LAURA: (whispering) Was it lacy panties?
ASHLEY: (laughs) Yes, it's lacy panties.
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: I will wear them always.
ASHLEY: This is something
that's been in my family
for a really long time,
and I've been thinking about it,
and I feel like I need to give it to you.
So come closer to me real quick.
It's a necklace.
And just... don't take it off.
TALIESIN: Okay. I will keep it on.
ASHLEY: And it will keep you safe.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
ASHLEY: You're welcome.
TALIESIN: And please
keep all this safe, as well.
ASHLEY: I will.
And keep them safe,
and keep yourself safe, please?
TALIESIN: (sighs) Let's all be safe.
To that.
ASHLEY: Cheers.
TALIESIN: Cheers, and god,
TALIESIN: I hope they're making out
in the next hour.
ASHLEY: Same.
TALIESIN: God, wouldn't that be lovely.
LAURA: I float down
and kick Grog in the head
and then float back up.
TRAVIS: Ow!
MATT: Make a perception check, Grog.
TRAVIS: Shit! 6.
(all laugh)
MATT: Someone fucking
threw something at your head.
TRAVIS: Who wants to go
right fucking now?
I was in the middle
of a gorgeous cup of ale
and I'm wearing half of it!
SAM: It was that guy
with the burnt chicken.
TRAVIS: I rush the guy
with the burnt chicken
and I pick him up,
and I throw him across the tavern.
MATT: "(screams)"
TRAVIS: Who's with
the burnt chicken piece of shit?
MATT: He slams onto a table.
You can now see
there are two guys in the back,
who are probably
part of the building crew here,
look at each other
and roll up their sleeves.
"We doing this?!"
ALL: YEAH!
LAURA: Big tavern brawl!
MATT: They rush in and start slugging at you
and it goes into an old-style -
TALIESIN: Outside. Outside!
LAURA: Trinket!
MARISHA: Keyleth picks up two chickens,
burns them with her hands,
and chucks them at the guys.
MARISHA: (shouting) Food fight!
TRAVIS: (laughing) Yes!
MATT: A giant brawl
breaks out at this time.
TRAVIS: (laughing) Whole-tavern brawl.
MATT: You hear people laughing,
and the music picks up more,
and there's tables being tossed over.
There's a hint of gingerness to it;
no one's damaging the -
TRAVIS: Not the face. Not the face.
MATT: - you can see,
in general, in the city,
there's a lot of tension to get out
from previous events,
and there are a few folks in this town,
in this particular tavern
that are enjoying
throwing a couple of punches
and taking a few,
and there are some folks
that are watching,
and enjoying watching,
this fight go down.
TRAVIS: (laughs) Yes! Amazing.
MATT: And while no one here
can throw a punch
to really give you much of an issue, Grog,
it is fun to feel the energy again.
TRAVIS: Take a few, yes.
TALIESIN: Slap fight.
TRAVIS: I sell them a bit more
than they're worth.
(all laugh)
MATT: All right. As eventually,
the fight dies down,
another round of drinks are purchased
by those who are involved.
You all find yourselves
now into the late, late hours.
Once again, probably pushing
another sunrise in the next hour or so.
You gather you
should probably find yourselves to rest.
TALIESIN: Sleep, then leave.
Sleep, then leave.
ASHLEY: I give Grog a big hug and say,
ASHLEY: You're my big brother, yeah?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
ASHLEY: Please be safe.
TRAVIS: I will. We're the original O.G.,
you know that?
ASHLEY: Yeah, we're the original O.G.
TRAVIS: Well, I guess original and O
is redundant, but -
ASHLEY: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
ASHLEY: Original Original G.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we're the O-O-G.
ASHLEY: Oo-G. Oog.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: You guys make your way
back to Whitestone castle.
Find a full evening's sleep.
Eventually, the late morning,
early afternoon comes about.
You're well-rested,
and a night of good dreams come to you.
In contrast to the bad night before,
you do manage to get full rest.
[no audio]
LIAM: - into my sister's room
with a bowl of lukewarm lentil soup,
and go,
"Oh, god, I'm still sick.
(vomit noises)"
LAURA: No, no!
ASHLEY: (laughs)
LIAM: And throw it all over her.
LAURA: You're such an asshole.
LIAM: Whoo! Still got it, baby!
And I run back to my room
and go to bed.
MATT: (giggles)
LAURA: I go take a shower.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: Ooh, ooh!
Can I find Pike? And I say,
"Hey, wait. Before I go,
"do you want me
to keep a special eye on Scanlan,
"since he proposed marriage?"
ASHLEY: Oh. Well,
that offer is off the table.
TRAVIS: What?
ASHLEY: Oh.
It's not happening anymore.
TRAVIS: Oh.
ASHLEY: So, yeah, he's free
to have some good times
at the old "lady houses"
that you guys like to visit.
The lady spas?
(all laugh)
MARISHA: Lady spas?!
TALIESIN: Lady spas?
ASHLEY: Whorehouses?
(all laugh)
LIAM: I'd rather go to the lady spas.
ASHLEY: You know what?
I think he's not quite ready.
I think it was just the idea of it.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
ASHLEY: The idea of me.
Because I'm just really great.
TRAVIS: I mean, you really are.
ASHLEY: Yeah.
TRAVIS: He got a little swept up,
carried away.
ASHLEY: Yeah, he did. It happens.
TRAVIS: Is there anybody
I should keep a special eye on?
(all laugh)
SAM: Yes!
TALIESIN: Wow, just -
ASHLEY: Oh. I have my eye on one already.
TRAVIS: Oh, yeah?
ASHLEY: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Like, magically?
TRAVIS: All right.
ASHLEY: Yeah. It's fine.
TRAVIS: You just let me know.
ASHLEY: Okay.
TRAVIS: I'm an extra layer of protection.
ASHLEY: Yeah. Well. Just be careful.
Keep yourself safe.
TRAVIS: Me?
ASHLEY: Yeah!
TRAVIS: That's never part of the plan.
ASHLEY: Well, just don't make
too crazy of decisions.
TRAVIS: All right. Hey!
When I come back,
those Gauntlets of Ogre Strength?
ASHLEY: Yeah?
TRAVIS: I wanna see 'em super beat up.
ASHLEY: Okay.
TRAVIS: Okay. We'll compare damage box.
ASHLEY: (doosh doosh doosh doosh doosh)
TRAVIS: (buuh)
LAURA: I run up behind Pike
out of my shower
and I twirl her around
and I give you a big old hug
and a kiss on the cheek.
ASHLEY: Oh. Ohh.
LAURA: We'll be back soon, darling.
ASHLEY: Okay. I hope so.
LAURA: Take care of everything.
ASHLEY: All right.
LAURA: I ought to get dressed.
ASHLEY: Yeah, will you - yeah. Okay.
(all laugh)
MATT: The flushed gnome runs off.
You guys all eventually
gather your materials,
your weapons, your equipment,
and anything else
you need for the journey,
and you all meet just on the outside
of the front doors to Whitestone castle
for a final goodbye.
There waiting for you:
Allura, the Realmseer, and Gilmore.
Kima's off elsewhere right now.
And Cassandra follows up behind
as you guys step out.
They all nod their heads.
Allura walks over to you
and pats you on the shoulder.
"Don't worry.
Have faith, and when you return.
"I'll know how to absolve you
of this cursed individual.
"And I think you'll have, hopefully,
"something else even more helpful
in your midst."
Cassandra comes up by you
and rests her chin on your shoulder.
"Percy, stay alive, please."
TALIESIN: All right. (sighs)
MATT: "I mean it."
TALIESIN: I know. I plan on coming back.
I'm not done.
MATT: "No, you're not."
And she smacks you in the face. (dshh)
TALIESIN: (sighs) I hate you.
MATT: Once everyone else is looking,
she rights herself again.
She takes her coat
and buttons it there in the middle.
"I cannot express, truly,
"how important
your influence has been in this city,
"and I don't think you realize
"just how many lives here
are for the better
"since you've
walked into our humble home.
"And it is for that reason
that I request,
"on the behalf
of all of us here in Whitestone,
"that you come back safe.
"That is all. Good luck."
She puts her shoulders back
and walks back into the castle.
TALIESIN: At your service, Lord Cassandra.
MATT: "Don't call me that."
TALIESIN: (laughs)
MATT: She walks back in.
ASHLEY: I put my shoulders back
and do the same thing she does.
And turn around and wave.
ASHLEY: I love you guys. (blows kiss)
MARISHA: Bye, Pike.
LAURA: Bye, Lord Pike.
TRAVIS: Bye, Pike.
ASHLEY: Bye.
VEX AND ASHLEY: (laugh)
LIAM: Bye, Pickle.
ASHLEY: Bye, Vaxy.
MATT: Allura and Gilmore
look at each other.
Allura nods
and walks in the castle after Pike,
leaving Gilmore there.
Gilmore looks at you all.
"Sorry about forgetting the hug
last time. It wasn't my intent."
LAURA: (laughs) Totally fine, dear.
MATT: "I have no words.
You all look fabulous.
"If you find anything really amazing
that you don't need,
"I'm trying to build up stock again.
"(chuckling) I kind of...
lost two shops in the same month."
LAURA: Are you building another shop?
MATT: "Well, I mean, eventually.
"You've got to have long-term plans,
my dear."
LAURA: Of course.
We'll keep promoting you, then.
MATT: "Please. I'm far beyond
the adventuring business,
"and income's been stale for a while.
"But stay safe. Be careful.
It's weird out there."
SAM: (laughs)
MATT: "Very, very weird out there."
LAURA: (laughs)
TALIESIN: So true.
MARISHA: Thank you, Gilmore.
TRAVIS: Should we -
since they're all smart and stuff -
ask them anything in particular
about the Feywild?
MARISHA: Yeah, yeah.
Any last words of wisdom for the Feywild?
MATT: "It's WEIRD out there."
LAURA: Okay.
MARISHA: Thank you.
TRAVIS: Deep.
MARISHA: I think that was it.
MATT: "Take everything with caution.
"Trust nothing.
"Keep your eyes open
and for the love of god,
"absolve yourself
of any preconceptions."
TRAVIS: Shit. Okay.
MARISHA: All right.
MATT: "Fly high, my bird."
MARISHA: Oh.
MATT: He walks up
and gives you a kiss on the cheek,
and then walks into the castle
after the rest.
MARISHA: Oh.
TALIESIN: (quietly) See?
That wasn't so hard, was it?
MARISHA: (whispering) Hush, Percy.
LAURA: Well.
SAM: Shall we?
LAURA: Oh, god. It's happening.
MARISHA: All form a circle and hold hands.
LIAM: All right.
TRAVIS: Oh, yeah,
let's actually do it, yeah.
LAURA: Oh, it's really -
LIAM: We're really doing it.
ASHLEY: I'm not here.
LAURA: Oh, Pike's not here.
LIAM: Ready, Stubby?
LAURA: Hum - oh, yes.
MARISHA: All right, everyone.
Close your eyes.
SAM: Do we have
to say a magic word?
MARISHA: No. Just close your eyes.
It helps -
SAM: Can we say a magic word?
MARISHA: If it makes you feel better,
Scanlan.
SAM: All right.
MARISHA: Close your eyes.
It helps with the nausea.
TALIESIN: You could sing.
MARISHA: And -
SAM, MARISHA, AND LIAM:
(gibberish noises)
(laughter)
LAURA: My pretty!
SAM: Wait, did it happen already?
We're still here.
MARISHA: My pretty!
LAURA: (cackles)
MATT: Where are you specifying?
Where are you going?
LIAM: (Brooklyn accent)
We're going to Florida!
(cheers)
MARISHA: We're going to Disney!
TALIESIN: Harry Potter Land!
TALIESIN AND MARISHA: Harry Potter Land!
TRAVIS: (laughing) Epcot Center.
MARISHA: I'm going to go
to the one place I know,
which is the portal
just beyond where Grog entered.
MATT: You haven't been in there.
MARISHA: But I know
that there's a portal there, right?
TRAVIS: There was a lake
in the middle of the -
LIAM: Yeah, Grog's girlfriend.
MARISHA: Grog's girlfriend.
SAM: But we weren't in the Feywild,
were we?
TRAVIS: No, no,
it's a portal to the Feywild.
MARISHA: No, but I've got a vague idea.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: Can I talk to - hang on, wait.
MARISHA: Grog!
TRAVIS: What?
MARISHA: Remember your girlfriend
in the Feywild?
TRAVIS: Pfft. Yeah.
MARISHA: Think about her and that place
very, very hard.
TRAVIS: Which part?
MARISHA: Going there.
LAURA: Oh, it's happening?
It's happening.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
I thought we already -
MARISHA: Think about Grog's girlfriend.
TRAVIS: Peanut butter and jelly.
LIAM: What did they do in there?
We don't know, still.
MARISHA: We don't know.
SAM: Maybe we'll find out!
MATT: For a moment,
there's just this still quiet,
and then this very cold breeze
begins to pick up
around your feet (wind noise)
and it's like someone smacked each of you
on your back really hard (boomf).
And with that,
your vision flashes for a moment,
and you look about
and everything has changed.
You step forward
into the now-temperate air.
You're struck immediately
by the vibrant purples, blues, and pinks
of a sunset sky
that envelops the clouds above you,
just above the treeline
that surrounds you.
The smell of fresh morning dew
and poppy upon the breeze
rolls past your nose and fills your senses
as you look down and see yourself wading
through what looks like two-foot-tall,
knee- to thigh-high grass.
Vine-covered tree trunks wrap
and rise around you,
curling as they stretch upward
like a bending dreamscape
of hundreds of small bobbing fairy lights
that float in the shadowed distance
of the forest.
You can see what looks to be
a few small pools of water
that have gathered in this small glade
that surrounds you.
And that's where
we'll pick up next week.
ASHLEY: Oh.
LAURA: It sounds beautiful.
MATT: Or two weeks from now, I guess.
LAURA: Oh, man, that's right.
ASHLEY: Boo.
TRAVIS: But we'll be back.
We'll do stuff next week.
MATT: You guys'll be back next week
for your own little fun time.
LAURA: Yeah, we'll do something.
MATT: We'll be back to pick up that line,
as the party enters the Feywild,
in two weeks.
TALIESIN: Man.
SAM: Who knows what we'll encounter.
MATT: It's going to be real interesting
here in the Feywild.
All right, so first and foremost,
thanks again to Loot Crate
for being our awesome sponsors.
TRAVIS: We're wearing
these awesome shirts.
Keyleth's got one. I'm rocking -
MARISHA: Yeah, everyone's
been tweeting at me,
asking "where did you get
your awesome shirt?"
Uh, LOOT CRATE, what.
ASHLEY: Loot Crate!
TRAVIS: Alex Murphy, RoboCop, holla.
LIAM: And our discount!
MATT: And Ashley,
if you hadn't picked up at this point,
is going back to New York
to shoot on the next season of Blindspot.
LIAM: No! No!
LAURA: Oh, no...
ASHLEY: Okay, wait, hold on a second.
SAM: Wait, what does she have?
ASHLEY: Guys, for those of you
in the Critter community
who made this amazing quilt.
This is going to come with me
and be on my bed, and I'll snuggle it.
MARISHA: Oh my god, that's amazing!
LAURA: They made her
the most amazing quilt!
ASHLEY: I love this so much.
SAM: Is that a Pike quilt?
ASHLEY: Yes.
LIAM: Yes, it is.
LAURA: And it's got art.
ASHLEY: It has all the art on it -
ASHLEY: - and then on the sides
it's just little quotes and things.
TRAVIS: Aim long, strike true,
a War God's Blessing upon you.
ASHLEY: People wrote on Twitter
LAURA: It's so amazing.
MARISHA: That's amazing!
TRAVIS: So many good messages.
ASHLEY: Never stop being yourself.
You empower others to be themselves -
oh, okay, now I'm just reading, like -
(all laugh)
ASHLEY: I thought it was going to be -
I wasn't trying
to read compliments about myself.
(all laugh)
MATT: I love this blanket.
It tells me how awesome I am.
TRAVIS: I like your hair!
LAURA: I'm pretty awesome.
ASHLEY: Your hair's great! I love it.
LIAM: Us pack of nerds
are going to miss you
more than Vox Machina misses Pike.
ASHLEY: Oh, goodness.
TRAVIS: Oh, yeah.
LIAM: We're going to miss you.
ASHLEY: I'm going to miss you guys
so much.
TRAVIS: We're going to steal you back
whenever we can.
MATT: We got better internet
in the studio for you.
LAURA: Yeah, it's true.
ASHLEY: What's he say, again?
MATT: We got better internet
in the studio specifically for you.
LAURA: So it'll be faster.
ASHLEY: Okay. All right.
MATT: When you can, Skype in.
ASHLEY: All right. When I can, Skype in.
MATT: I know it's not the same.
ASHLEY: Astral projection Pike. (laughs)
TRAVIS: (laughs) Yeah.
LAURA: No, no, no, you have the stone.
You'll be really there.
ASHLEY: Oh, I'll be really there.
That's right. That's right. Yes.
We're going to make it work.
MATT: I'll make it work.
ASHLEY: Matt will have to make it -
MATT: I'll figure it out. It's my job.
LIAM: Pike in a box
is better than no Pike.
MATT, TALIESIN, AND MARISHA:
(singing) It's a Pike in a box, ooh.
ASHLEY: It's a Pike in a box!
MATT, MARISHA, TALIESIN, AND LAURA:
(singing) Pike in a box, baaabe.
(singing peters out)
MATT: (singing) Step one, put a hole
in that box… put a Pike in that box?
MARISHA: Oh, god!
MATT: Not continuing the song...
(all laugh)
MATT: Guys,
thank you so much for watching.
I hope you enjoyed your time.
Looking forward to seeing all you folks
in Australia next week.
It's going to be awesome.
We'll see you guys Saturday night.
I believe it'll be Taliesin, Marisha -
MARISHA AND TALIESIN:
Not Taliesin.
MATT: Not Taliesin, sorry.
Liam, Marisha, Laura, and Travis
are going to play some Deadlands
for a couple of hours
on our awesome charity stream.
Check us out tomorrow, starting at 5pm.
Check out the rest of the stream
for all the awesome content
they're putting up there, guys.
ALL: Saturday.
MATT: Sorry. Saturday. Friday. It's -
TALIESIN: It technically is tomorrow.
MATT: No, it's not tomorrow yet. Sorry.
Starts tomorrow at 7pm, or 5pm.
It starts tomorrow at 7pm,
and then goes on.
LUCAS: Starts tomorrow at 7pm!
MATT: Thank you. Tomorrow at 7pm.
It goes until Saturday at 7pm.
My apologies.
I've had a lot on my mind today.
But yeah. So we'll see you guys
throughout the stream.
Until then, is it Thursday yet?
Have a good night, guys.