LIAM: Good evening, and welcome to another
episode of Critical Role, where a bunch of us
nerdy-ass voice actors sit around playing Dungeons
and Dragons, which is what we're going to do this
week, we're going to play some goddamn Dungeons
and Dragons. I've had crap bouncing around my
skull for two weeks. I don't know how Matthew does
it. I don't ever want to do it again, but I'm
excited for tonight. Ah, so welcome to my little
one-shot.
TRAVIS: I love it.
LIAM: What can we talk about? Hey guys, pay
attention to the video after our little welcome
here, because there's going to be some extra
stuff, and you guys, the cast, are verboten to
look at your smart phones, watches and stuff.
TRAVIS: Verboten from social medias.
MARY: We won't see any of your texts.
TRAVIS: Yar.
MARY: That's all.
TRAVIS and MARY: (speaking German)
MARY: Yeah. Well, that goes without saying.
LIAM: You're introducing the characters a little
early, but that's okay.
ASHLY: What are they saying? What's happening?
TRAVIS: It's okay, it's Spanish.
(laughter)
LIAM: Hey, I'm so chomping at the bit to fall on
my face, let's do our announcements so that we can
get to it.
TRAVIS: Hey! This week's episode's brought to you
by Lootcrate! The amazing Lootcrate, of which we
have a new crate to unbox. Grab your boxes.
ASHLY: Oh, are we all doing it?
TRAVIS: Open up. This is their anti-hero box.
ASHLY: What? Oh my god, what a charmed life we
lead.
TRAVIS: This is their anti-hero box. Well look
who's ahead of you, and immediately, I am greeted
by an Archer shirt.
LAURA: It's so hard! Why are you guys so fast?
ASHLY: This table's losing.
MARY: Sterling Archer, oh my gosh.
LAURA: Oh, shit.
MARY: Ooh! What size do you have?
ASHLY: I have a medium here.
MARY: We're going to switch boxes right now, tiny
tiny.
TRAVIS: Dude, we have Kill Bill socks.
LIAM: Oh my gosh! It's the right hand of doom from
Hellboy! Is this made just for me?
ASHLY: Hey, are these Kill Bill Socks?
LAURA: They are.
ASHLY: That's amazing.
LAURA: Hey look. World of Warcraft pins.
TRAVIS: You are the biggest Hellboy nerd I know.
LIAM: Stop the show! I'm going home!
MARY: Oh, World of Warcraft pins! Everyone, please
get the new expansion, it's fantastic.
TRAVIS: And Harley. Ah, Harley. Just waiting for
Mr J.
ASHLY: Oh, puddin'!
TRAVIS: Woo! That is your anti-hero Lootcrate box
that is out right now.
MARY: What is this?
LIAM: You turn the boxes inside out and they
become something cool. Something to do with that.
TRAVIS: That's the Hellboy fist. Look at that. A
sexual toy. A big red fist.
LAURA: Oh, look! It tells you how to do it!
Transform your crate.
ASHLY: Into what?
LAURA: I don't know.
TRAVIS: And coming up, they have a speed-themed
box.
LAURA: Oh my god, into a mallet.
TRAVIS: With a high-octane assortment of goodies,
ranging from Batman, CW's The Flash, Arrow,
Battlestar Galactica, Iron Man, Gone in 60
Seconds. It includes two collectibles, a figure,
and, as always, our monthly t-shirt, and
pan-speed. Coming next month. And if you have a
style need, along with the speed collection, there
are also some Sonic the Hedgehog socks. Being the
voice of Knuckles, I don't know if they're red--
you know, because I'm clearly the fastest person
in the show. They're probably blue? Fucking hell.
All right, well, they're probably the little blue
hedgehog's color.
MARY: But your Hellboy fist is red.
TRAVIS: That's right. And you also have a
Transformer's wearable for your world-saving
needs. And a MarioKart tee.
LAURA: And I think if you wear glasses, this shirt
is 3D.
MARY: What?
LAURA: No, I'm making that up, but it would be
really cool.
LIAM: Oh. I wish you weren't a liar.
TRAVIS: And as always, the promo code:
Lootcrate.com/criticalrole. Three dollars off your
subscription.
LIAM: Smooth.
TRAVIS: And a special message from this-- no,
there's actually no special message. But maybe
we'll work that in later.
MARY: China.
TRAVIS: Oh, really? (laughs) China.
ALL: Thanks, Lootcrate!
TRAVIS: I'm going to be walking around my house
naked in an Archer t-shirt.
MARY: I've been getting the DX boxes? Is that what
they are, the DX boxes are flipping awesome as well.
TRAVIS: Aren't they?
MARY: They're amazing. They're really legit, so go
for it, dudes.
LAURA: Ah, legit.
TRAVIS: And the LootBags, the LootPackages...
MARY: Yeah. I want to try the LootWear.
TRAVIS: Don't steal my stuff when the show is
over.
MARY: Don't any of you guys touch my stuff.
LIAM: Is it? He's here! It's real! It's happening,
it's happening!
LAURA: There's more!
TRAVIS: Come on in there. Come and sit down.
SAM: Hi, guys.
LIAM: Say Lootcrate three times.
SAM: Lootcrate, Lootcrate, Lootcrate?
ALL: Yeah!
SAM: You did it already?
LAURA: You missed it. Yep.
TRAVIS: The man is out of breath.
LIAM: As far as other announcements go, the only
one that I'm aware of, please add in after me, but
a bunch of us are going to SacAnime.
TRAVIS: Raise your hand. Oh, five of six.
LAURA: Minus one Ashly Burch.
MARY: Sorry, Ashly.
ASHLY: Yeah, it's fine. Cool. Cool, guys. It's
fine. It's no big deal.
LIAM: Sacramento doesn't want you, Ashly.
MARY: That's right. They told me.
ASHLY: I don't want them, either, so fuck it!
Whatever.
TRAVIS: We've got some super-sized carry-on
luggage.
ASHLY: Fuck Sacramento! I'll say it on air right
now.
LAURA: No. Don't say that!
ASHLY: Fuck them all! No, I actually really like
SacAnime. I've been there before. They're great.
MARY: Have you guys been? I've never been to
SacAnime.
LAURA: You haven't?
MARY: It's my first. Steve and I will be there
Saturday and Sunday. Steve Blum.
LIAM: I think I've been there eight or nine or
maybe ten times. I don't know why.
TRAVIS: Friday, Saturday, and Sunday, we'll be
there.
MARY: Are you going to be all right over there?
LAURA: Oh! I rolled two 20s in my pre-rolls.
ASHLY: Why would you do that now?
LAURA: I don't know!
LIAM: You know what? Later, you can slide them
out, positioned like that. How's that?
LAURA: I like it. Thank you. I appreciate that,
DM.
ASHLY: Yeah, thanks for letting us cheat.
LIAM: Okay, as a thin stream of wee goes down my
leg, why don't we dig in? Let's cut to the video,
because I'm so excited to go!
SAM: We're cutting to a video?
LIAM: Do you have any announcements? Is there
anything fun in your life?
SAM: Yeah, we'll be at SacAnime--
ASHLY: Do you want to talk about Loot Crate, too?
SAM: I... nope?
(laughter)
LIAM: All right, well. We'll be right back.
[dramatic music]
LIAM: Hey there, friends. Let me ask you
something: Chroma Conclave got you down? Aw, sure
it does. That's a heavy scene, man. Remember when
things were simpler? When the biggest threats
around were an eyeball under a mountain and a
Bohemian power couple? (sighs) Good times. Hey,
what do you say we turn the clock back a bit?
Welcome back to Emon, before the dragons came.
Anyone in the mood for a heist job? Okay, let's go
over what we're doing tonight.
Everybody remember this gentleman, Spireling
Shenn? Yeah, I like the look of this guy. You
probably recall him attempting to reach a business
arrangement between the Clasp and Vox Machina in
the days after Emon fell. It didn't really pan
out, and that's okay. He's always been a busy guy,
has multiple irons in the fire on any given day,
and on this cold and rainy evening, he simply
needs something retrieved for him. Something
important. Only trouble is, it belongs to someone
else. Someone who'd rather not part with it.
This is Adelaide Bluebutton, better known as the
Shrew. Adelaide is a rather successful
businesswoman here in Emon. She buys and sells
exotic curiosities from all the far-flung corners
of the world, mostly on the black market. Oh, and
she's really good at money laundering, too, which
the Clasp would know; they've used her extensively
in the past. Had a bit of a falling-out in recent
months, though. The Clasp invited her to join
them, but Adelaide wasn't interested, and with her
business growing the way it was-- well, the Clasp
prefers people they can control. And by the way,
if you're by any chance wondering how she came by
the moniker "The Shrew," she earned it. Bluebutton
is as mean a son of a bitch as you will ever meet.
A visiting merchant once tried to get the drop on
her and steal her wares. She ripped his arms off
without lifting a finger. But a mark is a mark,
and Spireling Shenn wants something specific.
Earlier this year, Adelaide acquired an emerald as
big as a cantaloupe: Tagmut's Eye. Priceless. That
is a substantial amount of capital that the Clasp
could bend to its purposes. That's where these
guys come in.
This is Tarvis. Yes, that is the name Travis went
with. He's an assassin-- a good one. Tarvis is the
lead on one of Shenn's many teams here in Emon.
He's also being groomed for more responsibility by
his higher-ups, and is entirely devoted to his
masters. His instructions: lead his team into
Adelaide Bluebutton's private residence, find the
gem, and get the hell out of Dodge. Simple.
Actually, I should probably confess something
here. All of our players tonight? They've been
given secrets, and they all think they're the only
ones. Tarvis's secret? The gem is actually a cover
Shenn has given him, specifically, to keep the
rest of his team from knowing the mission's true
objective: the Shrew's secret records. Shenn has
told him to find a green leather-bound ledger
containing the name of every shady character the
Shrew has ever dealt with in Emon, including
traitors to the throne. Valuable information. But
according to Shenn, intelligence indicates that
the book will most likely be found in the woman's
basement or possibly in some sort of vault on the
second floor, it's not clear. He's to find the
book and keep it secret from his team. (sighs) You
know what? I'd better hurry this along. We've got
a house to break into.
This fellow here is Obby the Rat. He's quick with
his hands and quicker with his mouth. He's the
break-in guy. Hasn't met many locked doors that
can slow him down. Obby has known Tarvis for
years. They used to play in the streets together
as kids, and Tarvis saved him from enough
ass-kickings that he is fiercely loyal to the
half-orc. Loves that big guy. Also, I gave him no
secrets, just because I thought it would be funny.
Next, we move on to Delweth. Good with a blade,
knows a bit of magic, just as easily kill you as
look at you. She's pretty badass. Also, just
between you and me: she secretly loathes Tarvis.
She's been with the Clasp for years, and is
itching for advancement, but instead of her, they
fawn over the half-orc instead. So she's decided
tonight is her chance to solve that problem.
That's her secret: once they secure this gem,
Tarvis is a dead man. Hell, probably the whole
team. What happens at the Shrew's stays at the
Shrew's. And as far as the Clasp will know, they
all died doing what they loved.
And this is Dren. She may be small, but trust me,
she can wreck your day. Although lately, she's
been doing a lot of babysitting. See, the team
actually has an outsider in tow tonight: someone
who knows Adelaide and knows the house almost as
well as the Shrew does. Dren has been assigned to
guarding this turncoat for close to two months
now. The Clasp has kept her under house arrest,
and Dren has been the one to bring her food, keep
her from bolting, pass the time with her... In
fact, probably too much time. See, she and her
charge have fallen in love. Or lust. You know
what? It's complicated. But Dren has revealed to
her prisoner that despite their word, the Clasp
intends to kill her as soon as the job is done. So
the two have cooked up a plan: once the emerald
has been secured, they kill everyone, take the
gem, and live happily ever after in another city.
Which just leaves us with Devan. Devan is... well,
a gambling addict, mostly. She's pretty good with
magic, too, but losing money is her real gift.
Three months ago, Devan drunkenly shot her mouth
off at the wrong card table and boasted that she
knew the Shrew, and what's more, she knew the lay
of the old hag's house like it was her own. And
she was even telling the truth. See, Devan is the
Shrew's granddaughter. Well estranged
granddaughter. All right, they hate each other.
Grandma Adelaide once trained Devan as she came to
master the family's innate magical talents. Only
for a few years, though, when she was younger,
after the kid's mother cut and ran. But for some
reason, it didn't end well, and the old woman
kicked her out on the street. What can you do?
Well, before she could blink, the Clasp had
promptly bought up all her gambling debt, and now
they have her under their thumb. They gave her a
choice: guide Tarvis's team through her
grandmother's death trap of a house or take a dirt
nap in the sewers. Now, remember, bringing Dren
back into the story, the two halfling lovers have
hatched a plan: once the gem is procured, they
kill the others and run off into the sunset.
There's just one thing: Devan doesn't love Dren.
She's playing her. Once the others are down, she's
taking out Dren, grabbing the emerald, and
splitting town on her own. Nothing personal.
So there you have it. Thanks for tuning in
tonight, and welcome back to Emon.
(laughter)
LIAM: Welcome back. I am very excited to share
with you all what has cooked inside my head for
two weeks. Before we go, I think it would be cool
to really quick, to clarify for the audience,
could you all introduce yourselves, your name,
your class, your race. That's racist.
SAM: My mouth is full!
LIAM: We can start on this end.
LAURA: Hi! My name is Devan Bluebutton. I spit as
I said it. I'm a halfling! And I'm a sorcerer.
ASHLY: My name's Dren, and I don't have a last
name, like Prince! And I'm an assassin, and a
halfling.
(laughter)
MARY: My name is Delweth, I'm a wood elf. I have
no last name, like Cher. Actually, my last name is
Cher. Is that it?
LIAM: Sure.
TRAVIS: I've got naan in my teeth.
MARY: That's his name, Naan-in-Teeth.
TRAVIS: My name is Tarvis.
(laughter)
LAURA: Sounds like a lot of thought went into
that.
LIAM: I texted Travis about five times over a
period of a week saying, "Hey man, you know, give
"me a name at some point so I can start." Crickets,
crickets, crickets. Finally, I'm like, "Hey man,
"I'm going to go with Tarvis." "Yeah, sounds
good."
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Brilliance, inspiration incarnate. And I
am a half-orc.
MARY: What's your other half?
SAM: Also orc.
(laughter)
LIAM: Also an assassin, and what's your
intelligence? What's it say on there?
SAM: Yeah, what's your intelligence?
TRAVIS: I am smart as balls, y'all, 18!
ALL: Whoa!
TRAVIS: Quantum physics, that's my shit.
MARY: Oh, I'm a rogue.
SAM: Yes, and I am Obby the Rat. I am a dwarf. I
am a rogue. That's it.
LIAM: Happy to have you!
TRAVIS: And you're handsome.
MARY: You have the best moustache ever!
LIAM: Really, I'm just procrastinating, we should
do this. Okay!
TRAVIS: Let's get it on!
LIAM: Let's get it on.
SAM: Roll for initiative.
(laughter)
LAURA: Oh! We got music!
ASHLY: This is exciting!
LIAM: There we go!
TRAVIS: Oh man!
LAURA: I'm so nervous!
SAM: I'm nervous for Liam because he has to be
under a lot of pressure right now.
LIAM: Liam's nervous for Liam, too.
For the last 24 hours, the city of Emon has been
blanketed in the heaviest rains in recent memory.
The streets have flooded with water, and the few
residents stubborn enough to brave the elements
hurry as quickly as they can to their
destinations, drenched and chilled to the bone.
But not so for you four. One of the Clasp's
countless hidden cells, you've been keeping warm
and cosy in the Diamond Nest tavern, waiting for
word from Spireling Shenn. You already know the
task that awaits you. You've been over it. All
that is left is for the Spireling to set you
loose. The Diamond Nest isn't horribly busy this
evening, but there are a few patrons scattered
about, trying to warm themselves by the fire,
trying to warm themselves with drink. You've been
here since the late afternoon, hiding from the
rain, and tedium set in hours ago. You've all been
pretending to nurse the same drinks since the sun
went down, and after minutes of staring at the
wall, out of the corner of your eye, Delweth, you
notice the door to the kitchen swing quietly open,
and a familiar figure come strolling over towards
your table in the corner. It's Garthok, a lean
looking half-orc you've run with a handful of
times. The rest of you finally notice him as well,
as he slides up to the table. "Evening, friends."
MARY: Hello Garthok.
LIAM: "You all as bored as you look?"
MARY: Pretty much.
LIAM: He looks towards the opaque windows facing
out on the street, the sound of heavy rain
spattering against them. "I'd hate to be the poor
schmucks wandering around out there tonight."
(chuckles) He looks back to you. Stares you dead
in the eye. "He's waiting." And with that the
half-orc heads across the tavern and seats himself
at the bar. Over the next few minutes, starting
with Dren, you leave, one at a time, slip through
the kitchen, down into the secret passageway that
leads to the Clasp's headquarters below the
Diamond Nest. And Dren, while you wait for the
rest to catch up with you, you make your way down
a long hall, nod at one of your brethren standing,
watching at a door. He unlocks it for you. Past
the door reveals your charge, Devan, lying on a
bed, who sits up and looks at you.
ASHLY: Hi. (giggles) Hi, Devan.
LAURA: What's going on out there?
ASHLY: Oh, we're very bored.
LAURA: Oh, okay.
ASHLY: Yeah.
LAURA: Have you heard anything from Shenn?
ASHLY: No, mostly everyone's been drinking. There
was a half-orc who's a little scary, and I wanted
to see-- do you need anything? Do you need like
food, or water, or--
LAURA: Oh, you're so kind. I think if you brought
me anything they might catch on, though.
ASHLY: Oh, right, okay. I worry about you. You
know, alone, in the dark.
LAURA: I worry about you, too. I think the sooner
that we can get to the house the sooner we can end
all this.
ASHLY: That's true, okay. I wrote a haiku for you,
do you want to hear it?
LAURA: I would love to.
ASHLY: Okay. What's your last name again?
LIAM: "Should I pull up a chair for this and
watch? I could get some popcorn."
ASHLY: Oh! Silence prisoner! Hi, sorry.
LAURA: Ow, it hurt when you hit me a second ago.
ASHLY: Hi, I was checking--who--how are--
LIAM: "You know the Spireling is waiting for you,
right?"
ASHLY: Oh! I'll go right now, to go-- don't you go
anywhere!
LAURA: (scared sound)
ASHLY: Oh yeah, you better be scared. Yeah, I'm
going, I'm gone.
LIAM: "Bring the girl."
ASHLY: Oh, right. I lock the door and--
LIAM: Everybody else catches up. You all gather
outside of Shen's chamber to wait. Four members of
the Clasp and this yutz. After a while the door
opens and another group of four files out, heading
down the hallway you all came from. And inside you
see Shen, looking down at some parchment spread
out across his table, his red monocle catching a
bit of light from a lantern in the room. "Yes,
"yes, come in. I know you all must have been going
a bit stir-crazy. Come. Right. I had hoped to move
"on this last night, but I'm afraid the elder
Bluebutton delayed her departure for a day.
"However, she has finally left for her little
excursion in Vasselheim. We've had her trailed to
"the city limits and beyond. Her house staff is
still on the premises, but they largely keep in
"their separate lodgings for the night. And even if
one of them decides to poke about in the main
"house, I'm sure they won't be much of a problem.
Any last questions before I send you out?"
SAM: (exaggerated Russian accent) Obby the Rat has
question.
(laughter)
SAM: Describe item again?
LIAM: "All right, I will. It's hard to miss. It's
a gem the size of a skull-- an emerald, as big as
"your head, sir."
SAM: Obby has big head.
LIAM: "That you do. Tarvis, do you have any real
questions, or are you good to go?"
TRAVIS: Oh, I'm ready to roll whenever everyone
else is.
ASHLY: I'm ready.
MARY: Yeah, all right.
LIAM: He walks up to you, Tarvis, and-- right up
close to you-- takes a little latch on your armor
and tightens it and says, "Now, bring me my
prize."
TRAVIS: Of course, Spireling.
LIAM: "I know you won't disappoint."
TRAVIS: Never dream of it.
LIAM: He then walks over to you, Devan. "Miss
Bluebutton, I hope you will put your trust in our
"very capable hands. I'm sure with your guidance
your grandmother's precautions will pose little
"problem. My people will keep you safe. Just do as
your escorts say, and there's no reason why things
"should go any differently than our little test
runs over the last couple weeks."
LAURA: Okay.
LIAM: "Once Tagmut's Eye sits on this table, you
will be free of your debt, as promised."
LAURA: Thank you.
LIAM: "I'm a good judge of character. I've no
doubt you'll do fine. Go."
LAURA: Now?
LIAM: You all leave the room, make your way
through the various halls of the Clasp underneath
the tavern. And you find the entrance to the
tunnels that connect to the sewers. The drainage
system underneath Emon is vast and labrynthine,
but Obby knows them well. He's traveled through at
least half of it at this point, sleeping below the
streets of the city as much as he has above.
Bluebutton's home-- Adelaide Bluebutton, your
grandmother, the Shrew--
LAURA: She is a shrew.
LIAM: She's over in the Central District. It's a
ways off from the Graveyard District where you're
starting. And even though The Rat hasn't been down
this stretch of tunnelwork before, with maps
procured from city planning, he's able to guide
the party there without any trouble.
SAM: I follow my nose.
MARY, LIAM and SAM: It always knows.
LIAM: So most of you can see in the dark, but the
two halflings would be blind as a bat, so Devan
and Obby are carrying torches to light the way.
There's also a lot of icky shit in the sewers, so
better to be prepared. And eventually you make
your way to your destination, which is a large
runoff from Adelaide's property. You come up to a
dead-end on a side path in the sewers, two equal
walkways on either side of a canal, and there is a
Shawshank-size pipe coming out of the wall, and
water is rushing out of it at a steady pace
because it is raining cats and dogs outside.
(whispers) I've got rain.
ALL: Ooh!
LIAM; And this is the plan: looking at the
schematics here, you know that the main pipe leads
to two smaller-- big enough for Tarvis, barely--
to shimmy up to two separate runoff drains on her
property. So that's the plan. It might be a little
trickier than anticipated because of the rain, but
you can certainly have at it.
SAM: And we pick one or the other?
LIAM: Well initially it's one, and then it
splits.
TRAVIS: A few marching orders before we begin.
Obby and I work together a lot, so we're familiar
with each other, wouldn't you say?
SAM: Yes, I'd follow you anywhere, Tarvis.
TRAVIS: Anywhere.
SAM: He's very smart.
TRAVIS: Delweth I've been learning a little bit
more about.
MARY: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Dren, not quite so sure what it is that
you do.
ASHLY: Well, I guard Devan, our prisoner. And on
the side I'm a bit of a poet. And I also assassin
people very well.
TRAVIS: Good. How do you like to assassin people?
ASHLY: Stealthily? Usually.
TRAVIS: With your hands?
ASHLY: No, I have like a crossbow type of
situation going on.
TRAVIS: Nice. A little range action.
ASHLY: Yeah, yeah.
TRAVIS: Delweth, would you mind sharing with Devan
what exactly you do to people like her in case she
thinks about running off or leaving--
LAURA: I'm not going to run anywhere.
TRAVIS: No, it's a hypothetical deal, you'll enjoy
this.
MARY: Starting at the head, or at the feet?
TRAVIS: You know what? Dealer's choice.
MARY: Really?
SAM: Obby prefers the feet.
MARY: All right.
TRAVIS: This is violence, not the other stuff.
ASHLY: Is this really necessary? She's being very
well-behaved.
MARY: You're rather small, so I can't really wear
your skin as a suit, but I could try. Maybe do--
I'd like a skirt, I'd probably make your skin into
a--
ASHLY: Hey guys, maybe we should pick a way to
go!
TRAVIS: That was lovely, thank you for that.
MARY: I could flay you alive.
TRAVIS: Yeah, that's really nice.
SAM: Tarvis.
TRAVIS: Yes?
SAM: Even though this Dren is guarding our
prisoner, we are all allowed to kill her if she
acts up, correct?
TRAVIS: Oh, did I not mention that, in the Clasp,
yes, if you betray one of your own, we will turn
you inside out and wear you as a hat.
MARY: Oh, all right, a hat's all right, too.
TRAVIS: But Dren knows that
ASHLY: Yeah, I know that.
TRAVIS: You knew that already, didn't you?
ASHLY: Yeah yeah yeah.
MARY: She's small too. It'd be a small hat, but a
nice one.
ASHLY: I wouldn't make a very good hat.
TRAVIS: Does anyone have a preference? Marching
order into the pipe.
SAM: I will go first.
TRAVIS: Really?
SAM: Yes. Let me tell you story-- you know why
they call me Obby the Rat?
TRAVIS: I mean, I do, you want to tell them?
SAM: Because I am small. Like rat. I go first.
LIAM: Okay. It is not easily walked into, it's
about 15 feet above all your heads. 17 feet above yours.
SAM: I will climb up there. Will it be an easy
climb or difficult climb?
(laughter)
TRAVIS: I'm going to die, I wasn't ready for
this.
SAM: Obby the Rat is now realizing he must
maintain accent for three hours.
(laughter)
SAM: With very limited accent abilities.
LIAM: If you'd like, you can make an acrobatics
check to get up to the pipe.
SAM: Hold my torch. Acrobatics. Ooh! 22.
LIAM: Yeah, you are a spry-- you're skinny-mini
for a dwarf. You scrabble up, parkour off of one
corner and then leap out and manage to catch with
your hand and hang from it.
SAM: I look back down at them. (clicks tongue)
LIAM: And then you yank your butt up inside. It is
slick and slimy from plant matter that has gone
through here, and also there is water rushing in
your face. You're getting toileted on for the most
part, here. I'd also make a quick strength check
to make sure you don't get flushed out.
SAM: Natural 20.
ALL: Wow!
LAURA: Already?
LIAM: Like a cat, you go up on the ends of your
fingers and the ends of your toes and all the
water scoots out under you. Okay, as he scrabbles
up, Delweth, you, bored and not interested in the
dwarf's ass, are staring at the wall, and you
notice off to the side a single brick maybe an
inch out of the wall. It's nothing major, but it
bumps you a little because the rest of the tunnel
is pretty level and clean.
MARY: I'm going to kill the party in the first
five minutes. Can I do a perception check?
LIAM: Sure.
MARY: 13.
LIAM: Yeah, without touching it, you get a bit
closer and can see that it is loose. That's going
to slide right in and out.
MARY: Hmm.
TRAVIS: Brick in the wall?
MARY: Yeah. Tarvis?
LIAM: We'll call that checking for traps as well.
You don't see anything hinky.
TRAVIS: Yes, dear.
MARY: Tarvis, did you see this?
TRAVIS: I do.
MARY: What do you think, Oh Great Leader?
TRAVIS: Hmm. You think it's trapped?
MARY: I do, actually.
TRAVIS: Maybe we should have Dren touch it.
MARY: Yeah.
ASHLY: Sure. I'll touch it.
TRAVIS: You will?
ASHLY: Well, once you guys are all up there. What
do we think it would be? Do we have to touch it?
MARY: No, we don't have to touch it.
LAURA: It's not trapped!
TRAVIS: Did you want to give it a touch? Oh!
LIAM: You pull and not one brick, but four bricks
all connected come out and uncover a flatter stone
surface inside. And you're right up against it now
and you see a very familiar circular insignia
there of a rodent curled in on itself in a little
ball. You know this. This is your grandmother's sign.
LAURA: Siggle?
LIAM: This is a house seal. It's a siggle.
MARY: Siggle.
LIAM: It's the siggle of the shrew!
LAURA: (gasp) I wonder if it works the way it does
upstairs.
TRAVIS: How does it work upstairs?
LAURA: I pull out my dagger and I cut my hand with
it.
SAM: Whoa!
LAURA: And I stick it on there. Anything?
LIAM: Yes, you remember how this works. It doesn't
happen instantly, but you feel the blood seep from
your hand into it. It stings a little bit, but
it's not too bad. And after like 20 seconds,
enough blood is pulled out and you hear a little
(click) and the seal spins a quarter inch. And the
door-- because it's a door-- pushes a little bit
in.
ASHLY: Ha! See? Yeah, it wasn't a trap. Good job,
Devan!
LAURA: Thanks!
TRAVIS: Good job, Devan.
LAURA: Thanks.
TRAVIS: Proving useful.
LAURA: I am useful! Also, I cast Dancing Lights
and throw my torch on the ground.
LIAM: Okay. Rolls into the canal, goes out, floats
away, down in the rainwater.
LAURA: See guys?
LIAM: And four beautiful globes of light swirl
around Devan and light up, and shadows sparkle all
around you. It's like a little disco--
TRAVIS: Was that our only torch?
LIAM: --in the sewer. No, Obby's got one.
MARY: No, we have two.
LAURA: Why do you need another torch?
ASHLY: So does the door open all the way? Or a
little bit?
LIAM: I don't know.
MARY: Oi. Devan.
LAURA: Huh?
MARY: Next time you think to throw something away,
check with us first, please?
LAURA: Okay, but I've got lots of light, though.
MARY: I'm so glad.
TRAVIS: Hat, remember. She'll wear you as a hat.
MARY: Skirt, actually. Yeah. With pleats.
TRAVIS: Could I check the partially open door?
LIAM: Sure. You want to check it for danger?
TRAVIS: I would like to check it for danger.
LIAM: Sure, make a danger check. Also known as
perception.
TRAVIS: Oh, perception.
SAM: Not great.
TRAVIS: Seven.
LIAM: It looks good. I mean you'd know if there
was something wrong with this. Seems fine. I mean
it's a door, right? Doors open and close.
TRAVIS: They sure do.
ASHLY: Can I check to see if I can fit through
it?
LIAM: You can almost fit through it. It catches on
your armor a bit so you're through and it feels
cool. And it's dark in there, you can't see shit
in there.
LAURA: Oh, I send one of the dancing lights in
with her.
LIAM: Okay. It floats in past and you looking
through can see the light-- the tunnel curves to
the right, and it goes around the corner, and you
see the light go (whoosh). Also, shimmying around
like this, the door goes a little bit further and
opens. It almost feels like it's on some sort of track or
rollers. And it slides back a little bit further.
And follows you in a bit. And there's actually a
way to step over to the right and go around. And
you're in.
ASHLY: I'm in, guys!
TRAVIS: Well. Keep it up. We'll follow you.
ASHLY: Can I borrow a torch or something?
LAURA: I send another dancing light in.
ASHLY: Thanks Devan.
LAURA: You're welcome.
LIAM: A little gold ball dancing around the top of
your head right now.
MARY: Check the walls for a torch.
ASHLY: My perception is not great, but should I
roll?
LIAM: You can. You don't see anything here.
ASHLY: I don't see anything here?
LIAM: It's a plain, flat, smooth, not curved but
goes straight and then angles, and then angles
again, and you can't see around the corner.
ASHLY: Okay, so I could walk down.
SAM: I stick my head out of the pipe, and say, I
think it found where it splits into two. I'm
covered in mostly number ones, a few number twos.
We can make it through here, it will be very
difficult, though. Where are you all?
TRAVIS: Obby?
SAM: What?
TRAVIS: We found a secret door.
SAM: I can come down from the number one and
number two place?
TRAVIS: We should leave him up there.
MARY: You want to?
TRAVIS: No, you can come down from the number one
and number two place.
SAM: All right, Tarvis. I jump down.
LIAM: Okay. Despite being covered in-- it's not a
lot of poo or anything.
SAM and ASHLY: Mostly number one.
LIAM: You land and do a nice little dwarven
three-point landing on one of the pathways. And
now you three are standing there. You're at the
edge, and you're inside.
MARY: Are there bricks around the door, or do we
need to--
LIAM: Yeah, you know that scene in Labyrinth where
she's running down that long brick passage--
LAURA: And the thing goes (spinning)?
LIAM: No, the one where it keeps going forever and
she can't find any doors. It's like that. I mean,
where the door was is uneven, there's teeth of bricks
sticking out the sides, and the whole thing moved
in straight.
LAURA: So it's a door.
LIAM: Yeah, it doesn't come out, it goes in. And
Dren was able to go (whoop).
MARY: Does the door keep moving all the way down
the hallway?
LIAM: I don't know.
TRAVIS: Devan, those dancing lights are awfully
cute. Do you mind if I ask you how you came to be
in the service of the Clasp?
LAURA: Oh!
LIAM: Let me re-jigger your memory, Tarvis. She's
not in the Clasp--
TRAVIS: No. Why you're indebted to the Clasp?
LAURA: Oh, well. Yeah, well. So you know,
gambling, huh?
ASHLY: I know gambling.
LAURA: How fun is that?
ASHLY: It's so fun!
TRAVIS: Dren.
ASHLY: Sorry.
LAURA: But sometimes it gets you into trouble. And
sometimes you can't pay off all your bills. And
sometimes your grandma has a lot of gold and some
treasure. And I said it and the Clasp heard me and
now I'm stuck with you guys. But I'm totally on
board and I'm real excited to help you out and be
free of you at the same time.
TRAVIS: Boy golly gosh, that sounds so nice. Do me
a favor. Gamble on your own time, don't gamble
with our lives. We work as a team here, so those
dancing lights down here are fine, but you check
with Dren or her or him before you do that again.
We clear?
LAURA: Sure.
TRAVIS: Good. Give Obby a hug for checking out
that dangerous pipe for you.
MARY: He's covered in number one.
SAM: It's okay, I am frequently used as
punishment.
ASHLY: You get used to it.
TRAVIS: I would like to stealth into the doorway
and, moving forward, be on the alert for traps.
LIAM: Okay. Would everyone like to make a stealth
check?
MARY: Yes.
TRAVIS: I don't normally stealth, so that's a
weird sentence for me.
LIAM: I know. Nor do you have an intelligence of
18, but it's going really well.
TRAVIS: I'm trying not to speak as Grog.
SAM: 16.
ASHLY: 24.
MARY: 26.
TRAVIS: 18.
LAURA: 17.
LIAM: 17, okay. And yeah, I would like a marching
order, so how are you guys going in?
TRAVIS: I'll be first through the door.
MARY: I'll be last.
SAM: I'll be number two.
LAURA: I'll be behind Dren then.
LIAM: Okay. You've got a very scary elf behind
you.
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: Yeah. All right, so very quietly, even your
gambling charge here, slowly creep around the door
and curve around the side. And it is pitch black
in here. You guys are fine, you can see in low
light and pitch black. It's pitch black in here,
or it was. And you see the tunnel stretch on
really far. You can see maybe 40 or 50 or 60 feet
ahead of you, but it keeps going and goes (whoosh)
into black. It's a long tunnel, and there's
nothing. It's very nondescript.
MARY: We still have one torch lit, yeah?
LAURA: And three dancing balls of light. Can I ask
a question?
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: Cantrips.
LIAM: Yes?
LAURA: How many do I get?
SAM: All.
LAURA: I just can do them?
LIAM: All you want.
LAURA: This is amazing!
LIAM: You can make it rain with cantrips.
MARY: Seriously. All day long, all night.
LAURA: Make it hail, baby. All right. That's gold
coins.
SAM: As much as I don't want to rely on our
prisoner, this would be a good opportunity to
throw a light down the hallway.
TRAVIS: I suppose you're right, Obby, maybe you
should be the one to let her know that she can.
SAM: Obby says do magic trick.
LAURA: Go down the hallway.
SAM: Thank you.
LIAM: A little ball swirls in a spiral down the
hall, and you watch this little circle, like a
firefly, go further and further.
LAURA: It's 120 foot range.
LIAM: Yeah. It keeps going, and then starts to
dim, and then you lose sight of it.
LAURA: Come back!
LIAM: And you wanted to check for traps, here,
right?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: Make a perception check.
TRAVIS: 16.
LIAM: Okay. From where you are, it's a smooth,
flat tunnel. It's plain. You guys want to move
forward?
MARY: I pull out my rapier and hold it as we
proceed.
LIAM: Okay. All right. So you move forward, in a
little conga line, down this tunnel. And it takes
a while. You're walking. The sound of the rain,
once I adjust, vanishes behind you. Come on,
buddy, there you go.
LAURA: As we're walking, can I make the four
lights combine together, in the shape of a human,
all the way down at the end of the hallway?
LIAM: Sure, in a rough--
LAURA: Yeah, it makes a humanoid form, yeah.
LIAM: Like one of those plastic signs that's
shaped like a person on the street, saying like
don't walk here because you'll slip.
LAURA: It says you can, into a vaguely humanoid
form.
LIAM: Yeah, that's vague.
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: So yeah, you've got a gingerbread-shaped
light man.
LAURA: Okay. Down at the end of the hallway.
LIAM: Okay. He's standing there, like this, and
goes-- And you can see him, you moved far enough
along, you've probably gone about 100 feet at this
point. You can continue to walk on down, or--
MARY: Tarvis? How are the traps looking? You
seeing anything up front?
TRAVIS: Nothing yet, my dear.
ASHLY: Do you guys want to hear a haiku I wrote?
TRAVIS: A haiku?
ASHLY: Yeah.
MARY: What the fuck is a haiku?
ASHLY: It's like a poem.
SAM: It's a 7/5/7 meter poem.
TRAVIS: Obby!
ASHLY: Well, 5/7/5.
SAM: Not where I'm from.
TRAVIS: Sure, Dren, we'd love to hear one.
ASHLY: Thanks, Tarvis! Wow, I really didn't think
you were going to go for that. Okay. We walk down
a thing. There is a bright man here too. We are
all much friends.
SAM: You wrote that?
ASHLY: Yeah.
SAM: Ahead of time?
ASHLY: Yeah! I worked on it really hard.
MARY: How long?
ASHLY: Couple hours?
LIAM: As you're having this little walk-and-talk,
down the hallway, Tarvis, you feel a little
(click) under your foot.
TRAVIS: Don't. Move.
MARY: What is it?
TRAVIS: I stepped on something that clicked.
MARY: Who's got the torch? You do? Put it down by
your feet. What do you see?
TRAVIS: What do I see?
LIAM: You see one tile, pushed diagonally down
about a half inch in. In a real odd way.
TRAVIS: Real quick, everybody check the walls,
ceilings, floors, see what this might unleash.
LIAM: Everybody make a perception check.
TRAVIS: 18.
ASHLY: 13.
LAURA: Four.
MARY: 17.
SAM: Four.
LIAM: Devan, you-- no.
MARY: 17.
LIAM: Who got the 18? You got the 18? Okay. You
guys both look everywhere, look all around, look
up, and starting right above you, Tarvis, and
stretching about 20 feet along the roof of this
tunnel, are maybe 100 tiny holes in the ceiling.
LAURA: Is it behind us too, or just in front of
us?
LIAM: It starts above Tarvis.
TRAVIS: The duration of the hallway?
LIAM: Right where Tarvis is. Right where he has
stepped.
LAURA: We could back up? We could just back up,
then.
SAM: We hold Devan above us as a human shield and
keep running.
LAURA: That's not smart! I'm the only one that can
get you to the actual thing that you need!
MARY: Can I do a perception check to see how much
weight pressure it would need to keep the tile down?
LIAM: Make an investigation check.
MARY: Investigation check?
LAURA: While she's looking at it, I'm going to
send a message to--
MARY: That's a natural one.
LAURA: --to Dren. No one else can hear. I'm going
to say: Hey! I'm thinking they might be catching
on to something, so maybe it would be smart if we
pretended that we didn't like each other a little
bit more than we have been.
ASHLY: I know, I'm sorry, I'm trying really hard,
I just like you a lot!
LAURA: I know, I like you so much!
ASHLY: Okay should I be meaner to you?
LAURA: Yeah maybe a little mean so they're not
catching on as much.
ASHLY: Okay. Let's use her as a human shield!
LAURA: Oh no!
TARVIS: Wow, Dren, that was really drastic.
ASHLY: Yeah!
TARVIS: Okay. Would you like to hold her up?
ASHLY: Sure! Okay.
LAURA: That was maybe a bit too much--
TRAVIS: Maybe not, Dren. I like your enthusiasm,
though.
ASHLY: Thanks.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Devan?
LAURA: Yeah?
TRAVIS: You have some tricks about you, right?
LAURA: Yes, I do.
TRAVIS: Any favorite spells that you like to use?
LAURA: Nothing that'll work on these things.
TRAVIS: The holes?
LAURA: Holes? On this trap? I can try casting Ray
of Frost on the tile and freeze it in place.
SAM: That's pretty smart.
LAURA: I mean, it might work. I can try it.
LIAM: That's true, it might work, and you can try
it.
TRAVIS: One could say, you can certainly try.
LAURA: But Tarvis, in doing so, I might actually
hurt your foot. But I don't want you to blame me,
because I'm just doing it because I'm trying to
freeze the thing.
TRAVIS: I appreciate your concern.
MARY: Well let's have a think for a moment, right?
So it's not behind us, there's nothing in the
ceiling behind us, it's just ahead of us.
LIAM: You don't see anything behind.
MARY: Little holes.
LIAM: The holes stretch above Tarvis for 15 or 20
feet.
MARY: 15 or 20 feet. All right.
SAM: We could all go, leaving Tarvis here.
MARY: Well what I was thinking, was what if I cast
Mage Hand and pushed down on the tile, you take a
step back, and we see what happens? And if it
holds, then we can move forward, because the Mage
Hand will last for 30 feet, and we'll be beyond
the 20 feet of ceiling shite.
LAURA: That's really smart!
TRAVIS: Objections?
ASHLY: Do we know that it only goes on for 20 more
feet? This tunnel?
LIAM: The tunnel goes for another, I don't know,
100, 150 feet, but the holes that they noticed
above Tarvis and moving about stop after about 15,
20 feet ahead.
TRAVIS: I like your idea. Devan.
LAURA: What?
TRAVIS: How about you use your Ray of Frost on the
holes, so that if anything decides to drop out of
them, it meets a little stopper.
LAURA: Do you want to pick me up? Because I'm
short.
MARY: Let Dren do it.
TRAVIS and LAURA: She's also pretty short.
TRAVIS: Sure, Devan, I would like to do that.
LAURA: Thank you.
ASHLY: I mean, don't get any ideas.
TRAVIS: Shall we?
MARY: Yes.
LAURA: As we go, I hit a Ray of Frost. Okay.
MARY: I cast Mage Hand, and place the Mage Hand,
direct it towards the tile that Tarvis is standing on.
LIAM: Okay. And we're moving forward?
MARY: Nope!
TRAVIS: As it appears, we'd like to do the old
Indiana Jones like foot off--
MARY: Foot off, put on, and they take a step back,
as she casts Ray of Frost to see whether or not
it'll hold.
SAM: Obby the Rat runs.
LIAM: Forward?
SAM: Forward.
SAM: This will not work. I run.
MARY: There's nothing behind us, Obby.
LIAM: Obby bolts to the side of Tarvis and books
it down the hall.
TRAVIS: Obby!
LIAM: He makes it like 15 feet, and you hear
another little (click), and immediately acid
starts spilling out of all the holes.
LAURA: Shit!
LIAM: Obby, Tarvis.
TRAVIS: Son of a bitch! Like trickles of acid, or
like a shower of acid?
LIAM: A little spew of acid.
MARY: So before you even got to step back?
TRAVIS: Yep.
MARY: That's shit. Well done, Obby.
LIAM: Both of you make a dexterity check.
SAM: Who, me, or them?
TRAVIS: You!
LIAM: Both of you.
LAURA: Am I on his shoulders at this point
already?
LIAM: Who picked you up, Tarvis did?
ASHLY: Tarvis did.
LIAM: Yes, you make a dexterity check as well.
LAURA: Fuck!
SAM: Me too?
LIAM: Yeah.
SAM: 25.
TRAVIS: 13.
LIAM: Was your dex check?
SAM: Yes.
LIAM: And you got what?
TRAVIS: 13.
LIAM: And you got?
LAURA: 19.
LIAM: 19, okay. Boy, this is crazy. Obby, hears
like (hissing) and you do a dive and roll, and you
feel a little drop of something splattering
against your butt and burning into the seat of
your pants a little bit. You immediately hear
(hissing), and you wriggle free, like a cat, and
scratch down along the side of Tarvis, and Tarvis,
you take a big ol' dump of acid on your head, and
take seven points of acid damage.
TRAVIS: Seven?
LIAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Oh Jesus. I miss Grog right now!
LIAM: You're burned, you've got holes burned into
your armor and into your shoulder, and it's still
stinging.
ASHLY: Are you okay, Tarvis?
TRAVIS: Oh, you know, I need a word with my good
friend, Obby. Just a quick chat. Would you mind
waiting here for one second? Will you keep your
finger on the button?
SAM: Is the acid still going?
LIAM: No, it was about a ten second pee of acid
from the holes.
TRAVIS: Can I make my way up to Obby, hopscotching
over the puddles of acid that I can see?
LIAM: Yes, yeah you can hear under your shoe is
going (sizzling).
TRAVIS: Obby, hey, Obby.
SAM: I'm sorry, I panicked.
TRAVIS: You did panic.
SAM: You know why they call me Obby the Rat?
TRAVIS: Why?
SAM: Rats survive.
ASHLY: Who hugs Obby when Obby needs to be
punished?
TRAVIS: That is a good question.
SAM: We'll never know.
LIAM: The Raven Queen.
MARY: Yes.
TRAVIS: Since you're so eager to make your way
through the hall, would you mind leading the way
for us, at a good 20-foot distance from the rest
of us.
SAM: Obby will oblige.
LIAM: So Obby hobbles ahead, shamefacedly.
LAURA: It might be smart, you guys, to keep
looking for little tiles, because my grandma's
really paranoid.
SAM: I will do a perception check to see if I see
any more tiles.
LIAM: Okay, go for it.
SAM: Five.
LIAM: Five. Well there's lots of tiles, there's
tiles from here all over.
TRAVIS: As he goes off, I will also check the
grounds around him.
LIAM: Great.
TRAVIS: 14.
LAURA: Better than five!
LIAM: You're scanning the ceiling really hard now
for little holes, and you're looking for any of
these tiles on the floor, any marble tiles that
look askew at all. You don't see anything. You do,
though, as you're walking, looking down, notice
the little leather pack with the three healing
potions that you guys were allotted when you left,
and go oh, good to know that's there. You've got
it. Don't need to use it now, but you have it.
Eventually, you guys all make it to the end of
this tunnel, and Obby, you're the first one there,
you notice the same-- no, you don't know what it
is, you point this out to you, Tarvis. Same little
circular shrew symbol, about three feet off the
ground, in a heavy wooden door.
TRAVIS: You know, Obby, before they get here, it
was opened earlier by Devan cutting her hand
really really deeply.
SAM: I cut my hand.
LIAM: Okay. Going to do anything with it?
SAM: I cut my hand and put it there.
LIAM: Okay. Your hand slowly dribbles out on the
door. You feel a little dizzy. Hungry.
TRAVIS: I meant to tell you, she cut it a couple
times.
LIAM: The others catch up with you. You see the
dwarf shoving his hand on it, and you know that's
not going to work.
LAURA: Oh, Obby, that only works with people that
are related to her.
SAM: I have a vast lineage.
LAURA: Well then keep trying!
SAM: Does it work?
LIAM: No, but you could keep trying all day, maybe
it'll collect.
MARY: Try cutting the other hand.
SAM: No.
LAURA: I loosen up the cut that I already dug in.
LIAM: Yeah, that's all you need to do is get your
hand open.
LAURA: Ow.
LIAM: 30 seconds. And the way that it works, it
takes your grandma something like five or six
hours to set one of these, or make one of these.
It takes your grandma about three seconds. You
watched her do it. You've never done this, you've
just watched her do it. She cuts it and it's open.
It's taking longer for you. It's taking like 20 or
30 seconds.
LAURA: Shit. It might not work.
LIAM: You're a weak-ass punk, is the thing. But
eventually (clicking).
LAURA: Hey! See?
TRAVIS: Nicely done. Very useful.
LAURA: Here to help!
ASHLY: So should we go in?
MARY: Does the door open?
LIAM: You open it?
SAM: I will try.
MARY: I'll cast Mage Hand again and push against
it.
LIAM: This spectral, purple, transparent hand
pushes against the door, and it goes (creak), and
soft, warm light spills from over on the right.
You're looking in at some sort of cool, dry
cellar. It's not that bright in here, but the
light that's coming from off to the side here lets
you see that there are shelves lining all the
walls. You see a lot of wooden boxes stacked next
to each other, something like 20 of them against
the wall, and in the middle of the room, which you
can see mostly from where you're standing, are
three pallets in a row of similar wooden crates,
but the ones on the pallets are wedged together
very tightly, very orderly, all in a row for
storage of some kind.
MARY: Well, looks like we've got a storage room,
I'm not sure if it's wine, there's boxes along the
wall, and there's three in the center. But they're
rather purposefully--
TRAVIS: Does this look familiar to you at all?
LIAM: No, it does not.
LAURA: No, it doesn't. I don't think I've ever
been down in this room before, but we've got to be
close to the basement!
TRAVIS: Are we looking for the basement?
LAURA: Well that's where she keeps a lot of her
treasure.
TRAVIS: In the basement?
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Can I insight check Devan?
LIAM: Sure.
TRAVIS: 12?
LIAM: Oh man, this is one of those instances where
I'm going to homebrew it, because I don't know
what the rule is.
LAURA: Do I roll against it?
LIAM: Yeah, sure you do.
MARY: That's it. Yeah, no chat room so it doesn't
matter!
LIAM: Also, don't tweet me because I don't care.
LAURA: I rolled a six!
LIAM: A six, okay. She seems nervous as fuck, but
she's not artfully carrying off any lie that you
can tell.
TRAVIS: She's nervous because Obby is so
attractive.
LIAM: I'm nervous because Obby is so attractive.
SAM: I'm squeezing the number one out of my
moustache.
LAURA: Ew. So foul!
TRAVIS: The Clasp, we like to do things quietly.
If we hear any rumblings of trouble, hide. Fair
enough?
LAURA: Yeah!
TRAVIS: Good.
LAURA: Believe me, if anything starts happening
here, you should hide, because her magic is really
powerful.
TRAVIS: What's your relationship with her, by the
way? Good terms, bad terms?
LAURA: Terrible.
TRAVIS: Really?
SAM: What did you do? Was it a boy?
LAURA: So you know, this thing-- have you heard of
gambling?
ASHLY: Oh, I know gambling!
LAURA: Yeah, it's really fun, right?
ASHLY: Yeah!
TRAVIS: Dren, Dren.
ASHLY: Oh yeah, sorry.
LAURA: So I took some of her money to do that.
That's all.
MARY: How much?
LAURA: I don't know! She has a big room of gold, I
just took some of it. I really don't know.
ASHLY: Could we take some gold too?
LAURA: That's what I mean! But she might keep the
emerald down there.
MARY: Do you remember which room that was?
LAURA: Yeah, it's in the basement.
MARY: The room of gold is in the basement?
LAURA: Uh-huh!
MARY: All right.
TRAVIS: You have pockets?
ASHLY: Yeah.
TRAVIS: If we find a room of gold, you can fill
your pockets.
ASHLY: Thanks, Tarvis.
TRAVIS: No worries.
MARY: Can I check for traps in this room as we
enter?
LIAM: You're entering?
MARY: Yeah.
LIAM: Okay, as you step in, you see where the
light is coming from. There is a small, little
writing desk in the corner, and there's a little
globe, very similar to your dancing lights,
floating above the desk. The desk is too small for
the bigger folk in this group, but it's about the
right size for a halfling. Just a couple papers
scattered on it.
LAURA: Ooh! Can I go over and look at them?
MARY: Do you want me to check for traps, first?
LIAM: Yeah, well, whatever you roll.
MARY: 18, perception. So 18, 19, 20, 24!
LIAM: You hold Devan back as she presses forward,
and you eyeball the room for a good 15 seconds.
Check the ceiling. No holes. Look around the room.
Seems okay.
MARY: Dren.
ASHLY: Yes?
MARY: You go check out that table.
ASHLY: Sure! Yeah.
MARY: You, stay behind me.
ASHLY: Stay behind, prisoner. I go over to the
table. Do I need to make a check or anything, or
can I--?
LIAM: You can, or I could just tell you what you
see?
ASHLY: Yeah, just tell me what I see. What's
Dungeons &amp; Dragons?
MARY: Where's the dragon? Is this a dungeon?
LIAM: There's a couple of pieces of paper on the
desk. There's a letter made out to a cousin about
a wedding. There's another letter about a
disagreement over the price of fabric.
ASHLY: These are boring so far.
MARY: Do you see a log book?
ASHLY: Do I see a log book?
LIAM: Just a couple pieces of paper.
ASHLY: Is there a drawer in the writing desk at
all?
LIAM: There is.
ASHLY: Can I open it?
LIAM: Sure.
ASHLY: I open it.
MARY: (explosion)
LIAM: No.
MARY: Roll for initiative.
LIAM: There are more pieces of paper in there, and
you find bills of sale, and amounts of coin
changing hands. Records of hers. You see the names
of a couple of money lenders listed in Emon, that
you're familiar with. You randomly pull a contract
for surveillance of General Krieg Tristan. That's
a name that raises your eyebrows. Everyone in Emon
knows him. That's it. It's a lot of business
transactions, but you can't really make out what
or who. I mean, not what, you can tell what's
being changed hands for the most part, but who
knows who bought, who knows who sold.
ASHLY: And there's nothing, like, hidden or
tricksy?
LIAM: Make a perception check.
ASHLY: That's not going to work, but here we go!
One!
LAURA: Oh no, we're halfling!
ASHLY: Oh hey! Except my perception is zero...
eight!
TRAVIS: Your perception's zero?
MARY: Yes!
LAURA: This is the one that got me killed, so I
don't know if you want to roll that.
ASHLY: So we're going to replace this guy with a
new one!
TRAVIS: There is no one more jinxy than Laura. No
one more superstitious.
ASHLY: Ooh! This is the pretty one. I'll use this
one.
LAURA: Yeah!
SAM: Oh, that got someone else killed.
LAURA: No, no, it didn't.
TRAVIS: She runs up her dice more than a
professional athlete, it's crazy.
LIAM: Tarvis, you also notice there's a couple
pieces of paper also lying helter-skelter on top
of the pallets as well. There's papers all over
this room.
ASHLY: I collect all of it and I bring it to
Tarvis.
TRAVIS: Are there any records, or binders,
ledgers, things like that?
LIAM: No, you crack the lid off one of these
boxes, and it is full of paper, and you pull it
out. You take a couple of minutes to look through
this stuff. What's weird is that, again, it is all
about amounts of money being moved around, and
bills of sale, but there's no names, but there's
weird words that pop up over and over again, like
you see the word "shortstack" like seven times.
"Whisperer" appears several times. You see on a
bill of sales Adelaide's signature, and then next
to it is the word "overbite," but you don't know
what it means. But it seems to have some sort of
pattern.
ASHLY: Does it make any sense to you, Tarvis?
TRAVIS: Not sure yet. Do I recognize any code or a
cipher in the writing?
LIAM: Make a straight-up intelligence check.
LAURA: Natural 20.
TRAVIS: Nine.
MARY: 11.
LIAM: It's like carpets being sold, some weapons
being sold. A loan.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MARY: Can I investigate the boxes on the wall?
LIAM: Sure. Make an investigation check.
LAURA: Ooh, are we doing this? I want to
investigate them too!
MARY: Eight.
LIAM: Oh, go for it.
TRAVIS: Dren, stay with her.
SAM: I'm going to look for exits and entrances to
the room.
LIAM: Yeah, you see a door.
LAURA: Seven! We suck.
LIAM: The walls are really shitty down here, and
not smoothed out or pretty. It's a rough room. But
there is a door straight across from where you
entered.
SAM: There's another? Not the one we came in.
LIAM: Yes. Another door.
MARY: So we did an eight and a seven on
perception, investigating those boxes.
LIAM: There's a lot of really boring paperwork
here, listing a lot of sales. Though you did find
a piece of paper that describes the sale of a
wyrmling dragon. That's cool.
LAURA: That's pretty cool.
ASHLY: I like dragons.
SAM: I found a piece of paper with codes on it,
like Maverick, Goose, Hollywood.
TRAVIS: Wolfman?
SAM: I can't make it out.
TRAVIS: Slider?
LIAM: That is true.
TRAVIS: Sundown?
MARY: Do you feel the need for anything?
LAURA: I start heading towards the exit of the
room.
MARY: Excuse me, dear.
ASHLY: Oh, excuse me, you can't go by yourself!
I'm in charge of you, get behind me.
LAURA: Sure.
ASHLY: Sorry, guys, she--
MARY: I do have rope if she gets out of hand, we
could--
ASHLY: We'll need it!
LAURA: Just make sure I can still use my hands.
MARY: Well, we could put it around your neck.
ASHLY: That means we'll kill you. If you get out
of line.
MARY: Would just make it easier.
ASHLY: She's funny. Should we go to the next
room?
TRAVIS: We will go to the door, and we will see if
it's locked.
LIAM: Okay, you grab it?
TRAVIS: No.
MARY: Obby.
TRAVIS: Obby just grabs it.
SAM: Obby the Rat can break any lock.
MARY: This I have heard.
SAM: I will check the doorknob.
LIAM: Okay, so you rattle it?
SAM: Yeah.
LIAM: Yeah, checking for traps? All right, make a
perception check.
SAM: Two.
LIAM: This shit is clear. You are golden.
SAM: We're good. I open the door.
LIAM: Okay. It's wide open. There's a set of
stairs that winds away and goes up.
TRAVIS: Is it lit by light or torch?
LIAM: Just from the light that's spilling out of the
room you're in. So it's dim, but you can see fine.
TRAVIS: Just leads to a stairway?
LIAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Wood? Brick?
LIAM: Wood.
TRAVIS: Do we hear anything up the stairs? Dren,
you're up. Be as tiny as you can be, and sneak up
those stairs and see what you can see.
ASHLY: Yes sir. Stealth check? Sweet. Goddamn it.
12.
LIAM: 12, okay.
ASHLY: Oh, you're cursing all of them, Laura!
LIAM: Sneaky little halfling skitters up the
stairs. There's another door at the top.
ASHLY: Guys, there's an-- oh, thank you. I don't
know how to say this stealthed.
LIAM: Yeah, they're down around a curve, so you're
doing that to no one.
TRAVIS: There's a fox bat flying?
ASHLY: I crawl over, and I go.
TRAVIS: All right. I motion for everyone to go up
the stairs.
MARY: I follow in the rear with my rapier. I pull
out a dagger as well.
LIAM: Poke, poke, poke, poke. Okay, everyone files
up the stairs.
ASHLY: Wait, I just realized we're trying to go to
the basement, but we're going up.
LAURA: Why are we going-- sure.
LIAM: They're going up. And there's a door
standing in front of you.
SAM: We had nowhere else to go.
TRAVIS: Wait a minute.
MARY: Yeah. Was that the only door to get out of
that room?
LIAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Did we check for hidden doors or
passages?
SAM and MARY: No.
LIAM: Well you checked for traps.
MARY: I did.
LIAM: You didn't see any doors.
MARY: There's nothing behind any of those boxes or
anything or under the pallets in the center of the room?
LIAM: I don't know.
MARY: All right. Wait. Before we go, hold on, come
back. Tarvis, get with me and let's push these
pallets in the middle of the room.
TRAVIS: Yeah. There's three of them.
MARY: There's three of them. They're probably very
heavy.
TRAVIS: Let's take the one on the left. And we'll
push it.
LIAM: (sliding) Nothing.
MARY: Center.
LIAM: (sliding) A dead rat breaks open and smears
on the floor--
MARY: Obby, your cousin.
(laughter)
SAM: Not related.
TRAVIS: The one on the right.
ASHLY: I thought you had a vast lineage.
SAM: That one I know particularly.
LIAM: There is nothing under these pallets.
MARY: Can I check behind the boxes on the wall?
LIAM: Yes, you may. So in the interest of time,
you spend three or four minutes, push push push,
lots of paper. Nothing you find that's hidden.
TRAVIS: There was nothing on the desk? No switches,
no--
LAURA: This is a storage room! The rest of her
stuff is in the house!
TRAVIS: I thought you've never been in this room.
MARY: But you said it was in the dungeon, or the
basement.
LAURA: Yeah, this is not the basement! This is a
storage room!
TRAVIS: All right, as we go back up towards the
stairs, can we check the walls for any secrets?
LIAM: In the room or in the stairway?
TRAVIS: Up the stairway.
LIAM: Yeah, sure.
TRAVIS: 22.
LIAM: You two are the big ballers with perception.
Yeah, it's a well-made staircase.
TRAVIS: Great, Dren, will you check that door at
the top of the stairs for traps?
ASHLY: Yes, boss. I go and I try the door.
LIAM: Oh, you just open it?
ASHLY: Oh, my perception's shit. Should I just do
it? Okay I'll do it. Seven.
LIAM: Seven, okay. Yeah. It's good.
ASHLY: Cool, I open it.
LIAM: Okay, it goes (creaking) and opens.
ASHLY: That's a good door noise.
MARY and SAM: Or a cat?
LAURA and TRAVIS: (meowing)
LIAM: You see not much. You still have your lights
going?
LAURA: Yes.
LIAM: Yeah, okay. There's light flickering from
behind the group all the way near the back. And so
you're seeing shadows and light flicker in this
room. And in this room, you can't see the whole
room yet, but you see glimpses of rows of chests.
Thick, wooden chests. Solid. Locks on some of
them, not all of them, but neatly done in little
aisles. Each one about two feet tall. Big, thick
bastards. You recognize this room, peering
through. This is where you used to skim from
grandma's stores. Although you're a little
confused because there's only one door to this room.
SAM: Wait. This is the only door in?
MARY: The door that we just came through is the
only door?
LIAM: You're disoriented. This is not how you're
used to entering it.
LAURA: Right, I came in from the other way.
Where's the other way?
MARY: What other way?
TRAVIS: You recognize this room?
LAURA: Well yeah! This is the basement.
TRAVIS: Excellent. Delweth, Dren, go with her and
explore.
MARY: All right. I check for traps.
LIAM: Okay, make a perception check.
MARY: 12. No! Yes. 12.
LIAM: Okay, Devan's globes of light are floating
lazily around the room, close to you. And again
the shadows are shifting, moving slowly. But you
have enough light to see. You walk along one of
the aisles and look around. You don't see
anything. Nothing in the ceiling, nothing in the
floor. The chests look normal.
ASHLY: Devan, do you know what's in any of these?
LAURA: Gold!
ASHLY: It's just gold!?
LAURA: I think so!
ASHLY: I open the nearest chest.
LIAM: You open the nearest chest?
ASHLY: Yeah!
LIAM: You open it up. There is a fuck-ton of gold
coin in this chest beyond counting.
SAM: Okay, I go to them and say: do not touch that
gold.
ASHLY: Tarvis said I could!
SAM: No, I'm going to check it for traps. What am
I doing, perception? Ten.
LIAM: Yes, there's no trap on the chest that she
just opened. Seems okay.
SAM: Okay, Dren, you can stick your hand in and
get--
TRAVIS: Wait.
MARY: Oh, such a bad idea. Stick a knife in or
something first so it's not your hand.
TRAVIS: Who can check for magic?
ASHLY: What's the difference between perception
and investigation?
LIAM: Perception is seeing and spotting things,
hearing things. Investigation is looking at stuff
left behind and going how does that connect to
that?
LAURA: Do you want me to grab some gold to show
you it's fine? We're not here for the gold, but
sure. And I pick up some gold.
LIAM: Okay.
TRAVIS: Yeah, that was bad. It's not on alarm.
SAM: A dragon appears.
ASHLY: Oh, that's why it's called Dungeons &amp;
Dragons!
LIAM: But as you dig your hand into this gold and
pull and up and coins fall away, you notice out of
the corner of your eye, the chest next to it
swell, bulge, open, and a mouth bigger than you've
ever seen (horrible screeching noise).
LAURA: I knew there were more than before!
LIAM: Lunges to bite you. And does, in fact, get
you.
LAURA: Oh no! Can't I dodge out of the way? Can't I
dodge out of the way?
LIAM: Everybody roll for initiative.
LAURA: Ah shit.
ASHLY: 16.
LIAM: Okay, hold on.
SAM: Oh boy.
LAURA: Oh no! Oh no!
ASHLY: You reroll it!
LAURA: Oh my gosh, I don't even want to roll that
one again.
ASHLY: That was so close! Oh my god!
LAURA: That was so close!
TRAVIS: Here we go! We got a map!
LIAM: We have a map!
MARY: What! It's the first map!
(cheering)
SAM: Liam, it's not in 3D, it's not color-coded.
TRAVIS: Where are the fucking trees?
SAM: There's no atmospheric mist, come on, man.
MARY: You didn't find twelve mini chests to put up
there? I mean, come on.
LIAM: Okay so, this big, massive chest opens its
mouth and you see one big, fat eyeball in the back
of its misshapen mouth. (growls) And it clamps
down on your hand full of gold, and you take eight points--
LAURA: Oh god! That's a lot!
LIAM: Did I get it right? Yes. Eight points of
piercing damage. And then also you take one point
of acid damage as its slobber drizzles all over
your arm and it latches down. And you feel what
feels like crazy glue seep all around your arm and
you yank. "Oh shit," you think. Okay, everybody
give me your initiatives please.
SAM: 22.
LAURA: 20.
ASHLY: 16 for Dren.
MARY: 19 for Delweth.
TRAVIS: Nine for Tarvis.
LIAM: Nine. Okay. And big man struck out at bat.
Okay, Obby the Rat, you are up.
SAM: I stealthily flank it using Devan as a
distraction and I will sneak attack it with a
dagger.
LIAM: Okay, you're coming around the side, you're
saying? Over here?
SAM: Wait, which one is it?
LIAM: This is you, this is it right here.
SAM: Yeah, I'll go straight from where I am.
LIAM: Straight at it?
SAM: Yeah, from the side.
LIAM: Okay, all right. Roll to attack.
SAM: Nope. 11.
LIAM: Okay. You lunge forward with your dagger and
it melts a little out of the way, seeing you
coming. Devan, you are up, and you are grappled,
you are in this thing's mouth.
SAM: With my bonus action, I still have some
movement, right?
LIAM: You have plenty of movement.
SAM: I will disengage and hop over that chest so
I'm more behind it.
LIAM: Here?
SAM: Right there.
LIAM: Okay. All right, Devan, you're up.
LAURA: With my hand stuck in it, I set my hands on
fire and cast Burning Hands.
LIAM: Holy shit! Yes you do.
SAM: Aptly named spell.
LIAM: Okay, 3d6, okay and what's your DC?
LAURA: That's a good question.
LIAM: Oh, it's a dex save versus your-- okay.
But there's no dex save because your hand's in its mouth.
LAURA: Just roll?
LIAM: Just roll for damage. Roll your 3d6.
LAURA: Oh come on! Oh wait, can I reroll ones? On
the damage, no.
LIAM: You do have that--
LAURA: I don't want to use a sorcery point yet.
LIAM: Okay, so what'd you get?
LAURA: Four on 3d6. Two ones and a two. Like the
worst.
LIAM: Okay, so your hand is stuck in there and out
of rage you feel the fire charge up in your hand
and you go (fire noise) and it goes (small
explosion noise).
LAURA: Does it let go of me?
LIAM: Delweth, you're up.
LAURA: Oh wait! Ugh!
TRAVIS: You get a bonus action.
LIAM: You can go.
ASHLY: You do have a bonus action.
LIAM: Get it, girl.
LAURA: I don't know. Ugh.
TRAVIS: Want to use your bonus action to call for
Dren?
LAURA: No, I'm good.
ASHLY: No, we're fine.
MARY: How many feet away am I from the chest of
death?
LIAM: 20.
MARY: 20?
LAURA: They're on to us.
MARY: What I want to do is run, take a flying leap
off that first chest.
LIAM: Okay.
LAURA: Oh no.
LIAM: You can do that.
MARY: And fly up, and do I have enough momentum to
go over the chest that is holding her?
LIAM: Well, make an acrobatics check.
MARY: I don't know. I'm asking!
LIAM: Yeah, sure.
LAURA: Could I have tried to wiggle free? Could I
have tried to break the grapple with my turn? Is
that possible? Should I have tried to break the
grapple?
MARY: 24.
LIAM: 24. (swoosh) You are out of movement. You
don't clear it, but you land on top of the chest
next to it.
MARY: I take my rapier and I stab straight down.
LIAM: All right, roll to attack.
LAURA: Ah, my hand!
LIAM: Yeah, don't skewer Devan's hand.
LAURA: She doesn't care. She wouldn't care if she
did.
MARY: Three. Six.
LIAM: Yeah! It goes (growls). Okay, and now we're
on to Dren.
MARY: Can I bonus action?
LIAM: Yeah.
MARY: I'd like to disengage and--
LIAM: Oh, you're out of movement.
MARY: I'm out of movement.
LIAM: Yeah, that flip cost you a lot of movement.
MARY: All right, I'm going to stand tall and proud
on this chest.
LAURA: Oh, by the way, it's on fire now. It ignites
anything on fire.
LIAM: Okay, cool.
ASHLY: I assume I'm not hidden.
LIAM: No.
ASHLY: The chest knows where I am.
LIAM: Yes.
ASHLY: And I can't move into a position that I am
hidden from him?
LIAM: You could.
LAURA: You could dance around the back of him.
LIAM: But again, since we've got so many rogues,
I'll remind you to get your sneak attack damage
you don't need to be hidden. If one of your friends
is on it, you get the same from that.
ASHLY: Oh, so I can do sneak attack right now?
LIAM: You can do it right now, yeah.
ASHLY: I'm going to do a sneak attack.
LIAM: All right, go for it.
ASHLY: Or can I try to get Devan free? Is there
any way for me to do that?
LIAM: You can cut her hand off?
ASHLY: I'll sneak attack.
LIAM: If you want to try to pry its mouth open or
something you could. Oh, also Delweth, your sword
sticks, it doesn't come out.
MARY: Yep.
ASHLY: I'm going to try to kill this thing with
my shortsword, sneak attack.
LIAM: Go for it.
ASHLY: Okay. Can you help me with this?
LAURA: Yeah totally, you roll. Roll a 20.
ASHLY: 14.
LAURA: Oh, that's good! Plus six, so 20 is the
attack.
LIAM: Okay, that hits.
LAURA: So d6 plus four.
ASHLY: And then sneak attack, I do an additional
2d6?
LIAM: Yeah, roll the initial attack first. Do your
damage without it.
LAURA: Ooh, eight, and then two more d6.
LIAM: Yep.
ASHLY: Four and five.
LAURA: 13.
LIAM: 13. Nice.
ASHLY: Sweet.
SAM: Guys, we're playing Dungeons &amp; Dragons just
like on Stranger Things!
LAURA: Demogorgon!
LIAM: So your pint-sized charge here and
the thing is slobbering all over her hand, not
paying too much attention to you and you're able
to go (stabs) and shove it right under one of its
teeth that's sticking out and it starts bleeding
down the blade and you go (grunts). Your dagger is
adhered to the creature, not coming off, your hand
is okay but the dagger is in it. Or what'd you
say, shortsword?
ASHLY: Shortsword.
LIAM: Shortsword is sticking out of this thing and
you cannot get it out, wedging back and forth.
LAURA: I'll feel real bad if I just fucked
everybody up.
ASHLY: Okay, I'm going to--
(Siri beeps)
LIAM: Hey, Siri.
SAM: Hey Liam!
MARY: Hello, Liam!
TRAVIS: Hello, Grandmaster Flash.
ASHLY: Disengaging means--
LIAM: Yeah, you can jump back and it can't get a
free swipe at you.
ASHLY: Okay, I'll do that. I'll disengage.
LIAM: Okay, where do you want to go?
ASHLY: I'm going to go on the other side of
Delweth? Can I do that?
LIAM: Here? Delweth, here? Yeah, yes you can.
Boop, and you hop up on a chest, all right. And
now we're on to you, Tarvis.
TRAVIS: To me?
LIAM: Yes.
TRAVIS: Can I take my scimitar out?
SAM, MARY, and LAURA: Ooh! Scimitar?
TRAVIS: And the chests that are on the wall
closest to you, those five chests that are there.
LIAM: Here, yes.
TRAVIS: Can I move to the one closest to me and
with my scimitar drag it along the face of all
five of them as I run along them?
LIAM: Your sword along the face?
TRAVIS: Yeah, the scimitar.
LIAM: Yeah, you go (scraping).
TRAVIS: Yeah, dragging it across the front, not
trying to penetrate it.
LIAM: You drag it across and this jagged line goes
(scraping).
ASHLY: You drag through all of them?
LIAM: All the way across. You break the lock, the
thin old rusted lock on the fourth one. Nothing
happens.
TRAVIS: Great.
SAM: Those are no longer mint in box.
TRAVIS: With my bonus action, I look at them all
stuck in that stupid chest.
LIAM: Okay, it's at that moment that Obby, behind
you, you hear (growling) and over your shoulder,
you see another one, a smaller one, but this one
starts to pustulate and get little bubbles all
over it and eyes go pop, pop, pop, all over and it
goes (screech).
MARY: It's The Thing! Give it CPR!
LIAM: It takes a bite at you, but you are so
scared shitless from the sound that comes out
behind you, you juke to the left and it goes
(screech) and didn't get you and now it's your turn.
SAM: Okay, I will attack the first one with a
dagger again, hoping to hit it this time. Nope.
13?
LIAM: 13 hits.
SAM: Oh, okay, so eight, plus sneak attack damage,
right?
LIAM: That's right.
SAM: Ten.
LIAM: You just Julius Caesar-ed it, yeah. Oh, ten
total? Okay. Your dagger is stuck in its butt.
SAM: No problem, don't need it. I'm going to try
to move. Well no, first I'll use my bonus action.
The feature that only I can do is sleight of hand
on my bonus action. It says that I can try to open
a trap or a lock. I'm going to try to pry open
its mouth.
LIAM: Which one?
SAM: The one that is holding Devan. It's a trap or
a lock, maybe?
TRAVIS: You don't know.
SAM: I have a crowbar, so I'm going to jam it in
and try to pop it open.
LIAM: You're going to take your crowbar and try to
ram it open?
SAM: Just enough for her hand to get out.
LIAM: Okay, make a strength check.
SAM: 15.
LIAM: 15. You jam it in there and pull as hard as you
can. It does open, your hand is exposed, your
crowbar is stuck.
SAM: No problem.
LIAM: That's where we'll end that. Devan, we're on
to you.
LAURA: Can I pull my hand out?
LIAM: Yeah, you can make a strength check with
advantage.
LAURA: I'm so weak, though. Natural 20!
(cheering)
LIAM: You see bits of halfling skin on the thing's
tongue and you are free. That is your action.
LAURA: That is my action?
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: (sad trombone)
ASHLY: You should run.
LAURA: Okay, yeah, I will try to move away from
it. I don't want to waste the spell; I don't know!
TRAVIS: You don't know how long you'll be alive.
SAM: Two hours.
MARY: Tops.
LAURA: I'm going to Misty Step next to Tarvis.
TRAVIS: Whoa, what the shit!
LIAM: Nicely done, you are now safe for the
moment. Delweth, you are up.
MARY: I'm going to use Acid Splash on the fucker
who's got my rapier at the moment. I'm going to
use it right by the rapier, but not on it, in
hopes that I can pull it out.
LIAM: Okay, Acid Splash is just 1d6, yeah?
MARY: Yeah.
LIAM: Read that spell for me real quick so I don't
have to flip a million pages. There it is. No, I
got it. 1d6, succeed on a--
MARY: I hurl a bubble of acid, I choose one
creature within range, or two within range that
are within five feet of each other. Hey, are those
little bastards next to each other?
LIAM: What's your spell DC?
MARY: Exactly, it is five plus five.
LIAM: Oh, you know what? Doesn't matter.
MARY: It's a cantrip.
LIAM: I know. Your hand extends out over it and
glows a dark green and black swirl of color and
acid goes (dripping) and runs down over its eyes
and face and then washes off like water on a
duck's back.
MARY: Like water on a duck's back?
LAURA: Oh, it's an acid creature.
MARY: So acid on acid doesn't work. I wasn't sure
if it did or not.
SAM and MARY: Had to try.
LIAM: And knowing is half the battle.
MARY: That's right. Hey there kids, do I have a
bonus action to disengage?
LIAM: You do have a bonus action, sure.
MARY: Really? I'd like to disengage.
LIAM: Okay, which way do you want to go?
MARY: I want to go, yeah.
LIAM: All right, how about right there?
MARY: Yeah, that's good.
SAM: It's okay, Obby the Rat can take them both by
myself, apparently.
ASHLY: I'm there!
LIAM: Dren, you're up.
ASHLY: Okay, so if I attack a foe before they've
gone at the top of the fight I can attack with
advantage?
LIAM: Say again.
ASHLY: If I attack a foe before they've gone at
the top of a fight--
LIAM: It's at the very beginning of the fight if
you get the jump on them.
ASHLY: Fuck it, all right, I'll attack them
natural-like with my crossbow. 15?
LAURA: Plus five is 20.
LIAM: Big guy or little guy?
ASHLY: The guy we've already been attacking that
had--
LIAM: The big guy? You got a 20, that hits.
ASHLY: Okay and then it's a 1d6.
LIAM: Plus sneak attack damage because Obby's got
its--
ASHLY: Oh wait, I can reroll it, right, or can I
not?
LAURA: Nah, it doesn't work on the damage rolls,
but that's okay. Plus three, so four and then
2d6.
ASHLY: Don't fuck me. Ten!
LAURA: So 14!
ASHLY: Woo, eat it!
LIAM: What was the weapon?
ASHLY: It was a crossbow.
LIAM: The thing's got its mouth open from where
Obby pried it open and Devan got away and your
bolt goes (impact) and gets it right in the eye.
(grunting) It's still going, though.
ASHLY: Aw, damn it.
LIAM: Tarvis, you're up.
TRAVIS: Which one did you hit?
ASHLY and LIAM: Big guy.
TRAVIS: Okay, I will go to big guy!
LIAM: You're going to go to him?
TRAVIS: Yes.
SAM: I want to go to him.
LIAM: Okay, you're there.
TRAVIS: And I will use a dagger to sneak attack
his anus.
LIAM: Okay. All right, roll to attack.
TRAVIS: Aw man, that's balls. Ten.
LIAM: Ten? Total?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: Yeah, you really wanted to get at that anus
so bad, you went around and tried to get at it and
it snapped right at your junk, at the last second
you went oh jeez and pulled back and did not get
to the anus. Okay, the mimic, having a great shot
at your junk right now, bites your junk. You feel
teeth sink into your abdomen, and into your junk a
little bit. You take 11 piercing damage and the
acid leaks in after it for five.
LAURA: Are you okay, Tarvis?
LIAM: (growling) Yep, that's the end of that, now
the little one (screech), it was almost a natural
20 but it wasn't, it doesn't try to bite you but a
little glob of its body goes (whipping noise) and
you feel a little whip hit in the air right by
your ear, didn't hit you though. And now it's your turn.
SAM: All right, Obby focuses still on big one. Is
Travis within five feet of him?
TRAVIS: Who?
SAM: I mean Tarvis.
MARY: He's dyslexic.
SAM: Natural one.
TRAVIS: We're so fucked.
LIAM: You take your dagger and in rage for your
friend, you bring it down and it sinks into the
forearm of your friend.
TRAVIS: Me?
LIAM: You take two points of piercing damage.
TRAVIS: Awesome.
LIAM: Things go wrong sometimes.
TRAVIS: Still in the double digits.
SAM: That's no good, sorry! And then I will use my
bonus and move to disengage and move so I'm on the
other side of the big one, hopefully out of range
of the little one.
LIAM: You can totally do that, yep, you're good.
It goes (yapping) as you leave. Now it is Devan,
your turn.
LAURA: Okay, I'm going to hop up over the chest
right there. Well, I'm going to Ray of Frost the
big one.
LIAM: The big one? You probably need a clear line
of sight--
LAURA: Yeah, I'm going to get a little closer,
yeah.
LIAM: Go for it.
SAM: (singing) Quicker than a Ray of Frost.
LAURA: On a hit, so I make a ranged spell attack.
But I don't know what my--
LIAM: Your bonus is six, so 20 and add six. What'd
you get?
LAURA: Ten.
LIAM: Ten. The frost totally freezes the chest
next to it shut. You still have a little bit of
movement if you like.
LAURA: Yeah, I hop up on a chest behind me.
LIAM: Over here? Okay and now we're on Tarvis.
TRAVIS: We're on me?
LIAM: Wait, no, sorry, I'm out of order, Delweth.
All the frigging 'D' names on this list.
MARY: All right, so the little fucker is by those
barrels to the left, yeah? I would like to move to
the top of the barrel all the way in the corner.
LIAM: Okay, you can do that, sure.
MARY: Okay, and I would like to cast Poison Spray
on the little fucker.
LIAM: Okay, go for it.
MARY: It's a cantrip, I just roll for damage
or--?
LIAM: Oh, it's a con save for my guy.
MARY: Yes, the creature must succeed on a
constitution saving throw.
LIAM: And it does not.
MARY: Okay, so 1d12, what's a d12--
LAURA: Ooh a d12, it looks like a ball, it's the
other one that looks like a ball.
TRAVIS: She's got it.
MARY: Four.
LAURA: We're rolling like shit!
MARY: Did he see me, was it a stealth?
LIAM: I don't think you can-- ooh stealth spell,
hmm, curious. No sneak attack damage on a spell,
but it does sputter and froth comes out of its
mouth and it pivots towards you.
LAURA: It's not dead yet, damn.
LIAM: And now we're on Dren.
MARY: Do I get a bonus action?
LIAM: You do, sorry, yes.
MARY: I would like to move back to the top of
the--
LIAM: You're out of movement though, to get there,
hopping on the barrels.
MARY: So what do I do, I get hide, disengage--
TRAVIS: Hide, disengage, dash-- oh well you can't
dash--
SAM: You can dash, right?
LIAM: It's looking right at you.
MARY: It's looking right at me.
LIAM: You're not going to be able to hide.
MARY: I do this.
LIAM: It doesn't get it, it's still slobbering--
LIAM: (dying noise)
MARY: It dies.
LIAM: All right, so Dren.
ASHLY: Can the big dude see me?
LIAM: The big dude see you? Kind of, it's got one
eye with a crossbow bolt in it.
ASHLY: Could I do a sneak attack?
LIAM: Yeah, it's surrounded. This is Julius Caesar
time here. Are you throwing something or are you
moving over there?
ASHLY: I'm doing a crossbow with a natty 20! So
25.
LIAM: How do you want to do this?
(cheering)
ASHLY: Well I want to take my dagger--
LIAM: What happened to the crossbow?
ASHLY: Well I didn't realize I was going to kill
him, now I'm in a flying leap, but that's fine,
I'll take an arrow and do a flying leap down on
his eye.
LIAM: You pull a bolt out and go, "Fuck it," and
ram it down into its protruding, bulbous purplish
gums and stab it and it goes (gurgling) and vomit
spills out of it and goes all over Tarvis' feet.
ASHLY: Sorry, Tarvis!
LIAM: Anything else you want to do?
ASHLY: I want to do this.
LIAM: Yeah okay. Tarvis, what would you like to
do?
TRAVIS: I would like to be useful in this fight in
any capacity and would like to hop the chest and
move towards the last remaining piece of shit.
LIAM: Dropping blood as you go.
MARY: Did he get any damage from the vomit on his
feet?
LIAM: No, his boots are already burned from acid,
I think they made a nice little crust on the
bottom.
TRAVIS: I'll take this scimitar. It's not engaged
by anybody else right, so no sneak attack damage?
LIAM: That's correct.
MARY: It's looking at me.
LIAM: It's got to be within five feet of his
friend.
TRAVIS: I will be the engagee for everyone else
and I will hit it with my scimitar because I'm
such a good fucking leader. I'll roll a different
dice. Jesus, nipples on a horse.
LIAM: What'd you get there?
TRAVIS: Ten.
LIAM: Ten, oh man, your guts are-- you're lucky
they're not spilling out, and you are in so much
pain that you swing and cramp and burning pain up
to the nipple, up to the horse nipple, and your
sword goes into a regular chest next to the thing.
Now it is the mimic's turn and it goes
(snickering) and another gooey rubber band punches
out at you--
TRAVIS: Wait! Can I use my bonus action to
disengage?
LIAM: Yeah, you can.
TRAVIS: I know, I want to do something.
LIAM: I'm going to say that's as far as you get,
and the little booger that came out and went
(whiplash), but didn't reach you.
MARY: Well done, Tarvis.
LIAM: Now it is Obby the Rat's turn.
SAM: Obby the Rat would like to move in and
attack, so I will take a couple steps towards him,
and I get a 14.
LIAM: Yes, that hits.
TRAVIS: I don't know what that's like.
ASHLY: It's really great.
SAM: Seven, it's not a sneak attack right? Travis
is out of the way? Seven points.
LIAM: Seven points, okay, and you use what
weapon?
SAM: Dagger.
LIAM: Dagger, okay. You jam the dagger down into
one of its 50 eyes, and it goes in diagonal, and
this fucking knife is glued onto this creature's
body. Keep track of your daggers, guys.
SAM: I will bonus action try to pull the dagger
out with sleight of hand.
LIAM: Jesus, make a dexterity check at
disadvantage.
SAM: Not good. Slightly better. Ten.
LIAM: No. You go, (grabbing noises) "Oh shit." And
that's it, you are staying put. Now we're back to
Devan.
LAURA: I'm going to hop down from the chests, the
other direction. The ones that Tarvis ran his
swords over, can I go see if any of those are
mimics?
LIAM: The one that he dragged his blade across? What
do you want to do? They look like scarred chests.
LAURA: You said one of the locks got busted when
he did it, can I open it up?
LIAM: Yeah you do, it's full of electrum.
LAURA: Electrum?
LIAM: Coins.
LAURA: I want them.
LIAM: Okay.
MARY: Greed.
LAURA: Do I have anything on me that I can dig in?
I take my cloak off and I dust it in there to see
if it bites at it.
LIAM: No, nothing's biting you, you get, I don't
know, 80, 100, 120 pieces of electrum into the
hood of your cloak.
TRAVIS: What's electrum?
LAURA: I don't know.
LIAM: It's another currency.
MARY: Unobtainium!
LIAM: All right, do you want to move any more? Or
are you going to stay here and drool on the coin?
LAURA: I'm going to keep looking at coins.
LIAM: Cool, okay, Delweth, you are up!
MARY: All right, let's Poison Spray that little
fucker one more time.
TRAVIS: Help me!
MARY: I am. I will Poison Spray the
multi-eyeballed thing.
LIAM: You go. So noxious gray-purple fume
floats--
MARY: Do I need to--
LIAM: You don't need to do anything. It needs to
do something. It just happens. No, it does
terribly again, so another poof of awful
surrounds the thing. Roll for damage.
MARY: On my butt. All right, roll for damage. What
do I roll on this?
TRAVIS: What do you roll on that?
MARY: 1d12. Is that a d12? Five!
TRAVIS: Plus anything?
MARY: Do I get plus anything on my spells? Spell
bonus attack?
LIAM: No, but it looks really miserable. The shape
is changing and it looks more like a chest and
then less like a chest and the eyes shrink back in
and go bloodshot. It looks disgusting, it doesn't
look happy. And we are now onto Dren.
TRAVIS: Dren, show them how we do!
ASHLY: Did he get rid of my shortsword? Do I have
my shortsword?
LIAM: It's sitting there sticking out of him.
ASHLY: I'll kill him with my crossbow. 15?
LIAM: 15 hits. Roll for damage plus sneak attack
damage.
ASHLY: Four and then sneak attack. Eight.
LIAM: Okay, so you stand coolly looking at it. You
watch as Delweth sends out this poof of noxious
gas around it. It sputters, it shifts, it changes.
You coolly go (crossbow bolt firing) (gurgling screams).
ASHLY: MVP!
(cheering)
TRAVIS: MVP!
MARY: Both chests down.
ASHLY: Do you guys want to hear haikus?
LIAM: I'd love to hear a haiku. Do you have one
ready for us?
ASHLY: I killed all the chest...s. They are now
all dead. So I am the best, y'all.
LIAM: So the room falls quiet, there are two
slobbery disgusting messes with daggers and your
shortsword is sticking out of it and you're
surrounded by money.
TRAVIS: I race over to Devan.
LAURA: Good job, guys! That was really scary, I'm
sorry about that, Tarvis.
TRAVIS: Are you all right?
SAM: Oh, he cares?
LAURA: I insight check him. I know he's full of
shit. Can I insight check him?
LIAM: Yes.
TRAVIS: I will kill her.
LAURA: 17.
LIAM: Why don't you roll against it?
TRAVIS: What is it, insight or wisdom?
LAURA: Insight.
MARY: Wisdom.
LIAM: Let's do straight charisma. I'm sure I'm
fudging it, but eh.
TRAVIS: I don't even have a thing for that.
MARY: Zero so it's five.
TRAVIS: Five.
LAURA: So I know if he's full of shit? Were you
lying or were you telling the truth?
TRAVIS: Well, you're the only one that knows where
the shit in this house is, so I was telling the
truth. Are you okay?
LAURA: Yeah, I'm okay. Wow, sorry I did that.
They've never been monsters before. It's just been
actual chests of gold.
TRAVIS: Nice, good to know. What's in the chest?
LAURA: What chest? Which one? All of them? Gold!
TRAVIS: The one right in front of you, what's that
currency?
LAURA: Oh, it's electrum.
SAM: Do we know what that is?
LIAM: It's a different value than gold.
TRAVIS: Like more than platinum?
LIAM: No, less than gold.
LAURA: Yeah, it's not as good as gold.
MARY: More than sterling, less than gold?
LAURA: It's like a nickel to a quarter!
TRAVIS: Glad you're all right, do us a favor:
remember that thing we said about gambling with
our lives?
MARY: That's two strikes, I'm throwing that out
there. That's two. I'm keeping score.
LAURA: Do you want to kill me and you'll never get
the--? Do you want to kill me?
TRAVIS: Oh, I wouldn't tempt her--
ASHLY: Hey, guys! There's a bunch of chests we
haven't opened here, right? Let's check what's in
the chests!
SAM: We are here to get a large jewel. Not gold.
LAURA: But maybe she's keeping the jewel in one of
the chests.
ASHLY: Yeah!
TRAVIS: Dren, I promise we will fill our pockets
on the way out because this will certainly be the
way that we leave, fair enough? We don't want to
have a little jingle-jangle--
LAURA: Maybe the mimic has the thing inside of
it!
ASHLY: Yeah!
MARY: I go over and try to free my rapier from
the--
LIAM: Yeah, it takes like a minute and a
half, but without the thing trying to bite you,
you are able to plant your foot on it, just the
edge, the corner of your boot and pull for a while
and it does come free.
TRAVIS: Other than the-- shit, sorry.
LIAM: It's okay, it smells bad.
MARY: There's still acid on it or is it just
glop?
LIAM: Yeah, I mean it's not as pretty as when you
got it at the shop, but it's functional.
TRAVIS: Other than the chests in the room, are
there any bookcases, or other paperwork like there
was in the other room?
LIAM: In here there are shelves lining these walls
as well, and there's clay pots with more coins in
them, and you see a tray with ingots, it looks
like gold. There's bolts of very fine fabric. You
open one box that is full of precious stones.
LAURA: Is there a big emerald in there? Is that
the stone you're looking for?
TRAVIS: Would you like to check?
LAURA: Sure!
LIAM: Box is about this big.
LAURA: Oh. I don't think this is the one.
TRAVIS: No. How about we each get one of those
nice, pretty stones, and then we don't reach in
any more booty until we leave? How about that?
ASHLY: You don't think the jewel's in any of these
chests?
LAURA: It really would be smart to look.
TRAVIS: Sure. Let's search the chests.
LAURA: I'll search the room for the jewel.
TRAVIS: Check them for traps before you open
them.
LAURA: Yeah.
MARY: I'll check the barrels that I was standing
on for traps.
LIAM: For traps? Okay, make a perception check.
Anyone who wants to check, make a perception check.
SAM: There's no other doors, right?
LIAM: There is another door.
MARY: Ten.
TRAVIS: 22.
ASHLY: 18.
LAURA: 11.
LIAM: In the interest of time, you all fan out,
open everything you can find, drag your hand
through chests full of wealth. There is a lot of
money here. There is no giant emerald.
LAURA: I pocket as much as I can.
LIAM: Make a stealth check.
LAURA: Shit. Six. Damn it!
LIAM: Coins are spilling around your feet going
(clinking).
TRAVIS: Obby?
SAM: Yes, sir.
TRAVIS: Do me a favor. Will you cut some holes in
all of her pockets, please?
LAURA: Aw, come on!
SAM: I retrieve my disgusting daggers from the
beast.
LIAM: Three minutes later they come out.
SAM: And I poke little holes all over. What are
you wearing?
LAURA: Really nice, awesome clothes.
MARY: No armor or anything?
LIAM: She's wearing some above-average robes and a
nice fur-lined cloak.
SAM: And it all has little holes in it.
LAURA: Damn it! This was worth a lot of money!
LIAM: You'll win it back.
MARY: I go over and grab a ruby out of that box. I
search for a ruby.
LIAM: Obviously?
MARY: Yeah. You said we could all take one.
TRAVIS: I did.
MARY: So I did. I'm taking a ruby. That big, I
find one.
LIAM: Okay. Biggest one in the box.
TRAVIS: I move to the door.
LIAM: All right. Are we moving out?
ASHLY: Yes.
TRAVIS: We're checking it for traps and seeing if
it's locked.
LIAM: Make a perception check.
MARY: Do you want me to Mage Hand the door?
ASHLY: I grab my shortsword before all of this,
also.
LAURA: Can I look around the room for the rat
symbol anywhere?
LIAM: Did you make a perception check already?
LAURA: I was looking for the jewel before.
LIAM: Okay. Make a perception check.
LAURA: Oh! Natural 20!
LIAM: This is a plain room full of money.
LAURA: Damn it, what a damn waste of a 20.
TRAVIS: So if you have been to the basement, then
you're obviously familiar with this room.
LAURA: This is the basement.
TRAVIS: This is the basement?
SAM: So what's next?
LAURA: Upstairs. You know, the entryway,
and then--
LIAM: No, it's been a while, think about it. Above
here is your grandmother's office. The office
leads to the rest of the first floor.
TRAVIS: Wait a minute. Those bookshelves--
Delweth, will you pull those away from the wall?
MARY: Of course. I check them for traps? We've
already done that. I pull away the bookshelves,
see if there's anything behind them.
LIAM: Things spill off, a couple of things break
as they hit the ground. Just a plain wall behind it.
MARY: There's nothing there, Tarvis.
TRAVIS: The floor is stone? Wood?
LIAM: It is wood.
LAURA: Well, if it's not in here, the only other
place that I can think of that it would be--
(groans)
ASHLY: What?
LAURA: Is down the hallway.
SAM: What room is that?
LAURA: It's upstairs. Up-up.
TRAVIS: Does this door lead upstairs?
LAURA: Well, yeah. I mean, it's the basement. Where
else is it going to lead?
TRAVIS: The wine cellar?
LAURA: It leads to her office.
MARY: All right. I check the door for traps.
LIAM: Well you checked already, you didn't find
any.
TRAVIS: 23.
MARY: I'll Mage Hand the door.
LIAM: Okay. The door goes (squeak). It is not
locked, it is not trapped that you can tell.
MARY: Pecking order. Who wants to go first?
ASHLY: Do you want me to scout, boss?
TRAVIS: Yes, Dren.
ASHLY: Okay. Stealthily, it's a million. 34.
LIAM: Okay. And you're in the lead, Dren? Did I
hear that right?
ASHLY: I'm scouting it out.
LIAM: Yeah, you're going up ahead?
ASHLY: Uh-huh.
LIAM: Okay, so you creep up, and you come up a
stairway, with little walls on each side, and you
start to see the insides of a nice office. She's
got a thing for these little globes of light. You
come up into a fairly well-lit room, it's big,
you're on one end of a large office. And the first
thing you see over there seems to be desk tables,
stuff you associate with an office. But right
where you're coming out, you see in the middle of
the floor going up to the ceiling a weird looking
brass column, going from the floor all the way up
to the ceiling. And there are constellations that
you are familiar with from books and from living
in Emon as long as you have, spiraling beautifully
all the way up this column, up to the ceiling. And
then around that are dog beds, five dog beds. You
also see a really large bone in the largest one.
You see a ragged hydra doll with a couple of heads
ripped away, and it looks like it's been whipped
around ragged. There's a crude leather ball made
out of leather fabric wrapped up, and that's this
side of the room.
ASHLY: I skitter back to everyone and I go,
Devan?
LAURA: Yeah.
ASHLY: Does your grandma like dogs?
LAURA: Does my grandma like dogs?
ASHLY: Like own them?
LIAM: She didn't have dogs when you lived here.
LAURA: Yeah, like, well, I mean not that I know
of. Why?
ASHLY: Because there's a bunch of beds with really
big bones and stuff ripped apart up there. Like
there's a bunch of dogs.
LAURA: Well my grandma is really paranoid.
ASHLY: Like they look like they're big dogs.
TRAVIS: You didn't see any up there?
ASHLY: No, but there's a big bone, and a thing
with its head ripped off. It doesn't look very
good. And a pretty thing in the middle, but I am
mostly worried about the dogs.
MARY: What pretty thing in the middle?
ASHLY: It's a brass pillar with like
constellations winding up it.
MARY: Huh. What do you think? What's your judgment
in all of this?
ASHLY: Looks like there's probably a bunch of
scary dogs there.
TRAVIS: Right.
MARY: But they're not in the room?
ASHLY: No.
MARY: Did you see any other doors, did you see
anything shut? Did you see...?
ASHLY: Did I?
LIAM and ASHLY: No.
MARY: Should we stealth up and see what happens?
I'm so sorry, I leave it to you, my fearless
leader.
TRAVIS: You read my mind, we're certainly not
going to find anything in here. What is the floor
made of in the room that she looked at?
LIAM: Are you up there?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'll go to the doorway.
LIAM: Doorway then stairs up out of this
basement.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: So you're going up to the top of the
stairs?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: Polished wood. And from where you can see,
you see a couple of dog beds. You don't see them all
yet because you aren't that far into the room.
Aside from the dog beds, it looks like a very
beautiful room.
TRAVIS: Can I see any animal hair, or any saliva
dried on the floor, any claw marks?
LIAM: Make a perception check.
TRAVIS: 14.
LIAM: 14? Yeah, on the dog beds you do see very
short, not a lot, and not long hairs, like short
hair. Bristly almost.
TRAVIS: What about the ceiling? Can I see the
ceiling at all? How high is it?
LIAM: Oh it's like 20 feet up. It's a very
beautiful room.
TRAVIS: No light fixtures, no chandeliers?
LIAM: There's a couple on this side of the room,
there's two of these floating globes.
TRAVIS: I step into the room.
LIAM: Okay. Coming around now you can see all the
dog beds, obviously this column and then you look
over to the side, and you see the office proper.
You see a large, beautiful desk. First thing you
see are two double doors that enter here, and then
there is a very impressive full-sized desk facing
that, there is a little wooden chair. Like coming
in for the interview.
MARY: So the desk is in the middle of the room?
LIAM: Yeah, if it's a long room, and coming up
here is where the dog beds are, and the column,
and then here's the middle with this desk, and the
entrance, and then further over this way there's
more. But it's a beautiful desk, and the chair,
it's like a miniature throne with little wooden
steps up the side of it, and you can see the seat
is higher than you would think it would be, for you
at least. And there's a beautiful globe in a brass
fixture on one side of the desk. On the other side
is a bookstand, like a bible stand if you've ever
seen one with a huge book with red ink in it and a
red ribbon hanging down. The binding of it looks
tan-colored, maybe leather. There's a huge table
on the far end of the room with papers scattered
all over it.
TRAVIS: Are there any windows or doors in this
room?
LIAM: There are two windows to your right here.
The rain is still coming down in sheets. They're
like ship porthole windows, circular, two of them
on the side you came up on. The rain is (crashing)
against the side of it, all the way across the
room. Same right behind you where you came up.
TRAVIS: Obby, will you come up here?
SAM: I come into the room and see the dog beds,
and I stop at the door.
TRAVIS: How do you feel about dogs?
SAM: Do you know why they call me Obby the Rat?
TRAVIS: No.
SAM: I hate dogs.
TRAVIS: Can you do me a favor and inspect those
dog beds and see what you can make of that bronze
column?
SAM: Obby would rather not, but I will for you.
TRAVIS: That's love, man.
SAM: I owe you for spilling acid. Hey, do you need
some health, or something?
TRAVIS: No, I'm good, why?
SAM: You're bleeding from your eyes.
TRAVIS: That's the color of my perspiration.
SAM: I will go and inspect the dog beds, is that
what I've been commissioned to do?
TRAVIS: Yeah, take Delweth with you.
SAM: I don't need her.
MARY: One night, that's all, you know, after one
night--
SAM: What am I doing? I'm checking the dog beds
for traps.
LIAM: What did you roll?
SAM: Five.
LIAM: You poke at them. They're soft, comfortable,
warm, they smell mildly like pee.
SAM: And I will sniff around and see if I can
smell any animals.
LIAM: Make a nature check.
SAM: Ten.
LIAM: There's dog toys sitting around here; it
does smell like dog in the room. The house is
quiet, other than the rain.
SAM: Time is of the essence, we should move.
TRAVIS: We should. Delweth, Dren, Devan, will you
come here?
ASHLY: Yes.
MARY: What can we do for you, Tarvis?
TRAVIS: Delweth, will you secure the room, and see
if there are any small dog doors that would open
and surprise us in a very nasty way? Will you
check the perimeter of the room? Dren and Devan,
shall we make our way to that lovely desk?
ASHLY: Yes!
LAURA: Sure.
TRAVIS: Your hesitation?
LAURA: I don't know why you want to check a desk.
TRAVIS: No?
LAURA: I mean, you're looking for an emerald,
right? A big fat one?
MARY: I do an insight check.
SAM: She gave you judgy face.
MARY: Is that what I do? I want to insight check
you.
LAURA: Me?
MARY: Yeah.
LAURA: Okay.
MARY: That would be a three. Do I add anything to
it?
TRAVIS: Yeah, you add two.
MARY: That would be a five.
LIAM: Make a roll and add your charisma bonus.
LAURA: I would have to roll, like, nothing,
because-- ten.
LIAM: Great. Clobbered. Yeah, I don't know.
MARY: I'm going to do a perception check on the
room to see if I find any doors, or anything else.
I do want to check out the bronze thing in the
center.
LIAM: Sure. You check out the column first. It's
beautifully made of brass. It's very ornate.
MARY: No holes, I can't detect anything on the
sides, no levers? Any constellations I can push
things into?
LIAM: No, you fiddle with it for a minute. It does
seem strange in the middle of a room. It doesn't
look like it's supporting anything.
MARY: And there's nothing at the top? It goes
floor to ceiling?
LIAM: Meets at the ceiling. In fact, it looks like
it goes into the ceiling.
MARY: We might want to check that if we go up
another story, see if we find it.
TRAVIS: And there's no balcony, riser, second
level, or anything in this room?
LIAM: In this room? Not in this room.
MARY: All right, then I check the walls for doggy
doors.
LIAM: Okay. You don't find dog doors. You do find
a wet bar hidden off to the side, on the other
side of where the-- yeah, old lady don't play. And
there's paper, you take a cursory glance at the
papers scattered on the large, long table, chairs
around it. There's an invitation from a Lord and
Lady Caldouin for a literary salon.
MARY: Nothing in the wet bar?
LIAM: Plenty in the wet bar.
TRAVIS: Obby, help Delweth with the wet bar.
SAM: Gladly.
MARY: What's your poison, Obby?
SAM: Vodka.
LIAM: I don't know what that is, but there's elven
wine, there's firewater.
MARY: I take a bottle of elven wine and put it in
my satchel.
SAM: Not interested.
LAURA: While they're looking at that, can I look
at the big book in the room?
LIAM: Yeah. What languages do you speak?
LAURA: I don't know. Halfling.
LIAM: You can't read it, then. It is beautiful,
but a little unsettling.
ASHLY: What if we busted open that pillar? Can
we?
SAM: It's made out of solid brass.
ASHLY: Is it solid brass? Is it hollow? Can we
tell that?
LAURA: I think the pillar probably supports the
room.
SAM: Was it always there?
ASHLY: I think he said it didn't seem like it
supports anything.
LIAM: You don't remember that.
TRAVIS: Do you want to go knock on it?
ASHLY: Yeah. Can I knock on it? Clunk clunk.
LIAM: (hollow ringing)
ASHLY and TRAVIS: It's hollow!
LIAM: The metal felt thick to the hit.
MARY: We could try some acid on it.
TRAVIS: Devan, to the desk, please.
LAURA: What do you want me to do?
TRAVIS: Search it.
LIAM: You go through.
LAURA: 18.
LIAM: You find more paper in there, more
parchments. There's more business in there.
There's more "flapjack," more "whisper."
"Tiddlywink" is a name that shows up.
MARY: Overbite, shortstack.
TRAVIS: No keys, no books, no binders?
SAM: Woodchuck. Gray squirrel.
LAURA: Are there any keys?
LIAM: No.
TRAVIS: Books or binders?
LIAM: There's quills, an empty journal, the
equivalent in Emon of a Farmer's Almanac talking
about the cycles of the moon and weather.
TRAVIS: An almanac? I'll take the almanac.
MARY: Do you remember your grandmother having any
celestial connection? She's a wizard?
LAURA: She's a sorcerer. Just like me! Only
stronger. Look, you guys want a jewel.
SAM: Where is it?
LAURA: You have me here. I don't why you're not
listening to me. It's going to be upstairs!
MARY: You stuck your hand in the thing and we had
to fight that.
LAURA: Yeah, but those weren't there before, you
know?
TRAVIS: Can I check the underside of the desk and
the chair for hidden switches?
LIAM: Yes, make a perception check.
MARY: What book was she looking at?
TRAVIS: 16.
LIAM: Big, massive book on a bible stand. You feel
under, knock on it. You know what to do in these
instances, you know to look for hidden catches.
You're not finding anything.
TRAVIS: Pick up the book.
LIAM: The big book? Yeah, okay.
MARY: What language is it, Tarvis?
LIAM: What languages do you speak?
TRAVIS: Common and Orc.
MARY: Elvish and Dwarven. Fuck.
TRAVIS: The globe is a planet globe, or is it an
orb?
LIAM: It's a planet globe, and you can't read
what's on that, either. You spin it around, look
at it for a while, you do recognize the
coast of Emon.
TRAVIS: If I open up the almanac and flip through
the pages really fast, are there any markings or
things that are circled, or anything that might be
a cypher or codex for the letters? No.
ASHLY: Has anyone done a perception check on the
pillar?
MARY: I did investigation.
LIAM: Anyone can try anything, and someone could
succeed where someone else failed.
TRAVIS: Want to give it a whack?
ASHLY: Sure. Maybe I'll get a natty 20 on this
roll. Sure didn't. It's a seven.
LIAM: You go, "I, I, I, want the knife."
MARY: You knocked on it; it's hollow?
ASHLY: It's hollow.
MARY: It's hollow, all right. Do you want me to
try some acid and see if it'll melt the bronze?
Or we could move on.
TRAVIS: It doesn't seem like it may have a support
function. All right, lead the way, Devan.
LAURA: All right! And I walk towards the--
LIAM: You know how big the house is. You're on the
back side of the house. You know that through
those double doors is the main hallway of the
first floor. There's other rooms in the house;
there's a kitchen, dining room, library, and
sitting room for guests. Out at the front of the
house are where the twin sets of staircases are
that lead up to the second floor, to your old
bedroom, and to the hall.
LAURA: The hall. The room. Can I lead them there?
LIAM: Are you going to go on a little march?
LAURA: Should we? Do you trust me?
TRAVIS, SAM, and MARY: No.
LAURA: Do you want a jewel?
TRAVIS and MARY: Yeah.
MARY: Let's go to the doors. I inspect the doors
to see if there any traps and go stealth.
LIAM: Make a perception check.
MARY: That's better. 15.
LIAM: You trace your fingers lightly along the
edges of the door, look for the telltale signs
that you all have trained to find. You don't see
anything.
MARY: Is the door unlocked?
LIAM: Yes.
MARY: I use Mage Hand to open the door very
slowly, just the right side.
LIAM: You're looking in. The only light is coming
from this room, but a dark long hallway that
stretches about 80 feet.
MARY: How far does my darkvision reach?
LIAM: 60ish.
MARY: I see nothing within 60 feet?
LIAM: No, you see some potted plants and a nice
red carpet disappearing a little bit into the
darkness.
LAURA: Do you hear dogs?
MARY: I don't hear any dogs, no.
ASHLY: Is this the hallway you were talking
about?
LAURA: No. This is a hall, though.
ASHLY: That's true! Should we walk down it?
MARY: I'll go in the lead this time. Again with my
rapier out. Is that all right with you, Tarvis, if
I take the lead in this?
TRAVIS: Please, yes.
LAURA: Do you want me to send some lights down the
hallway?
MARY: Not right now.
SAM: I will take the rear. I do not like dogs.
LIAM: So you guys slowly creep your way down.
Everybody make a stealth check.
SAM: Two.
LIAM: Really?
ASHLY: 24.
TRAVIS: 19.
SAM: Seven.
MARY: 14.
ASHLY: 24.
LAURA: 19.
LIAM: You quietly move your way down, this one
bumps a potted plant on the way--
SAM: Is that dog?
LIAM: Everybody holds still for a second. Nothing.
You continue on, you eventually meet another set
of doors, just like the ones you went through. You
know this leads to the front of the house.
MARY: What's through there?
LAURA: The foyer.
MARY: Again, I'll take Mage Hand and go along the
edge of the door, checking for traps--
LIAM: Make a perception check.
MARY: Perception. 18.
LIAM: Tickle the door open with this spectral
hand, sticks its pinkie into the keyhole. Seems
fine, nothing's happening.
MARY: Tarvis, it seems like the door's clear. What
do you want me to do?
TRAVIS: Be my guest.
MARY: Again, I use Mage Hand on the right door, if
there are two, is it two or one?
LIAM: It's two. You see the red carpet actually
continues into the next room, and you can barely
see two sets of stairways coming down along the
sides of this path and this carpet. You can see a
very beautiful set of large doors with circular
windows, one on each side, and you see the rain
coming down. You also can make out a person at a
distance walking by--
SAM: Outside?
LIAM: About ten or 15 feet, yeah.
MARY: Is there someone outside?
LIAM: You see a coat tree right by the door, and
then a little table to the other side of it with a
pair of white gloves sitting on it.
LAURA: (whispering) Do you hear any dogs?
MARY: I hear no dogs.
LIAM: Painting of some old halfling man with a
curly little moustache-
TRAVIS: Obby, check the painting.
SAM: Behind the painting? (groans) I hate art.
LIAM: Do you know why the call me Obby the Rat?
SAM: I look behind the painting.
LIAM: There's nothing there.
SAM: There's a man looking through the eyeholes of
the painting.
TRAVIS: Did you kill him?
SAM: No, he seemed okay.
TRAVIS: I trust your judgment.
MARY: So no doors, no nothing? It's two stairways
going up and two big doors, but what's on the
right and left?
LIAM: You were so fixated on the guy outside.
There's a door on the side of this room, and on
the other side as well. There's stairs leading up
to it.
ASHLY: Do you know who that guy would be, Devan?
LAURA: I don't know, probably a guard.
MARY: Devan, give us a layout. What's on the
right, on the left, up?
SAM: Come on, off the top of your head!
Quick! Quick!
LAURA: It's been ten years.
LIAM: There's a library on the right.
LAURA: There's a library on the right. And then on
the left is a little sitting area. And then
upstairs-- It's been a while. So unless she
rearranged, upstairs--
MARY: You lived here as a child, yeah?
LAURA: No. My mom, she split. My grandma took me
in. She was a horrible person though.
MARY: How long did you live here for?
LAURA: Couple years.
SAM: Devan? Family is very important.
LAURA: I know.
SAM: You should not have stolen from yours.
LAURA: She doesn't even pay attention to how much
is down there! It's ridiculous!
SAM: If you want attention there's other ways of
finding it.
LAURA: Thank you.
ASHLY: Is that a come on, or are we--?
TRAVIS: Do you have a haiku for this, Dren?
LAURA: Is her bedroom upstairs?
LIAM: Her bedroom is on the third floor. Your
bedroom is on the second floor.
LAURA: Okay. So my bedroom used to--
LIAM: There's a guest bedroom up there too, and
the funtime hall is up there as well.
LAURA: And then there's this room. I mean, it
could be in there. I'm thinking it's probably in
there, because there was this cabinet that I never
got to look in. I feel like that's where it would be.
TRAVIS: In which room?
LAURA: In the funroom. Then upstairs from that is
my grandma's bedroom, which I guess it could be in
there as well.
TRAVIS: This might be a strange question. Why is
it called the funroom?
LAURA: Oh, because that's where she keeps all
her magic stuff.
MARY: Let's go there.
TRAVIS: Her magic stuff.
ASHLY: There's not a situation-- forgive me,
Tarvis-- where we should split up and look at
different places?
TRAVIS: I wouldn't mind that. Do we want to check
out the rooms on the right and the left super fast?
SAM: You're the boss, boss.
MARY: We'll do whatever you say, Tarvis.
TRAVIS: I'll move to the door where the guard
keeps walking outside and crouch underneath one of
the windows. If he comes in, he's dead. And I'll
let Delweth go with Devan, and Dren goes with
Obby.
LAURA: Where are we going?
TRAVIS: One can check out the library and one can
check out the tea room.
LIAM: All right, who's going to the library, to
the right?
SAM: Me and Dren are going to the library.
LIAM: Okay. All right, you head in there. First of
all, you, Tarvis, look out the window. It's not a
man. It's a woman. It's a large woman, with shock
white hair and massive arms.
TRAVIS: Armed? She'll die.
MARY: She's got massive arms?
LIAM: Yeah. Well she's got a cloak with a hood,
and you can see the hair spilling out. She looked
right at the house a moment ago, but she didn't
look at you. She just glanced over--
TRAVIS: Does it look like she's standing sentry
and doing a guardsman?
LIAM: Yeah, and you can even see further in the
distance, like another 60 feet away is a gate to
the rest of the city, out of her grounds. You can
barely, in this heavy rain, see two more guys,
standing on the other side.
TRAVIS: Be quick about it. Search, come back, and
let's move on.
LIAM: So you guys split off to the library?
SAM: Yes.
LIAM: You can see in here. It's totally dark, but
bookshelves curve all the way around the entirety
of this room. There's one of those rolling ladders
that slides along to reach the books on the top
shelf. There's a nice loveseat with a small side
table next to it. There's a book, open, upside
down, on the table.
SAM: I'll do a perception check to see if there is
anything out of the ordinary or weird? 18.
LIAM: You do notice wedged amongst all the books
of history, philosophy, and arcana one erotic
novel.
SAM: I pick it up. I give it to Dren. And I say:
maybe you can use this, not for me.
ASHLY: I don't know what you're talking about.
Thank you.
LIAM: Meanwhile, in the tea room, it is also
really dark in here. It's you two?
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: You can't see shit, but you can see a
beautiful little round table with a china set out,
white and blue plates. It's hard to see that in
the dark. It looks more like white and black.
There's a little rolling tea table with sugar bowl
and all the stuff. There's also, what's the word?
Not an armoire--
MARY: A buffet?
LIAM: That's what it is! A buffet with a couple of
silver platters placed neatly for presentational
purpose. Looks like a presenting room or sitting
room.
LAURA: Delweth, do you want me to cast some
dazzling lights?
MARY: You know what, let's leave it for now. Save
it. Let's look around. I mean, you can't look
around.
LIAM: You hear a woman's voice sneeze outside the
window.
MARY: Quiet.
SAM and LAURA: What?
MARY: Outside one of the porthole windows?
LIAM: Yeah, not right outside it, a little ways
away. Through the heavy sound of the rain.
MARY: Can I approach the window very stealthily?
LIAM: The one in here? Sure.
MARY: And take a little peek out.
LAURA: Here's the thing, Delweth. I don't know why
we're not friends. I mean, I didn't really do
anything to hurt the Clasp. In fact, I'm just
helping you guys!
MARY: Devan, I understand that you might have a
problem with gambling.
LAURA: I mean, that's pretty innocent, really.
MARY: I know a lot about addiction.
LAURA: Oh, really?
SAM: Sex-a-holic.
ASHLY: I have a book for you later.
MARY: So, as much as I'd like to, it's difficult
for me to trust you.
LAURA: Right.
MARY: But I think if we both get out of this--
LAURA: I think we will!
MARY: I think we'll be fine. All right?
LAURA: We'll be friends afterwards.
MARY: So here's the thing. I know what you're
going through. I'm going to do whatever I can to
help you. All right? But that's between us.
LAURA: Okay.
SAM: Audience, she said that she's going to do
whatever she can to help you.
MARY: Let's go back out. I think. Are there any
drawers on the buffet?
LIAM: Sure there are. There's silverware, napkins,
really nice napkins, and tablecloths.
MARY: Any turkey carving knives or anything nice
like that? Turkey carving knife. Might need it for
later. You never know!
LIAM: You all have your weapons, so I'm going to
say you guys took a couple minutes earlier to yank
them out of the monstrosity downstairs.
SAM: We rejoin the group.
MARY: Stay close to me. This is going to get
dangerous.
TRAVIS: Anything?
SAM: Well there was--
ASHLY: Nothing! There was nothing.
SAM: There was a ladder on wheels that could be
the source of farcical comedy and hijinks. But not
tonight.
TRAVIS: And you two?
MARY: There was nothing. I heard someone sneeze
outside. It might be even the same person that was
walking in the front. But nothing.
TRAVIS: I quickly check the window to make sure
she still has her back to us.
LIAM: Yes, she's picking her nose quite vigorously
right now.
TRAVIS: We make our way to the stairs that lead to
the second floor.
MARY: There are two sets. Which one do you want to
go up?
LAURA: They go to the same place.
LIAM: They're identical, they're twin stairs going
to the same destination. You can tell even from
down here.
TRAVIS: The one on the right.
LIAM: You head up those stairs. I'll say you
quietly move your way up.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we would like to stealth.
LIAM: Roll it.
TRAVIS: 17.
LAURA: (groans) 13.
MARY: 24.
SAM: How about a natural 20?
MARY: That's two and two!
ASHLY: Wait, was that stealth?
LAURA: Yeah. Is that seven?
ASHLY: That's seven. Nine.
LIAM: Obby actually slips under Tarvis' legs and
then disappears through his cloak, and everyone
loses track for a second. He's gone.
TRAVIS: I got the whiff of some number twos.
LIAM: You move up those stairs. Directly in front
of you guys, you see doors that you recognize.
They're the doors to the hall. You also know that
right over here, over your shoulder, is your old
room. There's a guest bedroom across the hall.
MARY: Sorry, so I can get a layout, how many
doors?
LIAM: Coming up the stairs, you see double doors
right in front of you. And then, you look over
your shoulders, there's doors on the sides and
behind you.
SAM: It's got to be the double doors, right?
MARY: Where are we? What's ahead of us?
LAURA: This is the magic room.
MARY: Straight ahead?
LAURA: Upstairs is my grandma's room.
MARY: Where's your room?
LIAM: Yeah, and there's a curving stairway
directly behind you guys that goes to the third
floor.
TRAVIS: No interest in your room?
LAURA: She wouldn't have kept anything of mine.
TRAVIS: Shouldn't we visit it for nostalgia?
LAURA: I don't have anything in there. She
probably burned it all.
TRAVIS: Let's take a look.
MARY: How close were you at your closest to your
grandma? When she took you in, did she bounce you
on her knee?
LAURA: No, no, no. I would say I was one step down
from the cook?
MARY: So she didn't teach you anything?
LAURA: No-- I mean she taught me some spells, and
I do Dancing Lights, see? Just this is one. I take
it away. She taught me some stuff.
TRAVIS: Let's see your room.
MARY: Yeah.
LIAM: Are you taking them over to your room?
LAURA: I take them over to the room. There's
nothing in here!
LIAM: You open the door. You can't see into the
dark. But you guys, looking in in the dim light,
see nothing in this room except for furniture
grouped together with sheets over it for storage.
SAM: It's an old Backstreet Boys poster.
LAURA: *NSync, thank you very much!
TRAVIS: I reach up and take the cloth that's
hanging over a large portion of the furniture and
I pull it off.
LIAM: There is a chaise lounge with two beautiful
wooden chairs sitting on top of it. Not bedroom
furniture at all.
MARY: Nothing else, just three pieces of
furniture?
LIAM: Under that sheet, yeah.
MARY: Any other sheets?
LIAM: Two more.
MARY: All right. I pull off the second one.
LIAM: Oh my god!
MARY: Oh my god, and you die.
LIAM: A large table, and on top of the table,
lying on its side, is a little dresser drawer.
MARY: Dresser drawers. I investigate the dresser
drawers.
LIAM: You lift one drawer up, and it's empty.
MARY: There's only one drawer?
LIAM: You'd say it was shoved in here for
storage.
LAURA: I send a message over to Dren. How are you
doing? I mean, are you okay?
ASHLY: Yeah, I miss hanging out with you.
LAURA: I know, I feel like we don't even get to
talk any more.
ASHLY: I know, it's really dumb. It's nice being
in your room, though!
LAURA: Oh, well, it's kind of embarrassing.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: We take the last tarp and pull it off.
LIAM: It is another love seat like the one that
you saw down in the library. It's identical,
actually.
TRAVIS: I take a dagger out and shove it in the
cushions of the love seat and drag it across, open
it up.
LIAM: Stuffing pops out.
LAURA: No need for violence.
TRAVIS: Those dogs get all over the place and ruin
shit all the time.
SAM: Dogs? What dogs?
MARY: I know every child's got a secret hiding
place in their room. So I want to perception check
the room, the walls, if there's something, or the
floors if there's a loose floorboard, somewhere.
LIAM: Do the roll.
SAM: I pick up two playing cards, one with Corey
Feldman and one with Corey Haim.
LIAM: It's empty. The room, the furniture wasn't
even taking up that much space in here. It looks
like Grandma cleared it out, and started storing
shit in here.
LAURA: She does not give a shit.
TRAVIS: All right, fine.
MARY: Uno. Perception.
LIAM: Ghosts, there's ghosts everywhere.
TRAVIS: We'll leave this room, now. It's just a
hallway and the funroom door?
SAM: There's stairs going up.
TRAVIS: Yeah, up to her place. But on this floor
is the funroom. You know what?
MARY: Are there three other doors and the funroom?
Or one other and the funroom?
LAURA: Just a guest room and then the funroom.
TRAVIS: I don't know if you can control yourself
in the funroom, so I'm going to take the rope that
I have, and I'm going to bind your hands behind
your back before we go into the funroom.
LAURA: Oh, that's pointless because I'm going to
need my hands. If you want to get through the
funroom, I'm going to need my hands!
ASHLY: I can watch her, Tarvis. I'll make sure she
doesn't do anything--
TRAVIS: Oh, Dren, you said you wanted to tie her
hands behind her back for me?
ASHLY: Yeah, Tarvis, that's what I said, sure. And
I tie it, but really loose, but they don't see
that, maybe?
LIAM: Make a stealth check.
ASHLY: Fuck! Ten.
LIAM: Okay. Yeah, you walk behind her and tie it.
TRAVIS: That looks a little loose. Tighten it up
for me?
ASHLY: Sure, Tarvis, I'll tighten it up.
LAURA: Ow! That really hurt!
ASHLY: I'm sorry.
LIAM: I'll actually say it's slightly above medium
tight, because he couldn't see. Okay, what's up,
guys?
SAM: We're going into this magic room, is that
right?
MARY: Mage Hand the door, Mage Hand the lock, to
perceive if it's open or go along the edge.
LIAM: You twiddle your hand, your Mage Hand, all
over it. You spend a minute doing it, because
you're feeling nervous. Seems okay. You're
thorough.
MARY: Is it unlocked? Could I perceive if it was
unlocked?
LIAM: It's not locked.
TRAVIS: In this hallway and outside of the doors,
are there any of those sigils?
LIAM: No.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MARY: No rats anywhere, except for Obby?
TRAVIS: Does the doorknob look different than a
normal doorknob?
LIAM: It's not a knob. It's one of those--
TRAVIS: The levers?
MARY: Shall I Mage Hand the door?
TRAVIS: No, I got it. I'll open the door. And I
push it open.
LIAM: The door swings open in front of you and
that's where we'll take our break.
[break]
LIAM: Welcome back.
MARY: Balls!
LAURA: Too late. Way late.
LIAM: I hope you're all having fun inside my house
of horrors!
TRAVIS: We don't know what the fuck is happening.
LIAM: Well let's get back into it. As you open the
doors before you, you are met with quite a sight.
The hall is well-lit by the same amber baubles
floating in space all down the hallway. Stretches
out about 80, 90 feet ahead of you. The hallway is
absolutely littered with countless strange,
extraordinary, and occasionally off-putting
objects. This is Taliesin Jaffe's wet dream.
Objects of beauty and horror are mixed together in
a crazed jumble along each side of this hall.
There are paintings hanging all the way down, each
more unsettling than the one before. A large fish
skeleton hangs way down on the other end of the
hall. It looks about fifteen feet long. Things
right nearby that you spot: there are a crude pair
of heavy black iron tongs; a unicorn fetus in a
very large jar, pickled and curled in on itself; a
set of eerie looking dolls, beautifully crafted
but with no eyes, the front plate smashed in;
stacks of books everywhere; a large stuffed bear
rearing back, with a giant open snarl. Then all
the way down the hall, you see ornate, gothic,
creepy as fuck looking chandeliers. Three of them,
evenly spaced down the hall and they look like
cruel teeth pointed downward but they are
gorgeous. They're stunning to look at. You almost
don't know whether to shit or go blind. You don't
know where to look; there's so much stuff. And
you've seen this before. Most of it. There's new
things here. Things you haven't seen, and you're
overwhelmed, you're short-circuiting with all the
things you're looking at around you.
MARY: Devan, what do you remember?
LAURA: I remember.
MARY: Close your eyes, what do you remember?
TRAVIS: Do you remember?
LAURA: I remember a shield.
SAM: Shield?
LIAM: You look over your shoulder, and you see
that. There's two of them on the walls, to the
side of both doors. They're black with a red
barren tree in winter painted identically on each
one hanging decoratively.
SAM: Were the shields traps or something?
LAURA: There's a very specific thing we have to do
when we go down this hallway.
SAM: Okay, what is it?
LAURA: Well does somebody want to go over to the
shield on the right?
SAM: I will do it.
LAURA: Lift it up?
SAM: Will I die?
LAURA: No?
SAM: I lift it up.
LIAM: You place your hand, and you have to reach
pretty high, but you get up on your tiptoes and
reach and you push, and you feel it go (clunk).
SAM: Okay. Now what?
LAURA: Bring it back down.
SAM: I do.
LIAM: You dig your nails onto the curve and
(click) back to where it was.
LAURA: Pull it down.
SAM: Up down up down?
LIAM: Left right left right?
SAM: Sure, I pull it down.
LIAM: (click)
LAURA: Shit, I think I'm doing something wrong.
ASHLY: Something with the left shield?
LAURA: No, it was the one on the right.
SAM: Well this is just great, I'm glad we brought
you here as our guide.
LAURA: No, there's a second step. Can I look
around, do I see a wall sconce?
LIAM: Nope.
LAURA: There's no wall sconce? In the corner?
Shit. She changed some stuff.
SAM: All right. We should kill her.
TRAVIS: I think so too.
LAURA: No! You still need--
MARY: I pull out my rapier.
ASHLY: Wait guys! Hold on! We haven't even
examined the whole room! Right?
SAM: She's useless to us.
LAURA: The wall sconce is hiding behind these
books!
ASHLY: If we go deeper in the room you might see
something!
LIAM: I'll also remind you that there were two
doors that she opened using blood.
SAM: We've got to keep her hand with us.
MARY: We could keep a vial of her blood!
TRAVIS: Just bring her hand with us.
ASHLY: It's a lot easier if we take her with us, I
feel like.
MARY: So what were you trying to do with the
shield?
LAURA: Well I remember my grandma did some stuff,
and things happened, and we had to do things in a
very specific order, but she also said--
SAM: How did you do that?
LAURA: I don't know, these are so tight! I don't
even know how my hand came out of it. I also
remember her saying not to touch anything.
TRAVIS: (laughter) I can't imagine why.
LIAM: Obby, as she's rattling this off, you're
spacing out, looking around the room, checking out
the artwork on the wall. The one right above you
is of a ship, splitting open on the sea and the
crews are plunging into the waves in the center of
it. You look across the hall. Over there is one of
mourners at an open grave, filled to the brim with
blood. You also look around and notice a gorgeous
metallic egg, studded with jewels, all around it.
Beautiful.
SAM: How big?
LIAM: This big. A little bit bigger than a regular
egg. A teapot made out of... it looks like bone.
SAM: Well I like this art better.
LAURA: Don't touch it! I keep looking for a wall
sconce. Obby, when you touched the shield did you
hear a click? Did you hear anything click?
SAM: Yes. Felt a click.
LAURA: Let's look for the wall sconce!
SAM: We're supposed to push up the shield and then
tilt back a wall sconce or something?
LAURA: You pull out a wall sconce, yeah.
SAM: Pull out a wall sconce?
LAURA: Yeah.
MARY: Is there a holder for it behind one of the
paintings maybe?
LAURA: Do we see anything?
SAM: We can go look.
LIAM: Is there a what?
LAURA: A wall sconce.
LIAM: You remember where it was. It's not there.
The wall is smooth. There was a third step too;
you remember what it was?
LAURA: Well, yeah!
SAM: Where was the wall sconce?
LAURA: It was right there.
SAM: I feel right where she's pointing.
LIAM: You give a knock.
TRAVIS: Maybe we need her blood. Dren, cut her.
LAURA: No, there's more to do! Sheesh! Can I walk
down the hallway?
LIAM: You can, yeah.
ASHLY: Look, if there's traps, then she'll get hit
by them!
LIAM: Is that what you're doing?
LAURA: Can I look for traps as I'm walking down
the hall?
LIAM: Sure, make a perception check.
TRAVIS: Where were the shields? Were they at the
bottom of the hallway from where we are?
LIAM: No, they were hanging up on the sides of the
doors decoratively.
TRAVIS: That we came in?
LIAM: Yeah, the ones you came in.
ASHLY: I also make a perception check.
LAURA: Eight!
ASHLY: 17!
TRAVIS: Can I check the floor for traps?
LIAM: The floor, sure.
SAM: I'm going to check the shield to see if I can
intuit how it works.
LIAM: Investigation check.
TRAVIS: 19.
SAM: Four!
LIAM: Tarvis, you see poking out of the edge of
the carpet-- you know how downstairs there was a
long red carpet? There's one here as well. You see
a bit of scrawl, something poking out of the edge
of the rug about eight feet in front of you.
TRAVIS: Be careful of the rug. It's booby
trapped!
LAURA: (gasp) Okay! Do I see a bowl? A plate
anywhere? A bowl with water in it?
LIAM: Not off-hand, no.
ASHLY: Do I, because I got a 17?
LIAM: No bowl. You do see a really cool little
brass and wood clockwork owl? That's cool.
ASHLY: That is cool.
SAM: Should we start opening things and--
LAURA: No, don't touch anything!
SAM: Well something needs to happen or we leave
this room.
ASHLY: Devan and I will go deeper into the room,
and if anything goes screwy, we'll get hit by it,
and then maybe we'll find that wall sconce!
TRAVIS: No, Dren, you stay here. Delweth will go
with Devan.
ASHLY: Okay.
LIAM: Walking forward? Going down the hall?
LAURA: I send a message to Dren--
TRAVIS: I walk up to the little part of the carpet
that has the little bit sticking out from under
the carpet.
LIAM: You do that before they walk off?
TRAVIS: Yes, before they go.
LIAM: All right, you peel it back; there is some
sort of arcane scrawl on the floor.
TRAVIS: Like, scrawl?
LIAM: Yeah, like a ring written in a circle. You
tug the rug back a bit and you see it goes further
under the carpet and you see the edge of a spiral
pattern of writing that you can't--
MARY: Is it Elvish?
TRAVIS: I was going to ask.
LIAM: It's not.
TRAVIS: Oh, it's not?
LIAM: No.
MARY: Dwarvish?
TRAVIS: Orcish?
LIAM: Make an arcana check.
TRAVIS: Oh, me? No problem. That's a motherfucking
one.
(laughter)
LIAM: That is Esperanto.
TRAVIS: Cool.
SAM: I can jump on things and unlock things.
MARY: All right, we will start walking very
slowly. Can I do a perception check for any traps
down this hallway? Or is it all sort of fucked
anyway?
LIAM: It's a long hallway and there's so much shit
in here that it's like process a little bit as you go.
MARY: All right, let's take it real slow.
TRAVIS: What if you do an arcana check?
MARY: Can I do an arcana check on the scrawl?
LIAM: Sure.
MARY: Forget about it. That's 18 plus, what do I
add? 18 plus three, that's 21.
LIAM: Yeah, you know what this is.
MARY: Of course I do.
LIAM: How do you think you know magic? You had to
study.
MARY: Yeah! I know what this is.
LIAM: You don't know all of it. You would never be
able to make this on your own, but you recognize
some of the key glyphs in it. This is a magic
sigil. This will turn gravity haywire here. You
look straight up at one of the iron, gothic,
tooth-like chandeliers, right above it.
MARY: Right. Do not step here. From what I can
see, if you do, you'll be thrown up into the
ceiling, into the teeth of this fantastic
chandelier. So, my recommendation would be to go
around.
TRAVIS: If we cross this threshold or if we step
here?
LAURA: Are there any wall sconces up top?
TRAVIS: Are there?
LIAM: No. There is enough room on the sides to
gingerly step around this.
MARY: I grab the back of the rope of your hands.
You're in the lead. I'm behind you. I hold you
with my left hand and I have my rapier in my
right. We start to move very slowly on exposed
wood that we can see whether or not there's going
to be any--
LIAM: So what are you saying, someone's pulling
carpet as you go or? It's one carpet that goes all
the way down the hall and Tarvis went and under
this part of the carpet was one area.
SAM: We're avoiding the carpet altogether.
MARY: We can't because it's wall to wall, right?
LIAM: It's not wall to wall. It's a very wide hall
and it's down the center and all the eclectic
craziness is piled up to the sides of it. I mean
some stuff spills over on the rug, but it's pretty
hodge podge.
TRAVIS: Were there windows that were along the
wall?
LIAM: No windows up here.
MARY: So we make our way down the right side on
the wood.
LIAM: You can't do that because the wood all the
way down is taken up by things like jars with
pickled unicorns in them.
LAURA: But we can avoid the gravity scrawl--
LIAM: This one spot you can sneak around.
MARY: All right, we'll sneak around that and
slowly work our way forward.
LAURA: Keeping an eye on the ground for any more
of those things.
LIAM: Okay. You pass by a portrait of a woman all
in black, stiff, austere dress, a cold white face,
and you double take and look at it again and
realise that that woman is dead and there's a fly
crawling in the side of her mouth. On the other
side there's a painting of a large still lake
stretching away from the shore and there's a small
boat drifting off in the middle. And there's a
piece of fabric draped into the water and things
floating in the side of it.
MARY: Grandmother had a very strange definition of
fun.
LAURA: I think she might be into some creepy
shit.
TRAVIS: Is the dead woman behind a case or is she
out, the dead woman?
LIAM: It's a painting. You see an assortment of
bells covering the top of one table, all different
sizes and different colors of metal. A platter
with a series of bone needles lying on it. You see
a stuffed ostrich with a little skull cap metal
pith helmet with a spike coming out of it. On one
armoire, there's a shiny black stone wasp as big
as a bird, also gorgeous. A wicker rabbit with
antlers protruding from its head.
MARY: A wabbit with antlers.
LIAM: Yes. Arcane jackalope.
SAM: Tarvis has told me to pick up the wasp.
LAURA: Don't pick up anything! Don't touch
anything!
LIAM: Pick up the wasp?
LAURA: Seriously.
LIAM: Make a con save.
TRAVIS: Well you don't have to.
LIAM: It is done. Make a con save my friend.
SAM: Natural 20.
LIAM: Well you pick it up and look at it and it is
gorgeous and shines. It glints in the light. It
curls in on itself and the stinger goes into your
wrist. You take two points of damage.
SAM: What kind?
LIAM: Poison.
SAM: No, I am a dwarf, advantage on saves versus
poison, resistance against poison damage.
LIAM: Resistant, nice! You take one point and you
have a small red hole bleeding out in your hand.
SAM: I suck the poison out. I swallow it down.
TRAVIS: You are hard as nails, Obby the Rat.
LAURA: Through all of this have we seen a wall
sconce?
LIAM: You're still walking down the hall. What's
our order, by the way?
MARY: Devan's first, I'm second.
LIAM: Devan's first.
TRAVIS: I'm third, Dren's fourth.
LIAM: There's also enough room to go side by side,
which is--
MARY: No, I know, but I'm pushing her forward.
LIAM: Everyone going single-file, yeah? Who's
third?
TRAVIS: I am. And Obby in the rear, like he likes
it.
LIAM: So you continue to walk?
MARY: Slowly, investigating everything as we go.
LIAM: Are you looking for traps, further traps?
MARY: I use my Mage Hand to push the carpet as we
go forward to see if there's anything--
LIAM: Sure, but also make a perception check. This
is a crowded-- this is not your normal room.
TRAVIS: 24.
SAM: 17.
MARY: 21.
ASHLY: I got a three, so all things I could
perceive with a three just go ahead and tell me.
LAURA: I rolled a three as well!
TRAVIS: Jeez. Fucking turtledoves.
LIAM: All right, so you're still walking forward,
right?
MARY: Yep, Mage Handing the carpet.
LIAM: Okay. So as you're walking--
MARY: Balls.
LIAM: Devan (whoosh) is gone.
MARY: She's gone? Tarvis?
TRAVIS: Strike! Find her.
ASHLY: Devan?
MARY: Devan!
LIAM: Hold that thought. Devan. You are instantly
submerged in water. It is pitch black. You can't
see anything. You are underwater. Your hands are
tied behind your back.
LAURA: Oh shit!
LIAM: You hold your breath. You immediately feel
multiple bites all over your body. Make a
constitution save, please.
MARY: Do I have the end of the rope, that was...?
I was holding the rope.
LAURA: 19.
LIAM: 19? Okay. Whoops, that's the wrong one. You
feel small sharp teeth biting on every inch of
your body. Your neck, your face, your hands,
everywhere, biting through your clothes. You feel
a burning sensation under your skin in your blood,
and you take five points of poison damage. You
can't see what's going on. You kick and start to
panic. You can't tell which way is up. You can't
tell which way is down. You guys. She's been gone
for 30 seconds.
SAM: Where did she go? Feel the floor around where
she was standing.
MARY: I don't know. I step forward into where she
was.
LAURA: Oh no!
MARY: No? Is that a bad idea?
TRAVIS: You did it.
MARY: I did it.
LIAM: Nothing happens.
MARY: Nothing?!
SAM: Wait, what are the objects around us that we
can see immediately around us?
LIAM: Around you? There were bone needles. There
were bells. There were creepy as fuck paintings.
There's an ostrich with a little spike helmet on
his head.
SAM: One of the paintings was water?
LIAM: One was a lake.
TRAVIS: Do we see her splashing around in the
painting?
LIAM: 45 seconds have passed.
SAM: I go to the water painting and start feeling
it.
LIAM: What's your constitution modifier, Laura?
LAURA: Plus six.
ASHLY: I go and splash around in the water. Does
anything happen?
LIAM: What water? There's no water.
ASHLY: Isn't there water? Oh, in the painting.
SAM: I'm looking at the painting to see if there's
anything.
LIAM: Okay, make a perception check.
SAM: 12.
LIAM: Okay. Nothing.
MARY: I pull the painting off the wall and stick
my dagger into it.
LIAM: You pull the painting off the wall and see a
scrawl of arcane glyphs in a circle, there. No,
it's right parallel to where Devan was.
MARY: Okay. All right, glyphs, perception check on
the glyphs? Arcane check, arcana?
LIAM: Yeah, arcana check.
LAURA: Can I do anything?
MARY: Natural one.
LIAM: You are short-circuiting. You're so
discombobulated by this scenario--
LAURA: I'm going to die!
TRAVIS: I come up behind her because she's made
this discovery, I try one as well.
MARY: Tarvis, Tarvis!
TRAVIS: Wow! You're just destined to die! That's
two in a row!
LIAM: Just around this scrawl of arcana on the
wall, going gabba, gabba gabba gabba.
ASHLY: Four.
SAM: Don't worry, Obby the Rat knows what to do.
What is this? 13.
LIAM: 13. You don't know what the fuck that says.
SAM: I know what it says. I reach my arm into it.
LIAM: (impact) Ow! That's when you hear at the end
of the hall, in this hall you're in, in addition
to all this shit, there's six doors all the way
down. You've barely even paid attention to them
because of all the stuff that's in here.
You've already passed a set of doors behind
you, and then there's another two, and another two
all the way at the end of the hall. And at the end
of the hall, on the right, behind the closed door,
you hear (impact).
ASHLY: I run toward that door.
TRAVIS: I go with her.
LIAM: Okay, you two are bolting down the red
carpet. They all have the same turn-latch door
handle that the original doors do, and you get to
the door and freeze for a second?
ASHLY: I open it.
LIAM: As soon as you touch the door handle,
electricity goes up your arm.
SAM: All the traps have been sprung.
LAURA: Just all of them.
TRAVIS: Fucking fun room.
LIAM: Dexterity save on that.
ASHLY: Okay, five, and then I do this guy?
SAM: Tarvis. We can let Devan die.
ASHLY: 17?
LIAM: You take only five points of electricity
damage. So you've just been electrocuted by the
door handle, but the door does open, and you hold
your hand. You look in. The room is somewhat lit
from the lights behind you, and you see a large
20-feet-tall cube of glass, a fish tank, and
inside it, you can see a form going--
ASHLY: I start smashing it with my shortsword.
LIAM: Okay. Everybody roll initiative.
ASHLY: 19.
LAURA: 19 as well!
ASHLY and LAURA: Yes!
MARY: 20.
LIAM: 20, okay. What about you, gentlemen?
SAM: Eight.
TRAVIS: Seven. Leading from the front. Haven't hit
shit yet. Not one thing.
LIAM: Okay. All right, so Devan, the fish continue
to bite.
LAURA: Can I do anything?
LIAM: In a second, you can.
MARY: Do they bite the rope, and they eat the
rope? The fishes? They don't know what's flesh.
LIAM: Make another con save.
SAM: You are dead. You're a dead person.
LAURA: 24!
LIAM: All right, take eight more points of poison
damage.
LAURA: Seriously?!
LIAM: Okay, Delweth, you are up. You guys are
here. This is so stupid. There's a fish tank in
here you guys are looking at.
SAM: Draw a fish tank.
LIAM: Delweth, you're up, what would you like to
do?
MARY: I would like to try some acid against the
fish tank.
LIAM: Do what against the fish tank? Acid? Sure,
you throw it. You don't even have to do anything.
Your hand goes and a globule goes (splash) and
starts to sizzle down the sides of this glass.
Roll 1d6.
TRAVIS: That's the cube.
MARY: Three.
LIAM: Okay. It seems to be very thick. And now it
is Dren's turn.
MARY: If you want to be sneaky-sneaky, we can see
the corner of your--
ASHLY: Can I assassinate the fish tank? Is this
the top of the fight? I'm going to attack it with
my shortsword.
LIAM: Go for it.
ASHLY: Okay. It's 18.
LIAM: Sure, hit the shit out of that fish tank.
ASHLY: Is it a sneak attack?
LIAM: No.
ASHLY: Damn it. Okay. It is ten.
LIAM: Ten, okay. Devan, you may try to do
something.
LAURA: Okay. I'm going to cast Chromatic Orb.
SAM: With what verbal command?
LAURA: Well then, I'm going to use one of my
sorcerer points to do a subtle thing, because I
can do it without any verbal components.
LIAM: Good, well done.
LAURA: Okay, I'm going to cast Chromatic Orb as a
thunder attack.
LIAM: What about the hand motions, though? That's
what one of the other ones is. I see V, S, M next
to Chromatic Orb. Verbal... I forget what they
stand for. But one is-- components? One is verbal
and then one is doing this stuff.
LAURA: Can I try for a movement to wiggle my hands
out, because it's kind of loose?
LIAM: You can make a dexterity check at
disadvantage.
LAURA: Oh, shit, balls. What was the first one?
Was it a ten? 11.
LIAM: Nope.
LAURA: Come on!
LIAM: Tarvis, you're up.
LAURA: Wait, no, I still get to do something!
LIAM: Okay.
LAURA: I'm going to try and swim forward and start
kicking against the glass.
LIAM: You swim your way-- some light has shined
through once that door opened out there, although
you can't really tell why. The light's coming. You
swim towards light. You get over there. Tarvis,
you're up.
TRAVIS: I take the scimitar and try and hit the
non-moving, non-armed fish tank. Okay.
LIAM: Roll. Don't roll a one.
ASHLY: Did you?
TRAVIS: It's an eight.
LIAM: All right, you hit it, yeah.
TRAVIS: Yay! Seven.
LIAM: Okay. The glass goes (glass cracking). It
holds.
LAURA: Technically, did I have to waste a sorcerer
point for that, since I couldn't actually do the spell?
LIAM: No. Okay, Rat, you're up.
SAM: Did we all run down to the thing? I was
futzing with the art.
LIAM: You were. So you're there.
SAM: I'll use my movement to run into the room.
Can I get there?
LIAM: Okay. Actually nobody should have gotten
there, but it's okay.
MARY: It's all right, through the magic--
LIAM: It's all right, she's half-fucked anyway.
What would you like to do?
SAM: I'm in the room?
LIAM: No, you're not, because you were futzing
with the painting. So we'll say you were the last
one in.
SAM: Then I say: why is everyone in here? Oh!
LIAM: Okay, we're now back-- no we're not.
MARY: Oh shit.
LIAM: Make a constitution save.
TRAVIS: Take a big breath in. Everybody?
SAM: No, drowny girl.
LAURA: Ten.
LIAM: Ten is not going to do it. Three points of
poison damage.
SAM: She dead.
LAURA: Not yet.
LIAM: All right, now we're at the top. Delweth.
MARY: Right. Since Poison Spray won't do
anything, I'm going to take my rapier and stab it
into the biggest part of the crack, where the acid
is, and the crack meet.
LIAM: Roll to attack. I'm sure you'll hit it.
MARY: 13 plus whatever.
LIAM: That hits.
MARY: It hits? All right.
LAURA and ASHLY: It's a box.
LIAM: It's got a very low armor class.
MARY: Seven. Plus three. Ten.
LIAM: Okay, so you run up with your thin little
sword and go, "Ugh! Oh fuck this," and you turn it
around and go (impact) into the side of the glass
(glass cracking) and a little bit of water starts
spilling out near the bottom. Devan-- no, Dren--
MARY: And I don't get a bonus action to do
anything else?
LIAM: You do. Sure, if you have an idea, yeah.
SAM: Disengage.
MARY: I hide from the spray of water! Because it
could be poison. I back up three feet.
ASHLY: I'm going to attack it again with my
shortsword.
LIAM: Yes, yes.
ASHLY: I hit it. And I'm going to do one of these
guys. Nine.
LIAM: Okay. A piece breaks out and water starts
spilling out. It's very tall. Tarvis, it's your turn.
LAURA: Wait!
LIAM: Oh sorry, Devan's turn, Devan's turn.
LAURA: Can I try to get my hands free again?
LIAM: Yes. Make a dex save.
LAURA: At disadvantage. Come on! Five. Okay, I
kick at the crack. Can I at least kick at the crack?
LIAM: You spent your whole action going-- So you
get a bonus action.
LAURA: Sucks. I can't--
ASHLY: Can she swim to the hole and try to get a
breath?
MARY: Is there any air that's come out now that
the water's come down?
LAURA: It hasn't reached that spot yet.
TRAVIS: It's a cube, right?
LAURA: Oh! Wait! Okay, wait! Oh, this is stupid,
because I feel like I'm about to be free, but I
wouldn't know that, that's metagaming. Can I see
that there's a crack in it? All right. Then I'm
going to cast Misty Step and get out of the box.
It's a verbal, so I would use a sorcery point.
LIAM: Okay. There's a big (splash) as water slaps
together, and a drenched, coughing, pale-skinned,
veins going down her neck Devan appears on the
ground, between you and you.
ASHLY: Devan! Can I untie her, please?
TRAVIS: No. I turn towards the glass tank and I
hit it with the scimitar.
LIAM: Yeah, you also take your hilt and (glass
breaking).
TRAVIS: She's lying on the ground, right? The
water's hitting her?
LIAM: Yeah, all over her. Fish are hitting the
ground, flapping around on the ground.
TRAVIS: I walk over to her. I stand right over
her.
LIAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: I thought you'd been here before? You
didn't know that was going to happen?
LIAM: You've actually never been in this room.
LAURA: I've never been in this room.
MARY: You were in the hallway, though, before.
LAURA: Yeah. And I told you guys to look for a
wall sconce, and then you marched me down the
hallway.
MARY: Let's do it again.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MARY: All right. Anything else in this room?
LIAM: In this room?
MARY: Yeah.
LIAM: Have a look around if you'd like.
MARY: I'd like to look around the room.
LIAM: Perception check, please.
MARY: I'd like to roll a perception check, please.
I'll roll this die. It's a-- That
would be 18.
LIAM: Okay, you perception all the slowly dying
beautiful but poisonous fish in here and look
around, the room is empty except for this fucking
thing. You don't see anything else.
MARY: Right, there's nothing else, let's go.
ASHLY: Can I stealthily give Devan one of my
potions?
LIAM: Roll and I'll tell you if you can.
ASHLY: 14.
LIAM: Yes.
LAURA: Gulp, gulp, gulp.
LIAM: Oh, you mean, feed it to her.
ASHLY: Yeah.
LIAM: Oh yeah, sure.
TRAVIS: Does nobody notice this?
LIAM: So what happens is Dren crouches down and
slowly pours it in, and then when she feels like
someone's looked she goes (slaps) across the
face.
LAURA: Ow!
MARY: How much damage does she take from the
slap?
LIAM: Never again.
TRAVIS: Now you're getting the idea, Dren.
ASHLY: How much does she get back?
LIAM: Well, it's all on your character sheets. It
depends on which one you gave her. You guys have
one superior and two greater.
ASHLY: I give you greater.
LIAM: The big hitter is 8d4 plus eight. The
two smaller are 4d4--
LAURA: Should I roll or does she roll?
LIAM: Doesn't matter.
MARY: (singing) Every night in my dreams--
TRAVIS and MARY: (singing) I see you--
LAURA: That's great!
ASHLY: Yeah!
LIAM: I like the idea of this elf and this half
orc singing.
(laughter)
SAM: Why did we come in this room again?
MARY: We had to, to save her.
SAM: No, I mean the magic room. Why are we here?
There's no big jewel here. We're here for jewel.
LAURA: There's a door that opens if you do the
right things, and there's--
TRAVIS: You're not doing them.
LIAM: And Devan, you've never been in the room
you're in. But looking out the door of the room
you're in, you see, across the hall, a circular
"siggle."
MARY: "Siggle?"
LAURA: It's there!
TRAVIS: What's there?
LAURA: The room!
TRAVIS: The room?
LAURA: Jesus, Tarvis!
MARY: His first name isn't Jesus.
ASHLY: Oh, she needs to put her-- with the blood,
with the thing, on the thing!
TRAVIS: Oh, she doesn't need to do that. I
walk up and I cut her upper arm and get a bunch of
blood on my hand. And I walk over to the "siggle"
and place it on the--
LAURA: It's really a sigil, it's not actually a
"siggle."
TRAVIS: Well now you're making-- I'm confused.
LIAM: So you hold your hand there, and blood,
someone else's blood smears on. You wait, and you
wait, and that ain't doing shit.
ASHLY: I feel like we need to let her use
her hand.
MARY: I lift her up. How high up is it from the
floor?
LAURA: I really don't understand why you don't
want me to have my hands. What are you afraid I'm
going to do?
LIAM: Three feet.
MARY: Three feet. I lift her up, march her over, I
turn her around, I slit her hand, and I push her
up against it, hands still tied.
LIAM: Do you cast the spell?
LAURA: I don't think it works if I'm not free.
TRAVIS: Try.
LAURA: I'm trying. I can't get my hand on there
right.
MARY: I thought it was just blood and hands.
LAURA: Look, I can't get my hand on there right. I
can't twist it around.
ASHLY: She can't get her hand on there right.
TRAVIS: I walk up with one of the daggers and I
hold it right under her chin and I say try harder.
I push in a little. Try harder.
LAURA: (whispering) I'm trying real hard.
ASHLY: Guys, just for a second--
TRAVIS: Dren, shut up. Try harder.
SAM: Now would be a good time for a haiku.
LAURA: Can I have a haiku?
ASHLY: You can do it, my dear friend, Devan
Bluebutton. Please don't die now, please.
SAM: So inspiring.
LAURA: I feel inspired. I didn't know you thought
I was your friend, that's great!
ASHLY: Yeah.
LAURA: I'm trying. I'm trying.
LIAM: You can cast that cantrip. Okay, so it
takes a little bit of time, 20-30 seconds, held
up, hoisted in the air by an elf assassin, with
your hand bleeding out.
LAURA: Seriously, while this is happening, you
guys, I don't understand why you think I need to
think I have my hands tied.
TRAVIS: I don't understand why you're still
talking.
LAURA: You guys are the sneaky ones. I'm just here
to help. I'm just here to help!
LIAM: Click!
SAM: Hey!
MARY: See how well that worked? Patience is key,
right? Patience.
LAURA: Mm-hmm.
MARY: Door opens? What do we see?
LIAM: The wooden door opens outward, and you look
in and see a very well-lit room. A round room,
perfectly round. The walls are made up of curved
segments of dark, burnished metal. The walls go up
about 30 feet before curving in and up, very high.
It's almost like you're in the inside of a silo.
You guys cased this joint from the outside. There
is a bit of a tower on this side of it. This has
got to be that. Four of those golden orbs are
hanging and lighting up this room. You look up. It
goes very high. You can see down here and it gets
darker and darker the higher you go. You can't see
the peak. Across from where you entered, made out
of the same metal, is a pair of flat doors with
the same circle printed into the metal. Like a
cabinet, directly across.
TRAVIS: No furniture or anything in the room?
LIAM: Nothing in here.
TRAVIS: What is the floor made of?
LIAM: The floor is also metal. In the center of
the room is a smaller circle that's about a foot
and a half wide, and it's got a spiraling out
flower shape.
TRAVIS: Well, we found your room. What happens in
here? I don't see a gem.
LAURA: I don't see anything. I'm facing the wrong
direction.
MARY: I turn you around.
LIAM: There's the room that she took you to. This
is room where your grandmother showed you how to
create illusions and how to pull moisture from the
air to create shards of ice and use them.
LAURA: Yep.
SAM: Sounds like a pretty special woman. I think
you should be grateful to have a grandmother like her.
LAURA: (laughs) I think she would like you a lot.
SAM: Family is very important.
MARY: So what do we do?
LAURA: I don't know. There's another rat over
there.
MARY: What's in this room? What's in the center of
the room? What is it? That circular, beautiful,
spiraling outward, floral thing?
LAURA: I don't know.
MARY: You never used it?
TRAVIS: I'd like to insight check her. Does she
know?
LIAM: Roll for insight.
TRAVIS: 18.
LIAM: I'm going to call it for her. She appears
flustered and a bit of a doofus, but she seems
like she's telling the truth.
SAM: The circle in the middle of the room is a
foot and a half wide? How big was the brass
column?
LIAM: A foot and a half wide
MARY: (yelling) What? (whispering) Go investigate
it.
SAM: I'm going to go take a look at that without
standing on top of it or touching the flowery stuff.
LAURA: While he's doing that, can I message Dren?
LIAM: Sure, hold that thought.
SAM: 14. Not too great.
LIAM: Are you willing to touch it at all?
SAM: Oh boy.
(laughter)
SAM: No, looking for any signs that it could open
or be a door. Hinges.
LIAM: It's not like an etching, like that circular
sigil of a shrew over there. It does seem to be
made out of more than one piece. It's not a
decoration, but that's all you can tell.
MARY: What do you see?
SAM: There's something with this circle.
Something's under it. I don't know what, though.
LIAM: What's your formation in here, by the way?
TRAVIS: He's at the circle in the middle.
MARY: I'm behind Devan, still holding onto the
rope and my rapier. Oh, hello.
LIAM: Who's where?
LAURA: We're in the doorway, right?
MARY: We just took a few steps in.
TRAVIS: I'm halfway from Obby to the door.
LIAM: Who's got the gambling addict?
MARY: I do. She's in front of me.
LIAM: Where are you, Dren?
ASHLY: I think I'm just behind.
LIAM: Here?
ASHLY: Yeah.
MARY: Want to Mage Hand it? Want me to touch it?
What do you want? Want me to push down on it, see
what it can do?
SAM: Well if it's a monster, that would be bad.
LAURA: I want to message Dren, and say, I think
the jewel is in the cabinet on the other side of
the room.
ASHLY: It's in the other room. It's in the
cabinet?
LAURA: On the other side of the room. Just
remember--
LIAM: The cabinet doors are right here.
LAURA: These guys are tough. I think worst case
scenario, we should get it and go.
ASHLY: How are we going to get past them?
LAURA: I don't even know!
ASHLY: We need to get you down first.
LAURA: Loosen the ropes. See if you can loosen my
ropes.
ASHLY: I'm going to do a stealth. Try to do a
sleight of hand, is that what that was, to loosen
her ropes?
LIAM: Dexterity check.
ASHLY: Dexterity?
TRAVIS: You know that she is holding onto the
ropes.
MARY: Yeah.
LIAM: But you can still make a sleight of hand
check.
MARY: Give it a shot.
LIAM: Oh, sleight of hand, yes, sleight of hand.
ASHLY: Sleight of hand?
LAURA: While she's holding it? Jeez.
ASHLY: Why not! I'm brazen.
LIAM: At disadvantage.
ASHLY: At disadvantage?
LAURA: Oh, that was a good one. So roll it again.
LIAM: Got to roll it again.
LAURA: And take the lower. They were the same!
ASHLY: Were they?
LAURA: Yeah! They were both 16.
ASHLY: I thought one of them was six.
LAURA: No no no no, they were both 16.
ASHLY: They were both 16. Okay, so then 19.
LIAM: Okay. I'm going to say, Delweth, you were
staring up, trying to assess what was happening up top.
MARY: The shiny ceiling?
LIAM: You get her hands free.
ASHLY: Yes.
LIAM: At that moment, all of you hear the sound of
some sort of clank, very high, high above you. And
behind you, Dren, all of you, but you especially,
hear (metal slamming).
MARY: Oh, balls.
LIAM: And you look over your shoulder, and metal
barriers, or doors, or something, have suddenly
slammed shut. There's a thin seam between the two.
You guys are in here. And that's when you hear,
not in your ears, at the base of your skull,
inside your skull, "Not supposed to be here."
SAM: Is that your grandmother?
LAURA: If it is, her voice has changed.
LIAM: "Dogs, dogs, dogs."
LAURA: Dogs! Dogs! Shit!
LIAM: And then you hear, way high, at the apex of
this tower, a chime. "Ding."
LAURA: No!
ASHLY: Guys?
LIAM: (multiple fwooshing sounds)
TRAVIS: Five?
LIAM: Puffs of sparkling white and purple smoke
(fwoosh) to one side, to the other side, around
you suddenly. You're looking at four smoking,
misty, almost-hairless dogs. Angry looking,
slobbering. Three of a certain size, one much
larger, staring at you with glassy, milky white
eyes. It's big, it's muscular, it's ropey. And
they bare their teeth.
LAURA: I cast Minor Illusion.
SAM: Oh boy.
LAURA: Of my grandmother.
MARY: Oh!
LIAM: Okay.
LAURA: In front of me.
LIAM: Okay. Roll for initiative, everybody.
ASHLY: 13.
LIAM: Hold that thought, everybody. 13 is what you
rolled, Dren? Okay.
MARY: I did as well, 13.
LIAM: Okay.
TRAVIS: 16.
LIAM: 16, okay.
SAM: Obby rolls ten.
(snickers)
MARY: Do you know why?
LIAM: Roll initiative for me, too, Devan.
LAURA: 18.
LIAM: 18. All right. Then you are the first one
to go. Ooh, doo-loo-loo-loo! Okay.
SAM: Dogs all rolled 20s.
LAURA: (laughs)
LIAM: The idea flashes into your mind what to do.
You start to move your hands. The dogs lunge in on
all of you. The first one-- Oh hey, this music's too
chill.
TRAVIS: (laughs) I need more tension!
(music intensifies)
LAURA: There is it!
LIAM: This dog comes running toward you, and bites
into your arm, maybe?
LAURA: My arm?
SAM: Who, who's that, who's biting?
LIAM: What's your AC?
LAURA: 11.
LIAM: 11? Yes. Its teeth sink into your arm as you
start to cast and you take, oh, just two points of
damage. And the spell is gone.
LAURA: What spell? I didn't get to cast anything.
MARY: You did. The Minor Illusion.
LIAM: Yeah, I'm going to say it was so close. This
is within six seconds of each other. That's gone.
This dog rushes, does the same thing for you,
Obby. What's your armor class?
SAM: 16.
LIAM: You feel teeth sink into your thigh, and you
take five points of piercing damage. This dog goes
(whoosh noise) and is gone. (whoosh noise) He is
right behind you, Delweth, and what's your armor class?
MARY: 14.
LIAM: You feel teeth sink into your gut, on the
side. You take three points of piercing damage, and
the big one (snarling noise) lunges in to attack
you, Tarvis, and you feel teeth sink into the back
of your calf and take five hit points in piercing
damage. Tears away, and you feel part of your calf
come away.
TRAVIS: Aw shit.
LIAM: Devan, you may try something else.
LAURA: Try that again?
LIAM: Sure.
LAURA: I'm going to try Minor Illusion. And make
it look like my grandma now behind me. In front of me.
LIAM: I don't know if your grandmother qualifies
as an object.
LAURA: Oh, it has to be an object?
LIAM: Object within range.
SAM: Minor Illusion?
LAURA: A sound or an image of an object. You're
right, okay. All right.
LIAM: I'll let you do something else.
LAURA: All right, then I'm going to cast Chromatic
Orb.
LIAM: Okay, all right. Where's it going?
LAURA: Wait!
LIAM: This is your second level one, right?
LAURA: Yes. Yes, I'm going to cast Chromatic Orb
at the dog that's biting me.
LIAM: Yeah, yeah.
LAURA: And I'm going to do--
LIAM: Make a ranged spell attack.
LAURA: Oh, so I'm going to do it at the big dog
attacking Tarvis then.
LIAM: Okay, go for it.
LAURA: And I'm going to do it as a thunder
attack.
LIAM: Okay.
LAURA: That probably doesn't hit though. What's my
spell?
LIAM: Oh, man, it's on your sheet. On page number
two, it is plus six on ranged attacks.
LAURA: Oh, okay. So that's what I rolled. Ten.
LIAM: Ten?
LAURA: Oh. Nine.
LIAM: Okay. A ball of crackling energy goes
(whoosh noise) misses the dog entirely, goes
(impact noise) ricochets like a pinball off the
side of the wall and arcs up, and then (impact
noise) diffuses high up in the air. You can still
move if you want.
LAURA: All right, I'm going to back up behind--
who's next to me? Delweth?
LIAM: Delweth, yeah.
LAURA: I'm going to stand behind Delweth.
LIAM: Where you going to go? Over here?
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: You're going to walk there? Or run there?
LAURA: I'm going to dart under her legs.
LIAM: Dart under her legs? Okay, you start to move
under. The dog behind you sees you go, and--
what's your armor class?
LAURA: 11.
LIAM: 11. Yeah, bites into your back.
LAURA: Ow!
LIAM: And you feel part of your robes rip away,
and you take five points of piercing damage and you
get over here.
LAURA: Yikes! All right, I want to like stay under
her legs, basically.
LIAM: Okay. Oh, so you're sharing the space with
her?
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: Okay. Okay, and now it is Tarvis' turn, what
would you like to do?
TRAVIS: I see we have three daggers. Does that mean we
can do like the famous rogue, Vax, and dagger
dagger dagger?
MARY: No, that's what I asked him when we got
here.
LIAM: You need boots of haste and the feat Dual
Wielding to do that.
TRAVIS: I take my scimitar with its one trusty hit
today.
LIAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: And I swing at White Fang there.
LIAM: Okay, all right, roll to hit.
TRAVIS: Natural 20. Hey, finally! Which means I
also get the savage attack crit.
LIAM: Yes, it does.
SAM: Savage attack?
MARY: Savage.
TRAVIS: That's just savage. That's a three plus
three is six. Which means I get an extra damage
die, which is a four, for a whopping ten.
SAM: Is it near a thing, do you get a sneaky,
sneaky? You get a sneaky?
LIAM: Yes.
TRAVIS: I do?
LIAM: Yeah, from Obby. I mean, this fixes that.
TRAVIS: 2d6. So 18.
LIAM: 18? You pull out the blade, the curved
blade, and it sort of sings as you spin it in the air,
and bring it down in a slice, and it cuts into the
ribs of this dog. And the dog yelps, loud, and
sort of buckles down for a bit. And has murder in
its mouth and its blind eyes. What was the total
on that?
TRAVIS: 18.
LIAM: 18.
LAURA: Its blind eyes? It's blind?
LIAM: Looks like it.
LAURA: Oh.
LIAM: All right, now it is Dren's turn.
ASHLY: I can like call to Devan as like a thing,
right?
LIAM: You can do that, plus your attack roll.
ASHLY: Okay. Do you know anything about this sigil
in the middle? Is it open?
LIAM: Got to be six seconds of dialogue, though.
LAURA: I don't know anything about it.
ASHLY: Okay, I'm going to fight then. Let's see,
is that a dog right next to me?
SAM: They're all dogs.
ASHLY: So that guy is a dog? Okay, okay. So no
sneak attack for Dren for that guy, he knows I'm there?
LIAM: You do have sneak attack on this one.
ASHLY: But also potentially the big guy?
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: If you throw something, yeah.
ASHLY: If I do a crossbow?
LIAM: Or use your crossbow, sure.
ASHLY: I guess I might as well--
LIAM: Six more seconds to decide it.
ASHLY: I'm going to attack the guy right next to
me actually.
LIAM: Okay, go for it.
ASHLY: Okay. With my shortsword. 15?
LIAM: Ah, yeah, that hits.
ASHLY: Okay. And is that sneak attack?
LIAM: Ah, yes it is. Because of the crowd here.
ASHLY: So that's one, and then eight.
LAURA: That's good.
LIAM: Eight? Okay.
ASHLY: To the dog adjacent to me.
LAURA: Roll plus four. You didn't add that four.
ASHLY: Oh! Plus four.
LIAM: 14?
LAURA: So it's 12 total.
LIAM: Math in my head. All right, great, and that
was which weapon? Your shortsword?
ASHLY: My shortsword.
LIAM: Okay. You squat down, almost do a little
ballerina split, and then stick your sword up into
its gut from underneath. And the dog goes (yelp of
pain), underneath, and snarls through. And now
we're on to-
ASHLY: Do I get a bonus action?
LIAM: Yes, you do.
ASHLY: Okay. I'm going to dash behind Tarvis? Can
I make it there?
LIAM: You're going to go here?
ASHLY: Yeah. Can I get to the other side of him?
No?
LIAM: You can do that. You're tiny, too. Yeah, you
can get through-- where do you want to go, here?
ASHLY: Yeah.
LIAM: Yeah. I'll say you can do that.
ASHLY: Okay.
LIAM: Because of how small you are and how big he
is.
ASHLY: Okay.
LIAM: Okay. So you start to run and this dog that
you stabbed sees you running, sees your back, and
lunges at it. But you're too quick, and it goes
(noise of jaws snapping shut) as you slide
underneath Tarvis' legs.
ASHLY: Nice. Yes.
LIAM: Pop out here at the end of your turn.
Delweth, you are up.
MARY: I'm going to try Poison Spray on White Fang.
LIAM: All right.
MARY: What do I do, I roll--?
LIAM: Oh, I do it. What's your spell DC? It's the
numbers near the top of your--
MARY: 13.
LIAM: Fails.
TRAVIS: Nice!
MARY: All right, so what do I do?
LIAM: 1d12.
MARY: 1d12. Which one's a d12?
TRAVIS: This guy.
SAM: Trusty d12.
MARY: Two.
LIAM: Two? Okay.
MARY: Plus nothing.
LIAM: Plus nothing. But that noxious odor--
MARY: Sneak attack? Sneak attack?
LIAM: No sneak attack. But it floats into this old
blind bastard's face and goes (choking and
snarling) and it's blind, but it looks in your
direction and snarls. Did you want to do anything else?
MARY: I would like to disengage and go hide
behind--
TRAVIS: Hide behind Devan?
MARY: I would like to go behind White Fang.
LIAM: You're going over this way?
MARY: Yep.
LIAM: All right, as you go this dog, who's biting
people's backs today sees you go, and a little tip
to all you newer players--
TRAVIS: She disengaged, though, right?
LIAM: Oh, you disengaged, you're right.
MARY: Disengage, motherfucka!
LIAM: Yeah, you go (blip noises). Great, thank
you.
LAURA: No, but I was hiding!
LIAM: Thank you, thank you for that. And now we
are on to Obby the Rat.
SAM: I attack the big dog with a dagger.
LIAM: Yeah.
SAM: I get him. It's a 22.
LIAM: That hits. And you have sneak attack damage
on this.
SAM: Three.
LIAM: I'm even going to say you have advantage
on-- well you already hit, though, right?
SAM: Eight. Plus nine. 17.
LIAM: Oh my god. You come in low with your knife
and stick it in right under one of its legs and
then slide all the way down the length of its
body. And you see one noodle of intestine go
(splurting noise) out the side of it.
TRAVIS: Yes!
LIAM: Want to do anything else?
ASHLY: It's still alive?
SAM: I say to it, do you know why they call me
Obby the Rat? Because Obby is actually short for
Obenthal. It's a nickname. And then I'm using my
bonus action.
I will use sleight of hand to jam my fucking
crowbar, that I recovered from the dude, into the
floor to try to open the circle on the floor.
LIAM: Make a dexterity check.
SAM: 20.
LIAM: It glances off of this thing. It wasn't a
natural 20, right?
SAM: No, it was a 13 plus a seven.
LIAM: It glances off of it. That is the time when,
in the back of your brain, you hear (gurgling noises).
LAURA: Oh shit.
LIAM: Delweth. You, freaking out, look up and see
a bulbous, green--
LAURA: Oh god, we're going to die.
ASHLY: Ah shit.
LIAM: Slowly down out of the tower, in a fucking
weird sight. I don't know what the fuck this is.
Something coming down.
LAURA: What?
MARY: We're are all going to die. There's
something coming from the ceiling!
LIAM: (gurgling noises)
MARY: And it--
SAM: It's Sylvia Plath.
MARY: Sylvia Plath.
LIAM: And give me one moment please.
ASHLY: I almost said something really mean.
SAM: About Sylvia Plath? What did she ever do to
you?
ASHLY: She'll kill herself, so it's fine.
(groans)
ASHLY: (singing) Sorry, everybody at home. I'm
Ashly Burch and that's all for today.
MARY: Haiku that. We need a haiku for that.
(laughter)
LIAM: Delweth, I need you to make a constitution
save right now.
MARY: Oh, balls. All right, 18.
LIAM: Okay, you guys see a ray of blackish-gray
light go (thrumming sound) down from the ceiling
and cut along the floor right past you. But you
slide back against the wall and it misses you just
in time. And now it is time for the dogs.
ASHLY: Oh, not the dogs.
LIAM: So this one turns towards Devan and snaps
angrily. But Devan, scared to death, freaks out
and does this and it misses because of it.
(laughter)
MARY: With grace and style.
(screaming)
LIAM: What's your armor class, Dren?
ASHLY: It is 14.
LIAM: I'm so sorry, but you take five points of
piercing damage as the teeth sink into the bottom
of your sword arm. Obby, this dog lunges right at
you and you feel it get up under your neck and
bite right here at your shoulder. And you take
five points of piercing damage--
SAM: Better than 16?
LIAM: That's your armor class?
SAM: Yes.
LIAM: I take it back. You push its head up and
it's going (biting sounds) and you shove it off.
It rolled a 15. Thank you for that. I didn't
remember that your armor class was so high. And
this one rushes at our half-orc commander, but
it's so fucked up and so sad now, it blindly
misses you. And now it is Devan's turn.
LAURA: Can I run around the room?
(laughing)
LAURA: I'm going to run and try to get to the
other side of the room with the doors.
LIAM: Which way do you want to go? This way? You
can scoot under her legs or--
LAURA: Yeah, I'll scoot under Delweth's
legs.
LIAM: I'm going to do this one time. I'm going to
remind you that both of these dogs get an
opportunity attack. This is the last time I'm
going to remind any of you motherfuckers.
LAURA: I know that they will, but I don't really
have another option here. If I move, can I make it
across to the doors?
LIAM: What's your movement?
LAURA: 25.
LIAM: You want to go straight across?
LAURA: I don't know.
(laughter)
LIAM: No, you won't make it all the way across.
I'd say you'd make it to about there or there.
LAURA: Then I'm going to-- ugh! Burning Hands
everything in a 15-foot cone of me.
LIAM: I'll say you're here, so you could get these
two and I'll say you won't get Tarvis.
LAURA: Okay.
SAM: Lucky.
LAURA: So they must make a dexterity saving
throw.
TRAVIS: (singing) Living on a prayer!
LIAM: What's your spell DC?
LAURA: I really don't have it written anywhere on
these sheets.
LIAM: I have it. It's 14.
MARY: All the way on the right.
LAURA: I have the page! It's a 14! I really have
only been looking at these three.
LIAM: Okay, little guy makes his save, big guy
does not, so what's your damage?
LAURA: Okie dokie, here we go.
LIAM: She puts her thumbs together and fans her
fingers out, pointing at these dogs.
LAURA: Ooh, 13!
LIAM: And you have just Sigourney Weavered them,
fire spraying from your hands.
LAURA: Get away from me, you bitches!
LIAM: Sets this dog completely on fire, it screams
so pitifully and falls dead, charred.
LAURA: (screaming) Tarvis! Tarvis!
LIAM: What was the total damage? Was it 14?
LAURA: 13.
LIAM: 13. Okay. All right. And this one is singed
and blackened and one eye is burned away and it
looks bad.
MARY: You killed White Fang?
LIAM: And now it is Tarvis' turn.
LAURA: Oh, but can I try to-- no.
LIAM: You can do it if you want to try to do it.
LAURA: Will I get hit if I move now? There's a
little one next to me? I can't see what's next to me.
LIAM: There is one dog next to you.
LAURA: I'm going to run away from it. I'm going to
run under Gelweth's legs.
LIAM: This way or this way?
LAURA: Yeah. Oh, under Gelweth's legs. Delweth's
legs. I don't know why I keep calling her Gelweth,
I'm sorry. It's a good name, Gelweth is a great
name too.
MARY: Gelweth's great. I love it.
LIAM: So Delvy runs, you feel teeth sink into the
back of your neck and pull hair and flesh away
from the back of your neck for five hit points of
piercing damage. You still alive?
LAURA: Yeah!
LIAM: You run one, two. I'm going to say you're
there. Now it is Tarvis' turn.
TRAVIS: Can I turn to the little doggie that is
engaged with Obby?
LIAM: Yes.
SAM: Obby the Rat.
TRAVIS: And go a little scimitar on his punk ass.
LIAM: (blade slicing)
SAM: I do not like dogs or number ones.
LIAM: Again?
LAURA: I didn't get to take a potion as my bonus
action.
LIAM: All right, sure. Which one?
LAURA: Just the greater.
LIAM: So you have got one greater left and one
superior left?
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: Okay, Tarvis. In a rush of friendship and
loyalty to your good friend, you do that move that
you always finish fights with. You bring it up and
you bring it down in a circle and go (grunt) and
there's so much blood on your hand that you go
(grunt) and the blade flies out of your hand
across the room and clatters down.
TRAVIS: Clang-a-lang-lang-lang-lang.
ASHLY: Oh no!
TRAVIS: Don't worry, it's all part of the plan.
LIAM: Would you like to move at all?
TRAVIS: I would like to disengage and move to
where Dren is.
LIAM: To Dren? On the other side of Dren?
TRAVIS: Yeah, behind Dren.
LIAM: Ooh, you're dead. Here?
TRAVIS: Yep.
LIAM: Okay, and now we're onto Delweth. All these
fucking 'D' names.
MARY: 'D' names, so many 'D' names. How many dogs
are left?
LIAM: Three.
MARY: I want to cast Sleep on them.
LIAM: Go for it.
LAURA: Ooh, nice. You can cast it on all of them?
MARY: Yeah, I think. The spell sends creatures
into a magical slumber, roll 5d8, right?
TRAVIS: 5d8?
MARY: Yeah, creatures within 20 feet of a point
you choose--
LIAM: It's everybody within a 20-foot area.
MARY: Everybody, or--
LIAM: Everybody.
MARY: I can't be specific as to who, what, and the
where now?
TRAVIS: Big ass slumber party.
SAM: What are you casting?
MARY: Sleep, I was going to cast Sleep.
LIAM: Now, you can slap whoever you want awake
afterwards. But it's a 20-foot area.
SAM: You can also aim it straight up in the air.
MARY: I can. All right, I'm going to aim it
straight up at that thing. I don't know what that
is. I can't do a perception check on what the fuck
that is? All right, I'm going to cast Sleep on
that thing.
LIAM: Okay, roll the 5d8.
MARY: 22.
LIAM: 22?
MARY: The thing, straight up.
LIAM: Okay, so you cast and you see the barest
shimmer of starlight between you and it, and it
surrounds it. Nothing happens.
MARY: Is that a fucking beholder?
LAURA: No, it's not a beholder. Is it a beholder?
It looks like a beholder. A little beeby
beholder.
MARY: You said there was another set of doors?
LIAM: Yeah, sort of. Metallic doors. You want to
go over there?
MARY: Yep!
LIAM: What's your movement?
MARY: 35.
SAM: The door is for more monsters to come out.
LIAM: All right, you're there. Obby, what do you
want to do?
SAM: Wait, is the White Fang gone? Obby the Rat
would like to kill the dog in front of me.
LIAM: Okay, fuck yeah. This one?
SAM: The one on the sigil.
LIAM: Go for it.
SAM: Natural 20.
(cheering)
SAM: That's a lot of them. With the handaxe, what
is that, 1d6 plus two. Seven. And then--
TRAVIS: Roll another one, right?
SAM: Wait, is there sneak attack?
LAURA: No, there's nothing around it.
LIAM: Yep, nope.
SAM: So just seven, wait--
TRAVIS: Roll another six.
SAM: Ooh, another six. So wait, so five and five
plus two?
TRAVIS: Each time.
SAM: Each time plus two? 14.
LIAM: 14? Okay, and what weapon are you using for
that?
SAM: Handaxe.
LIAM: Handaxe, okay. You sink this axe right down
into its neck. And you feel cutting into the bone
of the thing, and it screams. The dog screams, but
it writhes and lashes in anger, in a fit. It is
still moving.
SAM: I will try one more time to open door on
floor.
LIAM: That's more than a bonus action, I think.
SAM: Okay, I will not do that. Instead, I will
say, Tarvis, do you need potion?
TRAVIS: Nope.
SAM: And I'll disengage and back away from the dog
then.
LIAM: Okay, you're going this way?
SAM: Yeah, as far as I can.
LIAM: (gurgling)
LAURA: Oh no, it's coming down!
ASHLY: Wait, I didn't get to go. Should I have
gone?
LIAM: You didn't go?
ASHLY: I did not go.
LIAM: Go for it.
ASHLY: Do I have sneak attack on any of these
dudes?
LIAM: Nope.
ASHLY: I don't?
ASHLY: Son of a-- Let's see. I'll attack--
LIAM: You know what it is? It's the 'D' names.
I've like scrawled everything so it's like
(gibberish).
ASHLY: I'm going to attack the dude that Obby the
Rat just attacked?
LIAM: This one? Sure.
ASHLY: Yes.
LIAM: Okay, what are you using?
ASHLY: My crossbow?
LIAM: You can use a crossbow. Sure.
ASHLY: It's not as strong as my shortsword though.
There's a dog right next to me, huh.
LIAM: Right behind you, yeah.
ASHLY: Can I move towards that doggy?
LIAM: This one?
LAURA: He'll get an attack of opportunity on you,
the one next to you, if you move away from it.
ASHLY: That's right.
SAM: Unless you disengage.
LAURA: That's your bonus action.
ASHLY: After I attack? I can do it first? Can I
disengage first?
LIAM: Yeah.
ASHLY: And move next to-- is it Alby over there? On
the side?
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: To Alby? Obby is over here.
SAM: Pronounced Obby.
ASHLY: Sorry!
LIAM: You can get that far. You bolt over there,
run towards the wall, you whip around and turn
with your crossbow?
ASHLY: Yes!
LIAM: You press your back into the wall and-- this
one?
ASHLY: Yeah, guy in the middle.
LIAM: Okay, roll the attack.
SAM: Short for Obenthal.
MARY: Or just Oben.
ASHLY: 23.
LIAM: That hits, roll to hit. Roll for damage.
ASHLY: But no sneak attack. Just normie style.
Seven!
LIAM: Seven total?
ASHLY: Yes.
LIAM: Okay, the bolt sinks right into the eye of
the thing (death rattling).
(cheering)
SAM: Thank you, Dren.
ASHLY: You're welcome, Alby.
LIAM: (gargling) You're getting a better look at
it. It is like some sort of green, scaly ball with
a big fat eyeball out of it with four little
stalks--
LAURA: It is a baby beholder!
LIAM: And one of the stalks hangs like dead, limp,
with a bandage around the eye. But three of them
are going like (whooshing).
LAURA: Aw, little buddy got hurt.
ASHLY: (singing) Beholder babies!
LIAM: In fact, he turns one of his eyes towards
you, Devan--
TRAVIS: Towards Devan!
LAURA: Me?
LIAM: Devan, make a--
SAM: Death saving throw.
LIAM: Make a constitution save.
LAURA: 23!
LIAM: Okay, you feel the ray goes (buzzing) right
down onto you, you're looking right at it, and
your whole body stiffens. (panting) And you shake
it away. You're okay.
LAURA: I'm okay.
LIAM: Now we're onto "Dogs, dogs, dogs, dogs."
This one sees you, Dren, lunges in. Totally bites
your face! Eight points.
ASHLY: Ah! All right.
LIAM: This one goes for the-- you know what? (two
puff noises)
LAURA: Come on!
LIAM: Totally bites your face for five points of
piercing damage. And when I say face, I meant it,
it took a piece of your cheek and ear away.
LAURA: Why are you being a dick?
SAM: Mostly skull at this point.
LIAM: Now it is Devan's turn.
MARY: Come on, Dev.
LIAM: Hot blood trailing down your--
SAM: Pop that potion.
LAURA: I'm going to Burning Hands him because that
seemed to work so well before.
LIAM: Okay. All right, he takes the full blast.
The dog put all its dog concentration on bamfing
out of one place right here and as soon as it got
here, it bit you and it went, "Surprise motherfucker!"
(whooshing)
LAURA: Ten!
LIAM: All right. There is a dead, charred dog.
(cheering)
LAURA: (panting) And I'm going to run forward
toward the doors! And while I'm running, I'm going
to bust out my other-- oh wait, if I get to the
door can I bonus action it?
LIAM: No.
LAURA: I'm going to take another potion!
LIAM: Gurgle, gurgle, gurgle, gurgle. All right,
Tarvis, you are up.
TRAVIS: With my 30 speed, can I go to the last
D-O-G?
LIAM: Yep.
TRAVIS: And I will take my whip!
MARY: What! Take your whip?
TRAVIS: (whipping sound)
(laughter)
TRAVIS: (shouting) What the fuck!
(shouting)
LIAM: You're so angry--
TRAVIS: Each one of those has been with a
different dice.
LIAM: You're furious at how this night is going,
this night is fucked, and it's all because of
this one. You come over, full of anger, and you're
going to take it out on this dog. And you go
(whooshing). Dog, you feel a cut up your own eye.
Two points of slashing damage.
ASHLY: Why is he our leader?
(laughter)
LIAM: Dren, you're up!
ASHLY: Okay! I'm going to, first things first,
take a potion.
MARY: Dren just went!
LIAM: I missed her.
SAM: We all missed her, really.
MARY: We missed her so much.
ASHLY: Thanks, guys. 11?
LAURA: Ooh, nice. Plus four.
ASHLY: Plus four's 15!
LIAM: For your hit points? Okay.
ASHLY: Yeah. All right. Back of the net! Okay, so
now, I'm going to fuck up that dog right next to me.
LIAM: Yeah.
ASHLY: So that is a 20.
LIAM: Yeah, that hits.
ASHLY: It's not a sneak attack probably, right?
LIAM: It is a sneak attack.
ASHLY: Oh, it is?
LIAM: Because Tarvis is right here.
ASHLY: Aw shit, son. All right, that's a nine.
LIAM: Here comes the general!
ASHLY: So that's nine. 19!
LIAM: Which weapon did you use?
ASHLY: Shortsword.
LIAM: Shortsword? Okay, you feel bad for your
higher-up here, and as conflicted as you are in
the situation, as as many things are going on, you
still trained a long time; you are Clasp. You
take your blade, and you bring it up, and you
swing it, and you're so short you push up, and
it's the smallest dog in the group, and you spear
it like a shish kabob. And blood and guts spills
down over your hands, and it slumps down to the
ground.
SAM: Has Dren killed everyone tonight?
TRAVIS: Nice job, Dren.
LAURA: I killed two things. Halflings.
ASHLY: Halflings. Woop woop.
LIAM: (gurgling)
ASHLY: Oh right, that guy.
MARY: I turn around and I look at the doors. And I
use Mage Hand to try and open them.
LIAM: The hand pries and walks around like a
little spider, pulls and pulls, and it's the
saddest little thing, and it turns around and
goes.
MARY: I'm useless. Is that my action?
LIAM: Yep.
MARY: Really?
LIAM: It still exists. Your hand is still there.
LAURA: Ooh, you could bitch-slap the baby
beholder.
MARY: All right, I'm going to bitch-slap the
little beholder.
LIAM: Your hand starts floating in that direction,
I'll say.
MARY: I'll take Devan and put her right in front
of me.
LIAM: Nah.
MARY: She's right next to me.
LIAM: Yeah, but you did some stuff already. You
already cast a spell.
MARY: Then I'm going to hide behind Devan. That's
my bonus action.
LAURA: You can't, I'm a halfling. You can't hide
behind me.
LIAM: You know what you do? You kick the ground in
anger and go, "Aww." And now it is--
MARY: I can't go behind Devan?
LIAM: Nope, she's pressed against the wall. She's
right up against the wall. You'll get yours. Obby,
you're up.
SAM: Obby the Rat moves to center of room, says
thank you to Dren for killing all dogs.
ASHLY: Welcome.
SAM: I give haiku to Dren. I say: I'm Obby the
Rat, you know why they call me that? 'Cause I hate
haiku.
ASHLY: That was a really good haiku.
LIAM: You didn't even have to rhyme, but you still
did.
SAM: Shit. Okay, I look down.
LIAM: You called that out as you ran to the center
of the room.
SAM: I look down real quick. Do I see any
imperfections, anything in the floor, anything
that I can--?
LIAM: At this moment you have the time to go, "Oh,
fuck," and that's what you accomplish.
SAM: In that case, I look straight up and I throw
a dagger.
LIAM: Go for it. Roll to attack.
SAM: 17 plus seven.
MARY: Hell yeah!
SAM: 24.
LIAM: The dagger goes (whooshing, impact) and you
hear (gurgling). Roll for damage.
SAM: Eight.
LIAM: All right. A little bit of ichor splatters
back down on your face as you look up.
SAM: Not the worst thing that's been on my face
today.
LIAM: Okay. It rotates in space and looks down at
you, Obby. And please make a wisdom saving throw.
SAM: Wisdom, not my strength.
ASHLY: This is going to be rough for me.
SAM: Five.
LIAM: Five? A ray shoots straight down into your
eyes, and you go slack. And think of colors.
And that is where you're at. And now it is time
for--
TRAVIS: What is he? Is he stupid? Charmed?
LIAM: And now it is Devan's turn.
LAURA: Okay. Can I turn around? Do I see the sigil
on the doors?
LIAM: You do.
LAURA: I want to open my hand and stick it on
there.
LIAM: You can. So far it's taken about 20 to 30
seconds to do that, and a round is six seconds.
LAURA: Shit. Okay. I'm going to try casting--
damn. Chromatic Orb, man, that's my longest range
attack.
LIAM: That's your last--?
LAURA: No, I've got two more--
LIAM: Two more?
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: Okay.
LAURA: So I've got one more.
LIAM: All right, make a ranged attack.
LAURA: Oh wait, did I forget to mark off a Burning
Hands?
MARY: You did two.
LIAM: You did two Burning Hands.
LAURA: I did two Burning Hands? Okay. And I did
another Chromatic Orb. So yes, this is my last
first level. Okay, yeah.
LIAM: So ranged attack with a plus six on your
roll.
LAURA: Okay. 24.
LIAM: What kind was it?
LAURA: I really want to do a thunder attack on
somebody.
LIAM: Sure.
LAURA: Thunder attack.
LIAM: Go for it, man, that sounds pretty good.
LAURA: Yeah. So that's 3d8, man.
LIAM: You hit, yeah.
LAURA: 24, man. No, wait, I did my math wrong. 22,
man.
LIAM: 22? Okay. This crackling ball with little
arcs of light spitting out of it flies up, hits
the thing. (explosion) The thing spins out of
kilter, down, lower-- shite. Aw shite. I don't
have the right boxes. I'm going to say he's right
there.
MARY: Precariously hovering in space.
LIAM: It spins end over end and starts to right
himself and hover right about there. Nice.
LAURA: And then I'm going to hide behind Delweth.
LIAM: Okay, okay. Yes, you can do that. Roll for
stealth.
LAURA: Because I'm smaller.
MARY: Oh, yeah. I understand.
SAM: Is his spell on me concentration?
LAURA: 17.
LIAM: Okay. I heard that question, and I'm
ignoring it. Tarvis, it is your turn.
TRAVIS: I'm so frustrated with how this night is
going. I'm questioning my own leadership. And I
follow my friend Obby's lead and I throw a dagger
at the mini beholder.
SAM: Hits you in the face.
MARY: And you die.
TRAVIS: I go closer if I have to.
LIAM: You could've done it, but it would've been
at disadvantage. Now I'll say it is not.
TRAVIS: I'll even go right up against the wall, so
I can look in the direction of other people.
LIAM: That's as close as you can get. Chuck it,
baby.
TRAVIS: It's a ten! I am impotent!
LIAM: The blood from the whip cut is down in your
eye and you can't see. You see two of these
things? And you got the illusionary one. You got
that one. But not the real one. Your dagger hits
the ground and clatters and actually spins right
down to the ground by you. And now it is Dren's turn.
ASHLY: Okay. Could I get to the other side of the
room?
LIAM: You can get one, two, three. Where do you
want to go? Here?
ASHLY: Yeah.
LIAM: You could get (counting). That's as close as
you can get. You're teensy-weensy.
ASHLY: I'm teensy-weensy. And then I'm going to
shoot at little beholder-man with my crossbow.
SAM: Nathan Beholderman.
MARY: His father, Zyrah.
ASHLY: That's a 24.
LIAM: You hit, man.
ASHLY: Okay. Is it sneak attack? Eight.
LIAM: Eight? The crossbow bolt sinks into the side
of its main eye and juice comes out. You hear the
most-- I'm not even going to try to do it,
because I had a rough warrior day today yelling
for four hours-- the most high-pitched squeal in
the side of your own mind, and the thing lurches
and stays up, but is gushing out of its large eye
in the front. And now it is Delweth's turn.
MARY: How far away is it?
LIAM: It's about 40 feet, 50.
MARY: Do we have a range on how far I could throw
something?
LIAM: You can throw 20 feet well and you can throw
60 feet at disadvantage. So you could throw where
you are at disadvantage, or you could run
closer.
MARY: I'm going to charge in and take my rapier
and--
LAURA: No, but I was hiding!
MARY: Sorry, love. Take my rapier and fling it--
LIAM: That's not what that's for, but you can do
it at disadvantage. Or your dagger.
MARY: Very good. I'll do it with a dagger.
LIAM: Okay. Roll an attack with your dagger.
You pull a dagger out of your belt, you take it by
the blade and flick it, and--
MARY: I got a ten plus what?
SAM: Plus five on the dagger.
MARY: 15.
LIAM: How do you want to do this?
(cheering)
MARY: How many eyeballs does he have left?
LIAM: Well it always had four. One was limp and
hanging and loosey-goosey--
TRAVIS: I know what that's like.
LIAM: It had one big eye in the front which Dren
gouged the side of. Most of it's there.
MARY: Right. I'm going straight in the center of
the giant eyeball in the center.
LIAM: Okay. The thing has just gotten hit in the eye
and bounced against the wall and starts to float
back in the other direction. And it slowly starts
to float downward, its ability to hold itself
up weakening and weakening, and it lands
slowly on top of Tarvis, falling asleep on him,
almost, dying, lowers you down to the ground on the
back, slowly and you're okay, you didn't get hurt,
but here you are on the ground with a beholder
junior sitting on your junk.
TRAVIS: Obby, get this thing off of me!
SAM: Yellow and purple.
MARY: I pull out my dagger.
LAURA: Can I cast Minor Illusion and make the
sound of more dogs barking on the other side of
the doorway we came in at?
LIAM: Yes.
TRAVIS: Is Obby released, now that the beholder's
dead, from the whatever happened to him?
LIAM: Yes, he is, he starts to shake his head.
TRAVIS: Get me out from under this thing!
SAM: Tarvis, what did they do to you?
TRAVIS: I killed it and it fell on me.
SAM: You are brave and wise leader.
TRAVIS: He doesn't need to know, come on.
SAM: I start cutting him out.
TRAVIS: Thank you.
LIAM: While you guys are talking, you hear down
the hall-- (barking)
MARY: More dogs!
TRAVIS: Devan, you fought bravely. Get the doors
open, now.
MARY: Come on.
LIAM: Oh, the cabinet? Okay.
LAURA: And I try to open the cabinet, yeah.
LIAM: Okay, so you already cut your hand--
you break open your hand and place it. And you
wait, and slowly blood pours into it, gets
absorbed in.
SAM: 20 more beholders.
LIAM: The cabinet doors swing open, and you're
looking in at a cabinet. You've never seen this
before. You've seen the doors, and your
grandmother alluded to it, but you're looking at a
shelf, here. And obviously the thing that catches
your eye first is an emerald the size of a human
head sitting on a large pillow.
TRAVIS: We all rush over to take a look. I pick up
my scimitar that got thrown across--
LAURA: I cast Minor Illusion and I cast another
big emerald next to it.
LIAM: Next to it, so there's two of them? Okay.
There's two emeralds, you all see. You all see
that. There's also a set of--
SAM: Which one is the real one? Ask a question
that only it would know the answer to.
LIAM: --panpipes, there's panpipes here, but
they're made out of human bones, but they're not
the right size for a human. They look
child-sized.
MARY: Next to the--
LIAM: Yeah, there's a couple of things sitting
here. There's two large emeralds, a pair of
panpipes made from children's bones. There's a
dark medallion made of iron with an eye etched
into it, and there's a green leather-bound book
here, clasped shut. And that's all that's here.
TRAVIS: Can we come up behind Devan? I thought
there was only one of these jewels.
LAURA: I did, too. I don't know which one's the
real one.
TRAVIS: What are these other trinkets?
MARY: Go put your hands on them.
LAURA: Don't put your hands on anything!
TRAVIS: I reach out and grab the green book.
LIAM: The book? Okay.
TRAVIS: What happens?
LIAM: Nothing.
TRAVIS: All right.
SAM: Can you read?
LIAM: Intelligence of 18.
TRAVIS: I'm pretty sure I can. I open it up. What
is it?
LIAM: Okay, you see lists of amounts, mostly. It's
pages and pages of lists of amounts, and
short-form code in Common with single letters,
anagrams. But at the back of the book, there's one
page with a list of names in it, and you see words
like "Quiver" and next to that "Quinton Puck", and
you scan down, looking for names, and you see the
word "Shortstack". Next to "Shortstack" is the
name "Grimthorne". You see the word "Sandwich",
and next to that it says "Wynan Joy." You see the
word "Whisper", and next to it it says "Riskel
Daxio". Those are the ones that stand out. There's
lots. There's about 30 names here.
TRAVIS: Oh, shit. I take a step out. Everybody try
grabbing one item.
LAURA: I grab the emerald.
ALL: The real one?
LAURA: Yeah, the real one.
MARY: I go and grab the other emerald.
LIAM: Your hands go--
MARY: What the fuck?
SAM: Must be some sort of trap that the grandma
left.
MARY: It's a fake. Everyone be careful. What do
you have in your hands?
SAM: I grab the iron thing with the eye.
LIAM: The medallion? Okay. You have to--
LAURA: I try to pass it to Dren.
LIAM: Like secretly, or just hand it to her?
LAURA: Here, you hold this, I'll try grabbing
something else. And then I try grabbing something
else in the room.
TRAVIS: After I stepped out--
LIAM: You pick up a pair of pipes made from
children's bones.
LAURA: Okay.
TRAVIS: As she's reaching for the pipes made from
children's bones, I look at Obby, and I say, I got
what I came for. I walk up behind Devan, I take a
dagger, and I reach around and slice her throat.
LAURA: I cast Mirror Image and I--
MARY: Sneak attack. Didn't see it coming.
LIAM: Roll for stealth.
LAURA: One.
TRAVIS: 11.
LAURA: That's my passive perception is 11.
LIAM: Then you're fine. Both of you roll for
initiative.
TRAVIS: Goddamn you piece of shit!
(laughter)
LAURA: 13.
TRAVIS: Seven.
LIAM: Seven. Do whatever you want to do, Devan.
LAURA: I cast Mirror Image.
LIAM: Okay.
SAM: What does that do?
LAURA: That creates three other images of myself.
LIAM: There are suddenly multiple Devans.
LAURA: And I take off running.
LIAM: Which way?
LAURA: I run straight forward.
LIAM: You're all over here, right? Okay. This way?
LAURA: Yeah, but all my mirror images are going to
run different directions, so he won't know which
one is me.
LIAM: Okay. Tarvis, what would you like to do?
TRAVIS: How many of her are there?
LIAM: There's four and you can't tell which one is
the real one. Two are running towards the door,
two are running to the sides of the room.
TRAVIS: I look to Obby and say: Devan doesn't need
to live; this ledger is all that matters.
SAM: You want the one on the right?
TRAVIS: Let's go for the two running towards the
doors.
LIAM: You're going to aim for the two at the
door?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: You attack, what are you doing?
TRAVIS: Are two of them heading towards the
opposite door or are they standing right where she was?
LIAM: One Devan is here, one Devan is here, two
are right next to each other one just ahead of the other.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'll take the one that's just behind
the one that's ahead of the other.
SAM: I will throw a dagger at the other one.
LIAM: Well you're not doing anything, you are.
SAM: I'm not doing anything, I'm looking at the
medallion.
LIAM: I wish I had a coin. All right. I know what
I'll do.
SAM: Wait, it's a d2, don't you have a d2?
LIAM: I'm good. So roll to attack.
SAM: Do the percentage die, we never get to use
those!
LIAM: Roll to attack.
LAURA: Oh god.
SAM: Finally.
TRAVIS: 18.
LIAM: 18? Okay. Roll for damage.
TRAVIS: Wait, it's a four for a dagger. Five.
LIAM: I don't know what your hit points are, guys,
I'm going to go on the honor code here. Five
points? You feel a dagger sink into your back.
LAURA: Wait! No! If I roll a d20, I determine
whether the attack hits me or another one of my
duplicates.
LIAM: Well there you go, I don't know that spell,
sorry. The mirror image next to you goes
(sizzling).
LAURA: (gasps) Oh shit.
TRAVIS: I thought she has to roll a d20?
LAURA: Yeah, wait, I have to roll a d20. If I roll
a six or higher, then it attacks a duplicate. The
duplicate's AC equals ten plus my dexterity
modifier, so 11.
MARY: Well he rolled a 17.
LAURA: So it would've hit it, but that's if--
Whoa, if I roll a six or higher and I rolled a
six. So if an attack hits a duplicate the
duplicate is destroyed!
LIAM: Okay, you still don't know which one is the
real one. I mean, I know you do, but Tarvis
doesn't know which one is real.
SAM: Tarvis is pretty dumb.
TRAVIS: Tarvis has an intelligence of 18, he would
probably think the two that were trying to
leave the room were--
LIAM: Okay. everybody roll for initiative right
now
LAURA: Oh jeez Louise.
ASHLY: 20.
LIAM: Wait, everybody roll and then 20 to 25?
ASHLY and LAURA: 20.
SAM: 24.
LIAM: 24. Obby, Dren is 20?
ASHLY: Yes.
LIAM: Okay, next? 15 to 20.
LAURA: 20 as well.
LIAM: 20 as well. Okay, ten to 15.
TRAVIS: 15.
LIAM: Okay, and that leaves Del?
MARY: Seven for me.
LIAM: Obby, what would you like to do in this
moment?
SAM: I would like to attack one of the to be
determined duplicates.
LIAM: Okay.
LAURA: Oh no, you aimed at me.
SAM: 16.
LAURA: You hit me.
LIAM: Roll for damage.
SAM: Seven.
LAURA: Okay, seven damage?
SAM: Seven damage.
LAURA: Would I have any idea how to actually get
out of this room?
LIAM: No, not in this second.
ASHLY: Are the doors still slammed shut?
TRAVIS: Oh, the doors are sealed closed.
ASHLY: Are the doors still sealed shut? Oh shit.
LAURA: Do you have the ledger in your hands?
TRAVIS: I do, I tucked it away. It's not in my
hands, I tucked away.
ASHLY: Well depends whose turn it is.
LIAM: It's currently, fuck these 'D' names! It is
Dren's turn.
ASHLY: Could I try to steal it from Tarvis?
LIAM: Steal the--
ASHLY: The ledger.
SAM: Sleight of hand.
LIAM: Sure.
ASHLY: Am I close enough to just do it?
SAM: But you're one of us, you're one of the
Clasp.
TRAVIS: She's in love with Devan.
LIAM: You move over ten feet and what do you do?
ASHLY: I try to steal the ledger.
LIAM: Make a sleight of hand check.
ASHLY: 18.
LIAM: Make a perception check.
ASHLY: Come on, ones.
MARY: Ooh!
LIAM: Dren runs forward and slams into you and
says, "Don't worry, I've got this." As you say
that, you pull the book out and stick it up your
shirt and hold your weapon out.
ASHLY: Okay, now what do I do?
LIAM: That's all you do.
ASHLY: That's all I do? Okay.
LIAM: You can move a little if you want.
ASHLY: Can I try and dash forward?
LIAM: Yes, you have three movement left and your
dash as a bonus action is another five, so you can
go eight. Where do you want to go?
ASHLY: Toward Devan, but I don't know which one is
the real one.
TRAVIS: Yeah, you don't, none of us do.
SAM: Roll that d20.
LAURA: Should I?
TRAVIS: How would she know?!
ASHLY: I'll give it away, though, won't I? Right,
I don't want to give it away. I'll run as far as I
can to the opposite side of the room.
LIAM: Okay, here.
MARY: All right, could you tell me who everybody
is?
LIAM: It is now Devan's turn. Here is Dren. Here
is Devan. Here is Delweth. Here's Tarvis. Here's
Obby.
LAURA: Oh my gosh.
SAM and LIAM: Obby the Rat!
ASHLY: Is it your turn?
LAURA: It's my turn. I don't have any idea how to
get out of this room.
SAM: Can you Misty?
LAURA: No, I really can't.
TRAVIS: Don't help her.
SAM: She's my family.
LAURA: Oh god. Okay, I'm going to use two more of my
sorcery points and get another level one spell and
I'm going to cast Color Spray at the three of
them.
LIAM: Okay, no, you're confusing them. So you turn
this way.
MARY: Describe Color Spray, what does it do?
LAURA: Color Spray is a dazzling array of flashing
colored light.
MARY: Lot of color tonight.
LAURA: Creatures in a 15-foot cone originating
from me. Is there any way to get all three in the cone?
LIAM: 15-foot cone?
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: No.
LAURA: Who can I get?
LIAM: If you want to move forward, you can get
them together.
LAURA: Okay, I'll get them.
MARY: What does it do to us? Just blinds us?
LAURA: So I'm going to roll 6d10.
SAM: Holy shit!
LAURA: No, no it doesn't do that.
SAM: 6d10?!
LIAM: It's not damage.
SAM: Is it for what color it is?
LAURA: And then it makes you go blind if I get
you, if your hit points are low enough.
LIAM: Delweth, how many hit points do you have
right now?
MARY: How many hit points do I have left?
LIAM: Yeah.
MARY: 26.
LIAM: Tarvis, how many do you have?
LAURA: Three? You have three hit points?
Yes, so that's one, two, three, four, five,
so I have one more. That's nine plus nine is 18,
(counting) plus nine is 32.
LIAM: A rainbow erupts from her hands and arms.
Blasts you guys in the eyes, it scorches and all
you see is white. All you see is white. You are
both blind.
TRAVIS: All three of us are blind?
LIAM: Just you two. Obby can see. Fuck a duck,
where did I put my initiative order? Oh my god,
it's the end of the world. Oh man. Dren and
Delweth both went right?
MARY: I haven't gone yet.
LIAM: Dangit, you go, Delweth. That's right
somewhere on one of these papers is the order.
LAURA: Yeah.
SAM: I was first.
MARY: All right.
LIAM: Delweth, go for now.
LAURA: Yeah, it was your turn, it's your turn
next.
MARY: No, I know, I'm trying to figure out what to do.
Why are you looking at me like that?
TRAVIS: Are you going to be a fucking
Lannister or you going to be a Gryffindor right now?
LIAM: No, it's not Delweth's turn right now it
is--
MARY: I haven't gone. I had seven. I was the
last.
ASHLY: I went, because I stole the ledger.
LIAM: Okay, go for it Delweth.
MARY: All right, I am going to-- fuck. I don't
know what to do.
LIAM: Bad scene, man.
MARY: I am going to--
LIAM: You can do anything with disadvantage at
this point.
MARY: All right. I'm going to, 60 feet, Acid
Splash. In my brain, try and remember where I saw
Devan, and I'm going to blindly cast Acid Splash.
LIAM: All right, roll a ranged spell attack. You
add your modifier. No, actually, sorry, Devan, you
make a dex save at advantage.
LAURA: Okay. Natural 20!
LIAM: Okay, you see a glob of acid sizzling, and you
drop to your butt and let it fly over your head.
And it sizzles.
LAURA: Does it sizzle near the sigil?
LIAM: No, it does not sizzle near the siggle. And
now it is Tarvis's turn.
MARY: Do I get a bonus action?
LIAM: Sure.
MARY: I'm going to take three steps to my left and
try and find the wall.
LIAM: You're right here, and your back is against
the wall.
MARY: All right, I'm going to slide three steps to
my left against the wall.
LIAM: Okay, you can feel you're brushing past
Tarvis as you go.
MARY: Okay.
LIAM: Okay. Tarvis, it's your turn.
TRAVIS: I have two daggers left, so I'm going to
take a second one and chuck it in the direction
that I think Devan was in.
LIAM: You hear her butt hit the ground.
TRAVIS: It's at disadvantage, right?
LIAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Yeah, the butt thumping. 12.
LAURA: I have 11. Wait! Wait, no, I still have
mirror images!
TRAVIS: Are they up?
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: Yup, two of them are up.
SAM: He can't see any of them.
LAURA: It's a seven, so he still would've rolled
for an attack on that.
LIAM: Okay.
MARY: I thought it was six or less.
SAM: Six or higher.
MARY: Six or higher, you're fine.
LAURA: Yeah, and I rolled a seven.
TRAVIS: Seven on the mirror image.
LAURA: So one of them disappears, there's only one
mirror image left.
LIAM: Poof, okay. Knife sinks into the back of a
fake and goes (poof) like a Naruto clone.
TRAVIS: Are you dead yet? You will be soon, you
conniving bitch!
LIAM: Obby, you're up.
SAM: Obby the Rat takes no joy in this--
TRAVIS: Wait! And my bonus action. I will take my
superior healing potion.
LAURA: Damn it!
TRAVIS: I need an eight.
LAURA: Damn it.
TRAVIS: You guys go ahead, sorry.
LIAM: Yeah, Obby the Rat.
SAM: I take no joy in attacking you, but it is my
duty, I'm sorry. 20.
LIAM: What did you attack with?
SAM and LIAM: The dagger.
SAM: I throw dagger.
LIAM: What happens with your last image?
LAURA: He hits the mirror image!
MARY: Wait, my superior is only 8d4.
TRAVIS: Superior is 8d8, right? 8d8 plus six?
LIAM: Yeah, 8d8 plus eight.
LAURA: No, 8d4.
LIAM: 8d4 plus eight.
TRAVIS: Ours say 8d8.
LIAM: It's supposed to be 8d4.
TRAVIS: Okay. Son of a bitch.
MARY: 8d4!
SAM: So I hit the mirror image, even though I saw
her shoot rainbows out of her hands?
LAURA: The mirror image shot rainbows from its
hands, too.
SAM: All right, fine.
LIAM: Like a kaleidoscope. It was amazing.
SAM: Colors I don't like.
LIAM: Dren, you are up.
ASHLY: Can everyone see now? Or is everyone still
blind?
LAURA: No, they're still blind until their next
turn.
SAM: Oh, and I used some movement to go a
little bit closer to her.
LIAM: This way?
SAM: Yeah.
ASHLY: So they still can't see?
LIAM: It doesn't look like they can see.
ASHLY: Okay.
LIAM: I'm going to give you an eight-count.
ASHLY: Okay. I hold up the ledger and I go, Stop!
Everyone stop fighting. If anyone makes another
move, I'm going to rip this ledger to shreds.
SAM: Are we here for the ledger, Tarvis, or the
jewel?
ASHLY: I also have the emerald. I have both things
currently.
MARY: You have the emerald as well?
ASHLY: Yes.
MARY: What the fuck are we here for, Tarvis?
TRAVIS: The emerald. You can tear up the ledger.
ASHLY: Can I shatter the emerald, can I do that,
is the emerald destroyable?
LIAM: Sure.
ASHLY: Then I'll destroy the emerald.
LIAM: Is that your action?
ASHLY: I'm threatening to, unless everyone stands
down.
SAM: Dren, you are one of us, why are you doing
this?
ASHLY: Because I love Devan!
SAM: What are you talking about, she's a gir--
ooh.
TRAVIS: You know that if you leave here, no matter
where you go, we will find you, and we will kill you.
LAURA: It doesn't matter, I'll take care of her, I
have a lot of magic.
TRAVIS: That's coming out of a dead woman as
well.
SAM: Dren, she has betrayed her own family, don't
you think she will betray you too over gambling
debts? I live with my wife, her mother, her
mother, and her mother, and I hate them all, but
we all get along because we are family. She will
lie and stab you in the back.
LAURA: I would never!
MARY: She will, she told me she would when we were
alone together.
LAURA: No, I did not.
MARY: Yes, she did.
LAURA: No, I didn't. Delweth, you said you would protect me.
She told me she was going to protect me.
MARY: She told me that she was going to kill
everyone.
ASHLY: Look, you guys, I don't want anyone to get
hurt! The truth is I always wanted to be a poet,
but my father forced me to be an assassin rogue. I
don't even want this emerald. I just want Devan
and I to be able to go and live our lives in
peace.
TRAVIS: If you smash that emerald, you will not
walk out of here alive.
ASHLY: If I give you the emerald, will you let us
go?
SAM: By the way, Tarvis, you're talking to the
wall right now.
(laughter)
LIAM: During the conversation, it fades away.
LAURA: Aw, man.
MARY: Throw me the idol? Give me the whip?
SAM: We've got a little Mexican standoff here.
(laughter)
MARY: All right. What do we do? Get the emerald?
ASHLY: You guys open that hatch and I won't
shatter the emerald.
MARY: What hatch? We don't know how to get--
ASHLY: The thing in the middle! The thing that
Abby was trying to open.
SAM: Obby! Obby the Rat!
MARY: We should kill her for not knowing your
name.
SAM: I can open any door, I can open that door if
that's what you want open, but we need that
jewel.
ASHLY: If you let us get down the hatch, I'll toss
it back up to you.
TRAVIS: I think we just kill them now.
SAM: Both?
TRAVIS: Yep.
LAURA: While she was talking, can I have tried to
pry open the hatch?
LIAM: Sure.
SAM: Hey, stop trying to pry open the hatch!
(laughter)
MARY: Are they both in the center of the room,
trying to pry open the hatch?
LIAM: I'm going to say for that she backed up, you
walked forward, you guys didn't move.
SAM: Tarvis, I follow orders. You tell me what to
do.
TRAVIS: Kill them. Now.
MARY: I cast Burning Hands on both of them.
LIAM: Everybody roll initiative again.
LAURA: Aw, come on.
SAM: Not good.
LIAM: 20 to 25.
ASHLY: 21.
LIAM: 15 to 20.
TRAVIS: 19.
MARY: 16.
LAURA: I'm going to die.
ASHLY: I think we both are.
LIAM: 16, okay. Ten to 15? Five to ten?
SAM: Seven.
LIAM: I don't have everybody. Devan, what did you
roll? Three. Dren, go.
ASHLY: Should I smash the emerald?
LIAM: Everybody can tell, everybody's moving, you
see everybody moving at the same time. What are
you going to do?
MARY: Tied together in a glorious love-- beautiful
moment.
ASHLY: I'm going to move in front of Devan.
SAM: Wait. Why are we seated at these tables?
(laughter)
MARY: It's all clear now.
ASHLY: And while I'm moving, can I give her the
emerald?
LIAM: Make a sleight of hand check.
ASHLY: 18.
LIAM: Plop it into her hands, yeah.
ASHLY: And then I'm going to whisper--
LAURA: I've got like a human head inside of my
shirt right now.
ASHLY: I whisper, get out of here if you can. And
then I attack Tarvis.
LAURA: Oh, Dren!
ASHLY: Am I close enough to use the shortsword?
LIAM: If you take one step forward, you are. Do
you want to do that?
ASHLY: I'm going to get so ganked. Yes. Bloop! 18
plus six.
LIAM: Yeah, that hits.
ASHLY: And then seven damage.
LAURA: Oh, god.
LIAM: Okay, blade sinks into his hip. Now we're on
to-- why can't I read these names?
SAM: The 'D' one.
MARY: I had 17.
TRAVIS: I had 18.
LIAM: Delweth, Tarvis.
TRAVIS: I look down at this tiny little Benedict
Arnold, and I take my scimitar and swing it. What
the f--!?
(laughter)
TRAVIS: And I'm overcome with nostalgia of when
she was cool.
LIAM: And you swing your blade down as hard as you
can, because you love the Clasp, you serve the
Clasp, and this little shit betrays you? You bring
your scimitar down, you go whoop, take a step to
the side. The scimitar hits the ground and
shatters into two pieces.
LAURA and ASHLY: Oh, shit!
LIAM: You're now holding a dagger.
TRAVIS: And a whip.
MARY: And a whip that you cut your face with.
LIAM: Delweth, you're up.
MARY: Right. Do I have a clean shot at these two?
LIAM: To do what?
MARY: To kill them. I need a 15-foot cone.
LIAM: You'll hit Dren.
MARY: I'll hit Dren. Can I move?
LIAM: Sure, you can move right there and do it.
Kablam.
MARY: Kaboom. I want to make sure it's just the
two of them in range. I cast Burning Hands.
LIAM: Go for it.
MARY: What do I have to do? Burning Hands. Each
creature must make a dexterity saving throw.
LIAM: Versus your DC, so your DC is 13. You've got
to beat 13 with a dex save.
ASHLY: 14.
LIAM: Yeah, you beat it.
LAURA: 13.
LIAM: You beat it. But you take half damage. So
roll for damage. Yeah. They both made the save. So
Delweth puts her hands together, fans out the
fingers, fire shoots out, for a total of three?
Four. It blasts, and if they had been human, they
would have been cooked, but because they're so
short, it goes over their heads as they crouch
down.
MARY: Yeah, you take four damage.
ASHLY: Four damage each?
MARY: Yeah.
LIAM: Okay, Obby the Rat, you're up.
TRAVIS: Go get it.
SAM: All right. I attack Dren. I do not like
haiku.
ASHLY: I've always loved you, Alby. Like a
brother.
(laughter)
SAM: You know why they call me Obby the Rat? I can
sniff out a traitor.
ASHLY: Really? It took you a long time.
SAM: I failed! Three!
TRAVIS: Plus what?
SAM: Seven? I don't know. Do you have an AC of
ten?
LIAM: Devan, you're up.
SAM: Bonus action, I disengage and run back.
MARY: Oh, that was mine as well.
LAURA: I'm going to put my bloody hand down on the
floor underneath me, and I'm going to cast Minor
Illusion. Oh, god. And I'm going to cast an image
of the ledger across the room, like over towards the--
TRAVIS: The ledger?
LAURA: I mean, the emerald. The emerald rolling
across the floor towards the door.
SAM: It can't move.
LAURA: It can't move?
SAM: The Minor Illusion, I don't think it moves.
LIAM: I'll allow it.
TRAVIS: "I'll allow it."
LIAM: And now we're at the top again, so Dren.
ASHLY: Okay. There's no situation in which I can
get a sneak attack on anyone, is there? If I dash
underneath anyone or--
LIAM: The only friend you have left is here, and
there's nowhere to hide in here.
TRAVIS: She's going to get you killed.
ASHLY: I'll do it for love. I'm going to attack
Tarvis again. 17.
LIAM: Hits.
ASHLY: What am I doing? d6. Seven.
LIAM: You feel the blood, hot.
TRAVIS: As hot as my rage.
LIAM: Tarvis, you're up.
TRAVIS: Again, I try to hit something with a pulse.
LIAM: With your broken, weird dagger, or the
whip?
TRAVIS: With the whip! That'll hit, 19.
LIAM: That hits.
TRAVIS: Thank you, Jesus. A one plus two for a
whopping fucking three.
MARY: We suck!
LIAM: You feel a sting, a cut on your neck, and
blood starts to pour lightly down your neck.
TRAVIS: As a bonus action, I will take a greater
healing potion.
LIAM: Man, this is a long game. Wow.
SAM: Shouldn't have given us so many potions.
MARY: I know. One each. That's all you need. I
don't know.
TRAVIS: Continue.
LIAM: Okay. Next is Delweth.
MARY: Fuck. Really?
LIAM: Yeah.
MARY: Who's that right over the grate?
LIAM: That is Devan.
TRAVIS: (strained) You can sneak attack on Dren
because I'm engaged with her.
MARY: Oh, all right.
SAM: If you attack with a weapon.
MARY: I'm going to attack Dren with my rapier.
LIAM: Okay, so you're going to move up.
MARY: Yes, get sneak attack. What do I do?
LIAM: Roll to attack.
MARY: Just roll this?
LIAM: Yes, roll to attack first.
TRAVIS: What are the motherfuck-- I don't know
what--
MARY: I missed, I had a three.
LIAM: Do you want to do anything else with a
bonus action?
MARY: I'd like to kill myself.
(laughter)
MARY: I'm going to stay where I am.
LIAM: Okay, Obby, you're up.
SAM: I run over to Devan. I stab her in belly with
dagger. I roll four.
(laughter)
LIAM: Devan, you're up.
SAM: Wait, with bonus action, sleight of hand, I
attempt to remove her pouch with healing potions.
LIAM: Roll.
SAM: I roll five.
(laughter)
LIAM: Devan, go.
LAURA: I keep my hand with the blood on the sigil
on the ground. I don't know if it's doing
anything.
LIAM: It doesn't feel like anything's doing.
LAURA: Shit! I guess then I'll do Ray of Frost up
at Obby's face.
LIAM: Go.
LAURA: I'm going to use a blue one, because it's
frosty. That would be 31. No, wait, no, that's a lie.
That's such a lie. 23.
LIAM: Hits.
MARY: Still really good.
LAURA: So that's 1d8, then. That's three. That's
it?
LIAM: That's it.
TRAVIS: We're like a bunch of drunks trying to
kill each other with foam noodles.
LAURA: And I say, look! Look! The jewel is yours!
Why are you still attacking me? I don't even want it!
LIAM: You do see the jewel across the room. Dren,
you're up.
ASHLY: Does it take anything to roll perception to
see if there's anything I can do to this thing on
the ground? Or to see if there's any other way to
get out?
LIAM: You can, sure. That'll be your whole action
and move if you want. You can do a perception
check if you want, though.
ASHLY: My perception is bunk. There's no sweeping
attacks I can do, I'm assuming. I can't do a crazy
flourish?
LIAM: No. You can disengage to get away out of
that little kill box, and then I'd let you do
perception if you want.
LAURA: That sounds smart.
ASHLY: Yeah, I'm going to move out of the kill
box. Disengage. I guess next to Devan.
LIAM: Here?
ASHLY: Sure. And then I'll do a perception.
LIAM: Perception check, roll.
ASHLY: (singing) Son of a bitch. If only it had
been a one. It's a two.
LIAM: It's a two? I don't know, man, it's hectic
in here. On to Tarvis.
TRAVIS: I run up to Devan, and I look at Dren, and
I say, this is your last chance. If you don't give
her up, I'm going to paralyze her and torture her
in front of you for a week. And then maybe I'll
let her die. I attack Devan.
LAURA: Me?
TRAVIS: Yes, you! 17!
LAURA: That hits me.
TRAVIS: And I get sneak attack on it.
LIAM: Yep.
TRAVIS: Hey, it's me. Six. Seven. Ten.
SAM: Hey! That's some real damage.
TRAVIS: Think about it. Think about the offer. I'm
talking bad torture.
LIAM: Delweth, you're up.
MARY: Fuck me. Okay.
TRAVIS: Plus, you'll live.
ASHLY: I will? I don't believe that for a second.
I stabbed you twice!
TRAVIS: Death's a certainty.
MARY: I am a member of the Clasp, so I attack
Devan.
LIAM: Okay, go.
MARY: With my rapier! Yes. There's no sneak. Was I
behind anybody?
LIAM: Sneak attack because she's flanked. You roll
at advantage because she's flanked.
ASHLY: Do you pass out?
LAURA: I go unconscious, but then if they keep
hitting, I get three death saving throws.
SAM: Aren't you attacking with the rapier?
LIAM: Hits.
MARY: Then I do 1d8. Hey! 11.
TRAVIS: And sneak attack.
LAURA: This is it!
MARY: 15.
LIAM: Down?
LAURA: Zero.
ASHLY: Devan!
LIAM: Obby, you're up.
MARY: Do I get a bonus action? I'd like to go back
up behind Tarvis.
LIAM: Okay. Over here? Okay. Obby the Rat, you're
up.
SAM: Tarvis. Devan or Dren?
TRAVIS: Devan. Do it. Devan's unconscious, so it's
an automatic two death saving throws.
LIAM: Yeah, if you hit.
LAURA: All I did wrong was play some poker. Just
saying. You know it in your heart of hearts, Obby.
All I did was play some poker.
SAM: Obby follows orders. I roll a two.
TRAVIS: No!
(laughter)
TRAVIS: It's an automatic crit, right?
LIAM: Yeah. You lean in and go--
SAM: It just hits? So what do I roll? Is she
dead?
LAURA: No, I've got one more death saving throw.
SAM: Holy shit. That was so mean of me.
LIAM: You push in, and you watch her back, like a
hole wells up in her back. None of you are good
people. Nobody here is a good person.
SAM: I use sleight of hand to try and steal her
jewel from her.
LIAM: It's across the room on the floor.
LAURA: No, it's not, it would've gone away as soon
as I died.
LIAM: Okay. Sleight of hand? You'd have to see it. I
mean, she's probably lying on top of it.
SAM: Well then I take the healing potions. 19.
LIAM: Okay. All right, Dren, you're up.
LAURA: You could give me a healing potion and wake
me up.
TRAVIS: Think about it, Dren. Life awaits you on
the other side of this choice. You can live, drink
wine, find someone else.
ASHLY: I'm going to give Devan a healing potion.
LIAM: How many is it? 4d4 or 8d4?
ASHLY: 8d4.
MARY: The superior?
ASHLY: It's the only one I have left. You can roll
them.
TRAVIS: Do death saving throws reset? Do they,
Lemur?
LIAM: Yes. She's awake. I'm going to say, to pour
that all into her mouth and make sure it goes
down, that's your action. You can move if you want
to.
ASHLY: I can't do another perception? That would
be another action? Okay. Can I pry at the sigil?
LIAM: Maybe on your next turn, you can.
ASHLY: Okay, that's it.
LIAM: Okay. Tarvis, you're up.
TRAVIS: It's me? Great. I would like to go and
strike Devan.
LAURA: Wait, I didn't get to go? My turn was after
Dren's.
TRAVIS: You got to wake up.
LIAM: You're after Obby.
LAURA: Just kidding. I had the lowest, I forgot.
TRAVIS: 14.
LIAM: What's your AC?
LAURA: 11.
TRAVIS: Awesome.
SAM: Oh man, poor Laura Bailey.
MARY: It's not Laura Bailey, it's Devan.
SAM: You're right. Obby has no feelings.
TRAVIS: 13.
LIAM: Bang. You want to do a bonus action?
TRAVIS: Nope.
LIAM: Nope. Delweth.
MARY: Right. Going back with my rapier. I don't
have anything stronger than that, really. I'm
going to keep the last thing that I have. I'm
going to run up and rapier.
LAURA: You're going to rapier?
MARY: Rapier. I said rapier.
LIAM: Roll that die.
MARY: 17 plus--
TRAVIS: 22.
MARY: And then the rapier is-- (counting)
LAURA: I'm back to zero. It doesn't matter, I'm
back to zero.
LIAM: Okay, she's down. Okay. Delweth, you want to
do anything on a bonus?
MARY: I want to go back behind Tarvis.
LIAM: Okay. So you dart around, then you darted
back. Obby the Rat.
SAM: I turn to Dren and say, where is the jewel?
Tell me or I kill your friend right now.
ASHLY: You'll kill us anyway.
SAM: Okay. I rolled an 11 to kill Devan.
LAURA: Well that's two death saving throws gone.
LIAM: Okay. Any bonus, Obby the Rat?
SAM: I'm going to search her body.
LIAM: You get down and you start looking, and you
feel something hard. And now it is Dren's turn.
TRAVIS: Think about what you're doing.
ASHLY: I'm going to try and pry open the sigil.
Can I use one of my weapons to do it?
LIAM: Sure.
TRAVIS: Yeah, go ahead, expose your neck for us
while you're doing it.
LIAM: Roll a strength check.
ASHLY: Okay, so it's 18?
LIAM: Yeah, you bring it down as hard as you can,
and scratches-- it ruins the surface. It is still shut.
ASHLY: Okay. And that's all I can do, really,
right?
LIAM: You can move if you want to.
ASHLY: No, I'll stay right there.
LIAM: Okay. Tarvis, you're up.
TRAVIS: You betrayer. Watch her die.
LAURA: He's terrible.
SAM: Tarvis.
TRAVIS: And I take my dagger out, and I kneel down
over Devan, and I take the knife, and I stick it in.
SAM: Oh, what a dick!
TRAVIS: And then I--
LIAM: Her body jiggles on the ground.
LAURA: It hurts, I don't even-- like, we've only
had a one-shot and it still really sucks to die.
I'm dead, yo.
LIAM: Delweth, what would you like to do?
ASHLY: No!
MARY: I go over to your body.
LAURA: My body. My sad little teeny-tiny halfling
body.
MARY: Does she have the emerald? Is that what we
discovered?
SAM: I'm still searching around there.
LIAM: Obby's on her. As Tarvis did that, he's got
his hands on it in a split-second.
MARY: All right.
LIAM: You can surmise that that's what's going
on.
MARY: I turn to Dren and say, you swore an oath.
You swore an oath to the Clasp. That's what you
did, and you've betrayed us all. And I take my rapier
and I attack her.
LIAM: Okay, roll to hit.
SAM: We're hardened criminals, right? This is what
we do, right? It feels real wrong!
MARY: 19.
LIAM: Hits.
MARY: 19. Sorry, love.
ASHLY: You're not sorry! Is this sneak attack?
TRAVIS: Yeah. She's engaged, right?
LIAM: Yes. Yeah.
LAURA: Is she?
LIAM: But you would have to move down. No, it's
not sneak attack. No, sorry.
MARY: Eight.
LIAM: Eight, total. Okay. You slash right down her
front in a long cut across her chest. Anything else?
MARY: I go back behind Tarvis.
LIAM: All right. Obby the Rat. You dart back, you
come around go-- you slash at her and then whip
around, get your place. Obby the Rat.
SAM: Do I find the jewel?
LIAM: Got it.
SAM: Find jewel. I look at sigil on ground. Any
symbol that looks like previous symbols? How do we
get out of the room?
MARY: It's a new sigil?
LIAM: It's not a sigil, it's a geometric pattern
on the ground.
SAM: What if we--
TRAVIS: Just kill her.
SAM: (sighs) I throw dagger at Dren.
LIAM: Go. Attack.
TRAVIS: Who's now engaged.
SAM: 17?
LIAM: Yeah, hits. No, there's no sneak attack. The
only person near her is Devan. You guys are not
within five feet of her.
TRAVIS: I thought Delweth hit her with a rapier.
LIAM: She bounced back on that.
SAM: Seven points.
ASHLY: Hope that feels real good, Alby.
LIAM: Are you still standing? Dren's still
standing?
ASHLY: Dren's still standing.
LIAM: Dren, you're up.
ASHLY: I'm going to take this action to rip up the
ledger that I have.
LAURA: Oh! What's up, motherfucker?
ASHLY: I rip it into shreds, and I say a haiku,
which is this: Though I die today/At least with my
love I go/Fuck all you bastards!
MARY: B-A-S-S T-U-R-D-S. They are fish, they are
shit.
SAM: That was probably your finest haiku.
LIAM: May be your final act on earth. Tarvis,
you're up.
TRAVIS: Oh, that ledger. I'm going to kill Dren.
LIAM: Yes.
LAURA: One!
TRAVIS: No. 15.
LIAM: Yes.
TRAVIS: Six plus eight and-- yeah. 12.
LIAM: What are you using to do this?
TRAVIS: My whip.
SAM: Oh, shit.
LAURA: That's so shitty.
TRAVIS: 16.
ASHLY: I am extremely dead.
LIAM: The whip wraps around her neck and you yank
and pull, and she chokes out.
LAURA: Oh god.
TRAVIS: Would you guys mind if I finished that
off?
MARY: No. I have no problem with that.
TRAVIS: Okay. I take a dagger, and I know she's
unconscious.
LIAM: Yeah. We don't need an action for this, go
ahead.
TRAVIS: And I turn her head towards Devan and sink
it in the neck.
LAURA: He's terrible.
LIAM: She's dead.
TRAVIS: Betrayal's a bitch. I'm dead, you guys, I
really needed that ledger. Is it in shreds? Is it
tapeable? I mean, did she office mash that shit, or
is it--
ASHLY: It's shredded! It's the most shredded! I
came from the afterlife to shred!
LIAM: If you can find Percival de Rolo to invent
tape, then maybe you could tape it together. The
pieces are there. The names are there. I mean,
she's not a paper shredder.
TRAVIS: Okay, good. I put them in a satchel. Are
those sconces around the room? Four sconces?
LIAM: They're magical transparent globes.
TRAVIS: They're just orbs. Can we go back into the
room?
LIAM: In here? Sure. You're going in there?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'll go in there, because I'm
probably dead anyway. Can I pick up the baby
finger pipes?
LIAM: Yes.
TRAVIS: Can I try and play some music on that
shit?
LIAM: You can.
LAURA: I had the baby finger pipes on my body.
LIAM: They're not there.
TRAVIS: They're not there? Oh, then I go and
Dren-- oh, she doesn't have them. Oh, look,
they're on Devan's stupid dead body. Can I try and
play some music?
LIAM: (raspberry sound)
MARY: We're going to die in here.
TRAVIS: What else is in that room?
LIAM: You're going to do a perception check?
MARY: Yeah. All of us.
LIAM: You're all in there? There's room for two
people to go in. Who's in?
TRAVIS: I'm in there, and I rolled a 14 plus five.
19.
MARY: 21.
LIAM: Yeah, you both-- really, you were so
bedazzled by what you saw on the shelf. You didn't
really look around this little room. There are
three levers directly to the right of the door on
the wall.
MARY: Is there anything around these levers at
all? Anything? Any markings, any arcane
something?
LIAM: No, just three.
TRAVIS: Hey, there's three of us. Let's all grab
one.
LIAM: There's not room for the three of you.
SAM: You have two hands.
TRAVIS: How about I do the one that's furthest
into the room?
MARY: He's a little tiny guy, isn't he?
LIAM: Who's going?
SAM: You have multiple hands that you can use to
pull levers.
MARY: I've got a Mage Hand.
LAURA: Jesus, pull some fucking levers!
SAM: While this is going on, I'm cutting off
Devan's hand.
LIAM: All right. So three levers are getting
pulled--
MARY: But I'm stepping out of the room and casting
my Mage Hand.
TRAVIS: Just the one that's closest to the back of
the wall first.
LIAM: Tell me what's happening.
TRAVIS: I have my left hand on the one that's
furthest in the room. Right hand on the middle one.
LIAM: And you're in there. You're standing
outside.
MARY: And I use my Mage Hand to pull the other.
TRAVIS: But we're only doing one at a time.
MARY: All right.
LIAM: One at a time? All right. So you're outside,
waiting. You're inside. Okay. So you're pulling
first?
TRAVIS: Yeah. The deepest one in the room. Crank.
LIAM: Okay. Delweth and Obby immediately take 8d6
electric damage from the floor in the circular
room.
ASHLY: 8d6?
LIAM: Yes.
TRAVIS: Who rolls that?
LIAM: I'll do it.
ASHLY: (whispers) This was a suicide mission.
LAURA: Oh man, if I'd grabbed that lever when I
was in there grabbing that big jewel.
LIAM: Delweth and Obby take 31 points of damage.
SAM and MARY: Dead.
LIAM: Unconscious? Electrified, up in smoke.
TRAVIS: Are they unconscious or dead?
LIAM: They are smoking and on the ground.
TRAVIS: I only have one healing potion.
SAM: Oh, I have tons.
MARY: I do, too. Take them from my body.
TRAVIS: Okay. I run out and go, oh, jeez-- wait a
minute. Is the floor still electrified? I put the
lever back up. I run out, I pour one greater
healing potion into Obby's mouth. He wakes up and
I go, hi, I need a healing potion. I run over
and pour it into Delweth's mouth.
MARY: Because I have a superior.
TRAVIS: That didn't work so awesome. How about
I'll stand out here now, and one of you go in
there and pull the second one in case--
MARY: I've got to roll some-- what do we do to get
back to--
LIAM: (sizzling sound)
SAM: What was that?
LIAM: There is a little old woman standing in the
closet behind you. She raises a staff. "You
"fucking assholes." There is a transparent cage
around the three of you, now. She walks out,
click, clack, click.
LAURA: The Shrew.
LIAM: "Do you little shits really think the Clasp
is the only one that has little birds who whisper
"to them?" In that moment, she raises her hand, and
you hear her utter the word (arcane gibberish).
The air around you grows dry. You feel the
moisture in your bodies pull out. You remember
that scene at the end of the Last Crusade? With
the cup? All the moisture leaves your body, and
your skin gets dry and flakes away, and your sight
goes, and the world grows dark, and you guys fall,
three husks upon the ground. The cage shrinks,
shrinks, dragging your three bodies together. Five
bodies together. "You don't fuck the Shrew. The
Shrew screws you." And she moves her hand, and the
circle in the middle fans open, and five bodies
fall down through a tube and land in a pile of
mimic corpse. Click, click, click. "Fuck family."
(laughter)
(cheering)
SAM: A classic Liam uplifting ending.
(laughter)
LAURA: All that work.
MARY: Never got a chance to kill you.
LAURA: You were trying to kill him?
LIAM: Everybody tell the group the secret I gave
you. Starting with Obby. What's the secret I gave you?
SAM: That I love Tarvis?
LIAM: That's it, no secrets.
SAM: Not romantically. I'm indebted to you and I
would do anything for you.
LAURA: That's so sweet!
TRAVIS: I had to steal the ledger, which was the
real objective, and Devan knew too much to be left
alive. She had to die.
MARY: I knew that we were going to kill Devan at
the end of this.
SAM: I also knew that.
MARY: And I also knew that I was passed over for
you, so I was going to kill you, because I was
jealous of power. I know, you kept turning to me
going, "Are you a Lannister?" I'm like, fuck!
LIAM: Ashly, what was Dren's secret?
ASHLY: Oh, it was very well-kept, that I was in
love with Devan and I wanted to run away with her.
SAM: I think your first line of dialogue was, "I'm
in love with you secretly!"
(laughter)
TRAVIS: "I'm secretly in love with you!"
LIAM: And Devan, why don't you tell Dren what your
secret is?
LAURA: I was going to fucking betray you.
(yelling)
TRAVIS: You are not the father!
LAURA: But I didn't want to! He made me! I didn't
want to do it! I even asked him, I'm like, can I
choose not to betray her?
LIAM: I said no. You're all bad people.
ASHLY: I know. Dren's a little dummy, so she
would've gone for it.
TRAVIS: You could've lived, man.
ASHLY: Fuck no, I would've died, please.
LAURA: That was awesome.
LIAM: I wanted an evil campaign, I wanted to play
it, no one would make it for me, so I made it
myself.
(cheering)
LAURA: We're all assholes.
LIAM: Thanks, everybody, you guys, the five of
you, and thanks, everybody, for watching if you
hung in to the end. I know it was long. I don't
know how to balance anything or know how long
things take. I threw a bunch of spaghetti at the
wall. But it was fun.
LAURA: You done good, bro.
ASHLY: You done real good.
LIAM: Thank you.
TRAVIS: Thank you to Loot Crate!
(cheering)
LAURA: Oh boy, Harley Quinn!
LIAM: Matt, Marisha, Taliesin, come home, and is
it Thursday yet?
[music]