MATT: Hello, ladies and gentlemen! Thank you all
for coming to our silly little Critical Role panel
this afternoon. How's everyone feeling this
Thursday afternoon?
(cheering)
MATT: That makes me happy.
OFF-SCREEN: I love you!
MATT: Oh my god, I love you, too! Getting here was
an adventure, but we're here. It's been a
delightfully chaotic start to Comic-Con, as I
think we've all kind of experienced, but let's go
ahead and get this panel on the road, work it
forward. First introduction here to our fantastic
human gunslinger of the party, Taliesin Jaffe as
Percy!
(cheering)
MATT: Following up on that, we have our
delightfully awkward but extremely powerful
half-elf druid, Keyleth, played by Marisha Ray!
(cheering)
MATT: Currently rocking a clay sculpture that a
fan made of the airboat in past episodes, so
that's awesome. Coming up next, we have our sly,
charismatic, and wink-inducing ranger, Vex, played
by Laura Bailey! Come on stage.
(cheering)
MATT: Wherever you'd like. Following that-- oh,
stop taking pictures, Tiberius. We have our
dragonborn sorcerer, Tiberius, played by Orion
Acaba. Come on stage, buddy.
(cheering)
MATT: I figured if someone would hit the couch, it
would probably be you, so well done. Following
that, we have the twin brother to our fantastic
ranger here, the other dangerous, stealthy
half-elf rogue, Vax, played by Liam O'Brien. Come
on up, buddy.
(cheering)
MATT: And rounding out the rest of our forum here,
we have the extremely strong in the body, not so
much the mind, goliath barbarian, played by Travis
Willingham, Grog!
(cheering)
MATT: Hi, guys. I myself, I am your humble dungeon
master, Matthew Mercer. Thank you very much for
coming. I guess I'll go ahead and I'll take a seat
over here. We'll share mics, we've got a mic here,
we've got a mic there, and Orion's rocking the
front stage. There you go! It's nap time for
Orion. All right, so I guess we'll begin with a--
What the heck?!
(screaming and cheering)
MATT: You guys did this. No, I had no idea! All
right, so we didn't know she was here. We thought
she was in New York, away forever. These are real
tears, ladies and gentlemen. Oh my god, that's
amazing. We've got more mics, perfect!
MARISHA: Ashley, what are you doing here?
ASHLEY: Oh hey, Grog. Hi! It's a long story, I'll
tell you guys after.
MATT: Well, I'm glad you could make it.
ASHLEY: Hey, I'm glad to be here.
MATT: Everybody, this is Ashley Johnson, our
wonderful cleric, Pike.
(cheering)
MATT: All right, wow, so after that emotional
moment. So, for those of you who don't know, we
are Critical Role. We're a bunch of voice actors,
actors that have been playing Dungeons and Dragons
together for going on almost three years, now. And
we recently had the pleasure to be approached by
Geek and Sundry to have us begin bringing our
wondrous little personal adventure out to you guys
via their Twitch channel. And we've done 16 episodes
so far, and the outpouring of appreciation for it
and the connection we've made with you guys in the
community has been absolutely electric and
amazing. I think all of us agree with that,
definitely. But yeah, it's been a really
interesting journey. Let's go down on the end here
and talk a little bit about ourselves and what we
do and how we got pulled into this craziness.
TALIESIN: Oh god, I've got to start? Really?
MARISHA: I mean, everyone's voice actors, so we
can get that out of the way, right?
LIAM: Probably also talk about how you got into
D&D, at what point in your life. Add that in.
TALIESIN: Okay, I can do that. That's much more
interesting than voice acting. My name is Taliesin
Jaffe. I got into roleplaying in high school
with-- well, I had funny hair and wore a lot of
black, so I played Vampire the Masquerade. And I
LARPed. I was a big LARPer, for those-- I don't
think I have to explain that. And had a group of
friends in high school, and we would do everything
from weird games, like we played GURPs and Rifts
and Cyberpunk and all those games in the early
90s, late 80s. And it had a been a while for me,
and then I got pulled into a completely different
game with Matt and a few friends of ours, so we
played for about a year and a half, and then we'll
get to the story of Liam's game, but I got pulled
into the game that was the first game, and it has
ruined me for every other game I could possibly
want to play.
MARISHA: Yes, I guess I first got into tabletop
roleplaying in particular with Matt. Matt was
actually my first DM six, seven years ago,
approximately. And I've had other games, I was a
part of a Buffy the Vampire Slayer tabletop RPG,
which was super fun. Yup. It's a good game. I was
a pyromancer, it was awesome. I will say, though,
once you have Matt, it's hard to go back. Once you
go Matt, you can't go back. It works. Shut up,
don't judge me, Travis.
MATT: That's not becoming a t-shirt.
OFF-SCREEN: Yes, it is!
MARISHA: Chris, hi! How are you? I didn't see you.
Oh, and it's Erika! Hi, you guys!
ORION: Okay, how about you, Laura?
LAURA: Oh, hey. Oh, hi guys. Hi, I'm Laura Bailey.
RPGs, huh? So the first time I ever played pencil
and paper RPG was with this group, because of that
guy. I always played RPGs, like I'm a big video
game fan, I'm a geek for that, and yeah, and so I
always chose RPGs as what I wanted to play, so
surprisingly, it wasn't anything new for me once
we started playing. I fell into it really, really
fast, because I was accustomed to all of that.
LIAM: Some would say instantly.
LAURA: Insta. It was so much fun. It was only
supposed to be a one-off game, when we started
this, and we all had so much fun playing together
that it was like, we can't stop this. When's the
next time we can get together and do it again and
again and again? Yeah, it was epic.
LIAM: The longer version of that story, for
anybody who doesn't know it, is several years
ago--
ORION: That's Liam O'Brien, everybody.
LIAM: Oh hi, I'm Liam O'Brien. Hi. Just so happy.
Several years ago, I was directing Matt for the
first time for a game. We knew each other, but not
as well as we do now, and he would come in, and
every time he came in, like a drug pusher, be
like, "You should come. We could do a one-off, I
"could play with you. You played when you were
younger. We should play together."
MATT: Hey, man, roll some dice. It'll be fun. What
could possibly happen? I won't tell your parents.
LIAM: And I refused every time, I said, "Oh,
that'd be great, but I got brand-new kids," 'cause
I had brand-new kids. And then fast-forward to
several years later, where Sam Riegel, who's not
here, and I do a dorky podcast, and we do
something dorky every time, and I thought, one
time, we'll play a pen and paper roleplaying game,
and we asked these yahoos, and we played the game,
and it was a blast, and then everyone left and I
went home that night and went, "Oh man. That was
"so good. How do I tell them I want to do it
again?" And I sent out an e-mail and nobody
responded for a long time.
LAURA: That is true, actually, yeah.
LIAM: Couple of days, so I felt like I had a big
red N on my forehead, but then the answers
trickled in and we kept playing, and now we're
here and there's a baseball field behind us!
(cheering)
MATT: Take that, sports.
LAURA: Yeah, sportsball.
ASHLEY: I shouldn't do that. What they do here is
really awesome.
MATT: No, this is great.
ASHLEY: Yeah, I got involved because of this guy.
They had already played a game, one game, and then
I remember we had a party for a friend of ours,
Troy Baker. It was his birthday, and you guys were
talking about it. And I was like, "Oh, dang, I
want to play!" And then we started and we were
putting our character sheets together, and then I
sent you, I was like, "Yeah, I think my name
"should be, I don't know, Pike Trickfoot?" You were
so helpful and emailing me back. Then the first
game, because I'd never really played anything like
this before. And I'm sure you guys can tell in the
game, I'm always like, wait, what is this? Or,
what does this mean? I was in awe of everybody,
because they were doing voices, and I was trying
to keep up, but I couldn't really. And I was like,
I want to do this all the time. Every night. Can
we? And then we started doing it all the time.
Honestly, some of the best nights of my life have
been from this game.
OFF-SCREEN: Love you, Ashley!
ASHLEY: Love you.
MATT: Orion?
TRAVIS: Oh, you? Me? Hi!
LAURA: Hi.
TRAVIS: I'm Travis. I play Grog. Super smart. I
never played any--
LAURA: Also, ale.
TRAVIS: Huh? Also, ale. I never played any RPGs
before this, but I had asked around our little
voice actor community for years, like Yuri
Lowenthal and Liam and Matt Mercer. I think the
first time I asked you about it was on a mo-cap
session. I was like, "I hear you do the Master of
"Dungeonings, what does that look like?" And he
started to tell me, and I couldn't concentrate on
anything beside the fact that I wanted to do it.
Then Liam had that birthday party, and I came 20
minutes late. I walked in to Laura being extremely
posh and bargaining with somebody for something.
Liam was going, "Yes, of course. Oh, hello, sir."
I was terrified. I think Matt had said, "Just
"prepare your class and your race." I said,
"Goliath barbarian."He goes, "Okay, so what's your
"name?" I was like, "Um. Grog." He was, "Grog, what
do you do?" I was like, "I make fine leather
"boots." He goes, "Okay, bootmaker Grog," and we
were off to the races. But that has led us to
this, somehow.
ORION: Greetings and salutations, everyone. I'm
Orion Acaba. I'm a voice actor. Did you guys--?
Okay. That's enough, Keyleth. I'm a big Magic The
Gathering guy. Also with Travis and Laura, I
hadn't played D&D before Liam's birthday. He was
like, "Hey, we're doing this D&D thing." I was
like, "D&D. Okay." I've known Liam the longest.
Maybe you the longest, but he's like a brother to
me, so I'll do whatever. I was like, "Yeah, I can
play and stuff." That led to a bond and a
friendship and experience that I can't replicate
or pay any money or do anything to even compare to
anything else to. This game has literally become
the most important thing and most fun thing in my
life. Every week. Through time and bullshitting
around, we'd find and tweeted stuff and randomly
in our privacy of our own game, and fucking now
we're-- what the fuck is going on?
LIAM: Let's play ball!
ORION: Scanlan sends his regards as he's too busy
fucking whores. Oh, that's right. Sorry, everyone.
Matthew Mercer is great. Now you talk.
(cheering)
MATT: You have disadvantage for the remainder of
the panel. Yeah, that's the story of how it all came
together. There are few things I enjoy more than
having people converse with me and say like, "I'm
"interested in role-playing games, but I don't know
how they work or what they're about. I hear it's a
"weird thing." And I'm like, "Well, kind of, but
the best kind of weird." Knowing that, once these
people, especially being geared towards
performance arts and putting ourselves in a
different place mentally for a lot of our job,
it'll be an easy transition for them to get into
it, watching them all suddenly click. That moment
of, oh, I can do anything. Yes. Well, you can try
anything. That doesn't mean you'll do it, but you
can certainly try. But yeah, it's been an absolute
wonderful joy watching this game grow and the
community grow since we started the stream, and
yeah, it's probably one of my favorite things,
period, ever in my life so far. The fact that we
get to share it with you guys now is even more
amazing, and you guys have been incredible this
entire journey, so thank you for that, guys,
sincerely.
(cheering)
LAURA: It's amazing the amount of times that we've
had conversations because when you're playing a
game, we all see it as real. We've lived those
experiences for so long that that world exists and
our characters exist and those experiences exist,
but only between us, and then as soon as we were
able to bring it to Geek and Sundry, and now you
guys are taking part in it too, all of a sudden
it's a real thing, if that makes any sense, to
know that you guys know who Percy is
is phenomenal, and that anybody loves Trinket as much
as I do. That means so much!
LIAM: It's like we were all quietly, privately
going crazy when we were just playing a game, but
now you guys are saying the weird whispers that we
heard in our head. You're parroting them back to
us. We're like, "Oh, Percy is real! He's real! I
know he's real!"
LAURA: We're all going to be insane in the next
five years, I know it.
MARISHA: Yeah, it does feel like being the little
kid who's like, "No, there's a monster under our
"bed." And everyone was like, "Oh yeah. No, you're
right. There totally is a monster kicking it under
"there." And you're like, "What?! They see it
too?!" And I feel like that's true every time we
get a piece of fanart that comes in, because I
know personally I was afraid-- I was like, I hope
this story translates. I hope what we see they can
see. But every time we see a piece of fanart or
anything like that, it's like, oh yeah, no,
that's-- yep, that's Gilmore. Holy shit. They see
it too!
MATT: And on that note, too, the fanart, the
letters, the recently penned Critmas that has
happened a few times, it's a strange experience,
because for us, just a humility standpoint, it's
like, why are they buying us things? They don't
need to do that! But it becomes this wonderful
connection point where we get the opportunity
through that to also realize how much it means to
other people through these letters and these
people that donate to our charity, 826LA, by the
way, which is an amazing charity.
(cheering)
MATT: You guys have done an amazing job helping us
support that, too. And it's been a really, really
incredible experience to know that something that
means so much to us also is starting to mean so
much to other people as well, and it's amazing.
LIAM: It's nice to have a show about D&D, huh?
(cheering)
MATT: We're having this strange tabletop
renaissance now, where you used to keep that stuff
close to your chest, you'd mention, "Yeah, I play
Dungeons and Dragons," you'd be kind of quiet
about it. Now we can say it a little more proudly,
and as opposed to people saying, "Yeah, D&D,
"that's nerd stuff!" they're like, "Cool, when do
you play?"
ORION: Yeah, I have to say, one of my favorite
aspects of what this is, is we have-- and I said
this to one of our fans, I signed something for
her-- is Travis is one of my favorite things about
the show. Tiberius is my favorite thing about the
show. But Travis as a human being, there's a lot
of-- it breaks down those stupid walls where it's
like, no, it's not a bunch of introverts in
somebody's basement. We have a big, hulking mass
of a man, you know? That can beat all of us up.
And he's there being as big of a geek as we are.
And it breaks down the thing where women can't
play, because you have these three gorgeous,
badass women kicking ass and also playing Dungeons
and Dragons. A lot of great things about this show
that I love.
ASHLEY: I remember I was introducing you to a
friend of mine, and completely out of context, I
was like-- and this was still when it was kind of
new, and I was like, "Oh! This is Matt, he's my
"dungeon master." And then I kept moving on, and
they looked at me, and I was like, "Oh, wow, that
"sounded really weird."
MATT: What you didn't see was me the whole time
behind you going like--
(laughter)
ASHLEY: I was like, "What I mean is, we play D&D,
that sounded so not what it is."
MATT: I can show you the velvet room if you like.
TRAVIS: Matt pulls out a d20, he's like, "Roll
it."
(laughter)
LAURA: Mr. Mercer's been waiting for you.
MATT: I'd forgotten about that. Well, before we get to
the Q&A session, is there anything else you guys
wanted to talk about here, particularly while
we're on a baseball field talking about Dungeons
and Dragons?
TRAVIS: We're on a baseball field!
(cheering)
TRAVIS: Stand up if you're wearing one of our
amazing Critical Role shirts, because they're all
over the place. (counting) That's amazing. We love
you. We love you for buying those! It's insane
that you have them and we love you.
MATT: We have original generation, we have the
second generation release, too. We have the new
generation, which, by the way, the new red shirts
you see with the Critical Role logo, designed by
Taliesin Jaffe over here, Percy designed those
himself.
ASHLEY: I was wearing my shirt on the plane, but
then I dropped my cinnamon roll with-- you guys
can probably tell on the show, I'm constantly
eating, because I'm always hungry.
ORION: So that was a cinnamon roll fail?
ASHLEY: Yeah, but it was a cinnamon roll, and it
was a Cinnabon with the fresh sauce. All right, I
can't wear this to the panel.
MATT: We wouldn't have judged.
TALIESIN: I love that today seven people have come
up to me with this intense look in their eyes, and
they've come up to me very quietly and been like,
"Hey. Briarwoods, man. Wow. Wow."
(laughter)
TALIESIN: This is weird private issues in my life
that I'm like, "Yeah, I know! Wow!" It is fabulous
to finally have an audience. We've been playing in
this little room knowing that there are people
there in theory, but to actually--
MARISHA: It's kind of like a reality show, but
we're not putting ourselves through the wringer,
we're putting our characters through it, so it's
great.
TALIESIN: Better them than us.
TRAVIS: People going, "Oh, Keyleth's mom, man,"
you're like, "Yeah. Wait, what?" Right, that's a
real thing. That's a real thing!
MARISHA: I will say-- no, you.
LAURA: Wait--
ORION: For the record, I'm really shitty at math,
so.
MARISHA: What I was actually going to say was, I
am actually really impressed at the Critters as a
whole and the Critter Nation. We had an awesome
story that we heard from our friend Dani who's a
Critter.
ASHLEY: Oh man, hi!
MARISHA: I know, right? Hi! Yeah, she came out
here and then was talking to another Critter, and
he was like, "You're in Southern California? Well,
I know people at Disneyland, so I can get you
"passes to Disneyland." And it was just because
they like Critical Role.
LAURA: Be a Critter, go to Disneyland, that's the
moral of the story.
MARISHA: So you guys are awesome because you guys
are taking care of each other, and I'm really
loving the communities that I'm seeing are being
built and the friendships that are being built
around this.
MATT: And the other campaigns that are coming out
of this. All you guys who have already been
playing or starting your own games and tweeting at
us your adventures and your stories and your
characters, it's so awesome to see that
continue to grow.
TALIESIN: It's like the internet, but nice! It's
so crazy.
ORION: Yeah, it's super weird! I've been YouTubing
comedy stuff for a bit. They're mean. And our
people are not mean and they're really intelligent
and compassionate. It's fucki-- really great.
LAURA: What is happening?
MATT: I don't know.
LIAM: We're all kind of playing ourselves, people.
Let's be real.
MATT: Yeah, Tiberius's wisdom, maybe not that far
off.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: My intelligence is still six.
LAURA: Well, yeah.
MARISHA: Questions? Q&A?
MATT: Let's go ahead and move on to the Q&A
section of this. We have a mic available, I
believe it's somewhere?
MARISHA: Yeah, is there a mic floating around?
ASHLEY: (singing) I believe there's a mic.
LIAM: I got it, I got it.
MARISHA: Liam's got it.
LIAM: Put your hands up if you've got questions.
ORION: Vax is stealthing into the crowd.
LAURA: You have to sneak through, though, they
won't be able to--
MATT: Microphone-microphone-microphone.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: I have a question for Orion. When
you wanted that thing from Scanlan, how long did
it take you to think that up, to do that on that
board?
ORION: I wanted that thing since he got it, and
really--
LAURA: And he wouldn't give it to you.
ORION: No. And I was going to approach it several
ways, and I talked to Matthew a lot outside the
game. I never metagame, but I get really excited.
I've been playing RPGs since I was ten, and so
half the time I think of strategy as opposed to
the player. I get really into that. Matthew's
really good at, "Think of who you're dealing with,
and then act accordingly." With Sam, he's an
interesting fellow to begin with. I was going to
pummel him to death. Really to get it back, at first.
MARISHA: To which I was like, "Remember, your
party would not take kindly to that. I don't think
"Keyleth would be able to take your back on that
one."
ORION: No, she wouldn't like that. So I didn't.
That's the simple Silence, Telekinesis and then
Fireball him to death. The thing is, I'm a UCB guy
(Upright Citizens Brigade), he's also a funny guy.
There you go, UCB! He's funny, I'm funny, I'll
use funny. Then it was empty chalkboard. I was like,
"Math? That'll be funny. I'll fucking come up with
something." I figured more bees with honey. Or
flies, I have no idea how that saying goes. You
know what I was trying to say, right?
LIAM: It's the honey.
ORION: Use the honey instead. I thought of that
for a month, of how to get that back.
LAURA: It was worth it.
LIAM: You mean you thought of that right there. In
the moment. It suddenly burst into your mind, and
you did it right there.
ORION: For the math thing, yes.
ASHLEY: That math moment, it was one of my
favorites.
TRAVIS: We love Scanlan, by the way. Every time he
comes up with a song, I ask him afterwards. I'm
like, "Did you have two songs on retainer that you
were going to sing during the show?"
LIAM: You guys have a baseball field behind you.
You look amazing.
MARISHA: Shut up. Oh my god!
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Everyone looks very pretty. You
touched on this a bit whenever you were talking
about how you started playing. How did you all
come up with your names individually?
LIAM: That's a good question.
MATT: Mine's my professional name. I use it for
most things. It's easy for me to hear when people
say it because it's my name.
ASHLEY: Oh man. I had been trying to put together
this webseries ages ago that was basically a
post-zombie apocalypse type of thing. Then cut to
a little while later, I work on a game called Last
Of Us, which was basically the same thing. But my
character's name in the webseries--
MATT: By the way, how amazing was she in that?
ASHLEY: Thank you. So, the webseries that my
character's name was Pike in it. I just like that
name, and I honestly don't know where Trickfoot
came from. I can't remember it.
MATT: Your imagination.
ASHLEY: I was like, "True, tritch, trutch, Pike
Tr-- Oh, Trickfoot!" I don't know. There was
nothing interesting about it.
LAURA: I, like I said, like to play RPGs a lot,
and Vex was always a name that I would go to for
my characters I would create in those games. Then
I always think that elves need to have apostrophes
in their names. Because in every RPG like Dragon
Age, every game that I play, I recreate characters
like ten times before I stick with one, so there's
a list to level four of characters--
TRAVIS: True story.
LAURA: Yeah, Vex is always in that list. There's
other names as well that I might get to. Someday
in this game. Hopefully not.
ORION: Wait, you did that for Skyrim too, didn't
you?
LAURA: Yes. Of course. I'm not Vex in Skyrim
because I feel like Vex is sacred now. I don't
want to use Vex on-- Is that weird? Then, when me
and Liam-- Okay. So here's the thing. I'm getting
off-subject. When I got invited to the game, Liam
had already taken rogue, and I wanted to be a
rogue. He had already taken half-elf and I wanted
to be a half-elf. And I was like, "What the heck,
"man, you're so stealthy." Then I remembered that
we actually are twins, and I was like, "Maybe we
"should be twins in the game as well."
LIAM: You said your name was Vex. So I said, "Oh,
I'll be Vax then."
LAURA: Perfect.
LIAM: That's not what you said. You said, "But my
name's short for Vex'halia, so you got to come
"up--" And I went, "I'll be Vax'ildan." Without a
beat, you went, "Oh, that's pretty good."
LAURA: That's really good. What's funny is, for
the first year you kept looking at me like,
"What's my name? How do I spell my name?"
TRAVIS: We still don't get it right.
LAURA: Is there an H in it? I don't know.
MARISHA: I actually still use Vaxy-stabby to
remember that. Cause we said vaxstab, like
backstab. So he does vaxstab as rogue.
LIAM: There you go. Now you all have that.
MARISHA: Vaxstab.
LAURA: That's an easy way to remember.
MARISHA: Vex-dex? Yeah, that works. I'll buy that
for a dollar. Workshop it. I also really like
elven names, but I'm like, "I feel that my name
should have meaning." I don't know why. I'll tend
to pick a character.
For Keyleth I was like, "She's an Air Druid, so
I'll name her something airy. So I'll type in
"'air.'" I'll go to an elven dictionary and I'll
type in, "air." It'll pop out all these elven
words for air. Or if my character was angsty, I'll
put in "angsty," and it'll pull out all these
elven words for angsty. And I picked something
based on that. So I think Keyleth was actually
originally spelled with a Q. It was a Que-- It
meant like a zephyr. It meant like a wind, so I
switched it and renamed it and got Keyleth.
LAURA: So your name actually means fart, and you
just don't know it?
MATT: Exactly. Yeah. In Sylvan.
MARISHA: No, it means silent but deadly.
TRAVIS: What's the explanation behind yours?
TALIESIN: Oh boy.
ORION: Yeah, what's your name again?
TALIESIN: Percival Fredrickstein von Musel
Klossowski de Rolo III.
ORION: They call him Percy, though.
TALIESIN: They call me Percy. I decided, after I
had an image of the character I wanted to play, I
wanted him to have a ridiculous name because I
love ridiculous names. It's actually a mixture of
three things, one of which is a character. I was a
child actor, also. One of them is the name of a
character I played as a child actor. The other
section of it is the name of an anime character
from Legend Of The Galactic Heroes. And the third
chunk of it is actually a friend of mine, who I
will not name, but who has the greatest name on
earth. Yes, I'll leave it a mystery because he
doesn't know that I stole his name for my little
D&D game.
MARISHA: And now we're trademarking it.
TALIESIN: And thankfully he's 80 years old and
lives in Italy, so he doesn't have to know about
this. And I want to keep it that way. That's
basically where my character's name came from.
This is a mix of all three of those things.
LIAM: Somewhere in Tuscany, a little old Italian
man is standing up in front of his computer, and
swearing in Italian.
TALIESIN: He types all in caps, too, so I'll never
know how angry he is.
TRAVIS: Other than just coming up with it because
I hadn't made a name yet, because I'm an idiot, I
loved Monkey Island, the game, and I remember that
was my introduction to Grog. I always figured that
a barbarian needs a really simple name. So Grog
was the first stupid light that turned on in my
brain. And that's what I am. And you came up with
my last name.
MATT: Strongjaw, yeah.
TRAVIS: That's right. Because I got possessed or
something at one point. It was bad. You.
LIAM: I'm done. Tiberius.
TALIESIN: Bring us home.
ORION: Tiberius, I named for two reasons. The
first is, Tiberius Caesar is Caesar's father. I
wanted the character, because it comes from a
political height to your family, to have that
weight behind it. And Stormwind--
TRAVIS: It's about farting.
LIAM: That's another fart reference.
ORION: This is, yes. I fart a lot. No. I was
actually--
ASHLEY: Who doesn't?
ORION: At the time, I was cracking the hell out of
Skyrim. Again. It came out, and you were passing,
and playing it again when we started the campaign,
and I think it's a place in Skyrim, or it's like
the Stormwind, or something like that. I was like,
yeah, Stormwind, awesome.
MARISHA: But I would like to point out, we didn't
even realize that you had done that until a few
weeks ago.
ORION: Yeah.
MARISHA: And we were like, ah! Because you were
playing Elder Scrolls Online. That's what it was.
ORION: Thank you. Two and a half years and some
change years pass, yeah, I'm really creative. I've
totally-- It's really hard not to curse, so I'm
trying not to. I was like, wow, yeah, I came up
with all that myself. And then I started playing
Elder Scrolls Online again, bad. Love that game. I
was, Dragonknight, cool. Fans were, hey, just try
Dragonknight. And then I started playing and I'm
like, "Draconic Power, Draconia, oh shit, I ripped
off Skyrim the whole time! I'm not creative at
"all!" Thanks for pointing that out, Marisha.
LIAM: Any more questions?
MATT: Real fast, I did want to give a shout-out to
our wonderful gnome Scanlan, who is apparently
watching from home and wants an ego stroke.
ALL: Hi, Scanlan.
ASHLEY: We miss you.
LIAM: All right. What?
MATT: We have about 15 minutes left of the panel,
so we want to make this questions we have pretty
quick answers to.
LIAM: But we're Periscoping.
(inaudible audience member)
LIAM: What each character's most heroic moment
was. On the show, any time, including the whole game?
MATT: Let's do whole game. I know Tiberius'. Want
me to tell the story?
LAURA: I feel like Matt would know our most--
MATT: I know a lot of them, yeah. There was one
sequence. I'll make it quick. They were fighting
their first umber hulk they ever encountered in
this nest that was in this cavern up at the top of
a giant underground cave. And there was an about
170-foot drop into a lake that had an island in
the center. And they were fighting it, Grog was
trying to grab it and throw it through the hole
that dropped into this giant cavern. However, it
bull rushed him and knocked him off instead. Grog
fell, took enough damage to put him unconscious
from full life, and the umber hulk then was pushed
out after him via Tiberius, and they all realized,
oh, we're all up here with a hole with no
creature. Grog's unconscious down there with an
umber hulk. He is going to die. And so Tiberius
decides he's going to jump out after him. And he
leaps through the hole, swan dive, I'm talking
Gandalf versus the Balrog style. You know, slow
plummet in darkness. I'm telling him, "You
"realize, casting Feather Fall is going to take a
really hard concentration check, and if you fail,
"you're probably going to die." And he said, "Yes.
Do it." He needed a 14 on a d20, and he rolled
exactly a 14, cast Feather Fall, landed, and
managed to stop the umber hulk in time to let the
rest of the party come down via rope. It was one
of my favorite moments for his character.
(cheering)
LAURA: It was pretty epic.
ORION: I got your back.
MATT: Anyone else?
LAURA: We thought we were going to lose two party
members at the same time. We were, like, "No! Ugh!"
MATT: Anyone else?
LAURA: Well, I got the kill on the creature that
killed Pike.
ASHLEY: You did.
LAURA: I don't get a final kill on a lot of
things, and it was like ugh, and so Pike is dead
on the ground, and I got the last shot, so I'm
moving forward shooting arrows. It was sad. Tears
falling down, screaming, "Pike!"
MARISHA: I was actually going to say, I think one
of my most heroic moments was in the same game
when Pike died, and Keyleth turned into an eagle,
and I scooped you up, and got you to the temple
first. Was it at the same time that the tower was
collapsing?
MATT: No, that was beforehand.
MARISHA: Oh, that was beforehand. Okay.
MATT: A battle with a treachery demon, by the way,
a glabrezu, for those who are in the know. I get
to say that in a panel.
ORION: Translation: He's a giant butthole.
TALIESIN: I was quite proud of the magic carpet
save. Our very first run-in with the magic carpet.
It's a very complicated story, but we found the
magic carpet out of luck while falling out of a
building and everything. Kind of worked out okay.
No one died.
MARISHA: The magic carpet was awesome, because we
were trying to use it as a parachute.
LAURA: That's right, because we were falling--
MARISHA: And it was essentially a gamble move
anyway. We were going to be like, oh, let's be--
LAURA: This carpet's never going to work, it's too
heavy.
MARISHA: Exactly. We are going to be like those
toy GI Joes that you throw over your balcony, and
it doesn't work. That's what we thought. Then
we're trying to parachute with a rug, and that's
when Matt's like, "And you float down slowly
because you learn the carpet is magic."
ASHLEY: Right before that, he goes, "Make a use
magic device roll," and we were all, "What?!" And
you screamed, "It's a flying carpet!"
LIAM: Many of you have seen this moment, because
Ashley made a video. It's online. You get a lot of
our reactions to that, real time.
ORION: That whole thing was another one of my
favorite Tiberius moments because he didn't deal
with any of it. Tiberius jumped out the window
while that shit was going down and Feather Fall to
safety while these guys had to deal with that
whole fucking thing.
TRAVIS: I did that, too. I jumped out of the
window with no Feather Fall.
ORION: They go through this whole ordeal and they
come out of this tower that's crumbling, barely
with their lives and I'm like, "Oh, hello
everyone."
TRAVIS: You go jump out of the window and I'm
like, "Great idea!" Jump out of the window. You
cast Feather Fall and I'm like, "Shit." Live and
learn!
MARISHA: (singing) I wish you would step back from
that ledge, my friend.
TRAVIS: My most heroic thing was when you crushed my
cask of ale and I avenged it by headbutting the
giant in the face. True love, people, true love.
LIAM: I don't know about heroic, but I think the
most intense moment I've had in our entire game
was sneaking in with Scanlan into the mind
flayers' little camp. You were just describing all
the things that were in the room and we were
walking quietly through the room looking at it. My
heart was going like a hamster. It was intense!
ORION: And then Sam throws shit on the dude's
face.
MARISHA: At any moment you hear us on the screen
being like, "Oh god! I'm hyperventilating! The
"adrenaline! My heart's racing! I'm shaking!"
That's all 100% real. We'll actually be like, "Oh,
"we've got to roll. Oh, I dropped it!" It's awful.
It's all real. It's good.
LIAM: Any other questions?
MARISHA: Ten minutes!
MATT: You have time for a few more, so start
getting these pretty rapid.
LIAM: Sword. Maybe take your filter out of the
way.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Thanks, man. Hey guys, how's it
going?
MATT: Good! Good question. Next? No, go ahead.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: My question isn't about D&D, it's
actually: How are you guys enjoying your time here
in San Diego or, more specifically, at Comic-Con?
What's the best, or most shocking cosplay you've
seen, or a cosplay where you guys were like, "Oh,
that's awesome!" Have you guys even seen any
cosplay, or have you been too busy?
TRAVIS: We've seen no cosplay!
MARISHA: We've been here the whole time.
MATT: I'm having a good time.
MARISHA: Yeah, we're having a great time!
TRAVIS: This sucks!
MARISHA: We have a baseball field behind us! So
that's cool.
MATT: Best cosplay I've seen here. It was a couple
years ago, I saw a really amazing Mass Effect
group that had an Urdnot Wrex that had a
functional animatronic face. It was incredible.
TALIESIN: I saw a guy dressed as Hodor with a box
of Raisin Bran on his back. It was awesome!
ORION: We've got another question.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Sorry, Orion. Hi. This is a DM
question for Matt because--
MATT: Oh hi!
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Hi! I had problems with this in
previous campaigns as a player and now as a DM
with six new players. How do you keep battle going
when players take time to roll? How can you
encourage people to keep a flow going so at the
end of the game you're like, "That was epic!"
instead of "That was math."
MATT: Right. The system helps. Our transition from
Pathfinder to Fifth Edition I did partially
because of that. Pathfinder's a great system and I
love it, but the more players you have, the more
you can get bogged down with floating modifiers.
"Wait, your Bless spells gives me plus one to
"hit and damage, and that gives me plus two to
damage, but I have a racial bonus against the
"kobolds, plus six to hit, four to damage, three to
damage." It gets to that point. Being able to
simplify the modifiers. You can homerule certain
things where you have a simple way of keeping
track of those. As a DM, keeping combat going is
just keeping your energy up. You're the guide for
everyone else, and if you start getting slow or laggy,
everyone else will follow suit. Music also helps.
I find battle music, really good sets. We can't
use any licensed stuff on the stream any more. I
had to gut my previous music selections. Good
classic Conan music works well. Lot of great
fantasy films and good soundtracks work.
MARISHA and LAURA: (horn sounds)
MATT: They know them all too well. Good music,
keeping your energy up, and making sure that when
it comes to players' turns, they know what they're
going to do. If they're not ready, you skip their
turn. You're hesitating.
LAURA: That's happened to us a few times. Before
we started streaming, he would skip our turns.
MARISHA: You would be like, "What are you going to
do?" And if we say "Uh," more than three times,
then he's like, "Nah." We'd go, "Uh, uh, uh,"
"Moving on."
MATT: Skip it or put them at the bottom of the
initiative order. Give them an incentive to be
present in the moment and already to have their
ideas ready to go. Things change in battle
sometimes. You'll get to your turn and
everything's changed in the battle dynamic. That's
also how battle works. You have to be like, "Uh!
I'm going to do this!" And you're like,
"All right!" Keeping that energy up. As the DM,
you're the holder of the flow of the story. It's a
lot of pressure on you, but keep up that energy.
Some good music. Make sure people are also putting
energy into it because you put countless hours
into that stuff! The least they can do is respect
that by being present and trying to keep up with
you.
TALIESIN: Really quick. Tell them about the
hourglass.
MATT: Also, hourglass helps! I got a nice five
minute and ten minute hourglass. Especially if
you're in a skill challenge or an event that has
more tension behind it, just putting an hourglass
on the table, turning it over and being like, "You
have this much time." "Until what?!" "You don't
"know. But what are you going to do?" You'll be
surprised how quickly in the moment every player is.
LAURA: It's terrifying. That hourglass you put
down when the lava was coming down and we had to
get out of the cavern. It was horrifying!
ORION: It adds a whole other layer of-- Another
question.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Hi, guys. What I wanted to ask--
LIAM: Get it right up there.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: What I wanted to ask is
especially for Grog and Pike since they personally
experienced this lovely thing. Was there ever a
time when you die in Matt's game where you're
afraid that this is going to be the death of the
character and they're not going to get revived
this time?
ORION: Yes!
LIAM: That's every game!
TRAVIS: When Pike died, she was crying, she was
crying, she was crying, you were crying. I was
asleep. No! Matt, you could tell he did not want
to say the things he was saying, and it was only
because we rolled extremely well when it counted
that we got that thing that brought you back to
life. Every time we go unconscious and then the
death sets in. Against the beholder thing, I was
just hoping we got around to Pike or Keyleth, so
that Greater Restoration could come around, I
wouldn't permanently be dead. There's a chance
that one of these days.
LAURA: When you were unconscious in the lava,
what? I thought he was done. If Trinket dies, I-- Yes!
ORION: In all seriousness, the K'Varn fight is a
really good example. Myself, Tiberius, was
terrified of fighting a beholder because I knew,
particularly as the only real caster of the group,
as soon as I get in the eyesight of that thing,
I'm useless. The reason that I didn't go in there
at all is because if I did, I would be no use to
anybody. I don't know the range. I'm not going to
cheat. You don't come back from disintegration!
MATT: Nope!
ORION: You don't come back from death rays!
They're called death rays for a reason! And then
he throws it at us and I'm scared for a while.
ASHLEY: That was the most nervous I'd ever been
in any game we've played. I think that's why it
was such a silent game. I was just like-- I just
never wanted it to be my turn because I was like,
"Uh! Well!"
TRAVIS: We didn't even talk in voices.
ASHLEY: I know. There were no voices.
MATT: You're twice the reason we still have Grog.
He technically would have died twice that battle
over.
LAURA: That is true.
ASHLEY: That's true. Oh, Grog!
LAURA: I went back and watched the stream of that
to see if you could see our hands shaking as much
as they were because all of us were terrified
during that fight.
MATT: Yeah. That was a crazy boss battle. What
were you going to say, Liam?
LAURA: And then the second one was even harder
than that! What the heck, Matt?!
MATT: That was less of a boss battle and more of a
scenario-based challenge. You walked into the
center of an illithid colony and freed them of
their oppressor!
MARISHA: Exactly! We're their saviors!
TALIESIN: We had a buddy!
ORION: More like a butthole.
MATT: Lessons were learned, people.
MARISHA: By the way, this is essentially a glimpse
into our time after the show cuts. It's us yelling
and being like, "Why did you do that?! You could
have died! Don't you scare me like that again!"
Feel like a protective mom being like, slamming
on the brakes.
ORION: One more question?
MATT: We have time for one more really fast,
rapid-paced question. We'll answer and cruise
through it. We have a minute left and then we have
to run.
LIAM: As Orion is running out, please take a
moment to appreciate the fact that we've been
talking about Dungeons & Dragons for an hour in
front of a baseball stadium.
(cheering)
LIAM and MARISHA: Our time is now!
AUDIENCE MEMBER: All right guys, real quick. Same
time next year?
MATT: Same time next year? We're down!
LAURA: Yeah!
ASHLEY: It's a date!
MARISHA: We brought sleeping bags.
MATT: We'd be happy to.
MARISHA: Yeah, we'll be here.
LAURA: You guys are awesome.
ASHLEY: All hail!
MARISHA: Oh, Ify!
IFY: Question for the DM. I heard rumors that
there might be a little space for a sellsword of
some type. If you got the gold for it, I've got
Regina and Linda waiting by my sacks of gold.
MATT: Classic dwarven request!
MARISHA: Money talks and bullshit walks.
MATT: We shall see if the adventures of Vox
Machina mind their way towards Vox Moronica. Guys,
that is the end of our panel. I want to thank you
all so much for coming!
(cheering)