MATT: Welcome, everyone, to a kind of Critical
Role. (laughs) Critical Rejects, and/or the
delightful return of some interesting characters
and some fresh faces you'll see here in a second.
Tonight, as part of the Extra Life Charity Stream,
we're going to be running a one-shot game,
continuing the current crazed adventures of the
illustrious Vox Moronica. (laughs) It should be
some interesting fun in that regard. Let's see, I
don't think we have much else to announce, other
than we're going for our next goal at 60,000.
ZAC: If we hit it, Felicia has promised to come do
a Rock Band concert for us.
MATT: Felicia is going to do a Rock Band concert
if we hit 60k tonight. I'm vying to maybe be the
drummer for that, because I'm pretty good at
drums, and by that I mean I'll destroy them. Good
or bad, you'll find out, but let's see if we hit
60k. Felicia will do that, it would be awesome.
You guys have already been fantastic, blowing
through the goals as we have, so we'll see how
much this momentum of positive awesomeness we can
carry through to the end of the stream tonight.
And as part of that, let's go ahead and bring ourselves
into the mood for some Critical Rejects.
[dramatic music]
MATT: Okay. Welcome. For those who weren't here
for the initial, completely improvised
introduction of Vox Moronica, these wonderful
characters, we have Dan Casey here who plays Salty
Pete. If you want to give a brief little
description of your character and what you're about.
DAN: For those who don't know, I'm a pirate. Well,
formerly a pirate. My name's Salty Pete, some call
me Sam, Money Sam if you're this guy over here.
And I am trying to get my ship back. I lost it in
a bet. I play for pink slips, and I'm missing a
few fingers, which you may remember from our
previous adventure. They were unceremoniously cut
off. Classic, I know. Classic times. That's me in
a nutshell.
MATT: Fantastic.
DAN: This is me in a mimed nutshell. I'll be here
all night.
MATT: All right, and following that up, we have in
the center over here the illustrious Snugglelord,
if you want to go ahead and give us a rundown of
what you're all about.
ZAC: Well, you can call me Snugglelord.
DAN: (laughs) He just did!
ZAC: Damn it! That was my intro. I'm a warlock
tiefling who used to be the prince of a land, and
I impregnated all the impregnable, and I got
bored, and given the strong word of my wonderful
and empowering leader, the Shathrum-- my god, per
se-- I decided to leave and go on a great journey
to find these riches that the Shathrum had
promised me. And that's when I picked up these
dum-dums and paid them to be my personal
bodyguards because I don't like to mess with the
riff-raff and things like that.
MATT: Fantastic. That is our illustrious
Snugglelord. And to his left we have, returning,
the wondrous, talented, and very forceful
personality--
IFY: Ulfgar Fireforge, baby. Money talks, bullshit
walks. Ex-pit fighter, now I'm a sellsword. Bring
the money to the table and Imma take it and Imma
do whatever you need me to do. Whatever, no
questions asked, just put the money on the table, and
we'll discuss the details after that. But keep it
coming. Yeah!
MATT: That's Ulfgar. All righty. On the other
table we have three-- well, characters in a bit.
We'll get to the introductions when they become
part of the story, but for now we have three of
our talented members of Vox Machina, and the
regular Critical Role crew will be jumping into
some new characters tonight that will be unveiled
later. Go ahead and introduce yourselves real fast.
MARISHA: Our characters or ourselves?
MATT: No, just yourselves.
MARISHA: Oh, hello, I'm Marisha Ray, and you can
catch us on Critical Role on Thursday nights, and
I'm a voice actor, and actor, and host, and all
that stuff, and today I'm playing D&amp;D.
MATT: Rocking.
LIAM: Hi, I'm Liam O'Brien.
ORION: Hi, Liam O'Brien is an amazing voice actor.
He's done a lot of amazing things in a lot of
amazing projects.
LIAM: Aww.
ORION: I'm DBM and your mind will be blown. I'm
Orion Acaba, who is far less impressive, but also
awesome. I'm a voice actor, also on Critical Role,
who-- I was in Final Fantasy, okay?
MATT: Thank you. Awesome. Great introductions, all
right. I do want to talk about the donation aspect
of tonight's game, or has that already been
established?
ZAC: The chat--The Shathrum is informing itself?
Yes. They are aware if they look in the Shathrum
for the "moderators" of the spoken word of thy
lord. I don't even know how to spin this. If you
donate 500 dollars, a message may appear that
could affect the outcome of the game.
IFY: Ayo, I just got that play on words. That's a
real good play on words now that I figured it out.
In my head. I'm on board.
DAN: Classic moderators. Clerics. This fucking
guy.
MATT: And on that note, let's go ahead and jump in
and begin tonight's game. So... Salty Pete.
Actually, the Snugglelord I believe has a custom
miniature. Is that in the studio at the moment?
ZAC: Oh, the miniature? Oh my god, I forgot it.
You know, I was here a little late last night and
didn't bring it like an idiot. I'm never going to
hear the end of it now.
MATT: That's okay. We'll use this for you in the
meantime, but--
ZAC: Okay, thank you.
DAN: But if we get to 70,000 he will leave the
studio. He will go home, get it, come back.
MATT: That's okay. You'll only hear about it on
Twitter. So. To begin. Salty Pete, Snugglelord,
and Ulfgar, having done some dubious, yet
strangely publically lauded deeds in the recent
months, enjoyed a small period of fleeting coin
surplus where they drank and gambled away most of
their hard-earned bounties. This period of hard
luck, almost seemingly brought on by the mildly
antagonistic scoundrel Shendo McCree, has you
nearing doing far dirtier work than you were used
to, which, that'd be quite dirty based on your
past history.
ZAC: I seem to have forgotten what some of those
things were. Could you elaborate a little bit? How
dirty are we talking here?
MATT: Well, things you've done in the past
involved, from what the public knows, saving a
small village from a poisonous arcane sand golem
and some artefact beneath. On the outside and not
known so well, you burned half the village down,
you nearly threatened to kill the few survivors
that were there, and took what little bit of gold
remained in the pockets of those completely
distraught villagers.
DAN: But we did save that woman from the house.
MATT: You did. You did. You're right, I take it
back. However. Currently ailing from the immediate
lack of funds, you sit about the raucous,
alcohol-misted tavern known as Verian's Beer Den,
drinking what remains from the inside of your coin
purses, and currently discussing amongst
yourselves how the hell to pull yourselves out of
this looming debt.
DAN: How are we going to pull ourselves out of
this looming debt?
(laughter)
DAN: It's just looming!
ZAC: Well, if you had done what I had asked you to
do, which is to communicate with these peasants
and possibly find us some good bounty work, or at
least something--
DAN: No one wants to talk to a man with seven
fingers. No one!
ZAC: Valid point. How about-- Will you tape on
another finger, maybe, perchance?
DAN: Ah, yeah, that's not suspicious at all.
IFY: I mean, if you want this finger I'm still
wearing around my neck, I mean, you can have it
back, but...
DAN: No. It looks good. It completes the outfit.
IFY: Thank you.
MATT: All right. If I could have you guys all roll
a perception check real fast. Go ahead and roll a
d20, add your perception skill to the d20 roll.
DAN: Nine.
IFY: 21.
DAN: Very perceptive!
MATT: Snugglelord.
DAN: Perception is right here. That is three.
ZAC: 19.
MATT: 19. Okay. While Salty Pete is currently
staring at the lowly stumps of what used to be his
digits on one hand, the two of you notice on the
far side of the bar, a young girl, maybe 16 or so,
rushes into the tavern from the back with a hooded
cloak covering most of her features. She runs over
to the tavern owner behind the bar, a rather
robust-looking gentleman in his mid-30s, big
square chin, Gaston in appearance, and a bit of
swagger to how he runs this establishment. This
being the Verian character. She runs up to him and
hands him a piece of parchment, talking to him for
a bit. You can't make out the actual speech, and
they're too far to make out what the lips are
saying, but she hands him the parchment and they
speak for a bit. Verian then reaches down and
hands her a little bit of gold. Ulfgar, you
recognize the amount of gold passed over, as you
are very tuned in to the presence of gold.
(laughter)
MATT: Five gold pieces have been passed on to this
young girl. She immediately nods, pulls her hood
up even closer, and darts back out the door she
entered from.
MARISHA: She was just getting a dime bag. It's
fine.
ZAC: Were you checking out an underage woman, or
was something else going on in that situation?
IFY: No, silly, I was checking out that gold over
there, man. I don't care about women. Just gold.
ZAC: What gold are you speaking of?
IFY: There's some gold in that pouch that she gave
to him. Now, I'm about to go over there and I'm
going to seduce him.
ZAC: Carry on. Go for it.
IFY: Hey there. I feel like two beefy dudes like
me and you can really share some gold and some
good times together. What do you think?
MATT: As you approach Verian at the bar and say
this to him, Verian looks at you with a quizzical
expression and goes, "Well... I don't mean to tell
you one way or the other, but I am first off very
"confused, but mildly blushing at this offer you've
given me. But, strangely enough, you walk with
"those two at the table you were just at, I assume,
yes?"
IFY: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
MATT: "All right, well, Snuggleface as well. Come
this way. It appears I have a notice for the three
"of you, and I would like to share this
information."
ZAC: Wait, wait, wait, hold up. On us?
MATT: "Yes. It's requested right here."
ZAC: Is it... notice or wanted papers?
MATT: "Well. That is information that comes with a
price in this place. Understood, information is
"expensive, and I paid quite a sum to be the
messenger. It's the way the work is done, my friend."
IFY: Yeah, I see, I see. But you also look so
stressed. Maybe I can massage you up, you know.
These fighter hands are mighty strong, and I could
really get those kinks out.
MATT: Go ahead and make a persuasion roll.
(laughter)
LIAM: Give that man advantage.
IFY: 13.
DAN: Minus one?
(laughter)
MATT: He goes, "A tempting offer, based on the
knots that have been acquired over many years of
"hard labor behind this bar, but I think, as you
would respect, money talks..."
IFY: Bullshit walks. I like this guy. This guy is
like me! He knows what I'm talking about. Yeah.
ZAC: Listen, how about you just tell me what's on
the fucking sheet you have right there. Right now.
DAN: Ah, straight shooter.
MATT: "For what? I fail to see, despite your
somewhat demonic appearance, the soft, cuddly
"exterior of the clothing you wear, I have not
this-- you stare at me with such darkness. I am
"confused by this."
ZAC: These two here, these two assholes that I
employ, are at my bidding. They may be stupid but
they punch hard.
IFY: Actually, at the current time, he has way
more money than you, and I'm liable to fight for
his sake and his body.
DAN: Listen. For the sake of hypothetical.
ZAC: Next time we're going to-- Can we step away
from the man I'm trying to intimidate, and we
discuss this as a group?
DAN: Well, maybe you can loop us in next time
instead of being like oh, they're so stupid. They
don't get it. They've got feelings.
IFY: I know, seriously! I'm over here having a
good flirt session. You guys, coming up here--
ZAC: That was going nowhere!
MATT: Snugglelord. Make an intimidation check with
disadvantage.
(laughter)
ZAC: With disadvantage?
MATT: Yes. Roll twice and take the lower.
(laughter)
IFY: Might as well just say it, it's...
DAN: It's going to go just like earlier.
(laughter)
MATT: Verian crosses his arms, clutching the
parchment in his hand, and goes, "Hah. That was
"adorable. But no, seriously. 15 gold."
IFY: God! That's a lot of money, man.
MATT: "So is the promises this parchment provides.
It looks very informative. Eh?"
DAN: Can I try to use sleight of hand to replace
it with a piece of paper in my bag?
(laughter)
DAN: Close up magic!
MATT: Go for it? With disadvantage. It's going to be
a hard one.
ORION: Do it. Double 20's.
IFY: That is a 20. That's a natural--
DAN: Hold on, let me see if that is a 20. Oh, that
was a 20.
MARISHA: Roll again and hope it's another 20.
IFY: Oh!
DAN: Hold on. 13.
(laughter)
MATT: As your hand slides across the front of the
bar, your finger touches the edge of the
parchment. You wink and point with your-- most
fingers in the direction. And he glances briefly,
and as you give a slight tug you feel his meaty
hand slap onto your wrist, and slowly pull
back your hand. His glance comes back towards
yours, meeting your gaze, and goes, "It is now 20
"gold, my friend."
DAN: Aww, you got me there.
IFY: I go ahead and take this opportunity to rest
my hand on his hand and say, we can work this out,
my friend. We got something here for both of us.
(laughter)
CHAT ROOM: Small street urchin boy runs by and
steals paper.
DAN: What?!
MATT: Suddenly, the paper is snatched out from
Verian's hand, the influence of the dark deity
somehow pushing fate along. This child that
shouldn't have even been in this tavern from the
get-go, is just small enough to stay out of sight.
Runs off going (laughs), clutching the paper in
his hand, out the back door.
ZAC: Let's chase him. This is our chance. He has
to hold to the business, we can go after him.
IFY: You guys chase him, I'll hold it down over
here.
ZAC: You are not sleeping with this man! There is
another opportunity, later, later, let's get the child, go!
DAN: It takes three of us to catch one orphan.
ZAC: Well, yes, obviously in this situation.
(laughter)
IFY: All right.
DAN: Let's go.
IFY: Let's do it!
MATT: All right, you guys charge out into the
night air, looking across both sides. Everyone
make a perception check real fast to see if you
can ascertain which direction the child went.
IFY: 18 for me.
ZAC: Eight.
DAN: Eight.
MATT: All right, Ulfgar, your keen eyes glance
back and forth. To the left you can see the small
child ducking into a nearby alleyway before
disappearing into the shadows. You guys continue
following and curving in that alleyway and you
realize that child, while trying to do their best
to escape, has somehow found themselves cornered in
the back of a dead end. The child turns real fast
(panting) breathing heavily. "I mean no harm!
Look, I need money for my mum to eat and I'll give
"this to you for five gold, it's cheaper than what
the man was offering, aye, aye?"
IFY: How about I give you some of my rations? You
said you want food to eat, you ain't going to buy
new Air Jordans.
DAN: Whatever those are.
ZAC: We are three-- one competent warrior and two
bodyguards, we could easily bully this small child into giving us
what we want. You give up some of our food? Take
the damn paper.
IFY: Nah, this kid, you know, I'm feeling bad for
him, you know. I feel like--
DAN: He's like a little me.
IFY: Yeah, he's like a little me right there,
trying to get that gold, that's real cute kid,
you're on a good path, this is the path you want
to be on right now, no?
MATT: "Thank you sir, thank you for understanding.
We were hoping that we could come to a deal on
"this. Five gold. Please?"
IFY: All right. Do we have five gold left?
DAN: I have one. One gold!
ZAC: We can't afford a piece of paper!
(laughter)
IFY: All right, how about this? We're going to
feed your momma, right? You want to feed your
momma, I want to feed your momma too.
DAN: Whoa.
ZAC: That's a small child!
IFY: I am not going to bully a child, that's not
the life I live--
ZAC: But you'll fuck her mother?
IFY: Maybe. Look!
DAN: He said, to be fair, he said feed. That's
open to interpretation.
ZAC: I knew what he meant and he did not deny.
MATT: The child is slowly backing away further
into the alley--
IFY: Hey, hey! Slow down. How about we each give
you a day's worth of rations?
MATT: Make a persuasion roll. I'll say with
advantage because you've been the one person nice
to this kid since you arrived.
(laughter)
MATT: Roll twice, take the higher.
IFY: Oh. Let's see. 13.
MATT: 13. The kid: "Well, I'll happily take your
rations, and the one gold you've got if that's
"okay? I mean, you've got one gold, that's an easy
enough transaction, right?"
IFY: See now that's my kid! Hey, do you want to be
my son? You want to be my son? I think I'm going
to make this kid my son. He's coming on this
adventure with us, guys.
MATT: "Are you going on an adventure?"
ZAC: Hold on.
IFY: I've always wanted a son.
DAN: He has, he has.
ZAC: The chances of this child dying very quickly
are very high. We won't have to feed the mouth for
too much longer.
IFY: Okay, you're taking a way cynical look. I'm
going to protect this kid!
DAN: We take him along with us like a meaty,
expendable intern.
MATT: "What does 'expendable' mean?"
DAN: Ah, dinnae ken when you're talking about,
Junior. You're driving a hard bargain. Hold on,
the adults are talking.
IFY: Let's take him! Salty. You know much how much
I wanted a little boy. I told you.
DAN: Ever since you were a little boy.
IFY: Yeah. Let me get this little boy.
ZAC: You idiots have known each other for that
long?
DAN: We're pen pals. He's a mountain dwarf, I'm a
hill person. You know. We communicate. Classic, classic.
IFY: Yeah, you can come with us, kid.
MATT: "Really?"
ZAC: You'll only speak to this one.
MATT: "All right."
DAN: Or this one.
ZAC: Oh, for fuck's sake.
IFY: You're going to help me raise him? You're
going to help me raise my son?
DAN: Oh, you read my mind.
MATT: "So I won't talk to the fuzzy one, and I'll
just talk to you two. Okay. Here's your parchment.
"Thank you. I'm so excited! I've always wanted to
be an adventurer." And he reaches to his side, and
he pulls out this wooden sword that's moldy and
haphazardly constructed, and he swings it around. "Hah!"
IFY: Oh, he'll make me cry 'cause it's so cute.
Oh, dang.
DAN: What's your name, little wee orphan?
MATT: "Stephen. My name's Stephen. My brother's
named Steven, and my mom wasn't very original, but
"at least this way we can tell each other apart."
DAN: It's all right. A P-H is more sophisticated.
MATT: "Oh, thank you."
DAN: Unless it's an F, in which case, little
continental.
MATT: "It's a P-H, then."
DAN: All right, great. Great.
MATT: "All right. Let's go!" You look over the
parchment that you received. The actual note.
ZAC: I take it from him, 'cause he can't read.
(laughter)
IFY: We just explained how we were pen pals.
ZAC: I know that those were small drawings.
IFY: Oh, pish-posh.
MATT: The note says, "Seeking the ones called Vox
Moronica."
ZAC: It's asking for us.
DAN: Is that what we're called now?
ZAC: It stuck.
(laughter)
MATT: "I myself am known as the alchemist Kioli. I
have an issue that seems to befit your skillset."
ZAC: It seems, if I keep reading, there might be
some sort of mention of money, so I'm going to continue.
DAN: Please, don't stop to tell us that, just
fucking read it.
MATT: "Come to my home, the grey brick building at
the corner of the town square. There, I shall be
"able to present to you, perchance, a way to make a
bit of coin for yourself."
DAN: You were right!
ZAC: You heard that? I was reading in my head.
DAN: What? Oh, man! Our cycles must be lined up.
ZAC: Basically, we need to go to this building,
and there's a possible job for us.
IFY: Oh, I like that, job means money. Stephen. Rule number
one: always do something if it's for money. No
matter what.
DAN: Always.
MATT: "Okay, for the money, then." As you guys
continue towards the center of the town square,
you eventually take a look about, and you find the
grey brick building on the corner indeed. The
windows themselves, a dim light from the inside,
the door is closed. It looks to be a small,
relatively unadorned or simple building, more for
function than visual presentation. As you walk up
to the edge of the door, the door appears to be
closed and locked.
ZAC: It's locked.
DAN: Ah, that's where I come in. I've got what's
left of my masterwork thieves' tools. I'd like to
unlock the door.
MATT: Okay.
IFY: Don't worry. If it doesn't work, we can
always burn it down.
MATT: Roll, add your dexterity bonus and your
proficiency modifier.
DAN: Come on, three fingers. All right, dexterity
is plus three, 18, plus modifier. What is this again?
MATT: Plus two should be your proficiency
modifier.
DAN: There we go. 20.
MATT: With but a swift move of your wrist, the
door slowly creaks open, and you can see the low,
reddish-orange light from the interior of the room
becomes visible. Immediately, as you push the door
open and glance inside, it is cluttered, wall to
wall small wooden crates and some broken glass
jars that contain dried weeds and other types of
plant matter. As you peek around the corner, you
can see there are a number of shelves and tables
set up before you that have strange, long glass
contraptions with small brass wires that wind up
along tubes, liquids bubble and churn in all sorts
of different colors and textures. The smell that
hits you is this very aggressively iron-like
viscous scent that causes your sinuses to
immediately expand with this burning sensation.
Across the room, you see hunched over a small iron
table, with big, thick leather gloves on, a
humanoid figure that is currently crouched in the
middle of a very, very intense-- some sort of a
situation such as working or tinkering.
DAN: It looks like a hoarder.
ZAC: This could be a dicey situation. I think this
might be a good opportunity to maybe get your new
son some experience. Possibly go and greet this
fine creature.
IFY: I'm not going to send my new son to go-- I'm
not sending my new son down the hall. He's not
going down there! Now, Stephen, stay with Uncle
Pete. I'm going to go down there.
ZAC: Fair enough. That's fine.
MATT: "I'll stay with my Uncle Pete. Hi, Uncle
Pete."
DAN: Hello, Stephen.
MARISHA: Oh, god.
IFY: I'll go investigate that hole.
MATT: Okay. As you open the door and step into the
room, you get a better view of the interior. I'm
going to have you go ahead and roll a stealth
check.
DAN: Oh, I'm the one who's good at stealth.
(laughter)
IFY: Three.
DAN: Whoops.
MATT: As you step in and look around the rest of
the door, you see there's actually three other
individuals inside this room on the other side of
the wall, all patiently sitting arm-to-arm. As you
step in, you get about two or three steps before
your elbow bumps one of the nearby tables. As it
hits it, a glass jar that's been on the edge
topples and falls, shattering on the ground.
Instinctively, the gentleman who's hunched over at
the other table goes, "Who's there?!" and throws
something in the air. I need you to make a
dexterity saving throw.
(laughter)
DAN: This is not going well.
IFY: Seven.
(laughter)
MATT: You take four points of acid damage as
suddenly this vial that's spinning in the air
shatters on the ground before you, filling your
space with this horribly caustic liquid. It fills
your lungs and pocks the outside of your skin, and
you're coughing, it burns the inside. He goes,
"Oh, I'm sorry, I'm sorry, you spooked me. Wait,
what are you doing here?"
IFY: You just throw acid at anybody who walks in your
house? Come on, man.
MATT: "That door was locked for a reason!
Intruder! Intruder!"
DAN: This isn't our hotel room? Oh. My goodness.
What? What's going on with you? Get out of our room.
ZAC: See, Stephanie, this is why you send the dumb
ones in first.
MATT: "Um, Steph--"
DAN: He's not supposed to talk to you. You're
sending him mixed signals.
IFY: Don't listen to this crazy dude.
MATT: At which point, "Wait, are you Vox Moronica?
I recognize you, the snuggle one. Yes, I called
"you here. I'm sorry about the vial thing--"
ZAC: Yes, we got your note.
MATT: "Good, step inside, step inside. Oh.
Interesting. Usually when I call in the aid of
"various mercenary groups, it takes them a long
time to inquire. I appear to have two that have
"arrived at the same time. Conundrum." At which
point looks over to the group of the other three,
who are currently waiting on the side of the room,
if you guys would like to describe yourselves.
ZAC: Hello.
DAN: Describe yourselves!
(laughter)
ORION: My name's Quaalude Methaqualone. Pleased to
meet you. Wood elf, druid. Do things.
DAN: Quaalude Methaqualone? Wood elf, druid. You
do things.
ORION: Nice to meet you. Hi, this is my
associate.
LIAM: My name is Kurt. I come from the northern
hills. Barbarian folk. I don't wear much. I don't
have much patience. Don't test it.
IFY: Yeah, I see it. I'm liking what I'm seeing
right there. Liking that outfit, baby, yeah.
DAN: Really working.
LIAM: I can go that way.
ORION: Open mind. Free open mind. Free open mind,
all of us.
MATT: What's your name again, Liam?
LIAM: Kurt.
MATT: Kurt, all right.
MARISHA: Hello! I'm Edna, and I'm 79 years young!
Can you believe it? (laughs) I know, that one gets
them every time.
CHAT ROOM: Josephine, leader of the Guild of
Moderators, steps out of the shadows and stares
unblinking at the party. She holds out an
enchanted red stapler and says, "It is dangerous
"to go alone. Take this."
LIAM: The fuck are you?!
(yelling)
IFY: Hey, come on, that's creepy!
ZAC: I somehow feel like all of these things are
being driven by some unseen force. This is the
proof I was telling you about! The Shathrum
exists!
DAN: I remain thoroughly agnostic. All I see is a
stapler.
ZAC: Of all the things that have happened--
DAN: I'd love to take this creation, this--
IFY: Wait, so you're not going to throw acid at
her?! She came out of nowhere, you don't throw
acid at her? I'm the only one?!
DAN: Presumably she was already in here.
ZAC: Let's calm down and figure-- let's--
MATT: At this point the poof of cloud smoke slowly
disappears as the guild leader has extended the
stapler, looks over towards the alchemist who
invited you and goes, "Oh! That's Josephine. I've
known her for quite some time. Don't worry, she--
that's how she gets in and out of the room, it's a
bit spooky. A stapler, that's curious. Have you
tinkered this item yourself?" And she extends it
and goes, "No, I just know that whatever you were
requiring in these groups was a bit dangerous and
I figure they should take this."
ZAC: I will take the-- thank you.
MATT: Fair enough.
ORION: (mumbling) There's something about you...
(unintelligible).
MATT: "That's not a language."
DAN: He's speaking in italics.
ORION: I think it's... I think it's... I love what
you're wearing, is what I'm saying. Eh?
LIAM: Nobody can understand what you're saying.
ORION: (mumbles)
ZAC: Is your party member high?
MATT: "Oh no, he's just Johnny Depp as a pirate."
(laughter)
DAN: Oh, burn.
MATT: She bamfs out, puff of black smoke--
IFY: Well, I guess it's time to introduce myself.
MARISHA: What does that stapler do? You know, I
might be able to Detect Magic on it, you know, I
have been doing a little bit of studying. Who says
an old dog can't learn new tricks, am I right? Let
me see.
DAN: I can't.
MARISHA: What? I can't? What? I'm sorry, I'm a
little hard of hearing. What?
ORION: He cat.
MARISHA: What? Cat? You're a kitty cat? Oh.
DAN: Lovely to meet you.
MARISHA: Oh, what was your name, Sonny?
DAN: Salty Pete. Salty. Pete. AKA Sam AKA
Money Sam.
IFY: Money Sam baby, how you doing baby?
ZAC: When did this new alias come about?
DAN: Approximately 15 to 20 minutes into last
adventure.
(laughter)
ZAC: Oh, last week, I remember.
DAN: Last time we had a big adventure.
IFY: I'm Ulfgar Fireforge, sellsword, ex-pit
fighter, money talks, bullshit walks, this is my
son Steph, Steph Fireforge, ex-street urchin, dope
warrior baby, 'kay? That's my warrior baby, he
does warrior baby stuff--
MATT: "Hi, I'm his warrior baby."
ORION: That's-- you're a lively bunch.
MARISHA: You know, he's a bit young. Don't you
think he's a bit-- he's a very young boy.
ZAC: As the leader of this terrifying group of
mercenaries, and I believe that you can possibly
tell if there's magic on this from here. I think
I'll hold onto it.
MARISHA: I may not-- I'm a bit hard of seeing but
I--
LIAM: Jesus, you fuckers talk a lot.
MATT: "Well, anyway, I've called you here for a
reason but--"
MARISHA: Who are you? The chat room?
ORION: What the hell's that?
(yelling)
ZAC: Stop! Stop! Stop! You know of the Shathrum?
MARISHA: I'm sorry, once again, hard of hearing,
Sonny Boy--
DAN: This is awfully convenient.
MARISHA: The chateau? Yes, I've been to the
chateau--
LIAM: He's asking you where the shitter is.
MARISHA: The shitter? The shitter is right around
the corner.
ZAC: No the Shat-- the Shathrum! The Shathrum
speaks to me, does it speak to you, too?
MARISHA: Oh, you know that voice-- are you
referring to that voice?
ZAC: Yes! Yes! The voice.
MARISHA: I heard that too. Did you hear that? Is
that what we're talking about now, I don't know--
MATT: "I'm certainly afraid no one's heard no
Shathrum. That's a dark god we don't speak of.
Dark days in the past. It rendered whole
communities forfeit of their lives. I really hope
that you're not saying that's what you're looking
for."
DAN: No, definitely not.
ZAC: Definitely, I would definitely not follow
every word and commandment of the Shath-- no.
MATT: "All right, well, down to business then."
MARISHA: Okay. Oh wait, let me-- can I Detect
Magic on that stapler?
MATT: Do you have an Identify or a Detect Magic
spell?
MARISHA: I do have Detect Magic.
MATT: Okay. You take a moment and it is indeed
emanating a magical force on it.
MARISHA: Can I tell what kind of magical force?
MATT: You gather it has some semblance of an
abjuration-based spell enchantment. You'd have to
actually take some time with it to ascertain its
nature.
MARISHA: You know, I have to take a little bit
more time with it, but I feel like it might have
some sort of protective qualities to it.
MATT: "Anyway! You've all stumbled loudly into my
home."
IFY: Yeah, but I also got acid thrown in my face.
Don't forget that.
MATT: "You snuck up on me!"
IFY: I'm never going to let you forget that.
ORION: We've been here quietly.
MATT: "I know, and that's fine. I have two
mercenary parties that are now vying for the same
job."
DAN: Shotgun. Blitz. No blitz.
ZAC: We don't even know what this is! What-- We
don't agree to a job before knowing what the
job--
DAN: Fine. Please disregard.
IFY: I agree to money, and it smells like there's
some money in here. And it smells like there's
some acid in my face because you poured acid in my
face!
MATT: "Perhaps it'll be worth it when you hear
what the business is about, all right? Now. It
appears I've lost my assistant. I would like to
find him. Checking in on his well-being is what I
ask of you. Discover where he is, and bring him
back safely if possible. It's been-- well, we've
been working on some sort of planar shifting
through alchemy and forgotten lore for a while,
now, and we found a nearby arcane nexus in the
east, toward the center of the Zorla swamp.
There's a nasty horde of goblins that live out
there, but we managed to barely sneak past them at
the time, and we set up a portal anchor at a place
underground. Now, our first attempt already proved
successful: we managed to open a doorway to some
unknown location. I'm not stupid, I'm not going in
there, so I sent my assistant in with a rope tied
around his side. Off he went, he stepped
through--"
ZAC: I like it, I like it. That's a good tactic.
MATT: "I think so, too. Protects my well-being and
what good's an assistant if they're not
disposable, right?"
ZAC: I completely understand.
MATT: "So I sent him in. He stepped through.
Didn't return for about 30 minutes, nearly
bringing all 300 feet of rope in with him."
DAN: That's a lot of rope.
MATT: "I know! It went taut, I pulled him back in,
and eventually he came back safe and sound. Little
chilled, a little confused, but fine. Came back,
sneaking past the goblins, a little bit of a run
as they discovered our passage, but we made it
back fine. That evening, he recalled a landscape
of shifting shapes and earth, purples and darkness
and forms without form and creatures that drifted
between the realms, all kinds of interesting
things. One swam through the air and through him,
leaving him tickled and unscathed. But that's all
he recalls. He says he only recalls about five
minutes of this portal, then darkness for a bit,
but he was in there for a good 30 minutes. I think
he lost some time in there. Anyway. Pulled him
back, he was fine. But he grew a little more
distant over the next few nights, not really
answering my calls as quickly, seemed to be lost
in thought a lot, and eventually, in the morning,
he went missing. I used my divinations, as limited
as they are, to discover that he had run off into
the swamp by himself, beelining for that doorway
that we originally found and opened. So. I count
myself lucky on a blue moon, and I wish not to
endanger myself by going after him myself. Thus,
I'm willing to pay 2,500 gold pieces to the group
who finds him and brings him back."
DAN: Like I said, shotgun.
IFY: I'm going to need to take a seat real quick.
That's a lot of money. Oh, yeah. Tell me how much
that was again?
MATT: "2,500 gold pieces."
IFY: Oh, yeah.
ZAC: I apologize. He's...
DAN: He's an enthusiastic--
IFY: Say that one more time for me, it's just
getting me there.
MATT: "I'm going to not, actually. There's
children present."
DAN: He likes currency.
LIAM: Are you asking us to work together? Or to
compete against one another?
MATT: "To be honest, I would prefer you work
together, because I get the feeling this isn't
going to go very far if you don't."
ZAC: I'm completely okay with this, as long as you
all understand that I am of course in lead of this
party.
LIAM: (laughs)
ORION: As he says that, I'm going to take a
special leaf pod that I have, and I'm going to pop
a couple seeds.
DAN: Was that an edamame?
(laughter)
ORION: You want one? It's great.
ZAC: No, no.
DAN: Just curious.
MARISHA: Is that Metamucil? Is that what that is?
DAN: Keeps him regular.
MARISHA: Ah yes, I forgot to take mine today.
ORION: [jumbled] --it'll make you poop.
MARISHA: What?
LIAM: We're going to get your shit done for you.
Where are we going?
MATT: "East, to the Zorla swamp. Past the goblin
hordes, you'll find some sort of a mound with a
tunnel in it. Beneath there is where we found
where the planes are weakest and where alchemy
allowed us to open that doorway. He's probably
somewhere within there, scattered. He does not
have the means of opening the portal himself. This
I know. He's probably somewhere lost in that den.
Don't know why. Try and bring him back safe, if
you could."
IFY: Do we want to rest before this, maybe stop by
the Valarian Bar for a little bit--
CHAT ROOM: Edna suddenly develops Tourette's and
can't stop saying Vilian and Dasmodel at random
intervals.
MARISHA: Did they say Edna?
DAN: They surely did.
MARISHA: Edna says what randomly now?
DAN: She has Tourette's and says--
MARISHA: I have Tourette's and I say what?
MATT: Balium and Deswomwom?
DAN: Balium and Desmond?
MARISHA: Balium and Desmond?
MATT: What was the phrase?
MARISHA: If I could get a confirmation on what my
Tourette's entails.
MATT: Belial and Asmodan.
DAN: Ah, classic mythology.
MARISHA: Classic voice-to-speech not knowing what
the shit nerds say.
ZAC: Did you hear that voice per se just now?
MARISHA: You mean Asmodeus? Asmodeum?
ZAC: Did you hear the voice?
MARISHA: Is that what he said?
MATT: Asmodan. Write it down. Asmodeum is what
keeps you regular.
DAN: That's what he took.
ORION: Here, have some Asmodeum.
MARISHA: Oh, Asmodeum!
ZAC: The voice? Did you hear the voice too?
MATT: "If you're talking voices, I want this out
of my home! Get out! Do this job, come back for
the money."
ZAC: We'll leave. Before we go, can we at least
get something in writing. Something to say that--
we've been screwed before, and I know that you
look like a fine individual, but-- businessman to
businessman, please.
MATT: Pulls out a parchment and takes an extended
45 minutes to handwrite with a quill an extremely
detailed contract, making you all wait, and then
he gets halfway through and goes, "No, no," and
crumples it up and grabs another piece of paper.
ZAC: It's worth it.
DAN: She said Asmodan 45 fucking times.
MATT: "I messed up this draft, too." Crumples it
up.
(groaning)
MATT: Eventually, goes, "And that should be
square."
ZAC: Thank you.
MATT: "There you go. Legally binding."
ZAC: Thank you very much. That's great.
MATT: "No worries, get out."
LIAM: Cort stands up and says, I've had enough. I
report to Edna and no one else. Let's fucking do
this. He kicks the door open and leaves.
ZAC: I didn't speak anything but two words for the
last hour and a half!
DAN: Well, that escalated quickly.
MATT: "That door is easy to dam--"
LIAM: Go fuck yourself!
ORION: What's going on?
ZAC: Somehow I've ended up with more idiots than
when I started.
DAN: Ah, classic escalation.
IFY: Oh, yeah.
ZAC: You two are now my commanders, because for
some reason you're more intelligent than the
idiots we're picking up.
CHAT ROOM: --obsessed with following Snugglelord
around. You are welcome.
ALL: Who?
ZAC: Was that Steph?
OFF-SCREEN: Crazy blackpowder merchant becomes
obsessed with following Snugglelord around.
DAN: Sounds like you've been pimped into doing
something.
ZAC: My lord, please, messages you could give me
that help me along my way would be very much
appreciated, my lord. Anything that could help me
get rid of these idiots and continue on my
journey.
MATT: With a sparkle of dark innovation, you look
up and see a star in the sky twinkle, a voice
behind you goes, (Victor voice) "Hi! You're the
one who's dressed proper. Where are you off to?
Oh, you're nice and soft. Whoa." Rubbing your
back, this crazed old man with bits of dirt and
soot all over his face. "I need a friend. I could
be your friend."
ZAC: No touching. No touching.
MATT: "Then why would you wear this? It's so nice
to touch."
DAN: That's practically his skin.
IFY: Congratulations, you've got a son.
DAN: Oh, he's got a boy, a wee baby. Oh, so cute.
IFY: Haha, yeah!
ORION: What's your name?
MATT: "My name is Victor."
ORION: Victor, welcome to the journey.
ZAC: No, we do not accept just anyone that comes
up to us and touches us.
DAN: We're taking a child to a swamp?
MARISHA: Belial!
(laughter)
DAN: What she said! Belial!
MATT: "No, no. My name is Victor."
MARISHA: Asmodan. No. Yes. Asmodan.
ZAC: Why have you cursed me so? Why have you
cursed me like this?
LIAM: Here. Take that. There, that's better.
LIAM: She'll be fine.
ZAC: Stephanie, don't do drugs.
IFY: Stop talking to my son, okay? He's my son,
don't ever talk to my son. Keep your words in your
zone and you got your own son, I've got a son--
ZAC: I do not have a son!
DAN: He's got an adult son.
ORION: I think you just call it a friend. You just
call them friends.
DAN: A ward of the state.
MATT: As you guys, through the moonlight, start
making your way outside of the actual town towards
the outskirts of Zorla swamp--
ORION: I say, I know the swamp. Whenever you have
something show up and everything pops up it will
reflect it back.
ZAC: Well, that's great. I have no idea what this
idiot is saying. Does anyone-- can anyone
translate?
DAN: He knows it's a swamp.
ORION: Yes. It's the same thing every time.
DAN: Something pops up and we reflect it back?
Like a funhouse mirror?
ORION: Or something.
MATT: "All right." The little boy who's following
you goes, "Okay! Don't worry, I'll protect you!"
And he pulls out a small wooden sword and is like
(fighting noises).
ORION: That's a good lad. That's a good lad.
IFY: So good. Oh my god, I'm crying again because
he's so cute. Oh god. I love my son!
MARISHA: He's so cute. Would you like a chocolate
chip cookie?
IFY: Go there and get a cookie from grandma.
That's your grandma now.
MATT: "A cookie? I'd love one right now, thank
you."
ZAC: Can we all shut up?!
DAN: You had pastries this entire time?
ZAC: Oh my god.
MARISHA: I raised two children in my day, I always
keep a good pastry on me. Here.
MATT: Stephan starts crying as the large, scary
devil man in the--
IFY: Don't yell at my son. You won't tell me how
to raise my kids, I won't tell you how to raise
your kid over there, okay?
ZAC: It's not my child, we--
IFY: Don't, don't-- Stephan, go over there to your
grandma and get a cookie. She your grandma now.
(laughter)
MATT: He dries the tears from his face and goes
"Okay."
MARISHA: Come here little-- Belial! Stephan! Come
here. Come here-- Asmodan! Come here.
MATT: The closer he gets the slower his walk is
and the more the look of trepidation is on his
face. You can see him struggling with the idea of
like, "I really want this cookie but she is really
freaking me out right now."
MARISHA: What? No. Look, I know I look old and
scary but trust me I was quite the hot little
shimmy back in the day, Asmodan.
MATT: "Thanks." Grabs the cookie and darts back
ten feet and starts chewing it rapidly. At which
point, in the distance you see catching up to you
now with heavy breath-- "You all move so very
fast, but you're not too fast for Victor."
ZAC: Oh, you haven't died of a heart attack yet?
DAN: A son can always find his father.
MATT: "To the swamp!" And he goes running off in
front of you.
ZAC: Let him go.
CHAT ROOM: Two great goliath warriors with two
large tigers attack Vox Moronica.
IFY: God, what?!
DAN: Are those two goliath warriors with large
tigers-- In a swamp.
LIAM: Classic encounters.
DAN: Wait, no, there are-- we need to reflect them
back, like he said.
IFY: We need to reflect them?
MATT: As you guys are having this conversation,
and we'll say going forward preferably don't
suggest encounters, because that--
LIAM: Yeah, no Tarrasques please.
MATT: Yeah, that's going to screw me up. However,
as you guys are having this conversation, you see
Victor go charging off into the swamp, turn around
and go, "Never mind! Never mind! Bad idea!"
(screaming) And from behind you see these two
dark-armored knights on top of these strange,
slightly shifting tiger forms come charging out of
the darkness of the swamp after you.
ORION: How far away? How far away are they?
MARISHA: I think my eyesight must be going
because--
MATT: About 25 feet.
MARISHA: I could swear I see two men riding giant
tigers in the distance. I really need to get some
glasses.
ORION: As I see this I'm like (mumbles) and I
entangle them.
MATT: Okay. As you cast Entanglement, all these
vines go (whipping noises), forming out of the
swamp and writhing in the air. As they reach out
towards the forms, they seem to pass through their
physicality.
DAN: I disbelieve.
ORION: Well then, they're tricky, sticky ones.
MARISHA: I'm telling you, need to get my eyes
checked.
MATT: I need everyone to go ahead and make a
history check, if you could. All of you guys.
DAN: 12.
ORION: 21.
ZAC: 18.
LIAM: One. I'm sorry, zero. Excuse me, zero.
ZAC: One!
ORION: 21.
MARISHA: 19.
MATT: Okay. You understand that the Zorla Swamp,
for as long as it's existed, especially during
nights of heavy moonlight, part of the dark
enchantment is it tends to conjure up series of
dangerous illusions; things that have temporary
form at moments. It almost has this weird magic
where imagination can cause forms to exist for
short periods of time. They're illusions and can
be destroyed or dispelled in certain ways, but
until then they can prove to be as deadly or
dangerous as what you see before you. This
knowledge hits you as they approach and both of
them ride by swinging these giant swords, one
swinging past you, Salty Pete. The second one is
going to go for-- (laughing) is going to aim for
Victor.
(laughter)
DAN: Oh no.
MATT: First, the one swinging towards you Salty
Pete, the giant sword, that is a 16 to hit. What's
your armor class?
DAN: That 100 percent hits. I'm 14.
(laughter)
DAN: Oh, just casually decapitated.
MATT: You take five points of slashing damage as
the sword (whooshes). It hits you and you can see
as it approaches to you in that instant, its form
is shimmering and doesn't seem to have physicality
to it, yet the impact still feels like a heavy
steel blade wings you in the front of the chest.
You feel a thick bruise beginning to form beneath
your armor.
DAN: My sternum!
MATT: As the tiger growls, rides past you into the
grasses behind you. The other one swings towards
Victor who's like (old man yelling) running
away--
ZAC: Please. Please hit him, please hit him. Lord
do me this one favor and please--
IFY: Is he close enough to throw Snugglelord to
protect his son?
(laughter)
MATT: Well, towards Victor, which is the old guy.
You want to--
IFY: Okay. I want to throw Snugglelord towards
Victor to protect his son.
MATT: Okay.
DAN: Aww, that's so sweet.
IFY: I'm going to help you protect your son,
baby!
ZAC: No, what are you doing?!
MATT: I'll have you guys roll athletics checks,
contested.
ZAC: Athletics. Where's athletics?
IFY: 19.
ZAC: Oh god, there's no way.
(laughter)
MATT: This is happening. Ulfgar grabs Snugglelord,
lifts him up and throws him forward--
ZAC: You idiot! What are you doing?!
IFY: Protect your son! Protect your son!
ZAC: He's not my son! He's-- aah!
MATT: At which point, you skid to a halt, your
heels grinding into the wet earth that begins to
initiate the formation of the swamp that you guys
are traveling towards. As you finally come to a
stop, you see Victor go, "Thanks!" and run past
you as the giant semi-illusionary warrior swings
at you. That's a 23.
DAN: Does that hit you?
(laughter)
ZAC: I believe that hits a 13.
MATT: You take six points of slashing damage as
the blade smacks you across the abdomen. You can
see part of your fuzzy exterior slash open and red
begin to slowly pool and darken the material.
ZAC: Oh motherfucker.
IFY: I look over at Stephen. "I hope to protect
you like that one day. I care about you a lot,
son."
DAN: That's a father's love.
ZAC: Stephanie, don't listen to your father. This
was a very dumb thing to do.
MATT: All right, everyone roll initiative.
LIAM: Oh Jesus.
DAN: 20.
MARISHA: 14.
LIAM: 11.
ORION: 15.
MATT: All right.
IFY: Initiative is just your dex, right?
MARISHA: Correct.
IFY: All right.
MARISHA: What are we doing? What are we fighting?
IFY: 12.
MARISHA: We're fighting these assholes?
DAN: We're fighting the swamp.
IFY: Can anyone dispel this at all?
ZAC: I have a three.
MATT: All right, well, first and foremost, Salty
Pete. As they turn around and begin riding back
for a second ride-by, you have your first turn.
DAN: I'm going to try and unfurl an arrow from my
shortbow at the goliath.
MATT: You pull it, go ahead and release the arrow
towards the first illusionary entity. Roll for
attack.
DAN: All right. Where's my-- it's okay. 18.
MATT: 18 does indeed hit. Go ahead and roll damage
on that arrow.
DAN: All right. That is eight points of damage.
MATT: Eight points of damage. Your arrow arcs
across, you can see it strike true in the front of
the armored goliath knight. As it hits it, you can
see its form disperse for a second, attempt to
reform, and a beam of moonlight comes streaking
out of the sky, hits it and it immediately
disintegrates. You can see both it and the tiger's
form roll into ash and vanish before your very
eyes.
DAN: Holy crap! That was awesome.
IFY: That's some good stuff right there.
DAN: Did you see what I did?
ZAC: I will give you that one. That was very
impressive.
DAN: I exploded him.
(laughter)
MATT: We had the 20. Who was at the 16? It was the
highest next I believe.
MARISHA: I had a 14.
CHAT ROOM: The stapler starts to glow. Use it to
kill the goliaths.
MATT: The stapler. Who's clutching the stapler? As
you're holding it it begins to shake and glow with
this weird goldish red energy.
DAN: Kill the goliaths!
MATT: At that moment, as you guys are carrying--
you find, though yourself are feeling scared and
cowardly, thus your inability to, this pulls you
to immediate initiative.
ZAC: Oh shit! I rolled a three on initiative!
MATT: I know. This pulls you to the front of the
initiative order with its magical enchantment. I
need you to go ahead and roll and add your
charisma to this.
(laughter)
DAN: Lot of charisma. Nailed it.
ZAC: Eight. I'm rolling poorly!
MATT: Did you add your charisma to it?
ZAC: Yes!
MATT: The stapler, for a second, begins to form
this large, glowing orange orb in the front that
all of a sudden releases the blast, knocking you
off your feet. You land prone on the ground as you
guys see this giant burning red metallic staple
flying across the darkened sky towards the entity.
However, the illusion passes underneath it and it
goes, disappearing into the distance.
ZAC: I think I should try that again possibly
because that was freaking awesome.
(laughter)
ZAC: I just need to get used to the-- it shakes a
lot, it's hard to aim, but I'm pretty sure I can
hit them.
DAN: Got a bit of recoil.
MATT: You finish your turn getting back to your
feet. Next up, I believe it was you. Edna, yes.
MARISHA: So there's a goliath riding a tiger?
Coming this way? All right. Oh boy, Magic Missile!
MATT: All right, go ahead, Magic Missile, go ahead
and roll damage on that one.
MARISHA: I'm going to do all three at him. So 1d4
plus four times three. So that's-- Those are not
good rolls. Six. Rolled ones every time. Six
damage.
MATT: Six total damage?
MARISHA: Yeah. (yelping) Belial!
MATT: As Edna releases this, screaming Belial into
the night air, the missile streaks off into these
three silver darts of arcane energy, smashing into
the sides of this semi-translucent armored
goliath. You can see its form sparking and
shimmering like it's having a hard time keeping
physicality in this world, but it's still
maintaining its position. Riding forward, now
towards you since you are the source of its
initial anger.
DAN: You've angered the goliath.
MARISHA: Asmodan.
MATT: Next up, who's the highest initiative?
LIAM: I believe it was me. I forgot to mention
before-- Oh you were? Go for it then.
MATT: Go for it, Quaalude.
ORION: There's a-- so as he's coming towards us
I'll-- I'm going to just do a spin like, hold on
darling, (claps) and do a Thunderwave. And get
thunder.
MATT: Okay. So you move over to get between Edna
and this entity. You release Thunderwave. Is it
just a saving throw on their part, I believe,
right? Yeah. Have your spells ready.
LIAM: Thunderwave.
MARISHA: It's super effective. It's a druid spell.
MATT: Found it first. Okay, so yeah, they have a
constitution saving throw. What's the DC of your
spell?
LIAM: Oh, you didn't prepare it. What's your--
MATT: It doesn't matter, it's a four. All right,
so that's 2d8 damage, it says?
ORION: Yes.
MATT: Actually, you roll that, you roll that
damage, go for it.
ORION: Nice. What's that? Eight?
MATT: Okay. So as you rush in front of her, you
put your hand out in front and slam your fist into
the ground. As it does, this giant light wave of
thunderous energy blasts out, flattening all the
damp grasslands around you and sending the
shockwave forward that, as it hits and impacts the
front of the illusion, it casts it into dust as
the wave passes over as it rushes, just about to
strike you. With that, the Thunderwave passes and
the entity is destroyed and is no more.
DAN: Holy crap.
MATT: So as you all stand there, clutching your
glowing, shaking stapler that slowly fades to its
mundane-looking self, the immediate danger seems
to have passed.
MARISHA: Does that stapler still appear to be
magical?
MATT: You go over and take it and as the vibration
is slowly--
ORION: You all right Edna?
MARISHA: What? I'm fine.
ORION: Oh good.
MARISHA: Yes, here. Can I see it? Can I detect any
magic? Does it look pretty meh?
MATT: No. It's definitely radiating some magical
presence. Essentially once per short rest you can
use your action to initiate it and it fires an
arcane, heated giant staple that does, upon
impact, if you manage to hit, does pretty hefty
damage.
LIAM: I walk over to the boy and I kneel down and
I say, listen, and I take the wooden sword out of
his hand and I toss it. You want to fucking let
some blood today? You use one of these. And I've
got-- all I'm wearing is a leather thong and I
have five small iron hammers on my belt, and I
take one out and I say, fucking use this and
you'll paint the blood out of anyone's skull. Use
this, Boy-o. It'll work.
DAN: It's hammer time.
MATT: "Of course, of course I will, sir. Oh, I'm
going to smash some skulls in for me dad."
IFY: Oh yeah, that's a good job, son. That's your
uncle now, that's your other uncle.
MARISHA: Stephen, how old are you?
MATT: "This many."
MARISHA: Oh that's good, that's old enough. That's
how old my boys were when they had their first
swords, yes, yes, that's a good age.
MATT: You hear a voice echoing from the distance,
"Is it gone?" (panting) "Thank you for saving me,
O Great Soft One."
ZAC: Oh no, it's nothing at all, I'm only bleeding
internally now, thank you so much.
DAN: And externally.
ZAC: Both, yes.
MATT: "Well come on, let's continue onward!" And
he goes running into the swamp. As the small--
ZAC: Why is he still alive?
DAN: Obviously you saved him. You selflessly
sacrificed your body and saved his life.
ZAC: I would do no such thing. I was thrown.
IFY: No, you saved your son. You saved your son.
You're a good dad. You're a real good dad. I love
you.
MATT: Pushing into the swamp proper as you guys
continue inward, you find, about 20 to 25 minutes
of walking through, the actual swamp sludge is so
thick that your boots are getting caught and stuck
with each individual step.
MARISHA: This is really bad for my orthopedics.
MATT: Everyone go ahead-- everyone make an
athletics check.
MARISHA: Not my strong suit...that's not a good
roll either.
ZAC: Ten.
DAN: 11.
IFY: 15.
MARISHA: Three.
LIAM: 15.
ORION: 15.
MATT: So you guys get about ten minutes in before
you realize that Edna isn't with you. You look
behind you and--
MARISHA: Oh, Asmodan!
MATT: In the distance you see her actually
physically stuck in the muck of the swamp.
LIAM: I head back and I pick her up over me
shoulder and I just put her on and I just start
carrying her through the mud.
MARISHA: Watch my back, Cort.
LIAM: Nah, it's good for you, you like it.
MARISHA: (groans) I'm not as nimble as I used to
be.
LIAM: Use it or lose it, lady.
MATT: Who's helming the tracking of this group
trying to find this Cyril, this assistant?
DAN: Not it.
(laughter)
ORION: I'll be at the forefront.
ZAC: He was the one who told us about the swamp. I
believe he--
ORION: I'll use that roll for a 24.
MATT: 24, okay. As you guys are moving forward,
you begin to pick up what looks like recently set
human tracks that are deeply sunken in and leaving
these pools behind in the swamp. So you kind of
start taking charge and everyone begins to follow.
The child, Stephen, is kind of following in step
next to you excited to kind of see that now
there's another leader of the group. You however
are now being very, very closely followed behind
with this slightly under-his-breath cackling and
muttering soot-covered old man who's like, "I
don't get out often, it's nice to see the moon.
Can I touch you again just once more?"
ZAC: Can you leave? I can feel you breathing on my
neck, just back up, please.
MATT: "Good! Good! I'm still breathing. Very good.
Keep that up, I need a reminder every now and
then. Smell this." And he gives you this weird
clump of blackish powder that's in his hand. He
reaches out and puts it in front of your face.
IFY: Oh man, your son is weird, ha!
ZAC: Get that out of my face. If you would just
please be quiet, you can walk beside me.
MATT: "Oh, okay! I will walk beside you. But this,
this may save your life one day." And he shoves it
into a pouch at his side.
IFY: Hey Snuggle's son! Is that dookie? Is that
dookie you just made him smell? You know, there's
this trick I used to play when I was little. I was
like "Hey, smell this powder," but it was dookie.
DAN: How'd you get it powdered?
IFY: You just punch it a lot.
MATT: In frustration for this conversation,
Snugglelord, in anger you all of a sudden just
flex and for a moment (poof noise), your little
imp familiar appears on your shoulder and just
kind of pats you on the side of your head.
DAN: What the fuck is that?
ZAC: I do in fact have a 'son', per se--
MATT: "I have a brother?"
IFY: Yeah, yeah.
DAN: Oh, is that the nature of your relationship?
ZAC: Yes. I did not want anyone to meet him under
these circumstances, but everyone meet--
CHAT ROOM: Oh no. Liam and Orion accidentally hit
heads and develop Foreign Accent Syndrome. They
now each speak in different foreign accents. Also,
Snugglelord realizes his costume's rear flap has
been open the--
MATT: --entire time.
(laughter)
MATT: So, pick different accents you guys. As
you're walking through the middle of the swamp as
they're having this conversation, he turns around
and you both hit your heads together--
MARISHA: Oh, be careful. I do that all the time.
You got to be careful. I actually have one of
these buttons so I can call for help if I ever
trip and fall down. Yes.
IFY: Oh, yeah, yeah. That's cleric alert, right?
MARISHA: It's a life alarm, yes.
IFY: Yeah, yeah. It'll call the cleric to come and
help you out.
ORION: (Russian accent) No problem, I changed different accent,
I sound different now, yes?
ZAC: The strange imp on my shoulder has now become
the slight-- very much the least awkward thing
that is going on at this moment.
MATT: Of which, the imp at this point reaches
forward with its smiling, young, boyish, handsome
face and whispers into your ear, "Uh, Snugglelord?
I'm afraid to let you know your flap is open."
DAN: Oh, that's embarrassing.
IFY: I knew it was open the whole time, I was just
looking at his booty.
ZAC: Grow up, that's where my tail comes out. Get
over it, it is-- It's tiefling anatomy, it's
totally fine, move on.
LIAM: (Brooklyn accent) Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Wait a minute!
The fuck happened to my fucking Celtic accent?!
This is fucking bullshit! God damn it, I'm from
the fucking Highlands. The fuck? What are you
looking at? God damn it. I would like to fucking
rage, and I take out hammers and I just start
punching the shit out of the trees around me. I'm
fucking angry. God damn it! I used to have a
fucking charming accent and now I sound like a
fucking mook.
IFY: He's swinging around all them hammers like
that. I guess you could say he's too legit to
quit, right?
ORION: I do not understand the reference. I'm so
sorry for you.
MATT: At this, your imp kind of leans in and says,
"My apologies for bothering you, master, but is
this a bad time?"
ZAC: Yes. Everyone meet my imp, Lucas.
MATT: He waves and nods and kind of smiles quietly
at everybody.
MATT: "Hi."
ZAC: By the way, Lucas is wearing absolutely
nothing except for a Pabst Blue--
MARISHA: What was his name? Mucus? What? Mucus?
That's such a strange name for an imp.
MATT: Describe him again, sorry.
ZAC: Lucas is wearing nothing but a Pabst Blue
Ribbon t-shirt and an American flag baseball cap.
I don't know what that is or what it means, but.
No pants. He's an imp.
MATT: No pants. Got it. It's like a strange,
alternate-dimension Donald Duck.
MARISHA: I feel like we should do something about
Cort.
LIAM: Top of the morning to ya. Top of the morning
to-- fucking hell.
MATT: This angry yelling, by the way, has been
echoing through the forest, and for a split second
you, Cort, hear this (whizzing noise) as-- what's
your armor class?
LIAM: My armor class is 16.
MATT: You hear the sound and instinctively push
out of the way. Your hand slaps what looks like
some sort of small, wooden shaft that just flies
past you. The rest of you in the middle of this
moment look around you and you see starting to
crawl out of the nearby trees a bunch of small,
angry, growling humanoid figures going
(growling).
IFY: Oh yeah, this them goblins they talking
about.
DAN: Oh, right, goblins.
IFY: Yo, yo gobs. Yo, what up?
MATT: Roll initiative.
MARISHA: Oh, new maps, new maps! New map things!
Look, it's a new thing!
MATT: So we have over here Snugglelord, Salty
Pete.
MARISHA: Don't die, Mucus.
ZAC: My imp just tripped on some cords, I'm
sorry.
MATT: All right, takes me a minute to set up here,
guys. Make sure you have your initiative numbers
ready.
MARISHA: Oh, we're rolling initiative, right.
IFY: I got a 20.
MATT: Oh wow. Hold onto that number just for a
second.
ZAC: I got a six. Oh, sorry, I add one, right?
Yeah, seven.
MATT: We'll say that this is, next to Snugglelord,
that's Victor. And we'll say that this little
kobold with the spear is Stephen. All right, so--
LIAM: When I find the Critter who took my fucking
Irish accent we're going to have words. We're
going to have words.
DAN: Certainly not Irish words.
ORION: He's so much more aggressive than before,
which I did not think was possible.
ZAC: You actually think a small woodland critter
took your accent from you?
MATT: Okay, so 25 to 20.
IFY: I'm 20. I'm up there, ha, yeah.
MATT: 20 to 15?
ORION: 15.
MATT: 15 to ten? Ten to five?
DAN: Oh. Six.
ZAC: Seven.
MATT: Okay. Double fours, all right. All right, as
you see all these goblinoid figures start
shuffling out from the sides of the trees nearby,
and some seem to be laying low in the swamp and
some have stealthed up upon you, kind of
chittering to themselves. We'll say they're
preparing for another round of either ranged, kind
of nasty arrows, or some of them are pulling out
these jagged little bladed elements. Ulfgar, you
have the initiative on this round, ready for
anything as you are, both swords out.
IFY: All right, I'm coming right at the first guy
who seems to be loading up the next bolt.
MATT: Okay. The closest to you would probably be
the one behind you, the one that hit you before.
All right, so, you go ahead and move up to it,
both swords out--
IFY: And I swing down at him with both my swords.
MATT: All right, go ahead and swing for the first
attack.
IFY: All right. 14.
MATT: 14. Okay. As you swing with the first one,
it swings down towards it. It manages to catch
purchase on the goblin's body armor but the armor
seems to streak it off to the side and your sword
plunges into the swamp floor.
IFY: Ooh. And then with the next one-- one.
MATT: With the second one you swing down, and this
time the goblin actually reaches up and somehow
catches the blade in its hand. You're like, "How
could a goblin catch a blade and not cut its own
hand off?" and you realize you were swinging it
with the flat end for some reason. The goblin goes
(cackling) and is standing there clutching your
blade, putting you in a very bad position. That
will end your turn. Alongside you, though, your
new son bravely runs up to your side, clutching
the hammer that you had, and says, "Leave my dad
alone!" Runs up to the goblin and swings. Natural
20!
(yelling)
IFY: Yes!
MATT: Double the four, that's eight points of
damage. While you're captured, your seven-year-old
son goes up with the war hammer and the side of
the goblin's skull explodes to the side. Its grip
is released as it falls to the ground.
IFY: That's my son! That's my son, he just killed
somebody! Ooh I'm so proud!
CHAT ROOM: --with his shield tightly for the rest
of the journey.
MATT: What was that one?
OFFSCREEN: You're going to love it.
DAN: I don't think we will.
MATT: What was that? I'm excited.
OFFSCREEN: I'll find it.
MATT: Okay. Bring it to us when you find it. All
right, no worries.
CHAT ROOM: Salty Pete a.k.a. Sam a.k.a. Money Sam
has a full 22-card Deck of Many Things appear in
his pocket and immediately plays three cards.
Also, Snugglelord turns into a body pillow.
OFFSCREEN: 60k.
MARISHA: Oh, 60k!
(cheering)
MARISHA: Yes, someone just threw a Deck of Many
Things on your ass!
MATT: Why are you guys laughing at me? Deck of
Many Things is a bad thing for you guys.
MARISHA: It's true. Yeah, we're going to die.
We're going to die.
MATT: So we'll get to that on your turn. That's
what you'll do on your turn. So suddenly you
realize-- you feel this strange weight appear in
the back pocket of your suit and you--
DAN: It's real Magic the Gathering in me pocket.
MATT: All right, we'll get to you next--
With that, that gets us to Quaalude, you're up.
LIAM: Dance, Mercer, dance.
(laughter)
ORION: Where am I on the field? I mean to say
(changes accent) where am I on the field? Oh.
Wonderful. I look at what's going on and go, oh, I
can barely stand this, and turn into a giant great
big bear.
IFY: You should've said you could do that back
when we first met him! That's the most exciting
magic.
DAN: Yeah, way to bear-y the lead.
MATT: You turn into a giant bear--
ORION: Yeah, and it's a brown bear. And, first of
all, I'd like to (bear noises) for a while and
then--
MARISHA: Yeah, looks like he's on some serious
hallucinogens.
MATT: All right, we got a goblin here and two
goblins here immediately in your vicinity.
ORION: All right, where's the Vox Moronica peeps?
MATT: Well, this is you, this is Edna, and this is
Kort. And over here you have Salty Pete who's the
pirate dwarf, you have Snugglelord and you have
Ulfgar.
IFY: And I'm crying, 'cause I'm proud of my son
right now.
ORION: I'm going to bounce over to the goblin to
my right.
MATT: Over here? Roll a claw and a bite. Go for
it.
MATT: (muttering) Deck of Many Things. Jesus Christ, guys.
DAN: Seriously, holy shit.
IFY: The deep cuts.
MARISHA: That wasn't the repeat one, there was
another one as well?
ORION: The bite misses. Right?
MATT: What'd you roll to hit?
ORION: Four.
MATT: Four misses, yeah.
ORION: And the other one is 18.
MATT: 18 does hit. Go ahead and roll damage for
the claw attack. The bite, you try and snatch up
the goblin, it manages to move out to the side,
but you manage to swing your claw wide and manage
to catch it in the face.
ORION: Seven damage.
MATT: Seven damage. As you swing, the claw hits
the side of the goblin's face. You hear it scream
as the claws spear through the side of its jaw and
neck, leaving open its jugular. Bleeds out and
goes gurgling to the surface of the muddy waters
of the swamp.
ORION: I'll turn to the other goblin and go,
(roars). And then that's my turn.
DAN: Did you motorboat his corpse?
(laughter)
MATT: By the way, you have enough movement to go
up to him if you want to.
ORION: Uh. Yeah, if I can.
MATT: Okay, so you move to there. So that goblin,
you're staring him down. He looks very scared,
watching that you just destroyed his ally. Okay,
that ends your turn. It is now their turn. This
one turns here. This one rushes into you, this one
comes up to Ulfgar, these two both rush into Salty
Pete. This one runs in against you. Actually, this
one's probably going to come over to Victor. All
right, so. First, we're going with it against you.
That is going to be a 14. What's your AC as the
bear? Okay, that hits. You go ahead and take five
points of slashing damage as its scimitar streaks
across the exterior of your bear hide. There's
going to be one against you, Kurt. That's not
going to hit, that's an eight. So as it comes
towards you, you dodge out to the side and knock
it away, it doesn't even get close enough.
LIAM: Eyy!
MATT: The one that's coming up behind you--
MARISHA: Oh, hello there little one!
MATT: That's going to be an 11 to hit.
MARISHA: Oh, my AC is 11.
MATT: 11? All right. You take five points of
slashing damage as it jumps in the air, and arcs
down with a blade, hitting your back.
MARISHA: Snugglelord, control your son!
(laughter)
MATT: The one that's going after Victor, that
hits. As you see one of the goblins rushes out
with this small spear and jams it into the side of
Victor, the blackpowder merchant, who goes,
(yelps) "My kidneys!"
ZAC: Oh, what a fucking shame.
DAN: That's some goblin dialysis.
MATT: This goblin here still has his bow out. He's
going to make a bow attack against you, Salty
Pete. That is a nine against armor class. It just
breaks off the outside of your armor. There are
now two of them-- or no, sorry, there's one that's
going after you, Ulfgar. That is a natural 20. You
take-- okay. Eight points of slashing damage as
the scimitar manages to hit you extremely hard
about the top of your armor. You can feel the
blade sink in about two inches and hit bone. It's
not very nice in this part. And this last goblin's
going towards your son, who just bashed the brains
out of one of its allies. That is going to be an
11, which does hit, because he doesn't have any
armor on.
ZAC: Looks like you didn't jump in front of that
attack for your son, there, dumbass!
MATT: He takes five points of slashing. You see
the other one come out with its scimitar and hack
into the side of your son. He screams out in pain.
You can see there's a big streak of blood down his
arm, and one of his arms is hanging limply to the
side. Tears welling up in his eyes when he looks
at you, like, "Dad?"
IFY: Don't worry, it's all part of the plan.
DAN: It'll grow back! Chicks dig scars.
MATT: And with that, Snugglelord, it's your turn.
CREW: Just so you know, "A bright light appears
above. It is Snugglelord's lost shield: his
pillow. He has to equip it for the remainder of
the journey."
MARISHA: Oh! You have a pillow shield.
MATT: In this moment, you feel a great boon come
down that same star that sparkled in the sky.
ZAC: Lord, what have you delivered to me?
MATT: And out of a sudden poof of dark shadow,
this pillow lands into your arms, holding,
strangely, the visage of both you and some other,
distant hero from another plane of existence. You
clutch it to yourself, knowing that having it will
give you a plus-two bonus to your armor class.
ZAC: This is really weird, Lord! Slightly
inappropriate, but I'll take it. Thank you?
MARISHA: Moving in the right direction. Don't ever
look a gift pillow in the mouth, all right?
MATT: So. What are you doing on your turn,
Snugglelord?
ZAC: I would like to Hex the enemy closest to me.
I can't see.
MATT: All right, the enemy closest to you is,
aside from you guys-- you're right here. There are
two enemies right here that are pretty close to
you.
ZAC: My right.
MATT: So right there. This guy here, you mean?
ZAC: Sure. Doesn't matter.
MATT: Okay. So this one that's currently attacking
the blackpowder merchant and stabbed him with the
spear.
ZAC: Wait, that's the one that's attacking the
blackpowder merchant? I'll attack the other one.
MATT: Okay. (laughs) You turn to the one that was
firing at Salty Pete.
ZAC: And I Hex him.
MATT: You Hex him, okay, it is currently hexed.
ZAC: And then I attack with the Eldritch Blast.
MATT: All right, all three of them? How many
Eldritch Blasts can you throw at this level?
ZAC: I believe just one. But I have the Agonizing
Blast as well, which adds four.
MATT: Right, okay. So go ahead and roll for an
attack against it. And add your spell attack,
which I believe is plus six, right?
ZAC: Eight, then?
MATT: Eight, okay.
ZAC: Help me roll better.
MATT: You come around and you focus, and your eyes
go dark black, and there's a burst of smoke energy
out the sides as all of a sudden the shadows from
the swamp reach up and cling to the body of this
goblin. It looks down, freaking out. It is now
currently feeling the entwined dark energy of your
hex. You put your hand out before it, and you
release a burst of dark arcane energy that goes
far too wide and strikes one of the nearby trees.
The goblin--
ZAC: I think the stapler's still having an effect
on me. Can you turn it off? I'd let it go, but I
can't stop shaking.
MATT: The goblin looks at you and goes (cackles).
ZAC: Oh, fuck you! I'll get you!
MATT: The blackpowder merchant is still holding
the spear to the side of him and goes (cackles).
You can move if you want. It's still your turn.
You can move, and then it'll be the end of your
turn.
ZAC: I can move, but can I do Misty Step, or is
that another--
MATT: Misty Step's a bonus action. You can only
move. Nothing's currently in melee with you, so
you can move however you want right now.
ORION: Let's just move away from Salty Pete.
DAN: Yeah, it's gonna get real messy in one
second.
ZAC: I'm going to move away from the blackpowder
merchant, and as I'm running away, I'm like, fend
for yourself!
MATT: Okay. And with that, Salty Pete, it's your
turn!
DAN: What's this in me pocket? It's some sort of
deck of many things.
ZAC: Wait, did you say 'dick'? There's a dick in
your pocket?
DAN: Deck.
ZAC: Did you say there's a dick in your pocket?
DAN: I'm just happy to see you. The answer is
both.
MATT: Is there a deck of cards somewhere, by the
way, guys? That's usually how this is played.
LIAM: An actual deck. We need an actual deck.
ORION: I only have my bullshit.
MATT: That's fine. We'll use what you have there.
ORION: Oh, shit, okay.
MATT: So go ahead and hand it to Salty Pete. Go
ahead and pull three of those.
DAN: Saints preserve us!
ORION: Let me shuffle-- that's fine, they're
shuffled.
ZAC: I'm still unclear. You have a dick in your
pocket--
DAN: Oh, you'll find out.
MATT: You draw three of them.
MARISHA: Draw good ones!
DAN: All right. Shall I flip the cards?
MATT: Yep. Go ahead.
DAN: King of diamonds, two of clubs, and two of
diamonds.
MATT: So, king of diamonds, you said?
DAN: King of diamonds, two of clubs, and two of
diamonds. We have many things in store.
ZAC: Well, that's not good. The DM's laughing.
MATT: You pull out the first card. Suddenly,
within your hands, it bursts into a golden flame.
Looking into it, your eyes spark, and the
experience of a thousand generations of your
family past come coursing into your body. You gain
50,000 experience points.
ALL: What?
MATT: You gain 50,000 experience points.
DAN: What the fucking christ?
MARISHA: You just went to like level 12.
ZAC: Super-Saiyan, man!
IFY: Hey, give me those cards!
MARISHA: Hey, shut up! Oh, we didn't hear it. No,
we were bitching.
CREW: "The guild laments the loss of your accent
and gifts you this blessed banhammer of doom."
MATT: There you have it. Banhammer of doom is
yours. Also acquired within your hands--
ZAC: I'm confused, because she said the loss of my
accent, but I didn't lose one.
LIAM: Salty Pete is now level nine.
(laughter)
MATT: So go ahead and roll 5d10 and add that to
your hit points.
MARISHA: That's amazing! Also, you get some fun
new abilities real quick.
MATT: It'll take a while, so we'll just go with
it. Add your hit points. You can tell him what
happens. All right, so. And the crossbow that's in
your hand all of a sudden fires aglow with bluish
magical energy. It's now considered a +2 magical
crossbow. So the second card you pulled is what?
DAN: That was one card? All right, the second card
was a two of clubs. Classic card.
MATT: (laughs)
DAN: Oh, shit.
MATT: All right. Your intelligence is now
permanently five lower.
DAN: Oh, that's-- I'm feeling fucking stupid.
ALL: (laughing)
MATT: You're allowed to draw an additional card if
you choose to.
DAN: Oh, 100%.
MATT: What's the third one you drew?
DAN: It's two of diamonds.
MATT: Okay. If you singlehandedly defeat the next
hostile monster you encounter, you gain experience
points enough to gain another level.
DAN: I'm doing it! My fourth card is the queen of
clubs.
MATT: Oh no.
DAN: This is going to end quickly.
MATT: Okay. The card disappears in a flicker of
fire, but you see in your mind, suddenly, your
vision press deep into the Nine Hells. You see a
large pit fiend demon all of a sudden glare back
and go, "Salty Pete. You are my quarry." And then
vanish in flame, just as the card did. You don't
know what happened, but you get the feeling
something very dangerous is now hunting you.
DAN: Yeah, I've got a horrible feeling.
ORION: So did that happen instead of the
intelligence thing?
MATT: No, that happened as well. Deck of many
things, guys.
ZAC: Your hair just turned blond.
DAN: I'm stupid now.
ZAC: Didn't know that. Good to know.
DAN: I've got a glowing blue--
IFY: I just want to know if I really did just feel
the presence of a demon pointing at you.
DAN: 100%. It kind of looked like that, but a
little bit meaner and not a waifu pillow.
ORION: And like four times the size, right?
LIAM: Matt, can we take intermission at some
point?
MATT: I'm going to right after this battle. Okay.
That ends your turn. So add your hit points. I'll
give you the sneak attack bonus that he gets now.
MARISHA: You can probably add more points to your
intelligence.
ZAC: Did you put this hammer in my hands?
DAN: No, I didn't.
MATT: All of your attacks and skills are also plus
two. Kurt, you're up. Kurt and Edna.
LIAM: Where's the boy? Where's the boy?
MATT: Little boy is right here.
ORION: Don't kill the one next to Salty Pete. He
has to take that one out.
LIAM: I want to walk over to the goblin. I know
there's one right behind me, I'm just going to
keep walking. If it takes a swing, I don't give a
fuck. I don't give a fuck, yeah. I'm going to walk
towards the goblins by the boy. Yeah.
CREW: The gods were unclear.
LIAM: And now, you
might not have noticed it before, guys, but I got
almost-- what do I got?
CREW: This is for the loss of your accent.
LIAM: Does it come back? I get a prop toy?
ZAC: What kind of sick game are the gods playing
on me?! You give me a pillow and a hammer and then
take the hammer away and I'm left with the fucking
pillow?
MATT: The hammer, all of a sudden, the edge of it
bursts into flames through the sheer force of
frustration and anger. Your accent does not come
back, but you feel the vengeance for losing it now
is coursing through the actual weapon that you
hold.
LIAM: So I walk over to him, and you guys might
not have noticed this before, but I got nothing on
but leather thongs and a tattoo of a badger on my
chest. Half of my chest is a tattoo of a badger,
and I'm already in a rage, because right before
the fight started, I went into a rage. I take my
free hand and I fucking rake it down my chest, and
I say, let's go, Gary! And take my warpick off my
back, and I want to recklessly attack the one that
struck the boy. I want to split him right down the
fucking middle.
MATT: All right, go ahead and roll for the
attack.
ZAC: You're going to not use the hammer that just
started glowing?
MARISHA: Use the hammer!
LIAM: Am I getting a magic weapon? Is that what
this is? It's unclear. All right. So I'm going to
use this magic weapon. I'm attacking recklessly. I
got two 17s, so that's a 21.
MATT: 21 hits. All right, so go ahead and roll the
damage for one of your regular weapons, and add
1d6 flaming damage to it.
LIAM: (counting) 12.
MATT: 12. You walk up and just smash it into the
mud. The actual flames cause a sizzling sound as
it hits the marshy ground. What was once a goblin
is now a charred and liquefied mess.
LIAM: The blood splashes onto me, and I look down
at the kid, and I wipe it off my face, and I wipe
it down his head, and I say, today you are a man.
IFY: I look at Stephen, and I'm like, it's all
part of the plan.
MATT: Edna. What are you going to do?
MARISHA: All right, so I have one guy on my butt?
Okay, so question. Jesus. Oh, goodness me. As part
of being a conjuration wizard, I can do a minor
conjuration as an action, and I can just conjure
things that are up to ten pounds. Can I conjure a
ten-pound rock over his head?
MATT: You could, yes.
MARISHA: Okay. So I'm going to turn around and be
like, I told you to get your son away from me,
Snugglelord! And I drop a ten-pound rock on his
head.
MATT: Okay. It appears. Just go ahead and roll a
d20 and add your intelligence modifier to it, to
see how you're able to conjure it in the right
space above it. What'd you roll? You rolled a one.
Okay. So here's what happens. Make a dexterity
saving throw. As you finish your conjuration, you
go, this way! And the rock appears right above
you.
ORION: Four.
MATT: Four. You take--
MARISHA: Five total.
MATT: You take four points of bludgeoning damage
as the rock slams down onto your head. You can
feel your neck jostle and your whole head ringing
for a second.
MARISHA: I'm still new at this! I'm still
learning.
IFY: Somebody save grandma!
Somebody go in there and save grandma!
MARISHA: What? Belial! What?
MATT: Ulfgar, you're up.
IFY: So now I look at this goblin fronting me,
it's like, guess what? Today you made a mistake.
First mistake: walking up into this swamp. Second
mistake: messing with me and my son and my family
I have here. I've got grandma over there who just
got hit by a rock. I've got--
ZAC: A rock she dropped on her own head, mind
you.
IFY: Semantics. So I'll sweep with Linda and
Regina.
MATT: Okay.
IFY: First one swings for-- goodness. 23.
MATT: That hits. Go for it, yeah.
IFY: And the second one is a one.
MATT: Okay. Roll damage on the first one.
IFY: All right, so for the first one. Where's that
d8? There it is. So nine.
MATT: Nine points of damage. As you bring your
first sword down, it embeds itself about seven
inches into the chest of this small goblin, who
looks at you, twitching, its eyes slowly rolling
back in its head. With a big grin, you bring your
second blade down and swing it outward. It cleaves
his torso in two, but the inertia pulls outward in
the direction of your son.
IFY: No!
MATT: Go ahead and just roll a d20.
IFY: 18.
MATT: 18, okay. You manage to steel your will
enough to stop the blade but an inch from his
face, the metal sitting there and shimmering with
power. He looks at you with a moment of sudden
confusion and fright.
IFY: It's all part of the plan.
ZAC: I think that small boy you took away from
wherever he may be from just wet himself. He
definitely peed himself.
MATT: Quaalude, you're up.
ORION: Oh. Roar! And he's still on me?
MATT: Go for it. Bite/claw attack on him. (laughs)
ORION: What is this, my dex?
LIAM: Strength or dex for him?
MATT: This is your attack, yeah, strength. The
attack bonus should be with the bear's stat
block.
LIAM: You weren't prepared for that, were you?
MATT: I've got the monster manual right here. If
you're a druid--
MARISHA: It's a brown bear, right? At the very,
very back.
MATT: Brown bear, there you go. Plus five to hit.
LIAM: Plus five to both of those. 17 and 12.
MATT: So 17 and 12? 17 hits. So the first attack
hits. That would be your bite.
ORION: Okay, sure. Yeah. That's 1d8?
MATT: 1d8 plus the strength modifier.
MARISHA: Plus strength. Five, right? What's your strength?
Plus two.
ORION: Oh, five.
MATT: Five points of damage. You bite at it with
your bite, get a big old chunk of its shoulder and
tear it off, and it screams out in pain, the dark
blood of the goblin pouring down, but it's still
standing angrily at you. As you swipe your claw at
it, it ducks back out of the way, and it looks at
you with this foam at the edge of its mouth.
LIAM: Is it the bear's strength bonus? Add two
more points of damage to that.
MATT: So it would be seven total. So as it darts
back and looks at you, growling, it's lost way too
much blood and tries to make a swipe at you, but
falls face-first down into the swamp. You can feel
the gurgling of its final breath pulling out into
the water at the top of the marsh. It is gone.
ORION: Oh. Sweet. That made a big difference.
MATT: You can still move if you want.
MARISHA: Help me!
ORION: Where's Edna? Let me go--
MARISHA: I've hit my head and I can't get up.
ZAC: Hit your stupid button!
ORION: I have that chunk still in my mouth that I
ripped off, yeah? I'm going to spit it in the
goblin's face.
MATT: Okay. Make an intimidation check.
LIAM: Wow, it rolled up on the dice. Not too
good.
MATT: The goblin catches it in its mouth and
starts chewing. Yeah, goblins are a little weird.
All right, that brings it to their turn.
Strangely, this fight-- most goblins are very
cowardly creatures, but you start noticing in
these goblins as you're fighting them, all of
their eyes are clouded over, and they're fighting
with a fervor and a perpetual anger where they
don't even really notice the danger they're in.
This is uncommon to a species that is generally
cowardly by nature. The goblin that you just
finished chewing looks at you and lashes out at
you with its scimitar. That is going to be a 20.
Hits, okay. You take five points of slashing
damage as it arcs its scimitar across your bear
form, leaving another big streak of slash damage
across the front of your body. We have the
goblin that is hexed. It is going to be attacking
you, Salty Pete. That is going to be a 17 to hit.
DAN: That hits.
MATT: All right, so for that, you take five points
of piercing damage from a shortbow arrow that
(impact) into your back.
DAN: I can afford it.
OFF-SCREEN: Incoming message.
MATT: Okay.
DAN: The anticipation is quite literally killing
me.
CHAT ROOM: Whenever an ally is injured,
Snugglelord has the uncontrollable urge to hug
them and they heal.
LIAM: Aw, that's sweet.
MATT: So you see this arrow sticking out of your
ally's back, and you suddenly feel like, oh no! I
need to go and help my friend! But we'll get to
your turn--
ZAC: When the fuck would I ever say or do that?!
(laughter)
MATT: We'll get to your turn when we get there.
All right, so. The one is going to be attacking
the powder merchant. It misses. You now have--
this one is off on the side. It is going to rush
up towards the Snugglelord now with its scimitar
in the air, and that's going to be a 14 to hit.
What's your AC?
ZAC: More than that. I have my trusty pillow. 15.
MATT: 15, that'll do. You hold your pillow out in
front of you, and the blade arcs off, sparks
flying, almost like the exterior of the pillow is
iron for a split-second.
ZAC: What the shit?!
MATT: Bringing it to your turn, Snugglelord.
CHAT ROOM: A black unicorn randomly appears and
permanently attaches itself to Snugglelord's
loins.
(laughter)
MATT: As this happens, you feel this urge to heal
your friend, you hear this tiny (hoofbeats) and
you see this really, really small pitch-black
unicorn comes up and runs up and just latches
itself to the outside of your crotch and forms
this protective barrier.
ORION: Unicorn codpiece!
DAN: You've got a unicock.
ZAC: Look, we both leveled up, Salty Pete.
MATT: So it's your turn.
ZAC: So now am I--
MATT: You're right here, this goblin's in front of
you. You feel the uncontrollable urge to go and
help someone who's been wounded recently, which
would be either Edna or Salty Pete.
(laughter)
LIAM: Work that unicorn, girl!
ZAC: Edna, I feel--
MARISHA: What? I'm sorry, you're going to have to
speak up--
ZAC: The Shathroom is drawing me towards you.
MARISHA: What?
ZAC: The Shathroom is commanding me to help you,
to heal you, I don't want to do it, but it's--
MARISHA: Oh, Asmodan.
ZAC: It's making me do it! (strained sounds)
MATT: So you move to her. Put you there, it's
fine. The urge makes you move a little bit faster
than you normally would. You get up to her, but
the goblin does get one swipe at you as you run
by. That is a 16. You take five points of slashing
damage as the blade streaks across the back of
your tiefling form.
ZAC: "Ah! This is stupid!"
MATT: You rush up and hug Edna from behind--
go ahead and roll a d8.
MARISHA: I missed you too, Snugglelord.
MATT: Go ahead and roll a d8, Snugglelord.
MARISHA and LIAM: The unicock!
ZAC: It's a three.
MATT: Three. You heal three points of damage from
the warm embrace of the Snugglelord. And you
almost take damage from the piercing of the tiny
unicorn horn in the side of your hip.
ZAC: It's like holding legos in a pantyhose! This
is gross! Ugh!
MATT: Salty Pete, who is now the Conan of this
adventure, it's your--
DAN: I'm feeling great! So, is it possible to use
my cunning action to hide until I go into
stealth?
MATT: You have to really be in a situation where
you can hide properly.
LIAM: You can run up to any enemy who's five feet
away from one of your allies and distract them.
MATT: Which, by the way, currently the powder
merchant is fighting this guy, so this guy you
could still do some sneak attack damage if you hit
it. You just want to try and get away from it
because if you're attacking with a crossbow, you
have disadvantage if it's right up next to you.
DAN: Got you. All right, and there's a guy who's
right next to me as well?
MATT: Right there, yeah.
DAN: Okay. All right, I'm going to use my cunning
action to disengage. Here we go, pretty cunning!
MATT: Where do you want to go from there? Do you
want to move--
DAN: I'd like to get behind him so I can flank him
with my sword.
MATT: Okay, so you move over there.
ZAC: Do you need my magical codpiece for this?
DAN: No! You're fine, just hug the lady on the
ground!
MATT: So you pull your sword out? Go ahead and
roll for an attack.
DAN: Okay. It's a 20, not natural, though.
MATT: Okay that hits! Go ahead and roll damage
plus sneak attack.
DAN: All right! That's going to be a lot, I need
6d6.
(laughter)
DAN: That's stupid.
LIAM: I played as a rogue for three years before I
could do that!
DAN: Listen, there's many things that are going to
happen tonight.
ORION: Annihilation! He's dead! Whatever it is--
MATT: How much damage is that?
DAN: Let's see. That's like 40. Some shit. Okay,
12, 22, 27, 28 points of damage. Wait, plus three
more... 31!
MATT: 31! It had seven hit points. So, as you
vanish stealthily into the darkness of the swamp,
you can see the goblin that's currently harrying
the blackpowder merchant, Victor, looks over its
shoulder, "Huh?", as suddenly the blade protrudes
from its chest with such force that its ribcage
tears open, spraying the contents of its torso all
over the blackpowder merchant.
DAN: "Oh, you're in the splash zone!"
(laughter)
MATT: (coughing) "Good job!"
DAN: "Surprise! Here's Salty!"
MATT: Kurt, you're up.
LIAM: How do I top that?
DAN: Do I level up?
ORION: Yeah he did! He leveled up! He got to level
ten!
ZAC: Guys, we have a message!
CHAT ROOM: Bahamut, impressed with his bravery,
imbues a "XIX, the Sun" card to Stephen. He is now
a monk.
MARISHA: Wait, Stephen's now a monk?
MATT: As you look over to your child in this beam
of-- a silver-platinum light comes down from some
mystical source, you hear the flapping wings of a
dragon--
CHAT ROOM: Suddenly, in the middle of whatever is
happening, a beautiful and dangerous princess
appears in battle calling herself Ryco.
Snugglelord immediately falls madly in love with
her and proclaims to his go--
ZAC: Ryco, if you made that message...
MATT: You mean Ryan Copple?
ORION: Ryco is--
MATT: Oh, Ryco. Okay, well--
MARISHA: That's hilarious. I'm hoping so.
DAN: I'm level ten, you guys!
ZAC: So a princess named Ryco-- I have not got to
do anything--
MATT: And just then Ryco appears on the
battlefield, three-point landing, Avengers-style,
looks over and you can see now, this beaming
platinum light that's on your son, coming down, is
now coming from her as she holds aloft her holy
symbol. She looks down and goes, "Stephen, you
shall be the savior of this group", at which point
you see now his muscles pulse into him and now he
looks intensely ripped, as bracers now attach
themselves.
MARISHA: Is he still seven?
MATT: He's still seven years old, but the
scariest-looking seven-year-old you've ever seen.
DAN: "The sweet baby's got a six-pack on his
six-pack!"
MATT: All right, so Kurt. All this happens around
you, the princess winks at you,"Go! Fight,
once-Irishman!"
(laughter)
OFFSCREEN: Nobody has the thing up on their phone
or something? They're being cut off, some of
them.
ZAC: Some of them are getting cut off? I don't
have my phone on me. I can do that.
LIAM: Oh, jeebus. What enemies are left? I
don't--
MATT: There's one there and one here.
LIAM: All right. I'm running towards-- there's one
by Edna and Snugglelord? I'm running over. And I
yell-- and it's attacking Edna?
MATT: Yes.
LIAM: And I say, (irish accent): "Nobody--" Fuck!
(Brooklyn accent) Nobody touches my fucking girlfriend!
Come here, you! And I take the hammer,
right in his head.
MATT: All right, go ahead and roll an attack.
MARISHA: "Oh, Kurt! Thank you so much, my sweetie
patootie!"
(laughter)
LIAM: That's a 19.
MATT: That hits, go ahead and roll damage.
LIAM: Seven, nine, 11. Age is just a number, all
right?
MATT: As you rush over, you take the hammer and
smack it into the side of the goblin and it goes
just scattered into ash, and slowly drifts down
across the bottom of the swamp floor.
LIAM: And I take some of the blood off my weapon
and I smear it on Edna's face and say, now you are
a man.
MARISHA: What? I've got nice cans? Why thank you,
I know! You should've seen me when I was 20!
MATT: Edna, it's your turn.
MARISHA: What? Oh, it's my turn. Okay, am I still
surrounded by anything?
MATT: No, there's just one over here and one
goblin that looks hexed and is currently very
outmatched. The party is ever growing.
MARISHA: "Is that your son, Olaf, or is that a
goblin? Is that a gob-- Magic Missile!"
MATT: All right! Go ahead and roll Magic Missile
damage.
MARISHA: Two, five, ten!
MATT: The goblin, which now pulls out a second
arrow and is aiming it towards you. As it pulls
back, the three arrows go (swooshing) as each
burst of arcane energy slams one into its chest,
one into its shoulder, and the final one slams
under the chin, causing the front of its head to
explode out into a glimmering spray of crimson
into the night.
DAN: Christ!
MATT: The current threat disengaged, you all look
around at the chaos that just ensued and have to
take a moment to really digest what has
transpired, and with that we're going to take a
quick five-minute break! We'll be right back to
continue what the hell this is.
MARISHA: We got to level up Dan Casey!
DAN: I have 64,000 experience points!
(laughter)
[soft music]
GIRL: Thank you.
BOY: Thank you.
[soft music]
GIRL: Thank you.
BOY: Thank you.
[soft music]
GIRL: Thank you.
[break]
MATT: Welcome back, ladies and gentlemen, to the
adventures of Vox Moronica and all the chaos that ensues.
ZAC: I have one quick message, guys. Because we
hit our goal, we've now raised it to 75,000, and we
have until the end of this game to raise it. Now,
don't forget, as you've probably witnessed, every
$500 donation, we've been reacting and doing the
crazy shit that you've been telling us to do.
DAN: I'm level ten now! Everything's on fire! A
child has a six-pack! You did this!
ZAC: And I'm about to, well--
MATT: All right, so here we go. So.
MARISHA: What level is Stephen, by the way?
MATT: Well, Stephen is now currently a level one
monk.
MARISHA: Level one monk, all right.
MATT: Which is still pretty good for a
seven-year-old, I'm just saying. So you guys, as
the battle winds down and the initial adrenaline
wears off, you can see Ryco, the princess that
landed in a three-point, stands up and looks over,
armor glimmering, beautiful face, long dark hair.
Glances about and gives everyone a look--
ZAC: Huge knockers.
MATT: Huge, enormous, and glances about the rest
of the party and goes, "You warriors have proven
"yourselves to delve into this dangerous night and
this swamp. Who do you call leader?"
ZAC: Me. This one.
MATT: She approaches you. "And what purpose do
you--"
CHAT ROOM: Gary the Badger comes to life as a
spirit animal and permanent companion of Liam's
character. Gary, feeling the deep hurt inside
Liam, restores his original accent. Liam can
change Gary change between.
MATT: So what was the top of that one?
ZAC: I think the computer volume needs to be
turned back up there, and I've got it right here.
"Gary the Badger comes to life as a spirit animal
and permanent companion of Liam's character. Gary,
"feeling the deep hurt inside Liam, restores his
original accent. Liam can change Gary change
"between the tattoo form and the spirit form at
will."
DAN: Holy shit!
LIAM: The accent is back?
MATT: The accent is back. The badger, Gary,
reaches out to you and (animal sounds).
LIAM: So Kurt drops to his knees and openly starts
weeping and hugs the badger to him and says, I
lost Gary five years ago, and there's been a hole
inside me ever since! You, little man, you and I
are going to go places! And he's into my tattoo.
DAN: That's freaky as shit!
ORION: I turn out of bear form.
MATT: Okay.
CHAT ROOM: Salty Pete suddenly sees his lost
fingers magically reappear. As he attempts to feel
them, the illusion fades and the fingers
disappear. He hears the demon's cackling laughter
in the darkness.
DAN: Why! Why would you take my fingers, then
bring them back, and then cackle at my loss?! Oh
no, my long-lost digits! I thought they were a
necklace, but no! They're a cruel fallacy!
MATT: As the illusion of the fingers fades, you hear
in the distance, echoing in the dark forest,
(cackling). You sense some very dark evil is very,
very near.
DAN: Oh, thank goodness I'm level ten.
MATT: At which point, Ryco has now approached the
de facto leader of the group and says, "Your name?"
ZAC: I'm Snugglelord.
MATT: "And your purpose in this swamp?"
ZAC: To take your hand in marriage.
MATT: Pardon me?
ZAC: I get down on one knee and I look at Ryco
right in the eyes, and I say, you're awesome and
amazing at everything. Will you be my
big-knockered wife?
MATT: Roll persuasion with advantage.
LIAM: That's fucking beautiful.
MATT: As the rays of moonlight come streaking
through the tops of the forest, this crystalline,
beautiful moment-- You roll twice; you take the
higher. Frames the two of them, this male and
female form, masculine--
CHAT ROOM: Crazy merchant man and Stephen both
shout, Look these! This burning red, an explosion
the size of a nuke goes off in the distance. (two
tracks playing over each other) feel of change
over why.
ZAC: I'm going to load those up.
MATT: Load those up. We still have a couple
messages to get to, guys.
ZAC: That was a 17.
MATT: Ryco glanced down at you, and you can see
this red flush in her cheeks. She goes, "Well,
"you, warrior, you shall be my champion. I accept
your hand."
IFY: Yeah, she accepted, but it was more than 17.
ZAC: I'm sorry. It was a 23 or something like
that. I was underselling it.
MATT: Nevertheless, she takes your hand and pulls
you up and, while you yourself are caught in her
eyes, she, in a very forceful warrior self,
reaches out, takes you by the hand, and Frenches
you deeply in the center of the swamp.
(whooping)
IFY: I cover up Stephen's eyes.
ORION: From that?
LIAM: Is Frenching you in the swamp a euphemism?
MATT: It is now.
DAN: Don't look it up on Urban Dictionary!
ZAC: I pull back and say, sorry, sorry, that's
actually just a unicorn. It's not what you think.
It's literally a unicorn. I'm sorry.
MATT: She looks disappointed, then smiles and
goes, "Well, I entrust you are here for worthy
"reasons. Now, as my future husband, I wish you all
health, and I gift you this." And her fingers go
out, and with a magical array, this strange
leather girdle appears and hovers in the air.
"This will give magical power to whoever should
wear it, and a gift of switching their sex to the
"other side to gain a new, beautiful perspective on
life. Who would take this boon?"
ZAC: Guys, my Ryco's into some freaky shit.
DAN: I feel like we all want that. I feel like all
of us really want it. All of us.
ZAC: I mean, you could give it to your husband if
you ever wanted, per se, a wife as well.
IFY: I think it should go to me and my buff-ass
son. I mean, we got a lot of stuff to work out.
ZAC: I would say it would be quite nice for your son to
have a mother as well.
IFY: You don't know. I need to play two roles. He
don't have a mom anymore. I need to be the daddy
and the mama.
DAN: I'm clearly the strongest one here. I need
the strength that comes with being a woman.
MARISHA: What?
ORION: I mean, by all means.
MATT: I would like the entire party to roll a
persuasion check. Whoever rolls highest--
MARISHA: I take seniority shit around here! I'm
old! Oh, I have an 18!
LIAM: I'm petting Gary under a tree and watching
all this.
MARISHA: What was it? Persuasion? 20 total.
ORION: Two.
ZAC: 17.
DAN: Six.
IFY: Five.
MARISHA: Look, you see, I've been around for quite
some time, and I have had to live under the
patriarchal values of this kingdom, and you know
what? It's really tough being a woman. I had to
birth two big, strong boys out of me.
ORION: From your vagina?
MARISHA: And you know what? My good late Charles
husband, God rest his soul, he was a good husband,
but he--
ORION: They always used to say, Charles would
charge.
MARISHA: What?
MATT: Ryco does this with her fingers, and the
girdle drifts toward you and goes, "It is your
"choice, then. You decide who takes the girdle." At
which point, she looks over to Snugglelord, winks,
and then vanishes in a puff of smoke.
DAN: Bye! Bye, Ryco!
IFY: It's all right. Sometimes we've got to be
nice to Grandma, okay?
DAN: Yep, well, sure. She'll be Grandpa.
ORION: Are you going to try it on? Does it make
you younger?
MARISHA: Yes. I don't think so. I think it just
makes me Ed.
ORION: So it will make you a gross old man with
low-hanging balls. That's not good.
MATT: So you take the girdle. Do you put it on?
MARISHA: Yes, I do.
MATT: All right. As she puts the girdle on, you
can see her older, elderly woman form shimmers and
shifts into instead an elderly, hunched-over man
with a hook nose and a cleft chin.
MARISHA: What do I look like? Am I handsome?
ORION: It looks like your name is Ed, now.
MATT: At which point, Stephen, the monk kid, and
the old blackpowder merchant, both together
shout-- which I can't shout together because I'm
one human being-- "Look! An explosion!" "Look! An
"explosion!" And you guys look off in the distance
and see this bright red glow as an almost
nuclear-sized red burst comes coasting through the
trees.
ORION: I hang onto the chain-link fence.
ZAC: I grab the merchant, and I put him in front
of me and hold him.
IFY: I grab and protect my buff-ass son.
DAN: I clench my body.
LIAM: I grab Ed and say, it doesn't mean a thing,
baby! And I kiss him.
ORION: I look at playground.
MARISHA: It's 2015! We can be progressive, god
damn it!
MATT: As the blast wave comes coursing through the
swamp, expecting to be turned to dust, instead a
wave of warmth drifts over you. You open your
eyes, releasing the tension, and you and you and
you and you are all women.
ZAC: I have boobs!
DAN: I'm Salty Pietra!
MATT: You turn back to Edna.
DAN: At least you have the girdle!
ZAC: I have boobs!
MARISHA: I didn't even get to see what my member
looked like! That's really unfortunate!
ZAC: Oh, I should look fast.
DAN: Now it's an innie again!
IFY: That don't mean a thing, baby! That's Ulfgar
Fireforge, ex-pit fighter, ex-bin, sellsword;
bullshit talks, money walks; I got a son now; his
name is Stephen--
MATT: "No, it's now Stephanie!" As you now seem to
have a monk daughter who all of a sudden, the
muscles rip even heavier as she all of a sudden
ascends to level ten to match Salty Pete.
DAN: Finally! Someone on my level!
MARISHA: What? Why? Just because?
MATT: Because the deity Shathrum demanded that
this blast of energy also instill the heroic
presence within this child, who ages four years
into the future. At the tender age of 11, this
daughter, now strong, Korra-style, glances up at
her mother and goes, "Now I can protect you, Mom!"
IFY: That's my baby. Aw.
ORION: I don't know about you, but I'm quite happy
with the results.
ZAC: I have boobs!
LIAM: Kurt holds her bosom and says, my tattoo's
now three-dimensional!
DAN: It's like a relief map!
MARISHA: I just want you to know, Kurt, that this
doesn't change anything. You were open-minded when
I was a man, and now--
MATT: Everyone roll a perception check.
LIAM: Feel these! They're fantastic!
MARISHA: Okay. Ooh!
LIAM: Roll a what? What's going on?
MATT: Roll a perception check, for the love of
God! Roll a perception check! All of you!
IFY: I rolled a one.
MARISHA: 25.
IFY: A one.
DAN: 15!
ZAC: 24.
MATT: Both Quaaludia--
ORION: You can call me Q.
MATT: Q and Edna glance off, and you see in the
distance this large mound of swamp earth that
seems to be similar to what the alchemist had told
you to go ahead and locate, where apparently this
doorway had been opened.
ORION: I go over to investigate. You want to come
in?
MARISHA: Ah, yes. I think we were standing next to
what we were looking for the whole time.
ORION: Is something wrong with your ear?
MARISHA: I don't know. I was talking to you via
comms, I don't know why.
ORION: What is a comm? You so crazy, girl. I love
you. Let's go investigate, yes? I walk over. I see
what is going on.
LIAM: I take the war pick off my back, and I start
walking toward the mound.
MATT: All right. Making your way deeper into the
Zola Swamp toward this mound, you begin to recall,
you've heard mysteries about this Zola Swamp, and
you've heard such things as rampant curses. The
magical energies here are so strong and cross over
so with many realms that chaos seems to burst out
at periods of time, and you feel like this entire
group has fallen into a nexus period in which the
magical energies uncontrollably alter the
landscape around, thus the events that have
transpired in the recent time.
MARISHA: This explains why it's been a very weird
day.
DAN: There's got to be a rational explanation.
MATT: As you make your way toward this earthy
mound, you look about the outside and you can see
there are a series of animal limbs and strange,
crudely carved runes and various skulls that are
all hanging by pieces of twine all around the
outside of this entranceway that seems to delve
into a deep, animalistically carved natural tunnel
into the swamp floor proper.
ORION: I want to do an insight check.
MATT: Onto?
ORION: To see if I recognize any of the carvings
or any of that stuff.
MATT: It wouldn't be insight, per se. Insight's
more of a person's motives. You can go ahead and
roll a religion check.
ORION: Okay. That's 14.
MATT: Okay.
IFY: Can I roll a perception check?
MATT: What are you looking for?
IFY: My vagina.
(laughter)
ORION: I guess we should explore ourselves.
IFY: That is a nine.
MATT: Nine? You're going to be busy for a while.
DAN: Take 20!
MATT: All right, so. Glancing about--
ZAC: When you find it, it's glorious.
MATT: --the rooms, as you look across them, the
carvings, there are these strange, ancient
symbols. You can see what looks almost like a G
and an S. These are symbols of the great, ancient
deity, Shathrum.
ORION: I recognize these things, eh, Snugglefoots?
Come over here and look. It seems like there is
some kind of G and S.
ZAC: It's the Shathrum! Shathrum! Our god!
DAN: Ah, your god.
ZAC: There's only one god!
IFY: Excuse me, did you not see that dragon come
out and make my daughter buff? Did you not see
that dragon come out and make my daughter buff?
Did you not see the dragon in the sky?
ZAC: That was God, the Shathrum!
IFY: No, that was Bahamut.
DAN: Then how do you explain the demon that took
away my fingers, then made them come back, then
took them away?
ZAC: It's the sick sense of humor of the
Shathrum!
ORION: Can I feel it? Is it open?
MATT: Yeah. It is an open tunnel that leads deeper
into the earth itself.
ZAC: We have to go! We have to! This is my
calling!
DAN: Let's do it!
ZAC: I was expecting resistance, but you want
to--? Okay, fine. I just thought you would be
against me on this.
DAN: It was a run-by fruiting.
MATT: The feminine bravery that seems to have
taken root in Salty Pete, you can see the
confidence of a modern-day woman taking over what
was once a relatively questioning male, leads the
charge deeper into the swamp earth before you. The
tunnel, dark and moldy from the interior, the cold
air hitting you-- you can smell mildew and rot and
what sounds like wood that has largely fallen into
dusty awfulness. Descending further into the
cavern, you hear in the distance low muttering,
this small, synchronized, cacophonous chant, this
(whispered incantations) echoing maybe, you'd
imagine, 20, 30 feet ahead of you, around a bend.
You can see a little bit of flickering light
that's pushing into the hallway from around that
turn.
ORION: When I hear that, I'm going to use my Mask
of the Wild, and I'm going to blend into the side
of the rock.
MATT: Okay. As you shimmer to the side of the
rock, go ahead and roll a stealth roll with advantage.
ORION: Yeah, that'll work. That's a 19.
MATT: 19? Okay. You crest around the edge. You
enter an actual chamber at the end of this
hallway, closed off, and there's a couple of small
rocks in the center. But in the middle of this,
you see a large bonfire. An orangish-blue flame is
flickering and burning. You can see stones
arranged almost like a haphazard, half-fallen
doorway. You can see what appears to be four
goblins around, one of which is larger than the
others with all this war paint across its face,
and they're all chanting in unison. (chanting)
MARISHA: I go ahead and cast Mage Armor on
myself.
MATT: All right, you have Mage Armor on yourself.
You can see though, the lead goblin is throwing
things into the flame. With each toss, the flames
flicker up into vibrant blue flames and then die
back down, the color turning more and more from a
blue to a bright, vibrant yellow. It's pulsing
now. The fire's pulsing.
DAN: I'd like to stealth.
MATT: Roll stealth, Salty Petunia.
DAN: All right, that is a 30.
MATT: Okay!
DAN: I'm level ten!
MATT: All right. So as you come around the bend
too, you see the druid, which is currently hidden
across the rock. You also have the same view, and
you can see the danger at this. Suddenly, as
you're watching, you see the flames flicker in,
and the goblins all stand up, and a tendril spikes
out of the flames. This small purple door seems to
open up, and a tentacle reaches out and wraps
around a goblin and pulls it in. It screams. All
the goblins keep chanting, keep chanting. It opens
up even further and further, and from what you can
see now, this entity starts pulling through. It's
this weird, fleshy mass, almost like this
amorphous, giant cluster of flesh that is
surrounded with teeth and eyes, eyes that glance
around in all positions, mouths that open up and
screech and squeal, and then disappear. It's
constantly moving and shifting in its position,
and as it comes out, this weird, twisting
cacophony of voices of all different shrieking
sounds and low guttural murmurs all happening at
once, (eldritch noises). The goblins smile and
look more and more feverish as suddenly it reaches
out and grabs another one, stuffing it into its
maw, until eventually only the lead goblin
remains. As he stands there, chanting and chanting
and chanting, the creature moves forward and
slowly envelops and rolls over the goblin. You
hear this scream as its body is completely
consumed. As it pulls back, you can see almost the
goblin's face appear as part of its fleshy mass
for a second and then vanish into it. You also see
a partially absorbed human arm and half of a face
that matches the description of the assistant,
Cyril, that you were coming to find.
DAN: It's Ulfgar's vagina! We found it!
IFY: Real funny, guys. You guys are real funny.
ZAC: I take my imp off my shoulder, and I say,
Lucas! Stand five feet in front of me! And then I
use Crown of Madness, and I attach it to the
merchant, my "son", and make him also stand five
feet in front of me, creating a human shield--
well, not human, but a shield, a body shield, what
children are for. They're ready to soak up that
damage.
DAN: How big is this entity, again? How gigantic?
MATT: There it is.
DAN: (nervous laughter) Not great.
MATT: So I would ask all of you to roll
initiative, please.
ORION: Matthew? As position goes, I'm right
there.
MATT: You're off to the side?
ORION: Up against there, and yeah. And my Mask of
the Wild, I look like the wall. That's what it does.
MATT: Yes, I'm aware.
DAN: Am I still stealthed for this, or did I--?
MATT: You are still stealthed, currently, as far
as you know.
DAN: I'll find out real quick.
MATT: Yes, you will. All right. So initiative
rolls, everyone? We have 25 to 20?
LIAM: 20.
MATT: 20, all right. All right.
ZAC: 18.
MATT: 18 for Snuggs over there. 20 to 15, 15 to
ten?
ORION: 13.
DAN: I also have a 13.
MATT: All righty. Salty. Ten to five? Five to
one?
IFY: One!
ZAC: Still looking for that vagina, eh?
IFY: I'm having fun here.
MATT: So top. Kurt, you're actually up first, and
you are back here with the rest of the group in
this circumstance.
MARISHA: Go get them, tiger!
LIAM: Right. Well, obviously I would like to
fucking rage! And I push my beautiful mane of hair
back and slap my-- oh, fucking hell, that hurts.
Let's do this, Gary! And Gary the badger flies out
of my breast and lands in front of me, ready to
fight by my side.
ZAC: You have boobs now!
LIAM: And I pull up one of my hammers and flip it
in my hand, and as soon as I catch it, I throw it
at the fucking thing.
MATT: All right, so as you move forward to get
within visual range of it, moving past your
allies, Gary appears right in front of you. This
dice will be your Gary badger. And you can go
ahead and throw the hammer at the entity. It is
with disadvantage because of the distance it is
from you right now. So go for it.
LIAM: Oh, that's terrible. Oh, terrible, terrible.
It flies right by.
MATT: It does. It actually lands over here. Your
hammer ends up slamming and streaking across,
hitting this piece of stone, and then arcing off
to the side. So is that a regular hammer or the
magical one?
LIAM: That was a regular one. I'm just fucking
glad I'm Irish again.
MATT: All right, that's your turn. Next, this
creature comes streaming forth
(eldritch chanting). Okay. As it moves forward, the ground
you can see around it, the actual stone floor,
begins to almost warp and bend like it doesn't
have, in its near vicinity, the same hard
physicality as it did before. All righty. So first
it's going to go ahead and start-- it's going to
go ahead and reach out with one of its tendrils
towards you. It has a bunch of these biting mouths
on it. Whips out toward you.
LIAM: Is it a dex save?
MATT: No, this is a 20 to hit.
LIAM: Oh, that hits.
MATT: It will actually move right up to there,
that side there. So it hits. You take 17 points of
piercing damage.
LIAM: That's rough.
MATT: Yes.
DAN: We're proper fucked!
MATT: And make a strength saving throw.
LIAM: Strength saving throw. I get advantage on
that, so that's a 15.
MATT: 15. The impact of it pushes you back and you
almost fall over, but you catch yourself and throw
the tendril off your body and angrily growl at it
in response. That ends its turn. Snuggle, you're
up. At the top of your-- okay, yeah, you're far
enough away. Okay.
ZAC: I'm still Snugglelord, mind you.
MATT: Sorry. Snugglelord. My apologies.
ZAC: My penis may have left me, but the name
sticks.
MATT: True. Snugglelady.
ZAC: So I control the merchant, and I have him run
directly at the creature, yelling like a fricking
idiot, saying, "Please kill me! Please kill me!
Please kill me!"
MATT: "Please kill me! Please kill me! Kill me!"
Running towards it. Is that all you wanted to do?
ORION: He has to make a melee attack.
ZAC: Is this Crown of Madness guy?
MATT: Yeah. It has to make an attack at the end of
it.
ZAC: Oh, he has to attack?
DAN: He gets to.
ORION: If you make him do something--
MATT: Go ahead and roll the attack for it. What'd
you roll?
ZAC: A four.
MATT: A four? This creature should be easy to hit.
It is large, and it's not moving very fast, but
the blackpowder merchant has bags of this dark
powder attached to it that it carries with it, and
runs forward and starts trying to punch at it, and
it's like hitting dough (impacts). No damage
whatsoever. But it seems to have gotten its
attention to some degree. So that's the end of
your turn. Do you want to move closer?
ZAC: No, I'm fine.
MATT: Okay. That brings us to Quaalude. Quaalina.
Q. However you wanted to be.
ORION: Call me Q. It's good. I'm going to shimmy a
little bit along the wall, right before, and then
I'm going to-- wait, no. I don't because I won't
be able to move out-- Oh wait, I can split up
movement! I can break movement! So I'll move-- am
I still ten feet away from it?
MATT: Here you are.
ORION: Okay, cool. So I want to get a little bit--
it doesn't matter because I'm going to spring out
and turn into a direwolf (howling) and bite the
shit out of it.
MATT: Go for it.
ORION: I'm going to gain advantage because I--
MATT: First things first, roll a wisdom saving
throw.
ORION: Who's a wazza-bazza?
MATT: Roll a wisdom saving throw.
ORION: No. Wait, wisdom. Four.
MATT: Okay. Oh, this is a d8. Okay. As you
transform into the direwolf right there, you
snarl. You hear all the voices in your mind, and
for a second you feel like you're really confused,
and you don't know where you are. You spend the
remainder of your turn trying to shake the voices
out of your head. You're unable to do anything
this turn.
ORION: Son of a bitch.
MATT: The chaos of this, the mouths speaking in
unison, drive you temporarily mad.
LIAM: Don't worry. Salty Petunia's going to save
us all.
MATT: Salty, you're up. At the beginning of your
turn, also make a wisdom saving throw.
DAN: Oh no, my worst skill. Oh, that's a three
with my modifier!
MATT: Okay. As you pull your sword out, you're
like, "I'm ready for this!" You hear the same
voices through your mind, and once again you start
looking about and rubbing your eyes, trying to
figure out where you are, what's happening, and
you spend the rest of your turn standing there
listening to the voices.
DAN: Well, that was embarrassing.
MARISHA: Edna, you're up.
ZAC: Petunia, what the fuck?
MARISHA: You know, this has probably been one of
the most exciting days of my life. Blindness!
MATT: Okay. All right. What's the save on it?
MARISHA: Asmodan! I mean, shit, what? You asked a
question? What are you, 30 feet?
MATT: What's the DC on that spell?
MARISHA: 13.
MATT: 13. As a flash of light bursts in the
direction of this creature covered with eyes, all
the eyes close and you hear the yelling becomes
more of a shrieking sound. And you see it starts
writhing around angrily. It is currently blinded,
so well done on that. You're way back here. Do you
want to stay where you are?
LIAM: Good job there, handsome.
MATT: Do you wish to stay where you are?
MARISHA: What? I'll back up a bit, if I can. I
don't know where exactly I am, but--
MATT: You are right here.
ORION: You're here, Grandma. You're here.
MARISHA: I need to remain-- oh, you know what, let
me shift on in a bit so I can see. I'm Edna.
MATT: All right, that's your turn, Edna. Ulfgar.
LIAM: Oh, right. Things change so fast here. It's
hard to remember.
IFY: Yes, and now I have a present for this thing.
ZAC: Did you find the present in there?
IFY: Now the name Larry and Robert and swing
down.
MATT: So you move to the side into combat with the
creature. Go ahead and roll for each attack.
IFY: So the first one is a 23.
MATT: That hits.
IFY: The second one is a natural 20.
MATT: I will ask you to make a wisdom saving throw
real fast.
IFY: All right. Wisdom. 16.
MATT: 16. Yeah, you hear the voices cascading
through your ears as you rush forward. However,
you steel your mind, focus on the attack, and push
through it unaffected.
IFY: That's my secret. I already had voices in my
head.
DAN: Oh, what a plot twist!
MATT: Go ahead and roll both attacks. The second
one gets double on the dice.
IFY: So the first one is a four.
MATT: Plus whatever the damage is of your
strength. It should be on the--
IFY: Oh yeah, that's with it. And then the second
one is nine, so 13 total.
MATT: Awesome, so a total of 13 damage. Whack,
whack! You're cutting off parts of its body. You
can see the slices of flesh that fall off on the
ground kind of quiver and squeal before going
motionless. You see the eyes close and kind of
slightly leave open as if a person had just passed
away. I'm going to keep this on it for blindness
so we have it as a reminder. All right. That ends
your turn, Ulfgar. Up to the top. Kurt, you're
up.
LIAM: When does Gary go?
MATT: Oh, Gary goes on your turn as well.
LIAM: On my turn instead of me, or in addition to
me?
MATT: I'll say in addition to you.
LIAM: In addition to me? All right. Well, first,
I'm going to attack this fucker with my war pick.
No, with this magic fucking hammer I have right
here, and I'm going to recklessly attack while in
a rage. But I get advantage with reckless attack,
right? So that's terrible. Get him, Gary! Go for
the eyes!
MATT: What'd you roll?
LIAM: Oh, a three.
MATT: With your bonuses? You have advantage
because of your reckless attack.
LIAM: Five with the--
MATT: With the advantage?
LIAM: No, seven with advantage.
MATT: Okay, that's still not enough,
unfortunately. All right, so you go to try and
swing it. As you go to swing-- I forgot to make a
wisdom save. I've got to remember to do that.
We'll say, for the purposes of storyline here, as
you go to swing, the voices come into your head,
and for a second you stop and slow your arc. By
the time your hammer actually hits it, it goes
(soft impact). There's no power behind it. Gary
also is going to rush forward. You go ahead and
make an attack for Gary.
LIAM: An attack for Gary? All right. Oh jeez, I
don't know what a badger's stats are.
MATT: I know. I'm making it up. Go ahead and
roll.
LIAM: I rolled a 13.
MATT: A 13? That'll hit. So go ahead and roll 1d4
plus two damage from the badger's claws.
LIAM: That's five of angry badger damage because
he's a barbarian as well.
MATT: So the badger reaches out and grabs the side
of it and bites into one of its tendrils. As it
does, it rears back, and there's a splash of
greenish, brackish blood that goes across its face
and on the ground.
LIAM: Oh, I've missed you, Gary!
MATT: All right, that ends your turn. It's now its
turn. It is blinded for this turn. First it's
going to go at-- you see one of its mouths
rescinds for a second and then releases this giant
globule of dark green goo that slams into the
ground and explodes right in the center here. I
need you two and you two to roll dexterity saving
throws.
MARISHA: Did you say me?
MATT: Yes. Edna, Kurt, Salty Pete, and
Snugglelord.
DAN: 22.
MARISHA: Ten.
CHAT ROOM: Lady Josephine, Leader of the Guild of
Moderators, casts a great spell. As long as they
sing like they are in a musical, they level up to
ten. Otherwise, they lose five to all stats.
LIAM: What was that again?
MATT: You will all have to sing in unison--
ZAC: I believe I heard that loud and clear, my
lord Shathrum. I believe if we, yes--
MARISHA: If we sing a musical?
DAN: If you sing like you're in a musical, we
level up to ten. Otherwise you lose five to all
stats. Question. Since I'm already level ten, is
there exemption?
MATT: No. You'll just lose five stats.
CHAT ROOM: Tilda Tilda Tilda Tilda Tilda Tilda
Tilda Swinton. Tilda Tilda Tilda Tilda Tilda Tilda
Tilda Swinton. (repeats)
MATT: Guys, sing along!
ALL: Tilda Tilda Tilda Tilda Tilda Tilda Tilda
Swinton.
LIAM: How long do we do this for?
ALL: Tilda Tilda Tilda Tilda Tilda Tilda Tilda
Swinton. Tilda Swinton! Tilda! Tilda Swinton!
Tilda! Tilda Swinton! Swinton!
MATT: And with that momentous occasion, as the
spittle hits the ground, suddenly it does not
explode. It's lifted in place and is shattered.
You feel all of a sudden the warmth of the
moderator guildmaster fill all of you, and with
this divine energy your bodies are suddenly
elevated to the strength, hardness, and experience
of a seasoned adventurer.
DAN: I feel the same.
ZAC: My boobs have gotten bigger! I'm level ten
now!
MATT: So go ahead and roll seven additional of
your hit dice to add to what you've got, except
for you.
DAN: What a fucking rip.
(laughter)
LIAM: Give me my fucking book. Jesus, Mary, and
Joseph.
MATT: All righty.
DAN: Shathrum preserve us!
ORION: Isn't it, you have to keep singing as if
you're in a musical?
MATT: Even with disadvantage, that is plus 12 for
its bite attack. This is going to be against you.
What's your AC?
LIAM: My AC is 16. I think.
MATT: 16? So even though you're kind of hearing
the voices, you see one of the tendrils whip out
toward you. You smack it to the side with your
hammer, disabling it and not taking any damage
from it. It's going to roll to see if it can get
rid of the blindness. That is a natural 20, so it
is no longer blinded.
MARISHA: Aw, pooper.
MATT: That ends the gibbering mouther's turn. That
brings it to Snugglelady.
ZAC: Now, if I heard that donation correctly,
we've now all leveled up to ten, or do we have to
keep singing--?
OFF-SCREEN: You do have to continue singing.
DAN: No, I think you read it wrong. (singing)
Perhaps you did.
ORION: You have to keep singing in a musical, and
then you gain up to level ten. When you stop, you
lose that and you go to level five.
MATT: (singing) That will destroy the game.
(normal) So we'll say, for the next round of
combat, you guys have to do-- anything you do or
want to do in this combat, sing it as if it's a
musical. When the round's over, then it'll stay
permanent and you can continue forward. So.
(singing) Snugglelord, what is your bidding?
ZAC: (singing) I'm being told that I have this
urge to run over to Kurtney and heal her of damage.
LIAM: Stop feeling my boob! What are you doing?
Well, that's actually quite nice.
MATT: (singing) And with that, you heal five hit
points from the hug of the Snugglelady.
LIAM: (singing) I feel better. I feel pretty and
alive.
ZAC: (singing) I love that my decisions are made
for me! This is bullshit.
(laughter)
MATT: (singing) Quaalude, I want you to make a
wisdom saving throw.
ORION: (howling) Okay.
LIAM: What the fuck was that?
MATT: It's his direwolf form singing. What's your
answer?
ORION: What is it? Wisdom? 14.
MATT: Sing it.
ORION: (singing) My wisdom is 14, dear DM.
MATT: (singing) Your brain resists the voices you
hear. Your mind is your own. Tell me what you
shall do, dear.
ORION: (singing) I'll tell you right now what I'm
going to do! I'm going to jump up as the direwolf,
and (snarling).
MATT: (singing) Roll your attacks!
ORION: (singing) Natural 20!
MATT: (singing) Double your damage now!
ORION: (singing) Doubling damage, we're doubling
damage, unh! That is four plus four, plus four
plus four is eight! That means a 16!
MATT: (singing) As you tear a piece of the
creature astray, your turn ends! Victory is yours,
I say! Soon! Next, the turn goes to Salty Pete!
ORION: (singing) But not before I knock it prone!
MATT: (singing) The gibbering mouther's immune to
prone! Its mass has no legs! It cannot fall over!
Salty Pete, it's your turn to be, moreover!
DAN: (singing) First I must ask, do I need to roll
a saving throw?
MATT: (singing) You're close enough where you must
make a wisdom saving throw.
DAN: (singing) Oh fuck. No!
MATT: (singing) All right. Salty Pete, you make a
melee attack, randomly determined creature within
reach. That would be the Snugglelady! Roll an
attack against the Snugglelady!
DAN: (singing) And now my fanfiction is complete!
You're not going to like this. 24!
MATT: (singing) Surprise attack of a 24 against
you counts as a sneak attack!
DAN: (singing) Holy shit.
ZAC: (singing) Oh fuck! Oh fuck! Oh fuck, oh fuck,
oh fuck!
MATT: What's your rogue class? I mean, are you an
assassin or a thief?
DAN: I'm a thief.
MATT: You're a thief? Okay, good. Good thing
you're not an assassin. (singing) If you were an assassin,
that would've been a critical hit as well. All
right, so roll damage against the Snugglelord.
DAN: (singing) Let's hope they're all ones. Mostly
ones.
ORION: (singing) Hoping for ones, and a lot of
them are all ones!
DAN: (singing) Eight plus three. 11!
MATT: You take 11 damage. (singing) 11 damage to
the Snugglelord, Snugglelord, Snugglelord.
ZAC: Bitch, what?
DAN: Was that from the guy who did Hamilton?
MATT: (singing) Edna, it's your turn.
ORION: (singing) Well the old gray mare, she ain't
what she used to be, ain't what she used to be.
MATT: (singing) Edna has more powerful spells now,
because you are level ten. Do not forget.
MARISHA: (singing) I do have more high-level
spells. And to this I say, Asmodan! And I cast
something from my higher-level spells.
MATT: (singing) A Lightning Bolt, perhaps?
MARISHA: Sure! (singing) I'll Lightning Bolt him!
MATT: (singing) The moment that Edna, not being
familiar with these high-level spells, has the
instinct to release this energy she's not used
before, the bolt streaks forth from her hands,
striking Snugglelord, Kurt, the black powder
merchant--
MARISHA: (singing) Wait, this is unfair. I was
being led and baited by the dungeon master!
MATT: (singing) Too late.
MARISHA: (singing) Shit.
MATT: (singing) And the gibbering mouther. Make a
reflex saving throw, you, and you, and blackpowder
merchant does not make it with a seven. What is
your damage? 8d6.
MARISHA: (singing) 8d6, my damage is!
ORION: (imitating a trombone)
MARISHA: (singing) 16 plus another four, so that
brings it to 20. That was six. How many? Eight?
Shut up. What did I say? 20? So that's 28. 28
damage. 28, 28 damage.
MATT: Reflex saving throw.
ZAC: (singing) 14.
MATT: (singing) You take 28 points of lightning
damage.
ZAC: (singing) Fuck.
MATT: (singing) You, Kurt, also roll it.
LIAM: (singing) I rolled an 11.
MATT: (singing) You also take 28 points of
lightning damage.
LIAM: (singing) That fucking stings.
MARISHA: (singing) Oh no, I just hit my lover with
lightning! I just hit my lover with lightning!
MATT: (singing) It's not over, you see, because
the bolt that you released also hit the
blackpowder merchant. He failed the saving throw.
He took almost enough life to take him to zero,
but it ignited the blackpowder and, boom!
(laughter)
ZAC: Oh no! Oh no!
MATT: (singing) A cacophonous explosion rocks the
cavern! I need another saving throw from all of
you! Except for Edna and your son.
MARISHA: (singing) I just want to point out, this
was a suggestion from the Dungeon Master.
DAN: (singing) What modifier do we add?
MATT: (singing) It's your dexterity saving throw,
so add your dex.
DAN: (singing) 21.
ORION: (howling)
MATT: (singing) All right, what did you roll?
ZAC: (singing) Two.
MATT: (singing) Ulfgar, what did you roll? Ulfgar,
what did you roll?
IFY: Did I roll a saving throw? What?
MATT: (singing) Yes. Roll a dexterity saving
throw.
IFY: (singing) All righty. I rolled a 13.
MATT: (singing) All right.
ORION: (singing) And I rolled a 14.
LIAM: (singing) I rolled a 13, and Gary rolled a
12.
MARISHA: (singing) I didn't have to roll.
DAN: (singing) Please remember, I have evasion!
MATT: (singing) Yes, you do. Anyone who rolled
lower than a ten just took 21 points of fire damage.
ZAC: (singing) Goodbye.
MARISHA: Oh no, is he unconscious?
MATT: (singing) Snugglelord is unconscious and
currently dying. That brings us to Ulfgar.
IFY: (singing) Oh, I've been brewing up some fun
while you guys were playing. I've been brewing up
some fun while you guys are playing. You see, now
that I'm level ten, I turn into an eldritch knight
and now I'm lighting shit on fire. Prepare to be
blasted away by my Chromatic Orb! Orb! Orb! Coming
at you, you weird thing!
MATT: (singing) All right, so you're attacking with a
Chromatic Orb attack? Is that what you're doing as
an eldritch knight?
IFY: (singing) Yes.
MATT: (singing) Roll for attack. Roll for attack.
IFY: (singing) It's 11, but I don't know what to
add to it.
MATT: (singing) That's all right, 11 still hits
this monstrosity.
IFY: (singing) Ooh yeah. Ooh yeah.
MATT: (singing) So roll your sword's damage plus
an additional 3d8.
IFY: (singing) Ooh yeah. Let me get them 3d8s. Ooh
yeah. We blowing stuff up. We blowing stuff up
like ooh, yeah! We blowing stuff up! We're blowing
stuff up like ooh, yeah! We're blowing stuff up!
We're blowing stuff up like ooh, yeah! I do 20
damage!
MATT: (singing) How do you want to do this?
(cheering)
MARISHA: One more time, all together!
ALL: (singing) How do you want to do this?
ZAC: (singing) I'm unconscious. I can't hear you.
IFY: (singing) I'll do it. I'll do it. I'll do it
with some cold damage, since you spitting fire at us.
MATT: (singing) How do you want to deal this final
blow? You've slain the creature; describe your
epic blow.
IFY: (singing) I look at my daughter in her eyes.
I said, everything came until this time because I
told you, I told you, it's all a part of the plan!
It's all a part of the plan! It's all a part of
the-- die!
MATT: (singing) You release your blasted orb of
arcane energy, the cold flowing from your
fingertips! The mouther, it skulks! It turns, and
it wails, but the cold energy holds it in place,
you see! Its flesh begins to freeze. It cracks its
claws! Suddenly it freezes in place, unable to
escape! You reach down with your blade and
shatter. It scatters across the ground. Victory is yours.
(air horn)
ZAC: That wasn't even Lucas! Who did that? I think
that means we don't have to sing anymore.
MARISHA: The musical is complete?
MATT: You guys have completed a round of combat
successfully, the musical. The battle is won.
ZAC: Where the fuck are those donations?
Seriously.
DAN: I'd just like to point out that he's at
negative 24 hit points.
ZAC: You don't have to bring that up.
MATT: But go ahead and roll a death saving throw.
A d20, roll a d20.
ZAC: Okay, that's a 17.
MATT: Okay, so you're fine. You're not bleeding
out, yet. So you guys all sit there and look about
yourselves in your sex-changed forms, except for
Edna. The Snugglelady lies on the ground, bleeding out.
MARISHA: I have never seen a party of more strong
and powerful women. I just want to say that.
ZAC: I'm dying!
MARISHA: I know, we are like the Golden Girls.
Thelma and Louise.
ORION: I change out of beast form, and I
straighten out my skirt, and I walk over to dead
Snugglebaby and do a Cure Wounds.
DAN: What are you doing to that baby?
LIAM: I make out with my girlfriend. We make out a
little.
MATT: As you heal Snugglelord up, you look about,
and you look down. The gibberling, which has
slowly turned to this frozen, shattered mass as it
begins to thaw over the next few minutes, as you
take a moment to take care of your wounds and
such, you see there is the arm and part of the
face of the assistant you were seeking there on
the ground.
LIAM: Oh, that's sad.
MARISHA: Oh right, the whole reason we came here.
ORION: Wait, is--?
MATT: The assistant you came here to seek, there
are parts of his body there on the ground.
DAN: Oh, we found him! There he is, and there he
is, and there he is!
ORION: What about blackpowder boy? What about
Victor? Is he nowhere to be seen?
MARISHA: Is Victor still alive or did he die,
right? Victor exploded?
MATT: Oh, no. There are a couple pieces of the
assistant; there are many pieces of Victor.
DAN: It's raining men! Or was he transformed as
well? I never heard him sing.
MATT: However, at this moment, you feel a shudder
of the room (impacts). You look over your
shoulder, and you see now, coming down the hallway,
these two giant, leathery red hands pulling its
way through the hallway as a demonic pit fiend
pulls its way down the tunnel behind you and goes,
"Where is Salty Pete?"
ZAC: He's not here!
DAN: I draw a card and play it.
MARISHA: Oh shit!
ORION: Oh shit! Do I see him doing this? Because I
back the fuck away.
MATT: It's too fast. Go ahead and pull a card.
DAN: Queen of Diamonds.
IFY: Is that a new one?
DAN: Yep.
IFY: Oh shit.
DAN: It's the fungus queen from down below.
MATT: You are granted the ability to cast the Wish
spell one time.
MARISHA: Oh my god, you get the Wish spell one!
You can't fuck it up!
MATT: So as you pull the card and look at it, you
feel suddenly the grace of the gods enter your
mind, and you see the face of that Reika woman who
appeared in the forest earlier. She goes, "I grant
"you the last of my power: one wish to save you in
this instant. Choose wisely." And the vision is
gone. You look down in your hand, and you see a
single pearl, pulsating with energy, infinite
possibilities there in your hand, as you see--
I'm going to pull up a picture just so you have an
idea of what you're about to face-- standing about
15 or more feet tall, this thing coming down the hall.
DAN: Oh shit, it's from Fantasia!
MATT: (impacts)
ORION: I quickly whisper, careful what you say!
ZAC: Would you like any advice? I know you're
quite dumb. You're quite dumb. Would you like any help?
DAN: I wish that the pit fiend was transformed
into an adorable, harmless puppy; that Victor was
reassembled; and that the assistant was also
reassembled into a living person; and also that
we're paid 2600 gold.
ZAC: That was a very clever thing to say! I'm
impressed!
MATT: The pearl vanishes from your hand. This cold
wind begins to blow throughout the tunnel. The pit
fiend goes, "I will destroy--" and turns into,
what were you asking again?
DAN: A harmless puppy dog.
MATT: (yapping) This little puppy dog now comes up
to you and starts gnawing on your ankle.
DAN: I snap its neck.
(laughter)
MATT: It falls limp in your hands. As you drop the
puppy, the pieces of Victor begin to shake and
slowly pull together. As it does, the arm and the
face of the assistant shake and all of them swirl
together to form one horribly mutated blackpowder
merchant/Cyril the assistant, going, "Augh! Which
"of you--? Help me!" He's quivering in place with
three arms and an additional face attached to it,
covered in soot. It looks at you, going, "What
have you done?"
ZAC: Do you think maybe we could get more money
for it now, since it's technically people?
ORION: That is terrible. That is amazing! That is
terrible.
DAN: I used the wrong conjunction.
ORION: Yes, you did. Oh my god.
MATT: As you make your way back to town, carrying
this moaning, horribly tortured entity right now
that's-- making speech itself is a pain-- you make
your way back to town, this legion of female
heroes, all level ten. You've returned--
ZAC: Big knockers.
MATT: Yes. Big knockers. You've returned to the
alchemist, who turns around and goes, "Oh, you've
"returned! Great! I'm glad you could make it!
Where's--? Whoa, what happened to all of you?"
DAN: We found him.
IFY: Hey, there.
DAN: We look different.
MARISHA: Unfortunately, I was hoping it'd make me
younger again, but I'm still an old woman.
MATT: "There's nothing wrong with age. Have you
brought my assistant back?"
DAN: You could say that.
MATT: As he hobbles in, he goes, "Oh, three arms!
That'll be even more useful! Thank you so much!
"For the extra arm, I'll give you a 100-gold
bonus!" He hands you the sack of gold coins.
ZAC: I quickly grab it, and I Misty Step out of
the apartment and run like hell.
IFY: I try and snatch it before he can do that.
MATT: Both of you guys make dexterity checks right
now. This is contested dexterity checks.
ZAC: Damn it.
DAN: Oh, this is going to end in tears.
IFY: 16.
ZAC: 17.
MATT: With that, as Ulfgar reaches out, "No!" the
Snugglelady vanishes. You hear laughing in the
distance, running into the night. So now we're
going to go through and have each of you guys give
me the epilogue of what your character's doing
post the story, just so we can wrap up here. So Ulfgar.
IFY: So Ulfgar is now wanted after casting a
Chromatic Orb on one said Snugglelady. No one
knows what happened, and only a roll can let you
know what truly happens.
MATT: Snugglelady?
ZAC: Oh yeah, what about your daughter?
IFY: Oh, she protects me for the rest of my life.
ZAC: I'm sitting on a beach somewhere on a far-off
island with my little imp, Lucas, chilling by the
water, drinking Coronas. They have Coronas.
MATT: Yes. Ye Olde Corona. It's an Elven wine.
ZAC: My wife left me when I became a woman.
Strangely, Ryco was only interested in men, so my
wife left me. So it's just me and Lucas now,
basking in our riches, enjoying a long life on the
beaches together, toasting our Coronas.
MATT: All right. Salty Pete?
DAN: Well, I floated around for a while from town
to town, playing the craps tables until I could
win enough money to fill a Scrooge McDuck-ian
vault in which I could swim around--
CHAT ROOM: Snugglelord slips, falls, and wakes up,
and realizes this whole thing was a fever dream
brought on by cheap ale that had gone off and
poisoned him.
MATT: So after this adventure, you imagine
yourself on the desert island. However, you
suddenly wake up with a headache and realize,
shortly after you were hit with the Chromatic Orb
by Ulfgar, you went unconscious. Your money's
gone, and you're left with a heavy bruise and a
bit of a sore back end.
ZAC: Lord Shathruum, why? Why, Shathruum?
Why?
IFY: (cackling) Oh, my gold! (cackling)
ZAC: Am I still married to a woman that doesn't
love me because I'm a woman?
MATT: Yes. That happened beforehand.
DAN: Eventually I re-purchased my ship, the
Obsidian Helen, and now I sail the seven seas as
the cruelest sea-hag that the world has ever seen,
with my seven fingers.
MATT: One finger for each sea.
DAN: Perfect.
MATT: All right. Quaaludia.
ORION: I go to the nearest temple and get a spell
of restoration to return me to at least half self.
It's permanent?
MATT: Unfortunately, it is a permanent
incantation.
ORION: I don't do that. I go and get--
MARISHA: Why are you suddenly Southern?
ORION: Fuck this. I'm going to finish this with
some sass. I move to a different area and I just
learned how to speak different, like the locals
do. I got me a nice little dress and a nice little
college with my earnings, and I just get one with
nature is all.
MATT: All right. Kurtney?
LIAM: Well, if she'll have me-- No, Kurt works
fine. If she'll have me, I ask Edna to marry me,
and I'd like to raise badgers until she passes,
and I carry on her memory.
MATT: Edna?
MARISHA: I happily accept Kurt's hand in marriage,
but beforehand I feel like I just need to get some
adventuring out of my system first, and I hear
there's this man. He's, like, a tiefling, and they
call him something like the Bounty Hunter, or the
Broker, or something like that, and, I don't know.
Maybe he's looking for more mercenaries. I think
I'll join up with him.
LIAM: I'll see you when you get home.
MARISHA: Okay.
IFY: And I donate some of the recovered money to
Kurtney's badger fund and make sure Kurt is well
taken care of so she can--
ZAC: So they weren't upset when you stole their
money?
DAN: 2,600 gold pieces goes an awfully long way.
MATT: And so concludes our adventure for the
evening. Thank you all so very much for joining in
and helping us guide this to a momentous
conclusion.
ZAC: This was bullshit. Mods, you're on my shit
list because I know most of those $500 donations
were from you, because those were in-jokes.
IFY: Thanks, everybody.
MATT: Seriously. Thank you all so much for all
your support on this entire Extra Life charity
drive. You guys have shown tremendous, tremendous
strength of heart for giving what you have over
these past couple days. Really, really proud and
honored to be part of this community. And from me,
thank you for everything you guys have done,
tremendously. We raised, what was the total?
ZAC: So we're at 68,000. We wanted to hit 75 as
the new goal.
DAN: We can still do it. Right now. I know one of
you is a rebel billionaire, Richard Branson.
ZAC: So how about, if we hit 70 in the next couple
of minutes, we'll do a big giveaway--
CHAT ROOM: Stephen becomes possessed by the Spirit
of the Overlord. She hunts down every member of
the former party and claims their power to becomes
immortal master of the universe, bringing about an
age of her.
ZAC: Which character was that?
OFF-SCREEN: Stephanie.
ZAC: Stephanie?
MARISHA: She goes on an Avatar journey!
ZAC: Stephanie. So if we get to 70 in the next
couple of minutes, guys, we'll do a big giveaway.
We forgot to give these away earlier, so we'll do
a big giveaway with everyone you see here's
signature on a poster, and some D&amp;D book and some
dice and all that stuff, and these wonderful--
handmade by our wonderful chat room member--
ORION: Little interesting fact, by the way,
because we only did 70-- guys, last year, LA, Los
Angeles, only raised about $113,000 alone, so
we're-- us right now, tonight, are accounting for
a lot of that, and I think we can hit the 70 as
well. If we did 113 last year--
ZAC: I think we can hit it. Everybody watching,
donate $1 or $2. Everyone watching, donate $2.
That would be amazing.
MATT: And these incredible implements here that
are being donated to this thing are made by Gil
Ramirez, a fantastic member of the community and a
really, really talented smith of many regards. So
these are hardcore, serious implements, guys.
Fantastic. But yeah. So as everyone goes on their
way, Stephanie, the now older, more trained,
hardened, and bent on vengeance daughter of
Ulfgar, goes around beating the ever-loving shit
out of all previous members of the party, except
for Edna who, for some reason, she can't seem to
find. Apparently disappeared at some point in the field.
ZAC: That's my girl. Stephanie, all along, you
know I was pushing you because I wanted you to be
something, and this idiot couldn't do it.
Tough love.
IFY: Stephanie will eventually murder the
Snugglelady. Stephanie, my daughter, will
eventually finish this guy.
ZAC: Look, it's still Snugglelord. Just because I
have breasts and no penis, you can still address
me as Snugglelord, okay?
MARISHA: It's Lorde with an E.
ORION: This is not canon. None of this is canon.
MATT: I want to take a moment here and say, real
fast, too, for all of you people who are watching
who are dungeon masters, let this evening be a
warning to you to never include the Deck of Many
Things into your campaign because all of that
hard-earned time you spent building your story,
your world, your NPCs, an epic arc, will go down
in flames in a very short period of time.
ZAC: Guys, round of applause to Matt for dealing
with that shit tonight. Woo!
MATT: That was unique. That was unique.
ZAC: I'm not going to lie. When I told Matt about
this idea, we thought the idea would be thematic
to the past Vox Moronica story, where I could hear
the chat room, and it would help guide us along
our way, but that very first $500 donation that
came in said, "Little street urchin runs by,
"steals it, and runs away." I was like, oh shit,
that's how this is going to play out. And Matt ran
with it, and kudos because I thought the cows was
nuts, and this was absolutely bonkers.
MATT: Yeah. You guys are real creative.
(laughter)
ZAC: Wow. All right, I'm going to check those
donations one more time.
OFF-SCREEN: We're 500 away.
ZAC: We're 500 away! Oh, Jesus.
DAN: Come on, don't you want to make the party do
something else crazy?
ZAC: Somebody needs to donate 500 now. Yeah,
retcon. Somebody give us a $500 donation right now
and set the story straight--
OFF-SCREEN: Wait, we're only 200 away now.
DAN: But still donate 500.
ZAC: We need a 500 to tell us-- somebody fix this
story, please, because this is fucked.
DAN: Right now, we ended on a Scorpius Malfoy. We
need better. Harry deserves better.
OFF-SCREEN: It's at 70k.
MATT: 70k! We got it!
(cheering)
ZAC: All right, guys! Everybody active in the
chat, no spam please! You only have to be active
once, and Lucas is going to draw for our big,
end-of-the-night winner, and we'll make sure it's
an awesome, awesome prize pack. It's going to
include a lot of stuff we didn't even bring up, I
promise you that. All right, Lucas. Should we
drumroll it?
DAN: Yeah.
OFF-SCREEN: Give us, like, five seconds--
ZAC: Oh, I'm aware it takes you a little bit. I
know. We're just going to roll it.
(humming Also Sprach Zarathustra)
DAN: Tilda Swinton!
(yelling)
ZAC: Stop!
OFF-SCREEN: CruelGroundhog!
ALL: CruelGroundhog!
(cheering)
DAN: CruelGroudhog, congratulations! You have won
an amazing prize pack including the following items!
ZAC: The ones that I listed earlier, plus more!
DAN: I assume they're scrolling up the screen.
ZAC: Nope, they are not. Guys, thank you for
tuning in to our Extra Life charity campaign!
Claudia, you have something you want to say?
MATT: Sneak in, sneak in. We've got Claudia here
to say something.
CLAUDIA: So I'm just sneaking in to let you guys
know that 70k is amazing, and we actually are
still going with this. This was our big push for
everything, but don't forget that on the 24th our
friends at Nerdist are also going to be running a
stream, and that's going to continue to add to all
of this number. So Geek &amp; Sundry's going to keep
pulling for that 75, hopefully by the end of this
week, but join us on the 24th on
twitch.tv/nerdist. Dan, if you want to say
anything else about that?
DAN: Yeah, absolutely. Guys, this is truly
incredible. The fact that you're able to do this
in 12 hours plus last night, it's insane. And the
fact that you guys are able to do this kind of
thing is amazing. And we're so excited because on
October 24th, Nerdist, we're going to be doing a
24-hour stream, full 24 hours. We're going to have
all of our friends from Geek &amp; Sundry, some of
your other favorite people from around the
internet, coming by, playing games for a great
cause. Again, this is all for the Children's
Miracle Network Hospitals. They do great work for
kids with cystic fibrosis, cancer, some really
scary stuff, and they do it for the kids who are
facing these conditions. They don't care whether
or not they have the money to pay for it. That's
what they're there for. They give them treatment
even if they can't pay for it, and that is
something to be applauded, something to be
supported, so thank you so much. And please, I
hope you join us October 24th, twitch.tv/nerdist.
We'll see you there, and hopefully all of you guys
will be there as well.
ORION: Of course.
ZAC: I'll be there, bro.
CLAUDIA: And our goal altogether is 100k right
now, but the more you guys donate, the higher we
go because you keep pushing us.
MATT: Guys, thank you all so much, sincerely.
Well, thank you guys for playing tonight. Thank
you guys for being so awesome.
ZAC: I have one more thing to say.
MATT: Go for it.
ZAC: I really wanted to die that game.
DAN: What are you, Harrison Ford in fucking
Empire?
ZAC: I really wanted to die, but thank you all.
It's time to go home.
MATT: To be fair, this whole experience would've
had a very high possibility, at a number of
points, of killing a number of you, had you not
all gone to level ten suddenly and gained all of
these powers. But such is the thing. We never even
got around to the-- one of the chat people gave
you the power to form Captain Planet.
ZAC: It was a "OP, game-breaking Captain Planet."
That's what was in the message. Smart move to not
include that.
MATT: They made some other cool things in there,
but there's only a certain point where you start
adding more to the wish before you get a
third-arm-merged assistant. But no, guys, thank
you all so much. Great suggestions. We hope you
had a good night, and all of us at Critical Role
will see you Thursday.
ZAC: And we'll see you Monday!
MATT: Boom. Good night.
MARISHA: Good night, everybody!