[upbeat music]
BRIAN: Good evening.
(laughter)
BRIAN: Good evening. Welcome to god-knows-what.
This is our very special fireside chat edition of
Talks Machina. Travis cannot stop looking at me,
as per usual. I would like to welcome the cast of
Critical Role minus one Ashley the Jenkins. As you
can see, Matt also got the memo about dressing
incredibly fucking sexy tonight.
MATT: Just saying.
BRIAN: We are here to discuss a bunch of overflow
questions from the wrap-up episode. If you guys
didn't get a chance to see, it’s free anywhere
that shows on this network are free. So go find
those places. We had a lot of stuff left over so
we wanted to lightning round it and do about 90
minutes worth of stuff, and then we'll do about 90
minutes of worth stuff off-camera that we can't
talk about. How was everyone's break?
LAURA and TALIESIN: Great.
LAURA: Happy new year!
BRIAN: Happy new year! I haven't seen you guys in
forever. I was up north dealing with a legal
situation about something that happened at Knotts
Berry Farm, but I got to Skype and see you guys
and Travis was one of my only phone calls.
TRAVIS: Yep, I'll never forget that.
BRIAN: Some of you went abroad.
LAURA: A lot of us went abroad.
TRAVIS: Raise your hand, you travelling dicks.
SAM: Does Hawaii count?
TRAVIS: That's off the mainland.
BRIAN: It is off the mainland, off the beaten
land. I stayed at home and watched a lot of Murder
She Wrote, in this very gown. Is this the one you
wore for the last?
MATT: Yeah, I haven't washed it since.
BRIAN: You haven't?! Do you have any idea how much
money this would have been worth before I put it on?
LAURA: It's a good thing it's not colder in here.
BRIAN: I have tape preventing, no matter how low
the temperature drops.
LAURA: I don't think the tape is doing its job I
can still see them.
TRAVIS: He's also getting some good pec quiver.
BRIAN: That's the tape literally squeezing milk
out of my breast because it was put on so tight.
On someone's phone there is an image of Ryan Green
putting nipple tape on me 20 minutes ago. Guys,
speaking of nipple tape, I can't believe this ties
into my first announcement but speaking of nipple
tape, Painter’s Guild with Will Friedle season two
begins on January 8th on ProjectAlpha.com.
MATT: I'm so glad that he's learning to paint
because seeing that first mini he did for your
guys’ home campaign, it damaged me on a spiritual
level. He's gotten so much better!
BRIAN: It damaged so many people the cat-petting
executives here gave him a show. They were like,
"You're so bad at this, we will pay someone to
teach you in front of a camera."
LIAM: He could eventually evolve into Michelangelo
of painting minis, but we will never let him
forget that one.
BRIAN: I have the picture of it on my phone
because I sent a picture to Gil and I said can you
paint this and he goes "Who the fuck?" I was like
Will did this himself!
MARISHA: I would have been like "Nah. We can't.
That can't--"
BRIAN: Yeah he was like, "I might need to just
bleach it and start all over." I said we should do
the same with Will.
MARISHA: We got that picture and we used it in the
first season to shame him in the very first
episode. The new season is going to be great!
BRIAN: It is, Painter’s Guild season two, January
8th. Critical Role: Vox Machina Origins number
four from Dark Horse Comics will be released
digitally on January 24th.
LIAM: That's too far away!
BRIAN: No it's a hop, skip and a jump. Grab your
copy at digital.darkhorse.com; Comixology, with an x;
iBooks, with an i; Amazon Kindle; Nook; or
Google Play. The fuck is a Nook?
SAM: A Nook, I think, is a Barnes & Noble
proprietary Kindle.
MARISHA: They were a thing before Kindle overran
them.
BRIAN: There are a couple of Barnes & Nobles
around still, but yeah.
SAM: Get yours at Ballard’s Books!
BRIAN: People buy their books from Ballard’s
Books. Waldenbooks? Hey guys the Vox Machina D20
set is still out of stock. We appreciate your
patience as we wait for the restock and will
notify everyone via social media as soon as the
inventory is in place.
LAURA: That’s true, but I can say that it’s going
to be very soon.
SAM: That is some bullshit!
LAURA: No, it really is gonna be super duper soon.
I just talked to Fernando today about it and it’s
coming up. You’ll be happy.
BRIAN: A crucial addition to that last update. The
last batch of the critical role podcast episodes
101 through 115 will be going up on Monday,
January 8th. Now that’s only a few days away.
SAM: I’m confused about that. I haven’t recorded
any ads for that, I should probably do that.
BRIAN: That’s because we replaced you with a
gentleman goes by the name of Darin De Paul.
SAM: Ooh! Okay.
BRIAN: He’s more expensive but, says here, easier
to work with.
SAM: I believe that.
BRIAN: Monday, January 8th.
SAM: It says it on your card?
BRIAN: I would not give people half-true
information. Those last batches, there’s no
batches, the last batch of episodes will be out
January 8th. Now does anyone who works here know,
and I look at you: The new campaign, are podcasts
going to be released like in groups also when the
new campaign come out for the new episodes?
LAURA: How’s that happening? Do we know yet?
BRIAN: That’s a great question that’s why I--
MARISHA: To be determined says a member of--
TRAVIS: Not in groups, but we're aiming to get
them out much more efficiently.
MARISHA: I think we wanted to do it, yeah, more
efficiently.
BRIAN: I say wait till you’re 101 episodes in
again and then do it.
MATT: They will be happening much more
consistently.
BRIAN: What else do I have to go over? Yes this is
live. You know Marisha’s guesting on As In N.E. Wisdom.
MARISHA: Good, close.
BRIAN: This Tuesday. What is it?
MARISHA: Asinine.
BRIAN: Asinine Wisdom. This Tuesday the 9th at
9:00 on Twitch.
MARISHA: One of our new shows where we debate
about really dumb shit.
SAM: Marisha.
MARISHA: Yeah?
SAM: I was asked to be on that show. Would you be
pissed at me if I did that show before your
Signal Boost show?
MARISHA: Considering Signal Boost has been on
hiatus for six months. It doesn’t matter.
SAM: I don’t watch the channel.
BRIAN: Yeah, we know.
SAM: Not a big fan of geek stuff really.
MARISHA: No, please do it, go for it.
BRIAN: Sam. Did you know that the--
SAM: Hey! What’s up with Marisha’s show?
BRIAN: We just plugged it for the amount of time
it deserved.
MARISHA: We wanted to just take a break, sometimes
we move on. This is actually a good question. This
is a good question because a lot of people will be
like "Why did you cancel this show?" "Why did you
cancel that show?" The answer is there are 1000
reasons why you could and maybe cancel a show and
each show is going to be like unique in its own
way.
SAM: Is it because I didn’t go on the show?
MARISHA: It might be because you didn’t come on
the show. No, honestly, we wanted to mix it up a
little bit.
BRIAN: Considering how well certain clips or viral
music videos of you how well they do on YouTube,
you would think a Signal Boost would have been
right up your Tiger Woods alley. Guys, did you
know the Critical Role podcast, speaking of, was
one of Podbean’s top ten podcasts of 2017? Can you
believe it? Sam, did you get an invite to the
Podbean awards because mine must have been lost in
the mail.
SAM: There was a mysterious bowl of pinto beans
left on my doorstep.
BRIAN: That’s from them! That’s the invite. It’s
inside the beans.
SAM: It’s like a secret society.
BRIAN: Yes, it’s inside one of the beans.
LIAM: I’m offended on behalf of All Work No Play.
I know we only do one episode a year.
SAM: Side note, we’ve had an episode recorded
since September that I haven’t edited yet.
BRIAN: Oh boy.
MATT: Quality over quantity.
BRIAN: Our questions for tonight are what was left
over from the thousands that were sent in for our
wrap-up episode. Dani and Courtney are here, as
they are every week, but this time they are
looking the the chat so if you guys have some
questions, they better blow us the fuck away
because in my hand is a stack. If you are going to
submit one, maybe, "Where did the name Critical
Role come from?" or "Matt, is DMing fun?" Some of
those questions maybe we could just leave for
another time. The last announcement for tonight is
the new campaign starts next week. Okay.
SAM: That's the most important announcement!
BRIAN: Okay, the new campaign starts next week
January 11th, at 7:00. I want to begin by asking
how it’s going in the creation of the characters.
What's the biggest hurdle or challenge you're
facing right now coming up with a new person?
MARISHA: Culture shock.
BRIAN: Tell me about it.
MARISHA: We're all doing pretty different things.
It’s like I don't know how to D&D anymore
and it's scary.
LAURA: Are we allowed to say what we did?
MATT: Yeah, every person is doing a session zero
at home in private, just like a very brief warm up
to feel out the character and if there's anything
they want to change before we really
started the campaign.
BRIAN: Those were not filmed or recorded for all
the people who have been asking us. None of that
is going to be released at any time.
MATT: Our little nuggets just for us to have for
ourselves.
LAURA: Has everybody played?
TRAVIS: No, Liam and Sam are tomorrow.
LAURA: Oh my gosh, so we're the only ones who have
done it. Oh gosh.
MARISHA: It was so fun! Oh my god!
LAURA: My hardest one is that I kept wanting to
say "darling" as I was talking. I caught myself do
it out loud one time and I was like, "Ooh, I
really need to not do that."
BRIAN: Because your disposition is just so
naturally pleasant in real life, it just flows.
It's how shitty things just flow out of me all the
time.
Who is happy with the way they rolled besides Liam?
LAURA: I'm happy with my roll.
LIAM: Marisha has got to be happy.
BRIAN: Yeah? Are you happy, did you do okay?
MARISHA: I did all right.
TRAVIS: I shit the bed.
BRIAN: You shit the bed? And then how did you roll?
TRAVIS: Not great. I got three single digit
categories again.
MATT: I think Ashley's got you beat.
LIAM: But it was all under his watchful eye.
MATT: She didn't roll poorly, but you know, she
has some--
LAURA: She rolled some pretty fucking low numbers, Matt.
MATT: And I'm so happy she did. Those are my
favorite! Low stats are awesome!
BRIAN: It's going to play well into the character.
MATT: It really is. I'm excited.
SAM: Matt, does anyone have a stat lower than my
lowest stat?
MATT: Which ones your lowest again?
SAM: Well, I can't say.
MATT: You can't say. I think so, I think Ashley's
is lower.
LAURA: Oh, I want to know. Hold up fingers
underneath the couch so I can see what it is.
BRIAN: This is the lamest-- Talk about silhouette
watch. Why are you showing me? Don't show me; I'm
not looking good. Guys, was there anything from
the wrap up episode-- I know we were here for five
plus hours shooting that-- but was there anything
that you wanted to ask each other or ask Matt, or
Matt that you wanted to ask, before we jump into
the questions?
Was there anything left unresolved?
LIAM: Well, months ago you hinted a little bit at
something, but didn't want to go into full detail,
behind the scenes, because we were still knee deep
in it all. It wasn't just me, a couple of us
asked, what would have happened if Vax hadn't
stuck his dick in the mashed potatoes and stopped
Raishan from doing what she was going to do, and
you mentioned that she'd--
and what would happen next?
MATT: Oh right, if he hadn't done that then she
would have gotten the information she needed from
Thordak’s corpse. The main thing was she was
trying to get to the corpse of Thordak to use the
torturous Speak with Dead spell to extract
information from him on where Opash's lair was,
would have found out information she needed to do
the dracolich transition and then she would have
just fucked off. She's a long term person, once
she had dealt with the immediate issue of the
disease and her slowly degenerating then she would
have taken
all the time she wanted as a dracolich.
LAURA: She could be a villain in this next
campaign.
MATT: That was essentially what was going to
happen, yeah. If you guys didn't stop her, then
she would have gone off on her own, done
everything she could to be untraceable and
probably would have come up as a villain later in
this next campaign. But that didn't happen.
LIAM: So if we hadn't run blindly in she would
have poofed--
LAURA: If you hadn't run blindly in--
MATT: Her whole deal was to let her have a moment
with the corpse.
TRAVIS: Quit sticking your dick in the mashed
potatoes man, god, fuck.
LIAM: That's what campaign two is for, that's a
Beastie Boys reference.
MATT: He gets that feature at level 14.
TRAVIS: Tater fucker.
(laughter)
LIAM: The new team presumably, what you had said
to me once was, would have run into her having
lorded over where we're going to be. You talked
about her being the next-- Shitting all over
everything where we're going to be.
MATT: There would have been a 20 year jump, she
would have had time to establish herself in an
area on the new continent and would have been one
of the major players in that area.
LIAM: Part of her argument during negotiations
was, "I'll get what I want and then you won’t have
to deal with me at all, I'll be gone." She would
have just pooped on Wildemount.
MATT: She would have been like, "You guys have
Tal'Dorei. That's fine; I have ideas elsewhere."
BRIAN: Taliesin, how’s your campaign for mayor of
Tucson going?
(laughter)
TALIESIN: I've got a firm shot at it.
MARISHA: Poor Taliesin. It’s been nothing but jokes!
TALIESIN: No, I've been loving it.
MARISHA: I said it looked like he was ending a
second year of finishing school.
BRIAN: Absolutely. Just for that, unless you guys
had more stuff you wanted to ask each other or
Matt, if you think of anything speak up.
ALL: (singing) So long, farewell,
auf wiedersehen, goodbye!
BRIAN: Taliesin, just for being a good sport--
TALIESIN: This was my purchase in Berlin. I'm
quite pleased with it.
BRIAN: It looks great. Well, just for being a good
sport,
I'm going to give the first question to Travis.
TALIESIN: Thank god.
BRIAN: Travis, this comes from Seth Taylor. "What
was one of the most memorable moments for you that
your negative intelligence made a situation go not
the way you wanted?"
TRAVIS: What was one of the most memorable moments?
BRIAN: Yeah.
TRAVIS: I mean I loved giving three vials of blood
to the Vasselheim trader instead of the two that
he was asking for. That was one of the first
moments where I was like, "Oh wait, there's so
much I can do being this stupid."
MATT: Oh yeah, man, bartering Grog, that's legendary.
TRAVIS: It's so fun and that was the first time
where I think Laura also was like, "I'm going to
fucking kill you."
BRIAN: The first time, yeah. Liam, question from
LazyGothy, little bit lazy little bit gothy.
Aren't we all? Where/when did you first get Simon?
What was the background?
LIAM: Oh shit, I don't remember, Matt.
Pathfinder. Home.
SAM: Did you buy him? Did you find him?
LAURA: No, you got him off of somebody.
TRAVIS: Did you make him in the forges of Nithfluflop?
LIAM: That's it, that's totally it.
LAURA: Nithfluflop?
LIAM: Nithflufloff.
MATT: No, he was a random treasure find. I don't
think I remember specifically when it was,
but it was early.
SAM: Is that a common item? Like is that a thing
that exists in D&D?
MATT: It existed in Pathfinder, yeah. It wasn't a
powerful item it just became a snake, then it went
and bit something and then it became a belt again.
But I think that good magical items are ones that
are not just useful in the game, but eventually
become a small portion of your character’s
identity. I think that's a good example of that.
It wasn't entirely useful all the time, but every
now and then it was but it just became part of Vax.
LIAM: He might have actually accomplished
something for me, once. Maybe twice.
MARISHA: Didn't you use him to scare some poor
merchant or something once?
LIAM: I cheered up a kid, showed him my snake.
MATT: At the end of the campaign, on your way to
the forge.
LIAM: He was my pet and he was less problematic
than Vex's pet, and it was easy. Like a belt that
turns into a snake.
BRIAN: Yeah, all right, I see you going all night.
Because we're five. Marisha, at some point in what
I'm about to read you there will be a question.
This is from TiamatZX: Marisha, over the course of
the Conclave Arc we've seen Keyleth slowly
overcome her hesitancy about falling in love with
Vax, with moments like the talk with Vex in the
hot springs and Pike trying to convince her to be
more comfortable with him. This is the part where
there's a question. What would you say was the
only thing that made her take that chance?
MARISHA: I mean it was answered actually in the
question.
BRIAN: Fantastic, we can--
MARISHA: Yeah. It was a combination of you giving
your seal of approval and Pike being like, "Hey
girl, someday we're going to die and you're going
to regret not loving somebody!" I was like "Aw
shit, she's right." That was basically it.
MATT: I don't remember it like that, but I want
to remember it like that.
BRIAN: That's how those characters sounded.
MARISHA: Actually I think what she said was, "You
should just have fun."
I guess it is what she said.
MATT: I'm pretty sure it is one of Sarenrae main
stipulations in the religion. "Just have fun."
BRIAN: You be you.
LIAM: Also, when Vex finally stop making the hork
sound, both of our shoulders dropped.
LAURA: It's true.
BRIAN: The hork heard around the world, a memoir.
Sam, question from @YourRedDog.
SAM: Oh, Clifford.
BRIAN: Yes, Clifford. Sam, Scanlan's one man
attack on the mansion as a triceratops is one of
my, @YourRedDog’s, favorite moments of the
campaign. How much of that went according to plan
and how much was improvised?
SAM: Plan? I think the plan was I was supposed to
create a diversion by setting a fire. Until I
realized I had no means of creating fire, and
found myself inside the place as a dinosaur
surrounded by archers. There was no plan at all.
TRAVIS: And then the Stinking Cloud and then the
goliath came out.
LAURA: I think that was the moment when I was
like, "I'm in love with Scanlan." Not Vex, Laura.
LIAM: Yeah, your face was manic,
for that entire thing.
SAM: That was an hour of just me and Matt, or felt
like an hour anyway.
MATT: That was about an hour.
SAM: It was amazing.
BRIAN: Every hour with Matt is.
SAM: Yeah, none of that was planned and it was
just so fortuitous and it was one of my favorite
moments of the whole campaign.
BRIAN: Well, it was @YourRedDog’s favorite moment.
SAM: The writers, you know, they had a different
scenario where-- it was contrived.
LIAM: There was a great art in the Christmas
Gallery. I don't know the artist's name yet
because it was their first art ever. It was one of
two clockwork pieces done, and it shows just
different vignettes, and they did, in a circle,
the Scanbo moment. And it had Scanlan with the
bandana on his head, but holding Bigby's Hand like
a gigantic AK.
BRIAN: That's amazing.
SAM: And that was fun. And that was early on too.
MATT: Yeah, that was during the
Whitestone/Briarwoods arc.
TRAVIS: "I'm going to kill everyone on this
motherfucking house!"
BRIAN: Yeah, that's right. That was back when it
was fun. Taliesin, question for you from
@bae_warden. "How aware or conscious was Percy of
everything that Vex was doing and saying in an
effort to help him out of his Orthax and
Briarwoods induced darkness/stupor?"
TALIESIN: Pretty aware, I would say. He was
definitely not the worst he’d been. I was not
prepared to where that was going to go. There was
no understanding of how the guns or the curse
worked, at all, until it just started happening.
MATT: Like a lot of curses do.
TALIESIN: There was no conversation about that at
all. That was just me as player sitting going,
"What the fuck is happening right now? What is
this? Oh no. I may have made very poor choices. I
didn't actually even know where my character was
at that point. You just went with it, man. It was
kind of crazy.
MATT: It was like the DM's gift. Like, here's a
really tragic backstory, filled with violence...
Loosely. Have fun with it. And I was like, "Oh, I will."
(laughter)
BRIAN: Well, the best part of doing the show with
our brand new fireplace. I don't know if we can
get a wide shot here. But when I'm done with the
card, I can just literally throw it into the fire.
(laughter)
BRIAN: Laura, question for you from
@magestictrinket, how fitting. "Vex promised the
Raven Queen that she would destroy Orcus, in
exchange for Vax returning after being killed by
the kraken, as we know. Does she have any plans or
concerns about upholding that contract?"
MARISHA: That's a good question.
LAURA: I totally thought that she was going to
make us do that. I guess I'm pretty happy that she
didn't' because, I don't-- I'm pretty sure that we
would've died before we got to Vecna, if we did go
and fight Orcus.
MATT: Well, it was more like, "I will give you my
soul, in exchange for my sister," is something
that a god could be like "Okay, I'll accept that."
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: "I myself personally will murder the Demon
Prince of Undeath in the bottom layer of the
Abyss," she's like, "Heh, sure."
LAURA: Aw. I volunteered all of us together.
MATT: Right. From her perspective, that was
something that, if Orcus became a prominent issue
immediately, then maybe she'd call it in. But for
the time being, I think she also felt that she'd
claimed enough attention and happiness from the
family here. Taking Vax.
LAURA: I also, as me and as Vex, had no fucking
concept of what Orcus really was, when I offered
that. Like, at all. It wasn't until afterwards I
was like, "Hey Matt, can I learn some stuff about
Orcus? Because Vex is doing a lot of research
after she did that," and he was like, "Okay." He
sent it over and I was like, "Oh no, this is
impossible!"
(laughter)
MATT: Some of the lore stuff that you had
discovered as Vex and you were like "Oh."
LAURA: "We're doomed."
BRIAN: That was after you said that?
LAURA: Yeah.
BRIAN: That shows your level of commitment to your
family, that you would choose to take on something
like that. I know you're not somebody who's
comfortable with compliments, but I thought I
might throw that one your way. Look this one's
just blank, what the fuck am I supposed to do with
this, write my own?
TRAVIS: Throw it into the fire.
BRIAN: Toss it into the fire! Up next, hey guys,
Madam Socks reminded us, did we not talk about
this on the wrap up? A, it was a while ago, B, we
were all quite drunk. "What happened to Keyleth's
mother?" We didn't go over that?
LAURA: Oh! That's right, we didn't! We didn't ever
talk about that!
BRIAN: I know we meant to get to it.
MARISHA: I thought we did a Talks forever and ever
ago.
BRIAN: I think it might have been discussed on Talks.
LAURA: I don't remember ever hearing about what
happened to Keyleth's mother.
MARISHA: She's dead. But I guess we don't know how
she died.
MATT: Well, there's elements of the story and
campaign that I like to leave somewhat vague for
people who are building their own
narratives and stuff.
BRIAN: Oh I see. It's all about money for you.
MATT: Yeah. if you pay me enough, I'll happily
tell you. No, that's one of the elements I want to
keep vague for the purposes of other writers out
there.
LAURA: I like to imagine she's alive, and living
under the water, with one leg. Because her leg was
discovered, and that's the only thing that was
recovered, right? So I think she's a pirate
with a peg leg now.
MARISHA: Like a mermaid pirate.
LAURA: How fucking cool would that be?
MARISHA: She's a mermaid pirate. That’s actually
kind of awesome.
LAURA: That’s what I think happened.
MARISHA: Oh yeah, that's right, all they did is
discover the leg.
MATT: Yeah, that was the one remnant of the battle
that they found.
LIAM: Cliff diving accident.
LAURA: Yeah.
MARISHA: That would be kind of rad.
LAURA and MARISHA: That would be tight.
BRIAN: Question for you, but before that, how are
you feeling about the new campaign?
MATT: I am super excited, and I am really
stressed, but I'm super excited. I mean, I've
disappeared for-- half of our holiday break was me
just working on the campaign, I'm sorry.
BRIAN: I disappeared for half the holiday break
too and I'm sorry, Ashley, but it was out of my
control, they came in the middle of the night.
Anyway.
TRAVIS: Pay those parking tickets.
MATT: I'm excited, I'm finishing up the details of
the whole continent map right now.
BRIAN: We are saving character reveal, we are
saving race reveal,
we are saving all of that for the campaign.
MATT: We're holding it for that. I want to
experience the first game where all the characters
come together as a group, the same with these guys.
SAM: You have long arcs planned? Do you have the
first session planned, do you have the first three
sessions planned?
MATT: Depending on what you guys do and where you
go because that's always expansive. I have the
first six or so episodes of story pretty well
beat-ed out, from there I have loose arcs to
bridge all those, and then I have long-term arcs.
I have level ten,
level 15 arcs already kind of worked out.
LAURA: What if we just completely fuck up and--
TALIESIN: We could basically do sim farm if you
want. We could all decide to become sharecroppers,
and that could just be the show. Are we going to
do eggplants for this next season,
or are we going to do carrots?
MATT: That would be the fastest sunset of a
campaign ever.
MARISHA: We just open a B&B, it's great.
MATT: We get to session 12, and I'm like "All
right, guys. As you all gather your harvest for
the fall, you look off to the setting sun and
think, 'My kids will eat well next year.'" And
that's our campaign. Thank you for joining us,
guys.
BRIAN: Probably not going to make a ton of shirts
for this one, but hope you like the characters.
LIAM: This game is just Cooking Mama.
LAURA: Oh, I love that game!
MATT: Stardew Valley: D&D Version would be great.
LAURA: Cooking Mama, taught me how to correctly
beat eggs.
MARISHA: Oh, yeah, because you actually had to do
the little--
LAURA: Yeah, do it and then switch.
BRIAN: Cooking Mama was the one that told me the
other nuns didn't like me.
(laughter)
BRIAN: I'm sorry. I snuck that one in there. We
did, however, you're not going to get too much
juice out of us tonight.
LIAM: (fart noise)
BRIAN: However we did tease you with something
over the break. Le Chiffre, show it to me at once.
We did tease you with something.
(cheering and clapping)
BRIAN: Put it back up! People don't want to see me
drink this!
LAURA: Oh my God! Do it again! Do it again!
TRAVIS: Yeah, put it up! Show me those legs!
(cheering and laughter)
BRIAN: There is a lot going on there.
MATT: Oh god.
LAURA: Those glasses!
BRIAN: We got to it, didn't we?
MARISHA: Oh, look at that, look at that!
(laughter)
BRIAN: Oh, wow, what a great fade! Wow!
LAURA: That whole day it's like, "Are we in a
cult? Are we in a cult right now?"
MATT: What's incredible is there are elements of
that image that aren't that different from my
middle school photos I took. Man, I've always been
a winner.
LAURA: I've seen that!
LAURA: Don't you have a picture of you on a
stairwell, or something?
BRIAN: With a Hawaiian shirt on or something like
that?
MATT: Oh yeah, I've got a bunch of pictures that
the world will never see.
MARISHA: Yeah, I felt like the whole time we were
doing the photo shoot, because it was like a house
in the Valley, I'm like, "Oh, they're going to
think this is the weirdest porn."
(laughter)
TRAVIS: The weirdest porn!
MARISHA: Throwback!
BRIAN: Yeah, the place where that photograph was
taken, you guys lucked out.
LAURA: It was a great place.
SAM: It was the only photograph taken there,
though.
BRIAN: No, that was it! They came, they posed,
they went their separate ways.
SAM: Yeah. It was about a five minute shoot.
BRIAN: Well back to questions about the last
campaign.
MATT: Yes.
BRIAN: What? Oh, Chiffre's going to put something
else on the screen. Side by side! Let's do the
look there. Do the face! There you go. Tilt the
head to your--There you go!
ALL: Yeah!
SAM: I love that we're comparing Matt to Matt two
months ago!
BRIAN: Yeah, Matt two months ago and Matt now.
MATT: Well this way you can tell just how much
weight I gained over the holidays.
Direct comparison!
BRIAN: Exactly. I know don't do a side by side of
any of us. Okay, back to questions about the last
campaign. TiamatZX is back with a
eloquently-worded question for Matthew Mercer the
Dungeon Master. "Percy had gotten two points of
corruption before having one reversed by Pike in
‘Against the Tide of Bone,’" I guess that’s the
title of an episode?
MATT: Yeah.
BRIAN: "What would’ve happened if he had gotten
more than two?"
MATT: I had made a custom kind of 5e version of
the Corruption-- what were actually called the
"Taint Rules" in the Heroes of Horror, but I
decided to change that because I knew, that this
group would never fly.
BRIAN: Stay taint!
LIAM: You shouldn’t have said that shit now!
(laughter)
MATT: Yeah, but it’s from the Heroes of Horror
book for the older 3.5 D&D. I had used it for my
Ravenloft game back in the day. I took all those
tables and I retooled them to Fifth Edition and
simplified a bunch of it. Past two points was a
threshold where you get to more of a moderate
severity of corruption, which you get a mental of
physical corruption. And so I’d roll--
TRAVIS: A physical corruption on your taint?
MATT: Yes. See what I got to deal with every
week?
TRAVIS: Listen!
MATT: You’re making Purvan cry.
ALL: Aw.
LIAM: Point of order! I believe the "Taint Rules"
apply in this situation!
(laughter)
BRIAN: I so bad wish I could read all those cry
babies on Reddit
complaining about "Taint Rules" instead of--
MATT: It would’ve been a physical or mental
corruption at that point, it would’ve been either
a moderate insanity or a physical ailment like,
the eyes would’ve started to rot away, or he began
to have the skin slough off a bit. Or he could’ve
began to have obsessive mental characteristics.
TRAVIS: Bring it back, man, we can handle it, that
sounds awesome!
We’ll totally be grownups about it!
LAURA: No that is what it is! We’re just not going
to call it the "Taint Rules".
MATT: No! That’s the "Corruption Points" now.
Because it used to be divided. Like a lot of Third
and 3.5 Edition rules, it was super complicated
when it didn’t really need to be so I pulled it
back a bit. I was going to put them in the
Campaign Guide, but like I said, it was based on
the Heroes of Horror and it was too close to the
original settings. I may just release them online
and if people want to give them a shot and, mess with them
them and retool them to yourself.
BRIAN: Something tells me that people will be very
interested in that.
MARISHA: We can’t even get through that question
without 30 jokes!
MATT: Yeah, I’m so excited for the new campaign!
TRAVIS: All your hard work is extremely valued.
(laughter)
BRIAN: Liam, question from (gibberish). "Vax
originally planned to become a paladin of Sarenrae
but was forced into the arrangement with the Raven
Queen. After meeting both, which goddess did he
favor more in the end?"
LIAM: In the end?
BRIAN: Yeah.
LIAM: (confused noises) I don’t know how to answer that.
BRIAN: Well, as Kirk Douglas wouldn’t help us.
TRAVIS: Go back to two episodes before the end,
and how did you feel?
LAURA: Just what does your gut say? Just answer!
LIAM: RQ, man, RQ let him be there at the end
there, at the end.
TRAVIS: Good call, man.
BRIAN: Yeah, that’s true. Sam.
SAM: Yes.
BRIAN: TheHollyPhoenix would like to know: "Was
Scanlan really trying to learn what it’s like to
be on drugs or was he just trying to find a way to
numb the pain of the whole Kaylie situation?"
SAM: Hmm. I think he was the latter, numbing the
pain. He had some issues and was having a crisis
of conscience.
LIAM: And taint points?
SAM: Yeah, and he had--
MATT: So much regret over here.
SAM: He had some grundle issues.
BRIAN: How do you think I feel?
TRAVIS: This has been its infancy.
SAM: It’s "taint-ancy."
TRAVIS: It’s a dwarf star, it’s about to-- A
supernova’s coming.
BRIAN: Liam’s had a month and a half to think of
stuff to yell at you right before we go live.
MATT: You’ve never seen a faster TPK.
BRIAN: Matt Colville, this’ll be his favorite
campaign: kill all the players before episode four.
SAM: He was genuinely seeking a way out of his
distress. He didn't know who he was any more, what
his purpose on the team was, or whether he should
be on the team or not.
So he was looking for a way out.
BRIAN: I had someone message me, I'm going to
share this because I died laughing. I had someone
message me and say: "I know that Sam did the whole
Scanlan Drug Arc thing because that’s what he was
dealing with in real life, but do you know if,
like whatever?" And I wrote back, and I was like:
"HAHAHA" in all caps because I was like: "If you
knew Sam, where did you--" And he was like: "I
just saw some people had said 'that's probably
whatever's going on.’"
SAM: I got in too deep?
BRIAN: Yeah, you were in deep, man! You got in the
streets!
MATT: A few weekends in Lancaster and you just
never were the same!
SAM: Part of the reason I was late to so many of
the shows was I would come in with just gold spray
paint. Then everyone would be like, "You have to
go clean up! Just say you were late or whatever!"
MATT: It was a very stressful period of the
campaign.
BRIAN: It was, man. To think that so many laughs
came out of such heartbreak.
(laughter)
BRIAN: Oh man, well, Taliesin. Run for sheriff of
Abilene with an answer to this question from
Schneeland.
SAM: The captain's uniform from Lufthansa Flight 91!
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Thank you! That’s what I was going for!
BRIAN: Oh man. "In a way, Taliesin, Percy's greed
and carelessness in the sunken tomb were
responsible for Vax's ultimate departure. Does
this ever plague him?"
TALIESIN: I mean, it's a long list, and also, I
would disagree with greed.
BRIAN: A long list of what?
TALIESIN: It's a long list of things that he feels
responsible for, because he's the only adult in
the entire world. It wasn't greed, it was just
hubris. Yeah, it was just hubris. He's a character
based on hubris. People make that joke
occasionally, like immediately going into hell
like "Okay, nobody ever make a deal, don't sign
anything," and then immediately within one hour is
like "I'm going to to make a deal." Yeah, it's
because this is what you do when you tell all the
kids "Don't touch the oven!" This is my oven, I'm
going to cook something. It's what you do when you
think you're the only adult in the entire world.
It always goes well.
MATT and TALIESIN: As we've seen!
BRIAN: The way I used to see it was, "I was always
the kind of guy who would steal your drugs and
then help you look for them."
(laughter)
BRIAN: "What man!? I'll be right over! I'll be
right over! I'm sure you left it in the can of
Pringles." Laura, question from subokunotora.
Isn't that the thing-- no, that's-- did Vex know
about Tary's feelings for Percy? If so, how did
that affect their friendship?
TRAVIS: Seppuku.
BRIAN: Thank you.
LAURA: I was thinking sudoku.
BRIAN: I was way off. Laura.
LAURA: I don't think so? Did she know about-- no,
she didn't know about him. No.
BRIAN: Okay. That wouldn't have been something
that was discussed.
LAURA: Yeah, that was obviously, we talked about
that in our best friend hangouts.
SAM: I'm sure you asked, but I don't know if he
was really into--
LAURA: Like, who do you like right now?
SAM: He was probably not in touch with his
emotions enough to even know.
LAURA: Right.
SAM: Plus you talk a lot.
LAURA: I did. I imagine that she did a lot of
talking.
TRAVIS: That was a one-way street.
BRIAN: He had to be a good listener.
SAM: Just on and on.
TRAVIS: Did you know that-- and oh my god. Have
you heard?
LAURA: I am so glad you're here because nobody
ever wants to hear these things.
TRAVIS: I feel like you really understand me.
BRIAN: Matt and Laura, this came from the
internet. Well, these all came from the goddamn--
SamanthaXYZ-- We've been off for a few weeks. This
isn't a permanent situation. Matt and Laura, what
would have happened if Vex would have said yes to
Saundor when she got her vestige?
MATT: Oh yeah, I think we mentioned that in one of
the Talks episodes.
BRIAN: Dani said only one person asked that
question.
MATT: The offer that would have come with your
character type going from humanoid to fey. You
would have become a fey creature. The tree would
have embraced and pulled her up into the canopy
and there would have been this transformation
process.
BRIAN: A fey-ancé?
ALL: Oh!
BRIAN: This is why I write the show, folks. This
is why I alone write the popular program Critical
Role.
LAURA: Now I am regretting not saying yes.
MATT: You would have transitioned to a fey
creature and some of the racial benefits would
have come with that.
LAURA: But then, some of the downsides, too.
MATT: Well, some of the benefits would have been
like a perpetual bark skin. You would have had
other fey abilities would have come to you, but
you also would have gotten vulnerability to fire
damage.
LAURA: Which would have been real bad.
MATT: Especially in the later battles.
LAURA: Yeah. I would have been dead fighting
Thordak.
There's no way I would have survived those.
MATT: And then you would have been bound to
Saundor, in which case he would have become a
patron for the remainder of the campaign to you,
or until you rebelled, in which case that would
have gone-- I don't know where that would have gone.
LAURA: Super south.
MATT: Probably pretty bad. But yeah, you would
have bound yourself to a not-so-good person.
LAURA: Yeah, but I would have gotten some sweet
tree loving.
MARISHA: Yeah, you would have had those nice curvy
tree hips. Yeah.
TRAVIS: Sweet tree loving?
LAURA: Saundor. I would have gotten some Saundor loving.
BRIAN: May be a better way to word it. I picture
some bad things happening with those trees from
the second Lord of the Rings. Travis--
LAURA: Ooh, there's got to be some fanfic online.
BRIAN: There is.
LAURA: Some ent fic? Yeah.
MATT: Guess what we're googling at break.
BRIAN: Yep. Not going to be a break, unless you want one.
MATT: Oh, no. Keep going.
BRIAN: Do you want a break?
TALIESIN: That'll be the 90 minutes after this 90
minutes.
BRIAN: Travis. Cardamonelaw wants to know, "What
was Grog's-- character you played in the last
campaign-- fascination with the lycans about? Was
he just wanting to tap more into his primal
side?"
TRAVIS: What was the--?
BRIAN: Fascination with the lycans?
TRAVIS: Oh, yeah. I think he just-- what was the
name of the big alpha lycan?
MATT: Oh, in the Feywild.
TRAVIS: Ukurat?
MARISHA: Ulrich?
MATT: No, not Ulrich. I can't remember off the top
of my head.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I can't. He was really in the face
of Scanlan right when he got there and Grog took
issue with that, and so I wanted to pick a fight,
but I was trying not to blow up too fast and get
us all into trouble, and then I got petrified by a
bunch of faeries. So that didn't go well. But
after that, I think Grog just realized that there
was maybe more to tap into,
plus Travis loves werewolves.
LAURA: Yeah. I was going to ask, when are you
going to say that part?
LIAM: That was my follow-up question. What
percentage is Travis and what percentage is Grog?
TRAVIS: Oh, it was 99% Travis wanting to get
werewolf art of Grog.
MATT: So internet, make that happen.
LAURA: Yeah, did that ever happen? Did you ever
get werewolf Grog?
TRAVIS: Yeah. I saw it. I saw some stuff. I even
got some minis while we were in-- I got three
werewolf minis in Australia.
LAURA: That's right. I remember that.
SAM: Speaking of petrified, how many fights were
you in as Grog where you were totally taken out of
the fight by being bamfed away, frozen solid,
killed instantly, turned into a dummy,
turned against us?
BRIAN: Check CritRoleStats later and see if that's
a thing.
SAM: It's got to be half, right?
MATT: Oh, it's not half by any means.
LIAM: No, but it's the only way for the DM to get
at him.
MATT: Well, it depends on what you're fighting. If
it's an intelligent creature, it knows what the
biggest threat is, the seven-foot, eight-foot guy
with the giant axe who looks like he could take
anything you throw at him. I'm not even going to
damage him, just (pop). Get out of the fight.
TRAVIS: Okay, bye!
MARISHA: You got grappled in that, not Kevdak, the
beholder.
LAURA: K'varn?
MARISHA: K'varn, thank you.
SAM: Yeah, in a holding cell or something?
MARISHA: Yeah, you got stuck for most of it?
LAURA: The mime box.
MATT: It depends on who you're fighting. A lot of
things that are not very intelligent will still go
after Grog and be like, "Ugh, he's just not going
down!"
LIAM: Wasn't he also grappled by something in the
fight with the elder brain? Like you got too close
to a cage and got snagged by something in the
cage?
LAURA: That's what he was talking about.
LIAM: Oh, that's K'varn?
MATT: Yeah, there were two of K'varn's experiments
in cages. Anyone got close, they would just
grapple and hold them to the cage.
TRAVIS: I had to be all curious and see what was
in there. I was like, "Ooh, allies! (clang)
(groan) Help!" Then I got stuck there forever.
MARISHA: You were just rolling so bad. I remember
that. Should have broken out, man.
LAURA: You were just rolling so bad.
TRAVIS: We were really good at strategy at that
point. We were the Avengers on point.
LAURA: No, that was some good strategy in that fight.
TRAVIS: We got fucking lucky.
SAM: We got worse at strategy as we went.
LIAM: But this is the year that we reclaim dignity!
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Gif that.
BRIAN: Says the guy who yells out taint whistle
three seconds before we go live.
LAURA: Hey, that's going to be the first one.
BRIAN: Matt, we had to mine really deep for
questions for this thing, you know, when we did
the original thing, and I found a gem-- and by I,
I mean Dani-- found a gem only asked by
TheHollyPhoenix. What does the Moon Hammer do?
MATT: Oh, right!
BRIAN: Literally 10,000 people show up at my house
asking me about the goddamn Moon Hammer.
TRAVIS: Mary gave me a Moon Hammer.
SAM: Did you use it?
LAURA: He never used it.
TRAVIS: No. Well, it had to be used under the
moon, apparently, but we rarely fought under
moonlight. But I don't know what it did.
LIAM: It's a plus one hammer.
MATT: Well, naturally, it was a plus one hammer,
and then when you brought it under full moonlight,
it would empower the hammer. What it would do is
it would give it a charge that would allow you to
cast Improved Invisibility on yourself or another
target until it was charged again. It wasn't some
grandiose powerful item.
TRAVIS: It didn't turn me into a werewolf?
MATT: No. That would have been cool, but it didn't
make sense for what Zahra's--
TRAVIS: I would have ripped my clothes off and run
out of this studio right now. I would have beat
myself to death during the rest of the stream if
that was true.
MATT: Zahra's enchantment capabilities weren't
super powerful, so she can craft something that
was somewhat useful given the circumstance.
LAURA: Probably at this point, she'd be able to do
some pretty badass--
MATT: By now, yeah. But at the time, limited to
enchanting something with a one charge Improved
Invisibility.
TRAVIS: Improved Invisibility is not bad. I never
went invisible.
MATT: No, especially if you could use it as a
person who was not a spellcaster. That was the
benefit of it. Anybody was attuned to the weapon
could then use it until it was recharged again.
TRAVIS: Grog would have forgotten he was
invisible. It's okay.
LAURA: Yeah, the minute you attack, you would have
been visible again.
TRAVIS: (yells) Aww.
BRIAN: Matt, OnceUponAPun wants to know, speaking
of interesting items, where and when did Sylas
come into possession of Craven Edge?
MATT: Craven Edge would have been probably one of
the artifacts that the cult of the Whispered One
had amassed. Even while Vecna was scattered
amongst the planes and trying to coalesce over
time, those who followed him, all the various
Remnants that were out there in the world were
collecting things for when he returned. There were
all sorts of artifacts and items that they were
pooling in places where they had the most
influence. Craven Edge was one of the most
powerful artifacts that they had recovered. When
he brought Sylas back and the Briarwoods had
proven that they were dependable right-hand men to
Vecna, he went, "All right, you can use this, and
since you are undead by nature and I was
responsible for your resurrection, Sylas, you
could ignore some of the penalties of this item."
TRAVIS: The dying part?
MATT: Yeah, it would have been harder for that to
happen to him. So it was just amassed by the
Remnants then gifted to Sylas when he became one
of the higher-ups within that structure.
TRAVIS: Was Grog the only one to take Craven Edge
to the limit? To its max anime status? Did he take
him to the ten? Give it to him?
TALIESIN: You maxed out the taint bar, man.
MATT: There may have been a handful of other ones
that had bankai-ed in the past, but you were the
only one in recent centuries.
TRAVIS: Fair enough. Recent centuries is pretty
good.
MARISHA: Good thing Pike was there.
LIAM: I wonder what Sylas' toilet chats were like?
MATT: Nowhere near as interesting. They actually
probably had good debates and
philosophical discussions.
LIAM: Does Sylas Briarwood even take a shit?
MATT: You know, that's a good question.
LAURA: Is it just blood poop?
SAM: Matt doesn't want to reveal anything that
might come into play in the next campaign.
BRIAN: Yeah guys, a couple of things he keeps
really close to the chest just in case Sylas poop
was something we talked about.
MATT: There are some great DM's Guild things I am
working on in the future around that so I don't
want to spoil anything.
BRIAN: Sam and Matt, was there any discussion
about how Doty was built? I know that got asked
about a lot.
SAM: How it was built? It was part of the
artificer class to have a-- something.
MATT: A mechanical automaton that would be his
companion.
SAM: Before I knew that and before he proposed the
class to me, artificer, because i didn't know what
it was, I had proposed to him a rich guy who
travels around with a biographer, who buys all of
his gear and has no actual skill. And he was like
"I've got it, artificer and you have a robot
assistant." I was like "Can he write?" and he was
like "Yep, done!"
MATT: Yeah it was a perfect union. The more you
told me about the character, I was like "Oh, well
this just came out very recently on Unearthed
Arcana."
SAM: Yeah.
MATT: It worked out great.
SAM. Yeah, it worked out great. I don't know about
that class so much. It seemed like it peaked. I
don't know how much--
MATT: It's in the testing phase. It definitely
isn't a powerful class it is a utility,
interesting class. I can see certain builds that
would be powerful but--
LAURA: I guess a support.
MATT: Yeah, a support and toolbox type class.
MARISHA: Your crown jewels saved me when I jumped
off a cliff. That was great.
LIAM: Story-wise, when he was a strapping young
buck, was he taking physics and engineering
classes, tutors?
SAM: Sure, yeah, tutors.
LIAM: Was it Lawrence who taught him how to make
Doty?
SAM: I don't know what Lawrence taught him. I
actually thought that Lawrence was more of a
literature tutor of romance languages or whatever.
But he definitely had all the best tutors.
BRIAN: Who do I want to talk to more in this
moment? Matt.
LIAM: Ashley is not here Brian.
BRIAN: I know. Erin Bradshaw wants to know, "What
were the plans of the illithid after Vox Machina's
escape? Would they/did they consider taking over
Kraghammer?"
MATT: The illithid rarely want to get closer to
the surface. They prefer to bring things to them.
They expand slowly from an inside standpoint.
Conquering a location isn't as important as
building up power to base and then possibly
jumping to a new plane or a new society. They are
one of those weird, alien colonization-type
species that jump between worlds. The Far Realm
gets real interesting, folks.
LIAM: And all underground when they dimension
shift it's just beehives under the earth.
MATT: For the most part. It depends on where
they're going. They're all about enslavement and
mind-control and fleeing their hunters, which are
like the githyanki. There are other species out
there that are constantly hunting and trying to
eradicate them. So they have this combination of
wanting to be as unseen as possible and then
drawing things into their fold and controlling
them. Probably, they were pulling things that got
too close, maybe eventually if Kraghammer became a
huge issue they would maybe core it out and
destroy the people and then leave the ruins, but I
don't see them hanging as close to the surface as
Kraghammer was.
LAURA: Just like, making some bedrooms in there
and summer homes.
MATT: Yeah, with some nice shawls or sweaters.
BRIAN: I don't understand why my friends who don't
watch Critical Role, that tune into this, say that
they are confused. With answers like that.
Question for everybody from Myurnaoneshot-- it's
as close as we are going to get gang. "What
happens with the Slayer's Cake? Does Vox Machina
stay involved with it?"
MARISHA: We loosely talked about this?
LAURA: Yeah. I think they opened up chains.
MARISHA: Yeah, we said they franchised it. The
next place would be Emon.
LAURA: Yeah.
SAM: They'd release a cookbook.
LAURA: Eventually an Ank'Harel location.
MARISHA: 100%.
TALIESIN: Eventually, there's like two a block.
You can't escape them.
SAM: They have a low price point option. SC2.
MARISHA: Well, part of my Honey Heist game, that
was part of the whole easter egg because it was a
year or two after everything had closed. I don't
think we ever actually got into this. Part of the
prize for winning the honey contest was that you'd
be able to sell your baked goods and your honey
tax-free. Remember Vex being like "We have to go
win this shit, and then open up our next chain--"
LAURA: Tax-free!
MARISHA: Yeah, in Westruun. I think, in my head,
we were trying to start making a name for
ourselves as the Slayer's Cake in Westruun.
BRIAN: Wow, that's pretty awesome.
LAURA: Plus, think about it. They're friends with
Gilmore, so he's telling them how to do stuff,
they got to like--
LIAM: Every Gilmore's Glorious Goods should have a
little Slayer's Cake inside it.
LAURA: Like Barnes & Noble with a coffee shop!
MARISHA: Oh my--
MARISHA and LAURA: (yelling) That's what happened!
LAURA: That's canon.
BRIAN: Speaking of Gilmore, and his glorious goods--
MATT: (as Gilmore) Yes, you rang?
BRIAN: People want to know, especially The Florist
Friar, what a great name, "How did Gilmore react
to Vax's death?"
MATT: Oh, terribly! He was heartbroken, just because--
BRIAN: I was so hoping you were going to say he
went, "Who?"
(laughter)
MATT: Even though long-term things didn't pan out
for them, he still cherishes the time they did
have, and the friendship he forged thereafter,
with everybody, so he's heartbroken for both his
connection with Vax, and for the rest of Vox
Machina and other people whose lives he'd come in
contact with. He's very thankful for the time he
had. The whole post-campaign for Gilmore was a lot
of self-reflection. He was very much this
self-started, wanting to prove to the world that
he can succeed and be as good as he can, and had
these dreams of perpetual expansion and
franchising. He backed off that a little bit after
all the events of the campaign, and just focused
on small local shops and staying on Tal'Dorei.
LAURA: You're screwing up our Slayer's Cake.
MATT: I'm sorry!
MARISHA: It doesn't work anymore.
MATT: Well no, he's an expansion of your
territory, you guys can go wherever you want!
BRIAN: After he got famous from that meme it all
went--
MATT: Yeah, exactly.
(laughter)
MATT: Enchanter bae.
BRIAN: Yeah, after he got famous from that he did
his own thing.
MATT: I think Vax's death and the whole events
there, especially in the tower at the end-- a lot
of self-reflection, a lot of showing more
appreciation to Sherri and the people that helped
him build what it was, and talking to his parents
more often.
LAURA: Yeah, that's great.
BRIAN: Liam, how does his sentiment about that
nonexistent person resonate with your sentiments
about your own nonexistent person?
LIAM: Oh man, tainted love is a complicated
thing.
BRIAN: Just to remind people out there these are
fictional characters. Despite how close you might
get to them.
MATT: It's just fictional from your standpoint,
man. It's been our life for three years.
BRIAN: I just mean when I get death threats
because I didn't ask enough questions about
Gilmore, he's not real. What is real is your lack
of life.
ALL: Aww.
BRIAN: I'm just kidding! I plan to read a list of
screen names at the end of it. Your reaction.
LIAM: (sighs) I mean he feels guilty about leaving
everybody. He didn't regret anything he did in his
life that was stupid and there was so much. But
leaving people behind were his biggest regrets.
For a long time, and I said this at some point
like six months ago, that his biggest regret was
disappointing Gilmore. That was eclipsed by
disappointing Keyleth, and leaving the family. But
Gilmore is a huge thing for me, Liam. I mean, I
kissed guys in college. You think I'm pulling this
out of thin air?
SAM: College?
LIAM: Come here, baby.
(laughter)
BRIAN: Sam was immediately hurt! I saw anger,
hurt--
SAM: Give me his name, and where does he live!? I
will burn his house down!
LIAM: His name was Kevin Harris, it was on the--
SAM: Did you like it?
LIAM: A little bit!
BRIAN: "I kissed guys in college" he says.
TRAVIS: Did you kiss him? Or did he kiss you?
SAM: Do you follow him on Facebook?
TRAVIS: Did you kiss him back?
LIAM: Gilmore was one of many things that was like
a huge, blessing and surprise, that I had no idea
that Dungeons and fucking Dragons would give to
me. And I loved that I had that story with Matt.
BRIAN: Like we talked about last time. Nobody even
expected him to become probably the most beloved
of all the NPCs or that he would play such a huge
role in campaign. At all.
LIAM: How many games did we have at home total?
Eleven? Fifteen?
MATT: Seventeen.
LIAM: Seventeen? Gilmore was not in the majority
of those. It was the minority, right?
MATT: I think he was in two sessions.
LAURA: That's it?
MATT: The one where you met him and the one where
you guys made the deal that he would sponsor you
guys' adventures.
LIAM: But he was super memorable and we loved our
encounters with him, but it wasn't a lot. And then
we're like, "Oh, we hope this NPC that we thought
was so entertaining and so amazing will show up in
the game." And then it evolved rapidly. Again, it
just comes from us doing it every week instead of
every week instead of every six weeks.
LAURA: We shouldn't have eaten all of those beans
and stuff before this.
TRAVIS: Are you saying that I shouldn't have eaten
all those beans?
LAURA: No, because that's what there was to eat
right? It was beans.
MATT: It was seventeen home sessions, but the home
sessions were like six to ten hours. They were
super long home sessions.
BRIAN: But I'm thinking about the home game that
I'm doing with Mary and Steve and everybody and
we're coming up on almost that number. And to
think of having to go weekly, online, playing in
front of like-- fuck no! That’s terrifying to
think about.
LAURA: I don't feel like your sessions are as long
as our were, right?
BRIAN: Some of them can be.
LAURA: Because we went like twelve hours.
BRIAN: If I drink, and then the dice fall of the
table, and I have to reroll.
LAURA: Brother, we had a twelve hour game.
MARISHA: Yeah, we got there at like ten and we
went until like ten.
LIAM: That feels right as well, like all day feels right.
BRIAN: Yeah we do like the big Sunday ones now
where we drink mimosas. Yeah. Mary's usually
throwing up by 10:00AM. But that's just Saturday.
To be honest.
MATT: Yeah, like I grew with that shit. We'd do
long weekends planned out where we'd go to a
friend’s house and we'd game all Saturday,
sleepover, and game all day Sunday.
It was amazing.
LAURA: That sounds amazing!
MATT: I miss those days.
LIAM, LAURA, and MARISHA: Big bear!
LIAM: You used to also have to corral us every
game too. For like the first hour, it would be
like "Ah!" And we would be catching up and
drinking mimosas. And you'd be like--
MATT: All right, guys, we’ve got to play. Get back
to the table.
BRIAN: Now we see each other so often it's like,
"So what have you been doing since 2:00PM?"
(laughter)
MARISHA: How was your shower and walking the dogs?
That was good? Okay, cool.
BRIAN: Matt, Mike Mahathy wants to know-- Don't
laugh, it makes me laugh Travis. "Who was the
mystery person who contracted the Clasp to abduct Vex?"
MATT: Oh yeah!
LAURA: Did we ever talk about this yet?
LIAM: Steve Bannon.
MATT: (laughs) Kind of. Well, there was an
individual. I didn't have to develop it too far
because you guys didn't go too deep into that plot
thread. But it was like a lower noble in Westruun
who, just in passing, had a run-in with Vex, and
she totally blew him off in a very Vex fashion.
And he kind of developed this obsession with her.
And so he would try to find information, send
people to follow her. It was really a weird,
fucked up--
LAURA: It happens all the time, actually.
MATT: Yeah. And so the story with that was--
MARISHA: (as Vex) I'm such a hazard.
MATT: Yeah. He'd try and court her, she'd knock it
away. He'd have her followed.
BRIAN: Sounds like me and Ashley's relationship.
MATT: Yeah, well, that's kind of what I was hoping
to show you this later.
LIAM: She is a relentless stalker.
BRIAN: She is, yeah.
MATT: And so he hired the Clasp and said, "Could
you please bring her to me?" And that was when Vax
had his first run-in with the Clasp. He noticed
this guy was following her, took him out, and in
doing so himself, was taken by the Clasp and
inducted into it as his means of paying back the
debt of knocking out one of their members.
LIAM: Which was the Pike and Vax game at home.
MATT: No.
LAURA: This was way before that.
MATT: This was a whole off camera storyline.
LIAM: Wasn't that the setup for the Pike and Vax
game?
MATT: It was the setup for it. But it was your
backstory to how you got involved with the Clasp
and got your branding and everything there.
Because at the time, this is really messed up, so
you had talked with the Spireling there at the
time in Westruun, and told the story about how
this was your sister and you were protecting her
and everything. And you offered yourself like,
"Whatever I can do to pay this debt back so that
this doesn't happen, let me know."
LAURA: Take me instead! You Spireling bitch!
LIAM: You're welcome!
MATT: The guy who you had knocked out who was
following her, who was also being held down while
you guys were having this back and forth in front
of the Spireling, he accepted what you were doing.
Then for failing, for punishment to the one who
failed, he pulled out this artifact, that's in the--
LIAM: Yeah, tongues. Stick of tongues.
MATT: It's an artifact in the Book of Vile
Darkness. That is just made of tongues stitched
back to back, and it can kind of still move and
flex and quiver.
LAURA: I remember you talking about this I was
like, "What the fuck are you--"
MATT: When you touch it to somebody, they have to
make a saving throw or their flesh gets changed to
whatever form you want it to be.
BRIAN: Oh, Taliesin has one of those at his
house!
LIAM: It's right here!
MATT: This would-be kidnapper that was hired by
the Clasp and failed, his punishment was to be
touched with this and then turned into a replica
of Vex, and then was sent to fill the bounty to
this guy who was obsessed with her.
LAURA: So there's some guy that looks like me
that's probably in a cage somewhere?
MATT: Probably.
LIAM: Is he not dead by now?
MATT: I don't know. Probably not.
LAURA: So if he ever breaks free, there's another
Vex in the world?
MATT: Yes. Who has lived most of their life as a
Clasp member who's probably really messed in the
head right now.
LIAM: That was backstory for one game that Ashley
and I played because we both missed a home game.
Matt was gracious enough to give us a game
together. Then three and a half years later, I'd
totally forgotten about it, we're live on the
internet, and you were like, "By the way," and I
was like, what the fuck was the story? How did it
go? I don't know. I'm telling it to Laura, but I
don't know what I'm talking about!
LAURA: I remember you saying something about
tongues and I was like,
"That's fucking weird, bro."
MARISHA: Hey, I have a question. What would've
happened had we not told the Clasp to-- the half
of us, that I got blamed for-- not told the Clasp
to fuck off? That thing that all but two of us
agreed to, but I got yelled at by Percy. Yeah,
that one.
BRIAN: Thanks, Keyleth.
MATT: The Clasp would've become a source of
information and material and fast movement through
Emon. You guys could've traveled through their
caverns beneath the city--
MARISHA: But they wanted access to the city and
other levels of the government in exchange.
MATT: They wanted in exchange for that
installation in Vasselheim. So they would've been
like, "We will help you. We can help get everyone
out of the city safely. We'll get them to places
that are safe. We can move you in and out of the
city anywhere in Emon safely. We can gather
information for you. We can supply you with
things. You have full disposal of the Clasp in
reclaiming Emon from the Conclave, but when all
this is done, we need you to help us install our
satellite beginnings in Vasselheim."
LAURA: I think that's acceptable.
LIAM: We all survived.
MARISHA: I felt like it wasn't our call to be
like, "Yeah, we can give you Vasselheim."
LAURA: I would've done it.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I'm totally into it.
LIAM: We know.
MARISHA: Keyleth still lingers on in my soul.
LAURA: Here's my theory about doppelganger Vex.
Later in life, she found the doppelganger and
hired him/her.
MARISHA: Where are you going with this?
LAURA: Because the paparazzi gets overwhelming for
the de Rolo family everywhere you go. So she's the
lookalike that goes out.
MATT: I will say, Vex is not aware of this other
Vex's existence and has not encountered them.
LAURA: Fine. But when she does, she'll hire them.
MATT: There you go.
BRIAN: Speaking of the de Rolo family, Lipululu
wants to know what are the names of Percy and Vex's kids.
LAURA: The pronunciation of the names are getting
worse and worse.
BRIAN: Look, it's not going to be a good year for
us, folks. What are the names of Percy and Vex's
kids? Unless you want to keep them private.
LAURA: It's Nugget--
TALIESIN: We named a couple of them.
LAURA: --Nugget, North--
BRIAN: Nugget North? Isn't that one of Nolan
North's kids' names?
LAURA: No, those are two names. Nugget, North--
LIAM: Nugget?
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: I'm coming back from the dead to ask you
why!
LAURA: Salsa. Percival Fredrickstein--
BRIAN: Rammstein?
TRAVIS: Cheddar de Rolo.
SAM: Capoeira.
LAURA: Bacon. That's a good one. Bacon.
MARISHA: Bacon de Rolo?
TALIESIN: And Qwop.
LAURA: And then Percival Fredrickstein the
Fourth.
MATT: When you guys decide those names, you should
put them on social media.
TALIESIN: I kind of like that they don't, so that
if people want to actually play the kids in their
own games, they can do what they want to do.
LAURA: I kind of want to name them, though. We'll
name a few of them.
MATT: You guys name your kids.
TALIESIN: We haven't had time to sit down and go
over this.
LIAM: It's like George Foreman. They are all
Percy. Even the girls are all Percy.
LAURA: Percy, Percy, Percy, Percy, Percy.
TALIESIN: A couple of them would've gotten the
other siblings' names, I think. We'll go over it.
BRIAN: Sam, JerrySalami wants to know--
LIAM: Good name.
BRIAN: Sounds like the world's lamest gangster.
Hey, it's Jerry Salami. He's going to put you in
the cement boots.
LIAM: Jerry Salami's coming for you.
SAM: Should I be worried?
BRIAN: It was going to be Andy Dicks' character on
Sopranos, but he got cut. Did Scanlan ever tell
Kaylie that he let her win the flute competition?
SAM: I didn't have to. She knew. That's my theory
anyway because, as I found out later in Scanlan's
life, Kaylie always knows when he is lying. So she
knew and let him so she could get upstairs and try
to kill him.
MATT: She knew, yeah.
SAM: Yes. She has this sense. She can always tell
when he is lying. She can see through his charms.
TRAVIS: Isn't that a great ability, babe?
(laughter)
BRIAN: Terrible. Watch a marriage crumble--
LAURA: You're like the cat with the thing on its
head.
LIAM: (sings)
BRIAN: Taliesin. BigCracker wants to know--
LIAM: Whoa.
BRIAN: Look, imagine a Ritz cracker the size of
this card that I hold instead of, perhaps, a
middle aged--
SAM: White guy.
BRIAN: White guy who is probably very friendly. He
asks a great question. "When Craven Edge killed
Grog, how much guilt did Percy feel knowing it was
somewhat his fault for giving him the sword? What
would he have done if Pike couldn't bring him
back?"
MARISHA: Yeah, you’ve answered this.
BRIAN: Have you answered this?
TALIESIN: Yeah, I feel like I have but--
SAM: You've never answered it in Christoph Waltz’
wardrobe.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Oh. Wow. That's a lot. I'm just going to
be sitting like this for the rest of the evening.
No, it's weird. One more--
(laughter)
LAURA: Out of all the things that Taliesin has
worn, this is the one you are getting the shit for.
TALIESIN: I'm so excited; this is everything I’ve
hoped for and more.
LIAM: That's bingo!
TAlIESIN: It hardly matters how guilty he was. He
wasn't going to tell anybody. He would have just
gone on the list of things I lived with. It would
be, "Oh, that's unfortunate, but it would be worse
if I actually got blamed for it so I am just going
to keep my mouth shut." Why make things worse by
actually taking blame?
LIAM: My abs.
MARISHA: Oh my god, that was so good.
BRIAN: Sam, ILikePorkAndFighting wants to know,
"Did Tary strike everything off his list?"
SAM: No. Shit. I have it somewhere.
BRIAN: Tweet the list.
SAM: I have a list. I wrote down the things that I
accomplished and the things that were left to be
done. I also had a separate list of all the things
Tary did with Vox Machina that he was going to
present to his Dad. Possibly. To prove that he was
worthy. But no, he did not accomplish everything
on the list. Yet. But there are many more
adventures to be had for the two weeks before he
gets killed as a member of the Darrington
Brigade.
BRIAN: That's awesome. Taliesin and Laura,
Vohollica wants to know: "If Percy's first death had
"not happened do you think that Vex and Percy would
have spent their lives as really awkward neighbors
"without ever realizing that they were pining for
each other?"
LAURA: We did talk about this, too.
BRIAN: God damn it, it was so long ago and the
mescaline and all the stuff.
It's just hard to remember.
LAURA: I think we said that they probably would
have eventually come to it, but it would have
taken a lot longer.
TALIESIN: And it would have been very awkward and
strange.
LAURA: Yeah for a while. For a good long while.
LIAM: You once said to me behind the scenes, "If
he doesn't make a move, it's never going to happen."
LAURA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: That may have just been because there
was a lot of tension of when that was going to happen.
LAURA: And you did hear what she said?
TALIESIN: Yeah, I did. So that was a thing.
BRIAN: What she said?
TALIESIN: When I was unconscious.
BRIAN, TALIESIN, and LAURA: Yeah.
BRIAN: Unconscience. Marisha, speaking of
unconscience, a question from you from our friend
TiamatZX. "How cathartic was it for Keyleth to not
submit to her vengeful desires and put Raishan in
"her place by killing what made her who she was,
thus leaving behind a
"feral shadow of her former self?"
MARISHA: It was pretty gnarly.
BRIAN: Neat.
MARISHA: Pretty gnarly.
BRIAN: An answer worthy of a great question.
MARISHA: I fulfilled my promise. Right? I guess. I
mean-- Kerrek killed her.
MATT: Really, you enabled the death, though.
TALIESIN: He unplugged the machine, you
actually--
MARISHA: It was fitting, as kind of my mentor.
Yeah, it's good.
LIAM: That fact would have mentally tortured her
far more than the actual killing blow.
LAURA: Isn't it so weird that so often the guests
got the killing blow?
MATT: That was crazy.
SAM: Mary especially.
BRIAN: Mary killed everyone.
MATT: It's frustrating from my end, because I wanted to
give some of these epic deaths to the mainstay
party, but... what are you going to do?
LAURA: I liked that the guests got them.
MATT: It made a good feeling. It does make for a
cool, memorable experience.
LAURA: Yeah, totally.
MATT: But also it's like the guest comes in and is
like, "Hey guys! Cool, thanks! I win, bye!"
SAM: Who was your least favorite guest?
BRIAN: That's a great question.
MATT: Will Friedle.
BRIAN: Probably.
MATT: I'm kidding, I love you Will, you're
amazing.
BRIAN: I didn't care for--
who was the fellow with the--
MATT: Danny Glover?
BRIAN: Danny Glover, yeah, ever since he got those
dentures, didn't understand anything he said. No
offense to the denture people out there. Guys,
little bit of a situation here. That's all the
questions that I have for the cast, I have several
questions left for Matt. Do you guys want to sit
here while I ask them to him or go out and eat
that delicious food that's out there?
TRAVIS: Peace out, see you guys next week!
LIAM: We'll just keep saying taint, that's fine.
BRIAN: Yeah, just say taint for every answer of
Matt's.
MATT: Please.
BRIAN: No, seriously, you guys are more than
welcome-- unless, do you guys have any other
questions for each other or anything you want to
ask Matt that you didn't get a chance to?
MARISHA: Oh, I have a question. What's with the
sphinxes and why didn't they live together
anymore? So sad, they were spouses and then they
were separated.
MATT: Well, when you live with somebody for a very
long time, eventually you enjoy the space you have
from each other.
LAURA: I'm going to throw something at you.
MATT: Well, they're creatures of purpose and they
had purposes in different areas, as was the
assignments of the Knowing Mistress. They have the
ability to communicate and every now and then
would probably meet up.
LAURA: For that sweet, sweet sphinx loving.
MARISHA: Yeah, I was going to say, they Skype.
MATT: Sphexting.
MARISHA: Sphexting?
BRIAN: What are you guys most excited about?
LAURA: For the new campaign, you mean?
TRAVIS: Just seeing what the fuck everybody's
doing. We haven't seen anything yet.
BRIAN: Any secrets among the group still?
LIAM: Sure.
LAURA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: I've been torturing everybody.
LIAM: Yeah, we don't know what his class is, we
know what everybody else's class is, but not
Taliesin Jaffe.
TALIESIN: I've been very specifically torturing
all of them. It's great, it's making me younger.
SAM: I don't know much about what Ashley's doing,
right?
TALIESIN: I know a little bit of what Ashley's
doing.
TRAVIS: Plus it was great releasing that
silhouette art that had nothing to do with the
campaign at all, everybody's like, "Oh, those are
the new characters!"
BRIAN: That's been the funniest part of the
silhouette watch.
TALIESIN: We broke that, right? They know that
those aren't the characters?
LAURA: Those are not even close.
BRIAN: Chris Lockheed has spent the last two weeks
telling people this is not the new characters.
LAURA: I have seen a couple people online that got
everybody right.
MARISHA: Really?
LAURA: I've seen like two people that got
everybody right.
TRAVIS: Now, that's out of 80,000 guesses, but yeah.
LAURA: But it's pretty impressive.
BRIAN: And those two people are--
MARISHA: That's like winning the superfecta at the
Kentucky Derby. If you had a prize pool for that,
oh man, be a lot of money.
LAURA: I think I saw one person who got--
BRIAN: Well, that was the Kentucky beat by Marisha
Ray. A regular segment on the next season of Talks Machina.
MARISHA: It's true! Do you know how much money the
superfecta pays up? Whatever, fuck you guys, it's
a big deal, it's millions.
TRAVIS: Superfecta, long island iced tea? No?
MARISHA: Fucking mint julep? No?
SAM: Coming up, Marisha tastes bourbons.
(laughter)
MARISHA: Let's go down Whiskey Road, you guys,
let's go on the bourbon tour.
BRIAN: Well, should we take five and then, Matt, do
you want to come back and answer some questions?
MATT: Sure, let's do it.
BRIAN: Let's do it. Thank you guys, stick around,
we're going to take five minutes--
can we do that, crew?
OFF-SCREEN: (hesitantly) Yeah.
(laughter)
BRIAN: It's my last night, they know.
SAM: Do they even have anything to go to, if you
go to a break?
BRIAN: Yeah, they can go to the delicious Critical
Role art or--
OFF-SCREEN: Yeah, art sizzle’s good.
BRIAN: Art sizzle’s good, okay.
LAURA: Ten minutes.
BRIAN: What? We can go as long as--
SAM: It's supposed to be a 90 minute broadcast,
it's almost over.
BRIAN: I know, but there's still 20 questions for
Matt that I want to get to, but I don't want you
guys to sit. I sprinkled some in, and then I asked
you guys all this stuff, but mainly this was a lot
of things that you guys could just get out the way.
LIAM: I have so many questions, though.
So many questions.
BRIAN: Well, then stick around on the set, then.
SAM: It's just Brian, Matt, and Liam?
BRIAN: Yes!
LIAM: Are we all getting kicked off? Is that
what's happening?
BRIAN: You're not getting kicked off, but you--
LIAM: Well, I think I'll have some of that fine,
Japanese whiskey that's in the other room.
BRIAN: Thank you, Aki, for providing. She even got
bored and left from Laura's answers. All right,
we'll be back in-- how many minutes, guys?
OFF-SCREEN: Ten? I don't know.
BRIAN: We'll be back five to seven minutes from
now, you'll see some of us back here on this
professional Q & A. Stay turnt, my friends,
we'll be right back.
ALL: Happy new year!
MATT: Good evening.
BRIAN: That's all we had planned.
MATT: Mm-hmm.
BRIAN: We're back! Your two dads, in our robes,
here to answer questions.
MATT: This is the best alternate universe "My Two
Dads."
BRIAN: This is, I know. That was a great show.
MATT: It was a show.
BRIAN: Was that a movie? No, that was a show.
BRIAN: I was thinking of "Three Men and a Little
Baby". Starring TV's "Magnum."
MATT: Yes.
BRIAN: Matt, I have some questions left over here
that people are dying to know. We're going to burn
through these. Everyone else left because there's food
and alcohol nearby. So, that's the way it works.
VexMeUpBeforeYouGoGo is back with a question.
MATT: Well played.
BRIAN: Might we learn more about Vesh in the
fut-ore, future. Fut-ore? Do I drive a Jaguar? Or
could you tell us about her a bit more? Her,
question mark, a bit more. You've said that
things, as in who Vesh is et cetera, weren't quite
as simple as Kash thought.
MATT: Correct. I mean, I'll go into it a little
bit, because, who knows, she's still an entity in
the world, it might play into the next campaign, I
don't know. There's a lot of questions where part
of me doesn't want to answer because I don't want
to rob people of their own interpretations, and
also because maybe things will show up in future
campaigns, I don't know. With Vesh in particular,
Vesh is an entity that presents itself as a god,
like anything powerful would that wants to be
worshipped or given attention. But isn't part of
the pantheon. As to whether or not she has
aspirations for it, or is just trying to convince
individuals of that to get what she wants, you
know... I'll say that she's a powerful entity,
powerful enough to grant divine spells to her one
follower. I will say that Kash is not the first
suitor that she's cycled through. Yeah, I'll leave
it there. Probably the most handsome. Not at all.
He's not handsome at all.
Kash has a very low charisma.
BRIAN: Yeah. Cariboukai wants to know what were
your original ideas for Kynan? Did you have any
plans for him had Vox Machina accepted him into
their fold in some way?
MATT: Kynan I had written to be their first
fanboy. As a party of adventurers begins to become
renowned and they've had a parade set for them as
thanks for helping Uriel Tal'Dorei. He was their
first interpretation of dealing with that
attention, and so my intent was for him to be that
lovable, slightly annoying young upstart that
wants to prove himself and be friends with them
and wants to learn from them.
BRIAN: Oh, like me with you guys.
MATT: Essentially, yeah, and we treated you
basically the same way.
BRIAN: Yeah.
MATT: So, yeah, the idea was for him to be this
interesting obstacle on the way of renown,
somebody that would want to tag along, that they'd
have to protect or leave behind, or could
eventually be groomed into a hero if they chose
to, or in the circumstances that laid out, give
such a harsh beat of reality, in a way that
someone as young and impressionable couldn't
emotionally process in a healthy way, and it was
so crushing to him at the time, whether or not
that was the intent, sent him on a very dark path
and thankfully they were able to manage to pull
him from that. I didn't expect any of his
story to go that way when I was developing him.
The whole interaction, I didn't expect it to go
that way.
BRIAN: Yeah, well that happened a few times.
MATT: A whole lot of times.
BRIAN: I don't know if I, or someone else, had
asked you who your favorite-- I know it's got to
be hard to pick one-- who your favorite NPC, as a
person and maybe as to play, is? Or maybe those
are different questions and that's okay.
MATT: That's hard.
BRIAN: I'm not asking you to choose, but I am.
MATT: There's different categories I'd put them
in. As far as villains go, as much as I was
excited to play, to jump into the role of my own
interpretation of Vecna, who's this classic D&D
villain, Raishan and the Briarwoods were both such
living entities in my brain, and for different
reasons I enjoyed jumping into those shoes. It's
hard to pick.
BRIAN: Senokir was one that you liked, right?
MATT: Senokir came out of nowhere, he was
completely spontaneous and he was a fun one. Just
because of the physicality and the creep factor
and being able to just make the players feel
suddenly very uncomfortable.
BRIAN: It was so uncomfortable.
MATT: It's great.
BRIAN: Oh, my god. And then, the box.
MATT: Oh yeah, that was fun. I have a special
place in my heart for Allura, because Allura,
wasn't intended to be, but in hindsight I can see
was my self-insertion NPC if there was. The one
where I felt was me trying to protect my friends
and trying to be a guide in places. I feel
there's a little part of me in each NPC, but in
Allura probably more than most. Her and Gilmore.
BRIAN: Have you had that happen in other campaigns
you've done, where you find an NPC or create one
that sort of is an extension of yourself?
MATT: A little bit, but I haven't had a campaign
that I've been so emotionally invested before,
it's been a variety of different players. I've had
some players that were more into the roleplay,
some players that were more into the mechanics and
the combat, I haven't really had a game until this
group of fuckers, where I can get so invested in
the NPC that I created, if that makes sense. It's
still a very new level for me as a DM.
BRIAN: Well, you wouldn't be able to tell. You
hate it when I say shit like that, I'm going to
keep doing that. Seedy88 wants to know, "Could you
share what happened to Cassandra between the time
"she took several arrows to the chest as she fled
Whitestone and the moment when Percy found her?"
MATT: Oh, yeah, okay. Cassandra was left to die in
the snow and as she was bleeding out she was
recovered by some of the Whitestone civilians, a
hunting squad that was out found her still alive,
brought her back and nursed her partially back to
health, knowing who she was. But in the time that
she was recovering, they were discovered by the
Briarwoods or the Briarwoods' lackeys and were
slaughtered, and Cassandra was recovered by them
and nursed back to health after that. She then got
to watch her whole family get hung, the corpses
anyway, on the Sun Tree and was subjected to a lot
of brainwashing over a long period of time, was
forced to become a member of their family, was
forced to eat dinner and breakfast with them every
day. They saw her as an asset to keep the people
under control. She was a connection to the old
regime, and they could kill her at any time, but
she probably was more useful in the long run. So
they kept her around, and she became this kind of
plaything, this adopted child that they kept
around. For years and years, she would try and
flee and escape and they would punish her for it
and eventually got, through a combination of
brainwashing and Stockholm Syndrome...
BRIAN: Oh, where you actually fall in love with or
begin to--
MATT: Yeah, and so they began to use her to weed
out seeds of rebellion in the city and destroy
them internally. They would send her out into the
city to find those, and be like, "I want to start
"a rebellion, who do I talk to?" They'd be like,
"Oh, talk to this guy," and she'd be like, "Okay."
She'd go and find out where the rebellion's
building in Whitestone and return and tell them
where it was happening and they would wipe them
out. And they would quell any sort of uprising
using Cassandra as an agent. When Vox Machina
arrived, seeing her brother still alive, and
seeing the possible fall of the Briarwoods was
just enough to break her from that and then there
was a recovery period. A lot of her just trying to
figure out who she was and dealing with the guilt
of the things that she did do, even though she
knew it wasn't her fault, you can't get over that
right away. That's something she's going to live
with for a while, but she's doing the best she can
to make it right for people, because of the things
she did.
BRIAN: But that's a lot of residual damage.
MATT: Oh yeah, she's a very complicated NPC that
we didn't get to express too much, but I didn't
feel it was necessary either. Her strength and
inner stoicism, I think, said volumes of where she was.
BRIAN: Yeah, and her mystery created a lot of
intrigue as well.
MATT: I hope so.
BRIAN: It definitely did. No, it definitely did.
Question that I have been thinking about, what are
for you, as you're in these weeks and these months
preparing for taking on a new campaign, and
luckily getting to start at low levels and you're
not dealing with a lot of the massive stuff that
you're dealing with at the end of a campaign,
but you are thinking about the end of that
campaign before it begins and how you map out and
everything. What are the truths of storytelling
that are the most important for you when you're
thinking about something like this? Because
obviously you know you can't be married too much
to an idea and hold onto it in a place of
preciousness too tightly, because you're with a
group of people who can change that course at the
drop of a hat or at a bad roll or-- some things,
other things take a lot more time to mess up. You
have to be malleable all the time in the
storytelling. So what are the pillars for you of
stuff where, "This is definitely something that I
have to keep"? Is that hard for you?
MATT: I don't think it's hard-- It's hard when
you start, because when you begin running games,
your comfort, your safety blanket, if you will, is
the stuff that you have prepared. That's what
makes you feel comfortable in the space. The more
you play, the more you run games, the more you
learn, that does bring comfort, but part of the
joy is listening to the players, seeing what they
do and change and actively alter what you've
prepared, and finding ways to incorporate that
into the things that you have already worked on
and prepared. For me, the core idea is making sure
you have a direction you're going, but be open
and willing to take the choices and the decisions
the players make and let that shift and alter what
you have prepared and in many cases will surprise
you and end up developing something much more deep
and interesting than what-- You're only one
person, your input in a vacuum is probably pretty
decent. But the final product of having all these
friends come together and eventually build the
narrative that leads to this points, as long as
you're paying attention and you're open to taking
these subconscious suggestions they're throwing
towards you as they develop the story, it'll end
up being much more fleshed-out and being much
more impactful for them, and they themselves will sense the
impact they've had on the direction they traversed
with this characters. You can't be too married to
it, you want to have a comfort of an idea where
you're going, but constantly be listening and
taking notes about the things the players do and
see how that would change the trajectory that
you're planning, and let it, honestly, in a lot of
cases. A big rule for me now is setting events and
factions and a direction that will be happening
concurrently with the game as they progress.
Whether or not they intersect with them in certain
times will gauge how they can influence the
directions where those different factions or
storylines are going. If they avoid them the
whole game, then it'll definitely change whether
or not they end up encountering multiple times and
plucking those threads earlier on. For me, that's
really exciting as a game master, is to see what
the players can alter at certain times and
surprise you.
BRIAN: So you're saying storytelling in this
context is as much about listening and being open.
You sitting down at the table every Thursday, with
your heart open to where what they bring is going
to change the story and ultimately end up
moving it forward.
MATT: I don't solidly the plan more than one
session ahead. I'll loosely plan arcs and maybe a
few sessions outlined and possibilities, but
session to session the players will make choices
that'll change what you've prepared. Now it is
either being a waste of time if you spent much
time preparing it in advance, but you
instinctively may be trying to railroad or push
them towards something that you had been hoping would
happen three, four sessions down the way, and
sometimes that can work fine, but for me, it's
more thrilling to let the players really guide their
destiny a bit.
BRIAN: Can we get a fog machine on the Dwarven
Forge this time? I see people tweet some pretty
awesome pictures of their Dwarven Forge setups and
they have dry ice and stuff like that. We've
got the budget, with them firing me we've got some
extra two, three, four, five, seven, eight bucks
lying around.
MATT: It's more like a free-time thing. I do what
I can with the time I have.
BRIAN: I know. Sometimes they get built during the
break.
MATT: Yeah, you'll see me change pieces between,
based on the choices they make. Battlefields
that’ll never happen versus where they're going
and I'm like, "Shit, I have to re-jangle this."
BRIAN: It's always funny because whatever pieces
you leave behind Ryan Green puts in his vest.
MATT: It's funny because sometimes they are eating
and rehydrating and I'm a mad man in here going
like, "Shit, ugh."
BRIAN: I know, and by the time we have to come
back, Matt is like, "I didn’t even get to pee! I
"was building what is hopefully going to kill all
of them."
MATT: Well, the new campaign will have a catheter
so it'll be much easier.
BRIAN: Yeah, we got one put in the chair.
MATT: I'm glad we got that approved, by the way.
It's a little expensive, right, you know.
BRIAN: Sucks that I have to wipe it down every
week. Cariboukai wants to know, "What were you--"
no, just kidding, we asked that. @Farandaway15,
"You’ve mentioned that if Scanlan didn't destroy
"the gun, that there was more planned for Orthax.
How would that would have come into play if the
"pepperbox have stayed around?"
MATT: Well, for one, Ripley would never have
acquired Orthax for herself. Ripley would have
been stalking the party for a long time to try and
scrape what information she could off of Percy.
Probably trying to find some way to steal some of
his weaponry or even try to steal pepperbox while
it wasn't being tended to or they were sleeping.
Orthax would have begun to push for the list, for
completion, and would begin to have a stronger
influence on Percival. It would have been to the
point where certain scenarios where he would have
moral decisions to let something live that
was either on the list or was impeding his
progress to vengeance that he would have begun to resist the
will of Orthax. He may have begun to exhibit more
fiendish capabilities and being offered more
powers from Orthax, the more it began to consume
him from the inside. I didn't develop it too far
from that point, but that was the direction I
wanted to go with it based on how long it was
going to be around.
BRIAN: Wow. Do you plan on, I don't want to say
being harder on them, now that they're all gone.
But this time around, since they aren't as much of a
newbie as they were when they started before, do
you plan on stepping things up a little bit or
maybe challenging them more? Even though they're
going to be obviously lower leveled, they're gonna
be a little squishy. You don't want throw
something crazy at them. But now that they do,
with the exception of Sam, understand D&D a lot
better, are you going to be harder on them or
maybe a little bit more
challenging this time around?
MATT: I don't want to say harder on them, because
the point of the game is for everyone to have fun, and
that doesn't always mean making it harder. But
challenge them more, I'd like to. I think, the
area where the new campaign is happening has a lot
more social ramifications for the choices they make.
BRIAN: Also, no doors in this campaign. I thought
that was a great choice, this land has no doors.
MATT: Just archways, which will be their new villain.
BRIAN: Hope they don't go into Spanish villas, then,
or Hobbiton.
MATT: To an extent, yes. I mean, 5th edition D&D
was still new to me and them when we started
streaming this, so there was a learning curve,
through every level I was learning the balance and
everything, and I've made mistakes here and there,
and I learned a lot going through the campaign.
Both on power levels and what makes an
interesting encounter, while also not making it so
hard to the point where it’s not fun. We've had
slogs and we've had battles that fall on that
category. But once again, that's part of the fun
of playing this live, is not everything is going to
be a perfect session. We're learning as you guys
watch it, that's what I hope is part of it. I
think so, because it's just us playing the game.
There’ll be those things. I've learned a lot from
it, the players have learned a lot. I feel
confident in their capabilities now of being a
little more tactical, of learning that not every
battle can be won, some things are more about
creative use of the battlefield than just running
and doing damage.
BRIAN: There's a lot about gods.
MATT: And learned a lot about preparation, and
learning what you're up against before you jump into
that also. And if not, they’ll learn that very
quickly. I will say it'll probably be a lot more
challenging. Also because, as is the nature of
D&D, once you get to the higher levels, a lot of
things can be circumvented easier. Death becomes
more of a nuisance to a certain extent. The lower
levels are definitely not that case. I'm both
excited and very scared for the new campaign.
We even ran our session zero with Laura, Travis,
and Marisha and in one attack, Laura's character
went to zero hit points.
BRIAN: She told me that.
MATT: Against a giant constrictor snake. And I
think that was a wake-up-call, as it should have
been. We’ll see how that plays out.
BRIAN: Don't show up with any weak shit.
MATT: Or at least just be mindful.
BRIAN: NuclearWhale94 wants to know-- remember
that one, from the big nuclear whale of '94.
MATT: Yeah, how could you forget?
BRIAN: I remember where I was the morning.
"Raishan was in it for a purpose, as we found out,
"can you elaborate on Brimscythe, Vorugal and
Umbrasyl?"
MATT: Most of that--
BRIAN: Oh wait, there's more, "Can you elaborate
on their motives and more of their characters as
"we barely had any time with them?"
MATT: I’ll try and be concise. Brimscythe loved and
had fascination with corrupting human political
structures, so Brimscythe had already, as General
Krieg, unrelated to the whole Conclave incident,
got himself ingrained in Emon's society and was
basically just digging it out from the inside.
That's why he had set a whole accommodation with
a home there and a lair that was not too far off.
Was out of just his own enjoying this degradation
that he had created. Vorugal was an animal, a very
powerful animal who was intelligent enough to get
by, but was more fascinated with the hunt, was the
thrill of the stalking and fighting. Imagine
Vorugal very similar to Akuma, from Street
Fighter, I guess you could say. A warrior who
is very powerful, but has no goal other than to
eventually find something more powerful than him to
give him a real challenge. Vorugal was very much a
similar mindset to that. I think Umbrasyl had been
hunted enough from lair to lair by people that
wanted to be rid of this black dragon scourge
that had destroyed societies to the far west, and
wanted an environment where he could rule without
worry of being bothered or assaulted, and
eventually hunted down.
Raishan and Thordak-- although mostly
Raishan-- brokered this idea that "If all of us
"work together, we can wipe out most of the
controlling society on this continent and the
"immediate threat of Draconia," which kept very close
tabs on a number of these members, "to just put us
"in a position of power, with no opposition, and we
can divvy up the land however we please, and then
"go about our business and help each other out when
we need to." Chromatic dragons don't work well
together in a long-term deal, so it was a short term
like, "we all do this together, then we all fuck
"off to our four corners and we rule these four
corners because we have wiped out opposition."
That was the whole premise there. For Brimscythe,
if he had survived, he probably would have wanted
Emon for himself, but Thordak-- honestly, if
Brimscythe had survived when the Conclave
happened, Thordak would probably have taken out
Brimscythe quietly, without the rest of the
Conclave knowing. They never got there so I didn't
elaborate too far on that one in the story but
there had been a conflict there between those
two.
BRIAN: That would have been cool.
MATT: Yeah, I mean, I can go on, but there are other
questions to get to.
BRIAN: Man, that Conclave arc was my favorite, I
think. Besides the one where Tary came in for a
little bit.
MATT: It's hard not to love Tary.
BRIAN: @LeDoomGov wants to know, "What were your
plans had Vox Machina entered the hag's house in
"the Shademirk Bog?"
MATT: Technically not a hag. They thought it was.
I think I talked about this a little on one of the
Talks Machinas, but this was another fey entity
that was there, that was a half-corrupted,
half-monstrous and half-beautiful woman. If they
had spoken to this woman-- and I can't remember
the name, I have it in my notes somewhere-- she
could have given them information about Saundor in
advance, could basically have informed them with
more history of his corruption, what his quirks
were, what he is seeking and would have given them
possible knowledge that could have aided them in
the battle, or to prevent a battle and there could
have been a fully wits-based encounter with him.
If they managed, after talking with her, convince
him of his own folly and that he was not righteous
in the actions he had taken, he may have felt so
guilty that he would have just withered away and
left the corruption to fade on its own without a
conflict. She was that, but she was also an
old-school ex of his from like a thousand years ago
and they don't like each other anymore. She was
excited to watch him fall, but it never happened.
It was more of an interesting social encounter
that if they navigated well it could have lent
more information with the coming conflict.
BRIAN: I can't believe you remember all this stuff.
MATT: I can't either. (laughter)
BRIAN: Myrennororunsha wants to know, "What
exactly did Jarett do that forced him to flee Marquet?"
MATT: Yeah, that never came up in the campaign.
Once again, I have it in my notes. Jarett was not a
very well-to-do individual in Ank'Harel, wasn't a
street urchin by any means, but was considered
probably very lower class, and had through
happenstance gotten involved with a very young girl who
was of a very high noble status in Ank'Harel. They
began to pursue this romance in private because,
from what her parents and family wanted was to
maintain a noble birthline and already had
suitors and I'm pretty sure had an arranged
marriage prepared for her at a certain point, and once
it was discovered that they had this tryst going
on for a number of months, he was going to be
executed. He got the hell out of there. So nothing
illegal, technically, by the heart, from the
family’s concern there. He got out of there
because he knew that if he made his way back there
it probably wouldn't end well. It had been a
while, he probably could be okay if he went back
and looked different enough, but you know--
BRIAN: It's the same reason I fled Nevada.
@ManlyBubbles would like to know, "If the party
"hadn't summoned the goristro to fight Vorugal,
what would the adventure to find the Spire of
"Conflux have looked like?"
MATT: Oh shit, that was a whole thing that never
happened. They would have to go to the
Abyss. They would have had to have gone to the Maze
of the Abyss where the goristro hailed from.
BRIAN: That would have been fun.
MATT: That would have been scary as shit because
they would have had to not just navigate the
maze, they would have had to navigate the maze to
get to the specific goristro that contained the
Spire, which would have involved them finding some
arcane means of tracking this entity, or making
allies in the maze that could lead them in that
direction. Let me tell you, making allies with
demons always turns out well.
BRIAN: Yeah. How do you think I got this job?
MATT: (laughs) Yeah. It would have been
complicated and very dangerous, so honestly, that
was a very inspired use of the Gate scroll. When
that item came up as a loot item, I was thinking
it would be-- It was one of those systems for the
DM, and I recommend this for a DM, sometimes
you'll throw things in your campaign and you're
like, "I don't know how or where they'll use this,
"but I'm sure it will be interesting whenever it
does come up." And it was their first real brush
with 9th-level magic. I was excited to see how
they were going to pull it out, and that was
pretty inspired on their end.
BRIAN: Heck yeah, one of those clutch
things. Speaking of Dr. Ripley from earlier,
CommanderClay wants to know: "What was Dr. Ripley's
plan, and what was her deal with the devil?"
MATT: She wasn't a major player, but she was part
of a structure of military development in
Rexontrum, which is the capital city of West
Wynandir of the Dwendalian Empire.
BRIAN: Recsyndrome.
MATT: Rexontrum! That'll show up in the new
campaign. She was, on a medium scale, a developer
of military technology. They were looking for ways
to improve their dominance of that region.
BRIAN: She was a Justin Hammer!
MATT: Kind of! But a little more of a
Goebbels, I guess you could say. She was looking
into, at the time, more arcane diseases and
things that could be a chemical-warfare type
of basis that was technically illegal at the time
and was using human experimentation, unknown. When
she was discovered, she was about to be tried for
it, and so she fled. But in part of that process, she
probably figured out that there was some bad blood
between her and King Bertrand Dwendal, which is
why he was on her list. And a number of
individuals on her list were people--
BRIAN: Yeah, we had another question, who were the
people on Ripley's list?
MATT: I don't remember off the top of my head, but
all these people were all individuals she worked
with that were responsible for turning her in to
the crown and getting her placed on a list for
trial. She had some small-level magic as a lot of
the higher-level members of Rexontrum and that
area do and utilized what she had to escape and
fled out of the kingdom over to the Menagerie
Coast at Port Damali, and that's where she met the
other fugitives, the Briarwoods. They had this
unification of ideals and decided their purpose
was to "Let's work together and see where this can
"take us!" So that was that, and as far as her
plans with Orthax, it was just her now fascinated
with this new technology that she saw a lot of
uses, and as this was the source of it, it seemed.
What secrets did it not tell Percy yet, what was
it holding back? And if she embraced this entity,
what more could she learn from it that Percival
would never, his moral code, allow him
to make the sacrifice for? She was driven a little
mad by that pursuit at that time.
BRIAN: One of the best NPC/PC emotional
tug-of-wars, sinister--
MATT: Oh man, I loved it! I was sad that she died
in that battle. I knew it was probably going to
happen, but I was hoping she would be a fun one
to string along for a while and just
be a recurring villain.
BRIAN: Maybe there will be a version of her in the
next campaign.
MATT: She almost got away!
BRIAN: Yeah, just like Ash. Hakumen Narukami wants
to know: "What would have happened if Vex couldn't
"find the grey render or if it had escaped?"
Anything would have happened there?
MATT: Technically it escaped.
BRIAN: Ran away, right?
MATT: She wasn't able to necessarily charm it to
her, and if she had been able to succeed to
convince it, the grey render would have bound
itself to her. Grey renders do that. Sometimes
they will pick an entity or a location they bind
themselves to and will protect it at all costs. So the
grey render would have become a force of nature
that whenever she was in the area of Whitestone
would protect Vex from the shadows and then
continue to protect her bloodline. So any
children she would have had, it would become the
protector of the family. She didn't succeed at
that, so instead it just continues to wander the
Parchwood around Whitestone, watching over its
young. So she did miss that opportunity, but
that's fine, it happens in D&D, not everything is
a success. Yeah, that's kind of it.
BRIAN: Interesting! Speaking of the last Fireside
Chat that you did, Brooke Casey says, "When the
"assassin created from the Fireside Chat was made
into a baker, was it pure serendipity that Vox
"Machina in the downtime had founded the Slayer's
Cake? Or had you influenced that at all? If they
"hadn't, how would she have been added?"
MATT: No, that was completely by a serendipitous
scenario. They hadn't even told me their intention
over the break to develop this, the Slayer's Cake,
at the time. It was the whole chat trying to be
ridiculous and trying to get me to create an NPC
called Troy Baker. That's where it came from.
BRIAN: Named after the video game voice actor Troy
Baker?
MATT: No. Named after the--
BRIAN: Oh, the guy from Deadliest Catch?
MATT: Yeah, exactly.
BRIAN: The game about football, Deadliest Catch.
MATT: Yeah, that one.
BRIAN: Yeah. It's like Death Race, except they
play football.
MATT: I would watch so much more football. Or any.
(laughs) It was purely a chat-based joke on trying
to get me to name an NPC Troy Baker. I was like,
"All right, it's a baker. Fine. It's a baker. I
"give you that." And then when they did the
Slayer's Cake, because I was trying to think how
the assassin was going to ingrain themselves into
the story. And that was the perfect in and I'm
like, "Well, thank you for solving a problem I
hadn't come up with an answer for yet. Fuck yeah."
BRIAN: Okay, last few here we've got for you.
Repete17, "Was there a way to avoid the fight with the
"gigantic forge guardian at the core anvil?"
MATT: Oh, right! There would have been if they had
brought any materials to craft or create something
using the anvil.
BRIAN: That was the trick?
MATT: As part of the worship to the Allhammer
that this location maintained, since the Allhammer
no longer exists on this plane, it would be to
create and craft something on the anvil and leave
it as an offering to the Forge Guardian and the
Allhammer's memory. So if they had brought
anything, whether it had been any of the raw ore
that they had found in previous rooms, and crafted
something that was deemed a worthy gift, then they
wouldn't have had to worry about the actual
encounter with the Forge Guardian. But, once
again, D&D!
BRIAN: Yeah, exactly. TCOblivion. "Is Devo'ssa's
cover story permanently blown now?"
MATT: Devo'ssa's cover story with the people of
Ank'Harel, no. Devo'ssa's cover extends to the
general populace. But to mainstream leaders in
other parts of the world that have had to work
directly with J'mon Sa Ord and their presence in
recent events, I don't think has blown any of the
cover there. And they're all very well aware of
J'mon's necessity to keep such things under wraps.
I'm sure rumors will spread, but rumors have
always spread. And whenever a rumor has gotten
close to J'mon's existence, they've been very
conscious to disseminate other rumors that would
just clutter and cloud that same space. Almost
like our current political structure. I'm not too
terribly worried about it. For hundreds of years
there have been theories that J'mon is a dragon.
But there have also been theories that J'mon is a
number of people that just pass through like an
office. Like the Dread Pirate Roberts. Or that
it's an alien entity from another plane that lives
forever. There's been a lot of rumors.
BRIAN: Or the Saint. The popular Val Kilmer film.
MATT: It's the film. It's an actual boxed DVD as
the leader of Ank'Harel.
BRIAN: Dani just started typing up her letter of
resignation after that joke.
MATT: Good job.
BRIAN: "Was Dr. Dranzel just looking to make a
score? Or as a leader of the Golden Grin, did he
"have other motive for sending Vox Machina back to
General Krieg's house?" This question’s also from
(mumbled).
MATT: That was purely out of need for money. Dr.
Dranzel is not a leader of the Golden Grin, just a
member. And it's a very well-hidden fact on his
end. Only those who keenly paid attention to the
campaign guide would have noticed that.
BRIAN: Few, I'm sure. Knowing this community.
MATT: I'm sure many. Dr. Dranzel is all about, as
is the Golden Grin, uplifting the underdog and
protectors of good in society. And Dranzel does so
whenever the opportunity arises. He's kind of a
passive member. More active in his youth. But that
whole element was just basically going, "Hey, so
"we need some cash. And I hear there's some things
that are pretty pricey that no one's watching
"over. Want to go get some?"
BRIAN: How much do, if at all, real events impact
any of the storytelling that you do? I think
about how David Milch talks about how George
Hearst in the third season of Deadwood is to
represent capitalism coming to America, 1876,
right? The forerunner for capitalism would be a
serial killer in the form of Garret Dillahunt's
character. So thinking about the campaign, do you
find that what happens in the world, whether it be
the injustices or our successes in any current
shape find its way into the story? Is it hard
to ignore what's going on in the real world?
Because so many of us look at this game as a way
to sometimes escape. You know. I'm not a big
escapism person, but for four hours to just go like, "This
will bring me to a place of happiness."
MATT: It's an interesting point. I would say I
don't tailor my stories to reflect the world, but I'd
imagine, subconsciously, it's hard to avoid it,
too.
BRIAN: It's hard to not be impacted by it.
MATT: The world is filled with so much variety of
conflict that no matter what you create in the story
that has conflict, there's going to be parallels.
Whatever is close to you is going to lead its way
in some way shape or form into the work that
you're doing. It's not just writing, or writing
especially, a lot things that you do, they just
find their way in. I think in hindsight there were
elements in the campaign that I'm sure were, you
know, things bleeding over. This upcoming campaign,
just in the way I've built the world I'm sure
there's been a lot that's bled into it as well.
There'll be parallels. And you want to tell
stories. For some people it's escapism. For other
people I think it's a therapeutic way of dealing
with the injustices of the world. I'm not trying
to show an example of a perfect world. I'm not
trying to be like, the world sucks out there so
come to our place where everything's great! I'm
like, the world there sucks. Come to this world
where some things do suck but people are standing
up and making a difference. People are trying to
actively make the sacrifices that are necessary
and stand up and be heroes in the face of
injustice and probable loss because somebody needs
to. And that's the tale I want to tell. I don't
want to inspire people to ignore the
darkness and find a safe space. There is an
element of that. But I think in that space you can
also teach people the importance of standing up
for what's fucked up in the world around you and
in what small way you can contribute to changing
the things you're unhappy with. I think we've seen
a lot of that in the community. We've seen a lot
of that in storytelling in recent years in
general. The good stories come from people that
are frustrated with the world and want to make a
difference and the only way they can is with a pen
and pencil.
BRIAN: That's true. That's a great sentiment.
What's the hardest thing for you to write?
MATT: Oh man! That's an interesting question.
BRIAN: Are you struggling with anything right now
that you're just like, "It's not coming together"?
MATT: Strangely, no. It's coming together. But
it's been a lot of months of percolating ideas and
throwing things down.
BRIAN: You've had some practice.
MATT: I think the hardest thing for me is
outlining enough faction perspectives to flesh out
a world but not have everyone feel like they're
constantly at war. If that makes sense. We have
all these various societies and factions that all
have conflicting ideals and interests. However,
they're not always battling. For me, it's a
conscious development choice to find ways in which
they have to coexist. Or find ways in which they
have to agree not to--
BRIAN: A trade deal or a thing, yeah.
MATT: Right. You know, with a long term idea of
how to do I take you in the end. Or the
mutual destruction type idea. Of like, you know,
well if we both do go to war we both will probably
kill each other. Let's best just hold this tension
for now, we'll table this at the moment and come
back to it later. History is a great source of
these stories. You look at the history of
humanity-- If you ever want to run a game and you
want to get something a little more interesting
and political, read history. I know it may have
sucked when you were in high school, but I
guarantee the older you get the more interesting
history is, and there is some fascinating history
in human civilization around the world.
BRIAN: Or just watch a bunch of Eddie Izzard
specials.
MATT: That too! Honestly, yes. So yeah. That's about
as elaborate as I can get on the topic before
rambling and boring you all.
BRIAN: Yeah, I get it. I'm just sneaking in a few
of my own questions here because I'm selfish. Did
you have alternative plans for Craven Edge if
Percy hadn't picked it up and given it to Grog?
MATT: No. It was just going to be a weapon that
was left behind and would have probably gone into
some archive somewhere. I expected it may have
been found, but also as you've seen in a lot of
battles sometimes, in the throes of a very
emotional sequence, loot will be forgotten. Or I
expected somebody to pick it up, somebody who
wasn't Percy, and be like, "This doesn't look good.
"Let me go ahead and find somebody who can identify
it." And be like, "Oh, this is bad!" and be like,
"Fuck this," and throw it away. That was the more
probable thing, but much like Grog finding the
Deck of Many Things, sometimes the people you
don't expect are the first to find the loot.
BRIAN: That changed the game.
MATT: I was like, if anybody finds the Deck,
except for Grog, they'll probably be okay.
BRIAN: Uh-oh. I know, yeah. And it being Travis,
too. VinceK42 says, "So the party was about one
"roll/decision away from never discovering Tyriok,
the mapmaker, in his petrified form."
MATT: Oh, right!
BRIAN: "How many dead or permanently incapacitated
NPCs who Vox Machina just missed are there?"
MATT: (laughs)
BRIAN: That happen a lot?
MATT: Not a lot, because not--
BRIAN: Am I showing nipple? Are we okay?
MATT: Oh, don't cover up!
BRIAN: Okay. Well, we're going to get banned on
Twitch. They told me as much. Sorry.
MATT: I mean, recurring NPCs? Not many, because
either they stay in places that are safe, or they
encountered them. Gilmore during the Chroma Fall,
when the Conclave attacked Emon; Tyriok; their
friends when they were going up Entropis at the
end. If they had not managed to protect or deflect
Vorugal's flyover of Whitestone, when they had put
up the illusionary barrier and his return from
Draconia, there could've been some bad stuff there,
because he wouldn’t have attacked then. He
would've flown up or pretended it wasn't there and then
come back later on with probably two other members
of the Conclave and wiped out a lot of Whitestone,
and that would've been bad.
BRIAN: Yeah.
MATT: It's not too often because I don't want them
to continuously meet NPCs they've already met.
There's probably NPCs they never met that probably
died off-screen that they never encountered.
BRIAN: Or ones that got killed within one line of
dialogue.
MATT: Or there was that, yeah.
BRIAN: That was hilarious. Gavrock wants to know,
"How are Shale and the Herd of Storms doing
"following the fall of Umbrasyl?"
MATT: The Herd of Storms, which technically is no
longer called the Herd of Storms at this point,
although the stigma around the title is a bit
rough, they're doing all right. They're
rebuilding, they're taking a little more of a
peaceful trade and interacting with local society
for goods and then staying to nature. A less
dominant Kevdak-style of conquer, take, and ruin.
Shale is not around anymore. Shale, according to
Chris Perkins, and I'm not going to rob him of his
character's end, probably fell down the mountain
shortly after that battle and died alone somewhere
in the Cliffkeep. By his own words! But Shale had
done well, and she had lived a good life up to
that point and contributed.
BRIAN: That's crazy.
MATT: Go Shale.
BRIAN: Go Shale. I know you're watching, Chris.
MATT: Drink to Shale.
BRIAN: I know you're watching, Christopher.
MetallicaGross wants to know-- Chris, you agree
with that?
CHRIS: I'm a Megadeth fan.
BRIAN: Oh, he's a Megadeth fan. I like Megadeth.
"Matt, was there any exciting backstory,
"sidequests, lore, or loot tied to that ship in
Vorugal's lair?" Was that anything?
MATT: The party put a lot more to that boat than
there was.
BRIAN: Okay. So it was one of those things like
Senokir's box where it was like, obsessed with it
but it was okay.
MATT: Yeah. Vorugal, who had just relocated to
make the ruins of Draconia their nest then began
to amass what goods were nearby, and so began to
do flyovers of nearby villages and civilizations
and grab whatever was there, kill whoever was
present, and take it back and began to build a
new hoard, and one of the things happened to be a
ship that was out in the ocean that Vorugal
destroyed partially and then took the rest of it
back and then began to sift through what was
inside, and over time began to freeze over. There
was nothing too special in there, I would have
rolled up some random magical items for it. I did
have some random items rolled up for it, but
nothing too crazy. But that's also one of the
things I love about being a DM, is you can
convince the party unintentionally of all the
possible intents, story-based mystery about a
scenario that literally is just a broken ship.
BRIAN: Yeah. That's kind of what happened on Lost,
too.
MATT: Yeah.
BRIAN: You know what I'm talking about? (sigh)
That ship. At least they killed the guy in there.
Hey, Ellie A. O'Neil wants to know, "What were the
specific triggers for the Vestiges awakening," did
we talk about that already? "and were there any
awakenings we didn't get to see?"
MATT: I largely prefer, and I put this in the
campaign guide a little bit for those who want to
use it, I prefer the Vestiges awakening at moments
of either heavy character development,
advancement, or a crux for their flaws or bonds,
if you run those systems, or something that is so
out of character and them embracing a level of
adventurous heroism they wouldn't otherwise.
Essentially, whenever you as the GM or the
director of the game goes, oh man, this would be a
fucking cool moment for this to awaken, you know?
When the player surprises you with something,
you're like, well, that's enough for this thing to
start glowing and get more awesome. You know, I
wanted to leave it kind of vague because to me
it's up to you to find those moments. All of the
Vestiges, I'm pretty sure, exalted in the
campaign, but not everything they found was
dormant when they found it, and this because I
didn't want people at higher levels getting
towards the end of the campaign comparably to have
to get a dormant item and be like, oh, I have to
awaken it and then I have to exalt it necessarily.
I wanted it to be at certain levels, so I built in
a system where if a Vestige is unattuned or unused
for a long time it slowly reverts back to its
dormant state. Some of them may have been already
awakened when they found them, but hadn't been
exalted yet and hadn't quite fully regressed yet.
So, that was my way of dealing with that scenario.
BRIAN: Yeah. So, you're saying for people who want
to do it in their own campaign, sort of
case-by-case it because if you pick it out
yourself, you maybe rob yourself of a moment where
the player does something that makes you go, oh,
that's it.
MATT: Yeah. I mean, you could do it. You could be
like, when they kill their 20th creature or when
they use this feature X number of times. Those are
totally viable ways to do it. I think I have a
suggestion of that in the campaign guide. But for
me, it's more fun to wait for those heroic moments
when a player surprises you and their party
members and does something really cool, really in
or out of character, or really elevates the
narrative in a way you aren't expecting, and you're
like, this is the moment where I reward you for
that awesome moment with your Vestige reaching the
next stage.
BRIAN: Yeah. Wow. Okay. Pretty cool. TheFoxyKarama
wants to know, "Would it have been possible for
Vex to call upon the help of Galdric," Galdric, right?
MATT: Yeah.
BRIAN: "--of Galdric while performing the trial to
become Mistress of the Grey Hunt?"
MATT: Yeah, totally.
BRIAN: Okay.
MATT: Yeah, that was totally an option. Galdric is
one of the the, since being assigned by Vax, now
is this perpetual guardian up until the end of his
life of the surrounding Whitestone scenario, and
has been through years of being kept inside the
necklace and through blessings of the Raven Queen,
probably has a much more prolonged life than a
regular wolf would. So Galdric will be around for
quite a while to keep watch on the woods. And if
Vex decided to go call upon him, then yeah, totally.
BRIAN: Wow. Okay. Good to know. If this character
doesn't work out, she can go start her own thing
with Vex.
MATT: (laughter) Exactly. There you go. Perfect!
BRIAN: ForsakenGrundle-- come on.
MATT: Still one of the best!
BRIAN: Just right below my beloved ArseQueef.
"What happened to the new
Lord of the Quadroads/ Crossroads?"
MATT: Oh! The one who was given the wishes by
Grog? Well, like most people that suddenly come
into a lot of money, spent a lot of it. He's well
established, he's living fine. He didn't have a
lot of aspirations with his Wish spells, other
than more money, nice house. He's probably still
holding onto his last Wish. Probably. Yeah. So
with the influx of money-- he's not super high
level, you couldn't wish for an exorbitant amount
of money to the point where he's the richest
person in Vasselheim. But he went from squalor to
a very comfortable, mid to high level nobility and
title and everything with the Wish. He's doing all
right. But I think he's also tortured of what his
final Wish is going to be and probably will never
use it. Probably live the rest of his life unsure
of what it should and then will probably die not
knowing what it is.
BRIAN: Wow. That's crazy. Last question.
MATT: Oh shit!
BRIAN: Minafae wants to know, "What is the
relationship history between J'mon and Gilmore?
They were having a pretty in-depth conversation
after that Thordak fight."
MATT: There's no history between the two. They
hadn't met before that. I think it was more
Gilmore realizing the opportunity to talk to what
is one of the most mysterious, prestigious figures
of his entire upbringing and culture. It was this
opportunity for Gilmore to be like, "Oh, Mr.
President. Let me shake your hand. And I've always
wondered, what are your thoughts on this, and what
are your thoughts on that?" I think it was less
J'mon being interested in Gilmore, although happy
to answer any questions that he has, I think it
was Gilmore more being interested in what they
were and what they had to say and just taking this
one opportunity to shake hands with this majestic
entity that would probably never happen again. So,
that was that. There wasn't a long history, it was
more Gilmore being like, "While you're here, can I
take a selfie?" That kind of feel.
BRIAN: Yeah. That's what our friend Chris did when
he saw Maynard from Tool at LAX.
MATT: Don't blame me. I will say on that part,
there's been a lot of questions about it. Gilmore
is fine. Gilmore is happy. Gilmore has, through
the years, developed his business on a scale that
isn't too fast and too expansive. Has found love,
lost love, found love again. Gilmore is happy. So
take that with you.
BRIAN: That's good to know. Has he ever gone into
a full beautiful delicious beard? I know mine was
trimmed recently.
MATT: Later in life maybe. But I think Gilmore
loves the fabulous jawline too much.
BRIAN: Yeah, he wants to show off the jawline. As
we wind down here and we've been thinking and
talking as much as we can, or as much as we want
to about the new campaign. I want to say as a
Critter and as a fan of the show, I think that
there's a lot of speculation on the internet.
There's a lot of the discussion thread on Reddit
about the new campaign is at some astronomical
number of comments and theory and everything.
Expectations being whatever they are, they're
going to range across the community if you were to
do a survey, which I don't recommend. I want to
say on behalf of anyone who feels this way, that
my only expectation going into this, and I hope
this in some way relieves any of that pressure. My
expectations going into the next campaign is
Thursday night I'm going to turn on Twitch. I'm
gonna be two drinks in already, but I'm gonna turn
on Twitch at 7:00 and I hope to just see a bunch
nerdy ass voice actors playing D&D.
MATT: That's the best I could hope for.
BRIAN: Yeah, and I just think like, I know there's
a lot of pressure. I know there must be, with the
success of the show especially after Talks Machina
came along. Before, I mean it was dead in the
water, let's admit.
MATT: Thank you for that. For elevating us.
BRIAN: Yeah, right. But I just want to say, as a
writer and as a friend, the foundations upon what
makes this show not only successful and people
watch it, but people watch it not because it's
entertaining only because they are a part of it in
many ways. And that creates a lot of healthy
things and it creates a lot of unhealthy
expectations. I just want you guys to feel like--
I've talked to so many Critters and so many
people. Everybody's excited to see you back, much
less in a new campaign and new characters and all
that stuff and a new story line. I just want to
set the precedent that the expectations for those
of us who really know and love the show is just
more nerdy ass voice actors playing D&D. Whatever
that ends up looking like. If somebody dies in
week two just have fun and keep doing what's made
it great.
MATT: Thank you, I'm hoping that. I will say these
past two and a half, three months or so where
we've been off the story, even with the one-shots,
it's been really hard. I've really missed getting
back to the table every week and playing a
consistent story with my friends. So I'm really
excited to get back to that. But also, for
everyone who came through the story of Vox Machina
with us-- That many years of character exploration
and relationship development lead to where we
ended that campaign. Do not expect the new
campaign to start with that level of relationship
development and investment! I mean anyone who's
played D&D, it's gonna be a weird ride for the
first beginning as everyone's figuring out their
characters, figuring out each other's characters,
figuring out the story and the world around them.
BRIAN: Accents.
MATT: That too, oh man. It's going to be fun. So,
all I ask is come to have fun, come to watch us have
fun, fumble around, and figure out where this is
going and I hope you have a good time.
BRIAN: Clear eyes, clear heads. What's the--
anybody watch Friday Night Lights?
OFF-SCREEN: Clear eyes, full hearts, can’t lose.
BRIAN: Thank you, Chiffre. Was that Le Chiffre?
Come over here. You guys, before we go, I have to
say: one year ago today Le Chiffre joined us as a
technical director, executive producer of all shows
on the network. He is one of the cat petting
executives. I don't know if you're gonna be able
to cut to a wide shot. Okay good. Come sit in
between Matt and I.
MATT: Come sit by my shoes, buddy.
BRIAN: Come curl up by the fire. Guys, this is Le
Chiffre, that's what I call him, which is his Bond
villain name. This is Zach, and you work really
hard, and you've been back there switching all the
cameras and doing all that stuff for us tonight.
How have you liked your first year at Geek &
Sundry? Talk into my chest because you don't have
a mic.
ZACH: Let me get real close here. It's been great,
this is a wonderful place to work.
Most of the time.
BRIAN: Still?
(laughter)
ZACH: This is a great place to work, this is
really a family. Everyone says that when talking
about working here, but it is. I couldn't be
happier working anywhere.
BRIAN: Only my family would love to be speaking
into my-- you can go. Thank you. We just wanted to
honor you for your one year of service.
ZACH: Thank you guys, it's been an honor.
MATT: You're amazing man, thank you.
BRIAN: And he's going to quit now. He's going to
quit. My nipple tape came undone.
MATT: It's okay, we got some good Foster sternum
in there.
BRIAN: Guys, to anyone still watching, if you're
still out there. We love you. January 11th, one
week from tonight, holy crap!
MATT: Oh God!
BRIAN: A week from tonight, the new campaign
begins. There will be tears, there will be fears,
there will be...deers? We love you guys, thank you
so much for watching. Thank you to everyone who
submitted questions. Thank you to our crew who
stuck around super late, but early for a Thursday
night really.
MATT: Enjoy it now, while it lasts.
BRIAN: Let's all go to Liam's and TP his house! We
love you guys, we will see you for the new
campaign January 11th. Don't forget to love each
other. And don't worry, it's almost new characters
that are going to die so fast. Stay turnt, my
friends, Happy New Year. I will wear this every
day from now on.
MATT: I think you should, dude.
BRIAN: My pleasure. Goodnight, my friends. Get
Matthew saying tonight, too.
MATT: Goodnight! Goodnight, guys!
BRIAN: Goodnight, guys!
[music]