(cheering)
BRIAN: What's up? We've got, like, a Keyleth's
hair of cables down here to get through. How are
you guys?
(cheering)
BRIAN: I know it's early. Thank you for lining up
and for coming, and man. Where's Manleth at? I saw
on Twitter. Yes! That is awesome. You look great!
That's cool. Come get some free shit after. Oh, I
forgot, there's a note here. There may be some
people under 18 years of age. It also says, your
kids are better off in a hot car than in a room
with Sam Riegel. If there's--
(laughter)
BRIAN: Oh, man. Going to check the lock on my
hotel room. Quick reminder: this panel will air in
its entirety Tuesday night, 7:00PM, in our normal
time slot on Twitch and Alpha, 7:00PM Pacific, so
tune in, listen for your voice not laughing at my
jokes. Lastly, before I bring out my guests for
this panel, we're going to have a Q&amp;A for about
probably second half to three quarters of the
panel. The mic is here. Thank you, Vanna. If you
get up to the mic and you get your question asked,
come up and get a Free Denise pin. Who has the
Free Denise pins? Denise!
(cheering)
BRIAN: Stand up, Denise! Stand up!
BRIAN: Come get a Free Denise pin from Denise if
you get your question asked today. That's awesome.
A lot of people still ask me if she's real or not.
Please don't pinch her to find out if it's true,
but you can say hi. Just be polite. #boundaries.
Without further or-do, I would like to bring out
my guests, the cast of Critical Role.
(cheering)
BRIAN: Travis Willingham!
BRIAN: Marisha Ray!
(cheering)
BRIAN: Taliesin Jaffe!
BRIAN: Ashley Johnson!
(cheering)
BRIAN: Sam Riegel!
BRIAN: Liam O'Brien!
(cheering)
BRIAN: Laura Bailey!
BRIAN: And Matthew Mercer!
(cheering)
LAURA: I feel like this chair is really low.
BRIAN: Do we have any phone books you could sit
on?
MATT: Get a Comic Con booster seat. It'll be
good.
LAURA: Excuse me.
BRIAN: We'll get one requested for next year.
TRAVIS: It is like an elementary school chair.
MARISHA: It is very-- yeah.
TALIESIN: I feel like I need a booster.
MARISHA: Yeah, I feel like I need a desk in front
of me.
MATT: Hello, everyone!
BRIAN: Hello!
(cheering)
MATT: Can I just say how happy I am that this many
people came out to join us on the godawful early
10:30AM on a Saturday at Comic Con? That's
amazing!
(cheering)
BRIAN: Yes. I agree. Well, we're going to talk a
little bit about the recent events of Critical
Role, we're going to talk a little bit about-- we
have a couple announcements, and then we're going
to take your guys' questions. I'll tell you when
to line up in just a minute. But first, Matt, I
think there's a pretty big announcement that we
were saving for San Diego Comic Con, if you want
to fill everybody in on what that might be.
MATT: Glad you guys could be here for this.
BRIAN: Oh, man!
MARISHA: Sorry, I was just hype-manning you. Yeah!
What?
SAM: We're starting with big reveals already?
BRIAN: Yes, Sam! The people have waited!
SAM: Aren't we supposed to wait to build tension
or--
BRIAN: No!
MATT: We're Vox Machina. We've never done anything
the right way.
(laughter)
LAURA: I'm surprised we made it to this room.
MARISHA: Besides, people leave at the end of
panels. We all know this. They want to get to Game
of Thrones.
MATT: I know.
LIAM: I don't want to sit on it any more, Matt.
MATT: All right. So. We've been working on this
for a little bit, but we finally get to announce
that we're making a Critical Role comic book.
(cheering)
MATT: It's going to be a telling of the origin
story of Vox Machina. How they first met, how they
became a group, and then all the adventures you
didn't get to see that were all pre-stream. Super
excited about that! Couple other cool parts of
this are, one, we were trying to find a person who
could write this properly and we could only really
think of a close friend of ours who's a fantastic
writer named Matt Colville. So super excited to
have him onboard and finally be able to announce
his involvement. His "secret project" for months
and months that he hasn't been able to talk about.
You can finally talk about it, Colville, you're
good. He's penning it, he's the actual words. And
then to find the artist for it, one of our big
things about Critical Role is to try to find a way
to lift the community and help get people the
opportunities that they deserve for this.
SAM: I'm doing the art. It's me. I'm drawing it.
Thank you. Yeah, I'm really excited about it. A
lot of splash pages.
BRIAN: If you saw Tary's art, you know what you're
in for. Save your money.
SAM: Sorry, Matt, go on.
MATT: It's okay. We had a bunch of artists thrown
at us, but we wanted to pick somebody from the
community where you've seen their incredible work.
The one we kept coming to is an artist named
Olivia Samson in the Critical Role art community,
and she has agreed to be the artist for the first
six-issue run. We have a couple examples here we
can show you.
SAM: Reveal! Reveal! Reveal!
MATT: Here's some of the early lineart that she's
done. It takes place in Stillben in the
surrounding K'Tawl Swamp.
LAURA: I recognize those half-elves.
MATT: We have a couple pages where we can show the
progression of some of the early art design and
coloring. Over on the next page. There we go. Show
some of the later--
TRAVIS: Eyeballs!
LAURA: Don't give away too much!
MATT: No, this is just a couple pages, don't
worry. Then we go to the next one. One of the
early color layouts there.
SAM: Vax is the one with the bow and arrow,
right?
MATT: Yeah, that's the one. Then we move onto the
actual character art layouts that she had done for
some of the designs.
SAM: It's been a wig on Keyleth the whole time.
Big reveal!
(laughter)
MATT: And then the final example of what the final
color and art's going to look like in the book.
We're excited to give you guys this first look.
MARISHA: We were going to call it Vox Machina
Assemble, but apparently that's already taken. So
still working on the name.
BRIAN: Matt, is there a release date announced, or
a window in which it will be?
MATT: That information is to come soon.
BRIAN: I'm asking on behalf of the audience.
ASHLEY: (British accent) On behalf?
BRIAN: (British accent) On behalf of the audience
who will be tweeting us the same question for the
next six months.
MATT: I understand. We will have that information
official to you as soon as possible. I guarantee
you at least you'll see something in your hands by
the end of the year.
BRIAN: Before the end of the year. That's amazing.
Well, in an orderly fashion, if some of you want
to line up for questions, we're going to start
taking those in a minute. Orderly! Love each
other! Respect, love each other! Oh my god, is
that donuts?
TRAVIS: They're loaded with LSD. Do not eat them!
We'll be tripping balls.
BRIAN: Denise, get this girl a car.
LAURA: This is my favorite panel!
SAM: Hey, we got a Pike over here. Who wants a
donut?
BRIAN: While you guys are lining up--
ASHLEY: Wait, bring them back! Hey, man, come on!
BRIAN: You know better than to do that.
MARISHA: This way. Thank you! And here, Travis.
And bye, box of donuts. I love you!
TRAVIS: Thank you!
BRIAN: You're awesome. What's your name? Kiana?
That's a beautiful name. While you guys are
thinking of your questions, Sam and I were talking
before the show and there's actually a couple
other big reveals that we wanted to announce at
this Comic Con panel. First of all, season three
of Critical Role has already been written and you
guys are going to love it. We were in the hotel
room this morning going over episodes 200 and
whatever and it was, my god!
(laughter)
SAM: One of the big reveals-- Matt is going to
reveal that Victor, beloved character Victor, he
just had lead poisoning. He gets treatment and
he's totally normal now.
BRIAN: What would that sound like, Matt?
MATT: (Victor voice) I apologize if it's been at
all difficult to have made a fool of myself in a
public venue. However, I am happy to sell any sort
of black powder to you if you come by my place.
SAM: Love the new twist.
LAURA: Still very charming.
BRIAN: Sam, some of the upcoming guests for
Critical Role coming up in season three: the
current and former cast of The View, including, it
says here on the card, Star Jones and some of the
Dance Moms.
TRAVIS: Excited about that.
BRIAN: Once you have Jon Heder, you can get
anybody.
TRAVIS: The world opens up.
TALIESIN: It's all downhill from there.
BRIAN: And lastly, the big reveal was that Vex and
Vax are married now.
(groaning)
SAM: To each other. Boom!
BRIAN: Travis has come out as a Redskins fan, it
says here--
(exclamations, cheering)
BRIAN: And finally, it says Liam and Sam are now
legally separated in real life.
SAM: Because he married his sister, so.
BRIAN: (laughs) He did, he did. Okay, let's take
some questions. Go ahead.
LIAM: You said you were cool with anything.
BRIAN: Tell us your name, please.
ANDI: Hi, my name is Andi--
MARISHA and MATT: Hi Andi!
ANDI: Hi! So Brian I took the day off today, so
I'm not working this time.
BRIAN: Oh, was that you at Wondercon?
ANDI: Yeah. My mom's sitting right there.
BRIAN: Aww, hey, mom! That's awesome. She was
working and couldn't come to the last Wondercon
panel, so I told her I would go to your work and
say hi and I got lost on the way. Thank you for
coming. What's your question?
ANDI: My question is for everybody. What's been
your favorite story arc so far?
(thinking noises)
MARISHA: Going through the 500 hours that we've--
TRAVIS: I think it was when Keyleth exploded as a
goldfish.
(cheering, applause)
TRAVIS: Is that an arc, or--
BRIAN: That's not an arc, but that's the right
answer!
MARISHA: There's a lot of math on it online.
TRAVIS: Might be a straight line--
MARISHA: More of a parabola--
LIAM: I believe the lack of arc was the problem.
MARISHA: I thought the joke would break my fall.
TALIESIN: I was sick for cows, so I got to sit at
home with a fever and watch the cow episode and be
like, (loopy voice) This is so nice! I like this!
It's great!
LAURA: I can't believe you weren't there for the
cow episode!
TALIESIN: I know, I've been like retconned into
it--
MARISHA: (gasps) That's right! There was that
fanart!
TALIESIN: None of you ever remember.
MARISHA: There was that fanart where we all come
back as cows and Percy's like, what?
TALIESIN: Everybody was like, remember when we did
that? And I was like, I didn't do that. And you're
like, yeah remember when we all did that, and
like, fuck--
(laughter)
ASHLEY: Did you go?
MARISHA: I mean, there's no--
TRAVIS: It's a free-for-all.
ASHLEY: I really liked the Briarwood arc. I really
did.
SAM: Oh, I have to answer too? The one we're on
right now is pretty cool, because we get to hang
out with gods and stuff-- no spoilers. But yeah,
it's interesting. I have no idea what's going to
happen because I barely know how D&amp;D works.
LIAM: I honestly can't remember anything beyond
meeting Sprigg. I'm just all Sprigg right now.
(cheering)
BRIAN: Where is Darin De Paul? Yes! There he is!
BRIAN: We love you, Darin.
MARISHA: Darin De Paul in the house! Yeah,
Sprigg's amazing.
TRAVIS and LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: (ominous voice) It's a shame he has to die.
LAURA: Oh no! Matthew!
BRIAN: Not cool, dude.
LAURA: I liked the visit to the Nine Hells.
MATT: That was a fun one.
LAURA: Yeah, that was great.
MATT: Only because it took two and a half years
for me to have happen and then it hit and then it
lasted a year which may have been a little long, but
you can't guide the length of the narrative in
D&amp;D. The Conclave arc, definitely, was a fun one.
(cheering)
MATT: Thank you very much.
BRIAN: Who's next?
MARISHA and MATT: (gasping) Lucy!
MARISHA: You're awesome.
LUCY: Thank you. I'm Christina, but call me Lucy.
There's a 5th-level druid spell called
Reincarnation, and if Pike wasn't around and you
guys had to be reincarnated, which means you come
back with your memories but you have a different
body, what would you like your character to be
reincarnated as?
MARISHA: What we would like them to be?
LUCY: Ideally.
LAURA: But we don't get to choose, right?
MATT: Right. But if you could choose, what would
it be?
LAURA: Okay.
LUCY: For Matt, if there's an NPC that you would
prefer to die and be reincarnated--
MATT: Oh. Kima as a wolverine.
(cheering)
MATT: That's more old-school D&amp;D, because back
then you could return them back as an animal,
which was fun.
LAURA: You can come back as animals?
MATT: In older editions, yeah.
LAURA: That's cool. I don't know. I would like to
come back as a half-celestial. Can you do that?
MATT: That is an aasimar, that's the two boys that
you met--
LAURA: Yeah, that's what I want. I want blue hair,
man. Slightly blue skin and blue hair.
MATT: Perfect.
LIAM: Why go off-brand? What are they called,
kuatoa? What are the little bird folk?
MATT: The frog guys?
LIAM: No, the birds-- the little raven or
were-raven--
AUDIENCE: Kenku!
LIAM: Kenku! Thank you!
LAURA: That's perfect.
MARISHA: I'm now envisioning Vax as Bird Person
from Rick and Morty. "Hi. Dagger dagger dagger."
LIAM: There are four more, keep going.
SAM: I'd love to see Scanlan as an ordinary human,
like a George Takei-type, in body and voice.
(George Takei voice) Hello.
MATT: Spoiler, we're replacing Sam with George
Takei.
SAM: (George Takei voice) Oh my.
LIAM: (George Takei voice) Bigby's Hand.
BRIAN: That's really good!
ASHLEY: I feel like Pike would probably come back
as an otter, or something and be like, oh no. That
wasn't the plan. I was thinking like a
regular-sized whatever. I think I could be a
little bit taller, sometimes.
LIAM: The second coming of Vox Machina rises out
of the water right in the middle, an otter pokes
up a head.
ASHLEY: Oh no! I'm even shorter now!
TALIESIN: I love the idea of, completely random,
but the whole notion of coming back as a pixie,
just a teeny tiny, dammit Na'vi level of (nyoom
noises).
ASHLEY: Pixies!
LIAM: Oh, the indignation.
MARISHA: I'd be all about a half-orc Keyleth.
TRAVIS: I'm pretty sure Grog would want to come
back as anything with breasts.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Chicken it is, all right.
TRAVIS: He'd never leave his room.
(laughter)
BRIAN: Yeah, that sounds about right.
MATT: Is that when he retires from adventuring?
(Grog voice) I'm good!
LAURA: I've got it!
MATT: Plenty of things to do!
TRAVIS: Let me know when you get back!
BRIAN: Can't wait to see the Titanstone Pasties.
(laughter)
BRIAN: All right. Did everybody answer?
MARISHA: Aww, that's going to happen now? You put
that into the world!
BRIAN: All right, you artists that I call upon for
the really twisted shit, you know who you are. And
I will say, go! Do it!
MARISHA: Go Tess go! Go, do it!
MATT: In canon, the Titanstone Pasties do have
tassels.
LUCY: I am both sorry and very much not sorry for
starting this.
BRIAN: No, you did good. Make sure to see Denise
after and get a Free Denise pen.
TALIESIN: I would like to rage.
BRIAN: Hey, what's your name?
ELEVATOR GUY: Elevator Guy.
BRIAN: Elevator Guy! That's a terrible name, but
I'm not going to judge your parents.
ELEVATOR GUY: Yeah. Clearly they hate me. My
question is for Ashley Johnson and Love Actually's
Martin Freeman.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: You broke Laura!
BRIAN: Do the impression! Do the impression,
Liam!
LIAM: Bilbo Baggins.
ELEVATOR GUY: So in Sam and Liam's podcast, Liam,
you mentioned that you went to NYU, and, well, I'm
going in the fall for the first time, and Ashley,
you live in New York a lot of the time, so I was
wondering if you guys had any tips for a
first-time New Yorker.
LIAM: Tips for a first-time New Yorker?
BRIAN: Get used to the smell of pee.
ASHLEY: Walk everywhere. Walk as much as you can.
Obviously go to Central Park.
LIAM: Get a can of mace.
(laughter)
SAM: Don't make eye contact with anyone.
ASHLEY: Wait, when are you going?
ELEVATOR GUY: August 25.
ASHLEY: Okay, so if you go into Central Park
almost when it's dark, which I know sounds a
little sketchy, there are so many fireflies, so
that would be really cool.
BRIAN: She's going to steal your wallet, dude.
(laughter)
BRIAN: This is-- no. Two seconds of googling,
you'll see, there are no fireflies.
TRAVIS: Behind the boathouse. Come alone.
TALIESIN: There's a big mermaid festival on Coney
Island I think that's coming up. Super cool.
ASHLEY: Yeah, it might be around that time? Yeah.
It's at Coney Island.
MARISHA: Is Bryant Park still doing the summer
movie festivals where you can do free movies? New
York's amazing.
SAM: When we were in New York last, all of us, we
went to Chelsea Piers, and we all did a golf
driving range together, and we were terrible.
BRIAN: I have a lot of videos of that. I should
post those. I have videos of each one of you guys
doing golf swings in slow-motion, and some of them
are painful.
(laughter)
LIAM: You can see most shows on Broadway for free
by volunteering to usher.
SAM: Or by sneaking in.
MARISHA: Or by being a student. Flash that student
ID card everywhere.
ASHLEY: Yeah. And go to Di Fara Pizza in Brooklyn
for a Grandma Slice.
TRAVIS: You're writing all this down, right?
BRIAN: Yeah, watch Tuesday night with a notepad.
SAM: The next three questions of mine are, what's
there to do in Cincinnati? What part of West
Hollywood should I live in?
ELEVATOR GUY: All right. Thank you very much.
BRIAN: Thank you, man, that was great.
MATT: That's our next book release, is Vox
Machina's guide to travel.
LAURA: Oh my god, that would be great.
LIAM: Tyriok's guide?
MICHELLE: Hello.
BRIAN: Hello. What's your name?
MICHELLE: I'm Michelle.
LAURA and MARISHA: Hi, Michelle.
MICHELLE: Hi. So my question is, if you have to do
a trial by combat, and can only pick one other
ally, and that can include guest characters, who
would you summon and why?
MARISHA: Like, across all universes or in ours?
SAM: Ours. Let's limit it a little.
(laughter)
BRIAN: Yeah, it's an hour panel.
LAURA: Wait, I need a question clarification. Is
this all of us as Vox Machina doing a trial by
combat and then summoning one ally, or each
individually?
MICHELLE: Each individually.
TRAVIS: Can we pick Pelor, like, the Dawnfather?
TALIESIN: Player character, motherfucker, player
character.
SAM: I'm going to pick the character of Noelle
Stevenson as Tova. Oh, wait, she's right over
there in the audience!
BRIAN: Oh, Noelle Stevenson is here, too! Wow.
This is an all-star panel.
AUDIENCE: If she's still alive!
SAM: Yeah, she's totally dead. Totally dead.
LIAM: You hush your mouth!
(laughter)
MARISHA: I think, based on our last Battle Royale,
and me and you going toe-to-toe, it'd be me and
you to the end, man.
TRAVIS: Word.
MARISHA: We'd be terrible to take on. We'd never
die.
TRAVIS: That's true. I'd pick the werewolf,
because as soon as he started to die, I'd be like,
bite me, dude. Just bite me.
LIAM: I mean, everybody should pick Keyleth. She's
the most powerful character in the group.
LAURA: But only with allies that we've traveled
with. Not Vox Machina.
LIAM: Not Vox Machina? Keyleth would be a great
ally. No. Come back to me, then.
LAURA: Allura.
LIAM: Do they have to be a friend? Could they have
been an enemy?
LAURA: But is it a trial by fisticuffs?
MARISHA: Man, we are way overcomplicating this. We
are overthinking this way too much.
LAURA: I just need to know.
MARISHA: People wonder why Vox Machina does this.
We're just like this.
LIAM: I mean, part of me would like to run with
Delilah Briarwood. Yeah.
LAURA: I feel like Vex is getting close to that
anyways, so.
TALIESIN: Wow.
ASHLEY: I feel like I'd have to go with my
tried-and-true. My bestie, Grog. I do actually
feel like we would be a really good combo, though.
Because you're the brains and I'm the brawn.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: You just keep healing me, we'll just keep
smashing them? Yeah. Like Overwatch tag-team.
MATT: Awesome, thank you so much.
MARISHA: This makes me want an Injustice Critical
Role DLC.
TALIESIN: We've got like a third of it already.
LAURA: That would be awesome.
BRIAN: Hey, what's your name?
BRETT: My name is Brett.
BRIAN: You can touch it, it's not electrical.
Electrocuted. That'd be a good prank, though.
(laughter)
BRETT: So my question is, if you could replace
your player character with any NPC, which one
would you play?
SAM: Similar, but different question.
ASHLEY: Victor. Yeah, Victor.
TALIESIN: I would go Gilmore super-fast. So much
fun. (Gilmore voice) I just love doing that voice
all the time. Hello.
SAM: I would go with Jarett, because he's so
dreamy and hunky.
LAURA: He is so dreamy.
SAM: (Jarett voice) Hello.
LIAM: The one that got away? I'd go Clarota.
(cheering)
MARISHA: Can I be Matt's illusory beholder from
the last episode?
(laughter)
MARISHA: Kitten's worth of hit points.
LIAM: (illusory beholder voice) Hah! I used to do
Broadway!
(laughter)
MARISHA: Next question.
BRIAN: All right, that's good, thank you. What's
your name?
JUSTIN: Justin.
ALL: Hi, Justin.
JUSTIN: Hi. So my home D&amp;D group also happens to
include a lot of stage and improv actors from the
Boston area, and so I take a lot of inspiration
from what you guys do, and I'm wondering, for any
of you, the whole approach or the headspace you're
in to do Critical Role, does it have any
relationship to what you would do or how you would
approach a stage role or an improv, scripted role?
Is there a relation, or is it totally different?
LIAM: Oh, yeah. Some of us were talking in the
green room before coming out here right before the
show started. I spent years in the theater, and
it's been ten years since my last one, and three
years ago, I was like, "Man, I'm getting really
itchy, I've got to get back on stage." And that's
gone. This scratches that itch so much. And we're
living in a role for five years? Is it five
years?
MARISHA: Yeah, in a weird way, it feels like the
longest longform improv.
LAURA: I feel like the preparation for it can be
very similar. I feel like we slid our way into our
backstories and everything like that. We had loose
ideas of what it was before we started playing a
lot, but when you're starting a new role in a
theater show-- what am I talking about? Then yeah,
you would do the same thing, you would establish
all of those ties in your mind, and you would
figure out what is their favorite music to listen
to, and what kind of food do they like, and all
that kind of stuff, and it's the same stuff you do
with this.
MARISHA: Yeah, part of the reason we did the
playlists is because we were all already doing
them. And then we thought, awesome, we'll publish
them out. And the playlists-- I think it's
actually a good tip for people trying to find
their character who might be new to it, is build a
playlist for your character. It informs a lot, and
it gets you in the mood right before you go.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Yeah, it's good for the drive over, you
really get the headspace.
BRIAN: Let the bodies hit the lava. Is that on
your playlist?
MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Those are actually all on my playlist.
These are the songs.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Just rage and death and destruction.
LAURA: What is it, C is for Cookie? That was one
year?
MARISHA: Yes, cute!
TRAVIS: Always learning.
(laughter)
MATT: Awesome, thank you so much.
BRIAN: Thank you very much. Hey, what's your
name?
DAVID: Hi, I'm David, hi, hello. My question is
for world-famous podcasters Sam Riegel and Liam
O'Brien.
SAM: Sure, yeah.
DAVID: Can we expect another episode of All Work
No Play within the next three years?
TRAVIS: Yeah, can we?! Please?! I want it!
BRIAN: Three years, you can make that happen.
LIAM: Let's get married all over again.
SAM: The marriage episode? Yeah. Yeah, for sure.
For sure. We do a couple podcast episodes a year.
We're averaging about two a year these days.
LIAM: I mean, we talk about doing it like 12 times
a year. So that's got to count for something.
SAM: Here's the status: we wanted to pitch our
podcast to Geek and Sundry to do on a regular
basis, but we can't even find a time to go pitch
it.
(laughter)
MARISHA: That's not true. I told you a bajillion
times we would just do it.
SAM: Oh, yeah?
MARISHA: I've told you a bajillion times we would
do it.
SAM: You won't even invite me on Signal Boost.
BRIAN: Oh, that is-- there is video evidence that
that's bullshit.
MARISHA: Gaslighter!
LIAM: Sam Riegel will be dead in under an hour.
SAM: No more All Work No Play. Yeah, we have one
planned, because we're going to do a live episode
soon, in a couple weeks, and then maybe we'll do
it where we're going to go into somebody's hot tub
to record an episode.
LIAM: Yeah, we've been threatening to return to
the hot tub.
SAM: Oh, do you have a hot tub?
LAURA: We have a hot tub.
SAM: Well, you were already a guest on the show.
LAURA: So?
SAM: Okay, can we go in your hot tub and bring a
stranger to interview?
(laughter)
LAURA: Sure.
SAM: You can hold the boom mic.
(laughter)
SAM: Thanks for the question.
BRIAN: What's your name?
ALL: Hi.
GABBY: Hello. So I'm Gabby. Real quick, thank you,
because last year at Comic Con, when I asked you a
question saying I couldn't find a group, I
immediately found my current Dungeon Master, and
we play on roll20 whenever we can. So thank you
for that.
(cheering)
GABBY: And my question is, due to everything that
has been going on with your characters, everything
that's been going on, I was wondering what your
characters are grateful for?
MATT: What are your characters grateful for?
TRAVIS: (Grog voice) I'm grateful for, um. Ale.
And my buddy Pike. And my friends. Also, ale.
MARISHA: Currently--
LIAM: Yeah, Kiki.
LAURA: Just tears.
MARISHA: Keyleth is-- she hasn't said it out loud
in-game yet, but she will, but she's thankful for
being taught how to love by a certain rogue.
ALL: Aww.
SAM: Well, I wouldn't call myself a rogue.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Definitely grateful for family at the
moment, is Percy's bag right now. He's feeling
good, all things considered.
ASHLEY: Yeah, family. The friendship that we
all... have.
(laughter)
SAM: Your family's weird, though.
ASHLEY: I know! That's why I appreciate the
friends that you've made into your family, because
the Trickfoots, as we know, are so terrible. And
also, I think being able to see Sarenrae, the
Everlight, in person, I think that's opened up
something else in Pike, and what else?
BRIAN: Technically via Skype.
ASHLEY: Via Skype, but still.
SAM: I think Scanlan values being accepted back
into the group. That's about it. And Kaylie.
LIAM: I mean, I've got to go with the boots,
right? I've got to go with the boots. I got my
boots back. Our long national nightmare is finally
over.
BRIAN: Oh, boy.
LAURA: I was never going to keep them! Until he's
dead, and then they're mine.
LIAM: All of us are grateful for family, he's
obviously grateful for his twin, he's grateful for
love. You know, life is short.
SAM: We're all dying every day.
LIAM: But mainly the boots.
LAURA: Grateful for Percy and for Whitestone and
for having a place she can call home. I know. And
for, you know--
SAM: I'm 'gramming it.
LAURA: For Vax being back. And even for, you know,
she's grateful for the time that they have. Yeah,
yeah, yeah.
MATT: I can't answer in 500 voices at once.
BRIAN: Well, that's why we're here. Do it.
MATT: It'd be very Lovecraftian if I did that all
of a sudden, you heard 500 voices come out. All of
your minds shatter together as one.
BRIAN: No one would be surprised. All right, all
right. Who's next? Thank you, that was a great
question.
TRAVIS and BRIAN: I like your ears.
BRIAN: Travis likes them, too. Hey, what's your
name?
TREVOR: My name's Trevor. First, I want to thank
you all for the hours of entertainment and the
inspiration. You guys are awesome. My question is,
the playlists are awesome. Will we ever see guest
playlists?
MARISHA: Ooh. Hey, y'all want to do some guest
playlists? Yeah, sure.
BRIAN: Okay, we got some thumbs up, all right.
TALIESIN: Legitimately hadn't thought of that.
LIAM: Tova slow-jazz.
TALIESIN: There is a song, I Want a New Duck.
NOELLE: (offscreen) --something by "Bear" Naked
Ladies.
SAM: "Bear"naked Ladies. Nice. (sings) It's
been--
LAURA: Oh, no. I see who this is.
BRIAN: Oh, hey, what's up? What's up? Oh, shit!
(laughter)
SAM: He just ran 480 feet.
LAURA: He was gone so fast!
BRIAN: Turns out you can go that many feet that
fast.
SAM: He ran 480 feet and threw four daggers.
(laughter)
SAM: Okay, what you got?
LAURA: What you got for us, Ray?
KRISTINA: Hi. So my name's Kristina.
MATT: Hi, Kristina.
KRISTINA: So you're currently dealing with an arc
of gods and those ascending to godhood. Say
somehow that happens to your Vox Machina
characters. What would they be the guardians of
the domains of, essentially? What would they be
the gods of?
TRAVIS: (cackles)
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Carnal pleasure.
TRAVIS: And all will worship me! So great.
MARISHA: I want to see Bacchus Grog now, only
wearing a grape leaf.
BRIAN: That evil laugh you heard is what happens
when Travis gets a softball question.
(laughter)
MARISHA: I mean, I'm Voice of the Tempest, so
probably some weather.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Curse your name every time it rains.
MARISHA: Basically turn into Storm. Everyone's
least favorite X-Man. No, that's arranged for
Dazzler, probably, right?
TALIESIN: You wound me. No, I think he would
definitely-- there's a history of machinist gods,
the gods of order and making things happen the way
they're supposed to, so he would definitely go
that direction.
ASHLEY: (unenthused) I mean, Pike would probably
be the god of love and kindness and feelings.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: Blah-blah-blah.
SAM: If there's a god of aerated wine, then I'd be
that. God of grapes and aerated wine.
LIAM: The temple's full of upside-down fountains.
(laughter)
LIAM: I'm gunning for your job, girl.
LAURA: What, you'd be the raven--
MATT: Oh, it's on now.
ASHLEY: Duke it out, right now.
LAURA: Right now! Arm wrestle.
LIAM: After the panel.
LAURA: I don't know. The goddess of commerce,
or--
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Commerce?
LAURA: All things sparkly?
BRIAN: The god of commerce? Sounds badass. I
wouldn't mess with the god of commerce.
SAM: The small business association god?
LAURA: Pretty much. Her temple would be where you
drop off your gold at, you know what I mean?
BRIAN: She'd cut you with a deposit slip.
MATT: The god of naps and free time.
BRIAN: Amen. Great question. Great outfit.
LIAM: We do deal in fantasy, Matt.
BRIAN: Hey, what's your name? Nice shirt!
MICHAEL: Thank you. My name's Michael, I saw you
at the Magic Castle.
MATT: Good to see you again.
MICHAEL: So my question is, I know you have a live
show coming up at Gen Con. I was wondering if you
guys have any plans to do a live show on the West
Coast?
(cheering)
SAM: Big reveal. No.
(laughter)
LAURA: That's a good question, though.
MATT: We're, you know, shows are a big
undertaking, and trying to get the logistics
worked out are always difficult, both within
locations and scheduling everything. We'd
definitely like to do more live shows, so if we
manage to put something together for that in the
future, we will be happy to announce it and
eagerly throw it in your face.
SAM: I've pushed for us to rent ourselves out,
like for bar mitzvahs and quinceaneras and stuff.
I feel like we could go, play a short game, and
then Hava Nagila. I don't know. Something.
LIAM: Life is short, kids. Happy Sweet 16.
BRIAN: Yeah, we'll keep you posted. We'll keep you
posted. By the way, Gil the Blogsmith over here,
ladies and gentlemen, in the green. Stand up, Gil,
let people give you some love.
TRAVIS: Stand up, Gil, Jesus!
BRIAN: Stand up, for god's sake! There we go. Look
at that beautiful, beautiful man. Okay, who's up
next?
SAM: There's more reveals, Brian.
BRIAN: Oh, there are. Hold on one sec, we have
another big-- we'll leak a couple more out as we
go here.
SAM: Pike's next storyline involves her covered in
tattoos and the rest of the team deciphering their
meaning.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: (grunts)
BRIAN: Laura has also decided to give away all of
her possessions and only own dice.
LAURA: I could probably build a house from them,
so. It's fine.
BRIAN: Okay, who's next?
VAUGHAN: Hi, my name is Vaughan. This question is
for Matt, but I'd like the rest to answer,
including Brian "Cabbage" Foster.
BRIAN: That's a good one. Format it however you
want.
VAUGHAN: What is your favorite 16-bit JRPG?
MATT: Ooh.
TRAVIS: 16-bit?
MATT: That's a neck-and-neck battle between Final
Fantasy VI and Chrono Trigger.
(cheering)
MATT: With, like, a little bit of Earthbound
creeping up there. But I'm probably going to have
to say Final Fantasy VI to me. But it's a tough
one. Just barely because the story goes a little
bit darker and intense in the third act. Not that
Lobos wasn't intense.
LAURA: It has to be 16-bit?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I think you're forgetting about the
amazing 16-bit JRPG Jurassic Park. I love that
one, on the Gameboy?
MARISHA: The ones in arcades where you got in it?
That was a great game.
LAURA: I was a PC gamer during that time, and so I
was King's Quest and Quest for Glory, so.
LIAM: Yeah, I have a big gap in my gaming history.
I had an Atari, and a Commodore 64, and then
nothing until Playstation, so I skipped the whole
16-bit era. I really liked Dungeons and Dragons:
Pool of Radiance on my Commodore 64. Yeah.
Bloop-bloop-bloop.
TALIESIN: Pass?
SAM: Pass.
TALIESIN: I was a Phantasy Star 2 kid. That was
really my jam. That was a weird, weird game, and
the sci-fi vibe was--
MARISHA: Was Secret of Mana 16-bit, or was that
8-bit?
MATT: Yeah, it was 16-bit.
MARISHA: Secret of Mana. I loved that game. Yeah.
Light applause, light applause.
BRIAN: Travis? Oh. Terranigma? Or Evo? Anybody
play Evo? Search for Evolve? Search to Evolve?
Search of Evolve?
LAURA: (sings) Thank you for your question.
MATT: You got a Laura song.
MARISHA: Manleth!
(cheering)
BRIAN: What's your real name?
MILES: Hi, my name is Miles.
LIAM: I am intrigued.
(laughter)
MILES: So my question was for the entire panel.
Critical Role has kind of inspired the other RPG
shows on the Geek &amp; Sundry format, so I was
wondering how Vox Machina would react if they were
to plane shift to Vulcana, for instance. From
Titansgrave.
LAURA: Well.
TRAVIS: Electricity would be really interesting.
MARISHA: I think Keyleth would be like, "I knew
it!"
TALIESIN: I'm so delighted by this entire notion
that I can't think straight. Oh my god, D&amp;D
crossovers, what a crazy idea.
MARISHA: Can we jump into Shield of Tomorrow and
do a Star Trek crossover?
TALIESIN: I would love to do a Star Trek
crossover. I've got to admit.
MARISHA: I'm into that.
MATT: Oh my god, Vox Machina in Star Trek would be
so horrible.
(laughter)
BRIAN: Look at all the Shield of Tomorrow people
going, bring it on.
SAM: Yeah, Scanlan would spend a lot of time in
the holodeck.
(laughter)
LIAM: (knocks) What are you doing in there?
SAM: One more minute!
LAURA: I've always wondered about the holodeck in
that way, because--
LIAM: Just because they don't put it in the
episodes doesn't mean it doesn't happen.
LAURA: It has to happen, right? You have an entire
crew of people that are like, (hums).
SAM: That room must be so nasty.
LAURA: I know! Maybe they have a secondary
holodeck, you know what I mean?
MATT: I'm not going to Dungeon Master your
holodeck experiences, guys. I'm sorry. I got close
enough with an audiobook once, and that was weird
in its own right.
LIAM: I'd like to see Vox Machina skinned into
cyberpunk, I think.
LAURA: That's actually Valkana!
LIAM: It's more Blade Runner-y, a little bit.
Whatever.
LAURA: I think they would all get along with
Lemley so well.
MATT: That was an awesome question.
BRIAN: Thank you so much, Manleth.
MATT: Vax, if you are that intrigued, Alter Self,
she can use at will.
(laughter)
LIAM: I'm aware.
MARISHA: Once again... never mind.
LIAM: Just because Vax has never pooped in an
episode of Critical Role and you haven't seen it,
doesn't mean it doesn't happen.
LAURA: Vex doesn't poop. I'm just putting that out
there. She never poops. Ever.
MATT: #Vaxdoesntpoop.
LIAM: Not anymore.
LAURA: Oh! Do you eat?
LIAM: I don't know.
LAURA: Oh no! How are you going to have a Heroes'
Feast?
LIAM: We'll find out.
MATT: Next question.
BRIAN: Yeah, we've got to move on or we're going
to get spoilery.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: So the rest did enough questions,
so super nerdy inquiry to Matt about old school
D&amp;D. Since you've introduced the current arc and
you start going to the upper planes of the gods,
pretty much all I can think about is the final
AD&amp;D book: Die, Vecna, Die. It's an essential
story about him, and I'm wondering-- I've been
going through the campaign book and looking at
your pantheon and so forth, and have you
considered the stuff from those old stories in
regards to the Serpent and Lady of Pain and Sigil
and the stuff above the gods, if you have that
figured out and those cosmology and whether it
will come out either in this campaign or
eventually. I assume they fight Tharizdun in the
next campaign.
MATT: Right. I take a lot of inspiration from
elements of that Vecna story, because Vecna's such
an intrinsic villain to D&amp;D lore. To change him
too much would be upsetting to me. And a lot of
you guys, as well. There is a lot of expectation
there. So I want to make him unique to this
campaign in this world, because he's definitely
not the exact same character. There are elements
of that that are classic lore that are pulled into
this that may be revealed in the future.
Especially now that we're releasing campaign
guides and this has become a world now that we can
bring to you guys to play in, I have to be careful
to not pull in too much of the very licensed D&amp;D
lore. Otherwise, we would have to reskin
everything and you all are like, "oh wait, which
"one's which? Oh no." I'm trying to keep that to a
minimum. But if you know a lot about Vecna--
LAURA: Then tell us.
MATT: Then don't tell them anything.
LAURA: Tell us his weaknesses.
MATT: Don't listen to her...
LIAM: This is the perfect time to segue into our
next Comic-Con announcement though, which is in
season three, we are converting to first edition
D&amp;D.
MATT: The characters will die before you get
artwork done.
BRIAN: Okay. Next question. Thank you very much.
Hey, what's your name?
SEAN: Hi. My name is Sean.
MATT, MARISHA and LAURA: Hi, Sean!
SEAN: Hi. I actually saw Matt first in front of me
for the ThunderCats panel in this room.
MATT: Yeah! Oh, way back then! Oh man.
SEAN: My question is actually related to that. How
much Critical Role's grown over the years. I'm
sure none of you expected it to grow to this type
of audience, and I still remember the days when
you were reading all the donations, even on
stream. Do any of you miss anything from those
early days when it was still such a small show?
LIAM: I liked eating fried chicken on set.
LAURA: That was great.
MARISHA: I feel like we can't go through all the
fanart-- we do, but after the after-show reactions
and responses, we can't really go through it as
much anymore.
TALIESIN: It was much easier. We're getting to a
point we're like-- whoa.
TRAVIS: Excuse me.
TALIESIN: I miss when the correspondence was more
manageable as opposed to this is something I have
to set aside time every day to do it. But yeah.
That's the one thing I miss. Oh, five minutes a
week. I can deal with this.
BRIAN: Does anyone miss shooting in a
three-year-old child's bedroom?
LAURA: It was pretty. I liked it.
BRIAN: Me, too. I was just wondering.
LIAM: The race car bed was just out of camera. I
mean, I love what we're doing now, but I also
liked-- we were still dumb idiots at the beginning
of the show. We didn't have the weight of the
world on our shoulders, really, so it was nice
being carefree.
MATT: Sorry, what am I supposed to do at level
16?
LIAM: Exactly what you're doing!
MATT: Some clown scared a family! Things get a
little heavy in the later levels, but we'll get
back to the carefree feeling probably in the next
campaign.
LAURA: When we're all dead.
(laughter)
BRIAN: Great question.
MATT: For me, I guess what I miss a little bit is
the anonymity to go into the Dealers' Hall. But
other than that, I wouldn't change anything. This
is amazing. This is amazing.
BRIAN: Put on Ivan's demogorgon outfit and wander
the floor and nobody will know it's you!
LAURA: You could put on a mask.
MATT: Well, now I can't do that costume. Thanks,
Brian.
BRIAN: I might have not thought that through all
the way, he said to a microphone. Thank you for
the question, though. You're awesome. You're
great. Hey, what's up? All right, we're going to
have to lightning-round this because we've got
about seven minutes left, so go ahead.
MC: All right. Hi, my name's MC. Really quick.
What has surprised you about all of your guys'
character developments, and I guess for Matt, the
world developments, that have come up over the
past few years?
MATT: For me? Surprised that people want to play
there and everything's been reactionary. Creating
the campaign guide was reactionary. That wasn't
our idea. Green Ronin came to us; they were like,
"You want to do a campaign guide?" Okay. So we're
amazed that people have interest in them.
LAURA: Um...
SAM: Skip her!
LAURA: No! Oh, it's lightning round. Shit. Shoot.
No, I'm surprised that she is willing to take
responsibility for more than just herself and her
brother and her bear.
LIAM: Never thought that Vax would get dark as he
has. It ties into the last question. I thought, we
were like a couple of Han Solo characters for our
entire home campaign, at the beginning of the
campaign and would never have predicted that it
would be so freaking serious. Ever.
SAM: I was surprised that Taryon lasted longer
than two episodes. And... that's it.
ASHLEY: I think most recently, I'm surprised I
didn't realise Pike would ever be able to have
wings. That's pretty good.
TALIESIN: I was expecting Percy to end a terrible
mess, and it somehow has not happened. He's
actually kind of a functional human being, which
was not the plan, ever.
MARISHA: I think it's that the development's never
over; the world is always affecting the way you
go. Keyleth fell from pretty high and got dark.
Literally smeared on broken rocks. That was
shocking. I'll pick that.
LIAM: That was not in your vision.
MARISHA: No!
LIAM: This one's for Keyleth! (thuds)
TRAVIS: I was surprised Grog became the smartest
member of the group.
(cheering)
TRAVIS: That happened, right?
BRIAN: Thank you. Who's up next?
MIKELYN: Hi guys! My name is Mikelyn. I was
wondering, Matt, what scenario were you most proud
of throwing at the group, or what is your favorite
kind of scenario to throw at them?
MATT: Timed scenarios. D&amp;D is a lot of planning
and arguing and trying to figure things out, and
there's game time versus planning time, and I love
a scenario where I can tell the players, "well,
"you have this much time to do both. Go." It ups
the intensity, so I love me my hourglasses,
definitely.
LIAM: Stupid rakshasa.
MIKELYN: Thank you.
MATT: Thank you!
BRIAN: Next question. What's your name?
ALEX: Hi, I'm Alex. Thank you Ashley for Gortys,
because she's the most adorable character ever.
LAURA: She's pretty great.
ALEX: Thank you Laura for Lucina, because she is
the best. And Matt, what time is it?
MARISHA: Man! Almost got through a panel.
MATT: (McCree voice) It's about 34 minutes till
it's high noon.
(cheering)
ALEX: Thank you.
LIAM: Panels, Mexican restaurants, the dentist's
office...
BRIAN: Anywhere.
MATT: I am so conscious of what time it is at
all times now.
(laughter)
BRIAN: All right. Go ahead, man. What's your
name?
ALEX: My name is Alex. Really quickly, couple
years ago, I attended my first panel with you
guys. I had no direction; now I'm auditioning for
things, all because of the advice and inspiration
you guys have given.
(applause)
ALEX: As a fellow DM, Matt, if you're able to tell
us, for the next campaign, it's going to be
chronologically after this current timeline or is
it going to be before?
MATT: Yeah, I've mentioned a little bit, I think.
But the next campaign I'm planning to be
roughly 20 or so years beyond the end of this
campaign. And it's going to be in a different
continent, and there's a possibility, depending on
which characters and NPCs survive this final arc,
they'll be existing somewhere in the world.
ASHLEY: What?!
LAURA: So we could visit ourselves if we live?!
(yells) Oh man! That's so cool!
SAM: Reveal!
LIAM: I remember your great-great-grandfather,
Trunket. Oh.
LAURA: Oh! Trinket babies! Oh no, Tova, you have
to come back!
(laughter)
BRIAN: Oh my god. What a sentence!
MATT: Next question.
BRIAN: Okay, we've got time for one more. It's up
to you.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: One more? So for all the couples
on the stage, how do you guys deal with each other
after the game? You guys have the car rides
home. How do you deal with some of those more
intense moments that somebody gets something;
Matt, you may have killed a character or whatever.
I can't get through a game of Monopoly with my
wife without going to bed angry. How do you guys
deal with it?
MARISHA: I push him out the window at the Taco
Bell.
MATT: Yeah. Seriously, calm down Taco Bells,
definitely after an intense session. Like driving,
scratch the knee. You want Taco Bell? (mopey
voice) Yes. Okay.
TRAVIS: That's insane because we live ten, 15
minutes from you guys and we do the same shit.
MARISHA: Yeah!
TRAVIS: We have our own Taco Bell. I'm like, "why
did you take my Deck of Many Things, Laura?!"
MARISHA: I feel like for us, at the end of the
game, for Matt, he's like, (sighs) "Done for the
"week!" And I'm just getting revved up.
MATT: Why did you ever get the thought it was me
going, "Oh. Done for the week." It's me going,
"I'm sorry. It's what the story did."
MARISHA: I'm just saying, your stress seems to
happen before the game and mine happens after. So
the whole time, I'm like, "I mean, I don't know.
What's the Raven Queen's deal? Is she to be
"trusted? I don't know." And he's like--
TRAVIS: You don't know.
MARISHA: I'm just talking to a brick wall.
MATT: You want to talk about people that prod,
though; Travis, every given moment turns to me and
goes, "So what's this item do?" You don't know.
And he'll go, "Ugh!"
TRAVIS: He's going to fold one of these times.
BRIAN: Oh wow. Okay, we got to end there, guys.
I'm so sorry. Thank you for your questions. Thank
you guys for waiting. Thank you for lining up and
asking questions. We've got to run. I would like
to thank my guests: a bunch of nerdy-ass voice
actors!
(cheering)
BRIAN: We'll see you guys. Thank you so much!
Thank you!