MATT: Hello everyone, and welcome to tonight's
episode of Critical Role, where a bunch of us
nerdy-ass voice actors sit around and play
Dungeons & Dragons.
LIAM: It's been a while! So long since Matthew
Mercer ran Dungeons & Dragons!
MATT: It's been a nice break.
TRAVIS: That chair has been violated by more than
a few people.
MATT: I can smell it.
TRAVIS: They told me to wear pants.
MATT: The very onion musk you got from that end of
the table. I miss it; I do! I'm excited for the
new campaign and the new year. I've been working
really hard on that world. I hope you guys are
excited, too. We'll have information about that
first game soon. But tonight, we're excited
because we get to have the fantastic Jennifer Hale
join us!
JENNIFER: I am honored and terrified. I am a
virgin.
TRAVIS: A quote, right above your head, "Honored
and terrified."
JENNIFER: Call me HT.
MATT: There you go. Hashtag. We're happy to have
you. Excited for you to play. Once again, don't
feel stressed. Ask questions if you need them.
People are here to help you. You'll be good.
LAURA: Be stressed. Very, very stressed.
MATT: Laura, we talked about this. Tonight, on top
of that, we have a very special one-shot. The
fantastic folks at Blizzard have come together and
asked us to do a Hearthstone one-shot in
celebration of the upcoming expansion, Kobolds &
Catacombs. Super excited about that. For those who
aren't aware of it, it's an upcoming expansion for
the card game, Hearthstone, that brings the
classic fantasy dungeon crawl element to the
awesome, existing card game. It incorporates a
bunch of cool, mysterious magical items, nine new
legendary weapons, some of which you'll recognize
if you've played World of Warcraft in the recent
expansions. There's unidentified magical items
that you can find in the game, so this has
definitely more of a D&D, classic-dungeon-crawl
feel. There's spell stones you have to power as
you go through. It's got a lot of really cool new
mechanics that add to the game. They have a
single-player dungeon run mode now, where you're
actually doing a dungeon delve with your Hearthstone
deck, playing through a storyline, making choices.
It brings a whole new kind of tabletop element to
the game. I've seen a bunch of it. They even had
me come and sing in the trailer, so I've been tied
to this--
LAURA: It was so fabulous, Matt!
MATT: Possibly other elements of the expansion.
But it's been really fun and we're excited for you
guys to check it out. For those who've been
playing the game, there's a new mechanic called
recruit, which allows you to recruit members to
your party, basically minions from your deck, to
help you out. So there's a whole bunch of new
mechanics that work out for the new dungeon-run
mode and other elements of the game, so definitely
look forward to checking that out. It is coming
out December 7th, so right around the corner. Keep
an eye out for that. Go to bit.ly/crhearth to stay
up to date and learn more. Also, to celebrate the
release of Hearthstone, the people at Blizzard
have created a custom kobold escape room, based on
one of the lairs in the world. They'll be
live-streaming players and personalities from the
Hearthstone community going through that escape
room on December 5th, at 4:30pm Pacific time, at
twitch.tv/playhearthstone, or
youtube.com/hearthstone. Check it out to get to
vote on items to try and make their way through
it. It's actually a community-interactive event.
Looks to be pretty cool, so definitely go check
that out on December 5th. And then the expansion
on December 7th!
TALIESIN: This is why I feel bad in not reading
the announcements, now. That sounds like fun!
LAURA: It's all a surprise for us. Oh, I have an
announcement! Wait, but I don't think I have it
with me!
TALIESIN: Wait, is it this?
LAURA: It is that! Okay. I'm ready.
MATT: All right, go for it.
LAURA: Okay, it's my turn? Da da-da da! We have
new merch in the store now! We've been waiting on
these ones for so long, and they're finally here!
It's so beautiful. This is the artwork that's on
my save screen on my phone. It's been that way for
a long-- me and Ashley both. We're in love with
this art. It's got pages so you can take all your
personal D&D notes in here. That's why we did it.
And it goes with our pencil set, so you can have,
you know. You can have one, Jen, if you want!
TALIESIN: You can make your own art book.
LAURA: So yeah, go check it out! It's in the store
now!
MATT: Awesome. Thank you, Laura. Also, cool note.
The third issue of Critical Role - Vox Machina:
Origins comic is available. It's getting more and
more intense as each issue goes along. Check it
out if you haven't had a chance. It's on
Comixology, digital.darkhorse.com, and wherever
else you can find digital comics online. It's
pretty radical. Me and Liam, who have read the
scripts and given notes on the scripts for future
issues, this is getting better and better as it
goes.
TRAVIS: Kings of the kingdom! We don't even know,
but you do!
LIAM: Three just came out. I just read five, and
it is so baller. Oh my god.
MATT: Be patient with the rest of them, Taliesin.
LIAM: Also, to rewind, that beautiful art on that
book is by @NatRoze. Roze with a Z. Made that ages
ago, and Laura's been in love with it for ages.
LAURA: Yes, and so we had to put it on a notebook.
And doesn't it look so perfect? It's so perfect.
And by the way, it's the Feywild!
TALIESIN: I'm very excited. I was not aware this
was coming down the pipe.
LAURA: Yeah, and it's shiny. I don't know if you
can see it, but there's a little shimmer.
TALIESIN: Thanks to the art book, I know what this
is called. It's called spot gloss. Thanks to the
art book, I know it's got a spot gloss cover.
LIAM: That is one shiny bear ass.
TALIESIN: You can rub it for luck.
LAURA: If you're so inclined.
MATT: So you are all here tonight to witness
somebody in a very, completely honest way, shout
excitedly, "And it's in the Feywild!" And I love
that that is a thing that happened. Couple other
quick announcements so we can get into the game. I
will be at Paradise City Comic Con in Miami,
January 12th to 14th. All of you folks out there,
east coast Florida. I'm visiting my old stomping
grounds where I originally grew up. Check me out
there. Also, later in 2018, I'll be at Otafest in
Calgary, May 18th to 20th, and A-Kon in Texas,
June 7th through the 10th. Early announcement for
those dates, but that way if you want to come and
say hi, you can mark it in your calendar.
TRAVIS: We're at SacAnime, January 5th or 6th or
something. It's the first week of January. We
hated missing when Sam and Liam went.
LAURA: We love SacAnime. It's great.
JENNIFER: I got to hang with you guys at SacAnime
a few years ago. We did an interview. It was so
fun!
LIAM: We tried to get you to talk about killing
your friends and you would not do it. Why won't
you kill your friends? What's the matter with
you?
JENNIFER: Tonight I will.
MATT: No, you're supposed to collaborate, but
we'll see how it goes. Did a new episode of
Madness go up?
LIAM: New episode of Madness came out! We have
this guy to show. Oh! This is the shirt for Sagas
of Sundry: Madness. I am a Jenga pro! If you want
to learn how to play Jenga, you must watch Sagas
of Sundry: Madness. This eye glows in the fucking
dark.
JENNIFER: Let me see!
MATT: I like the idea that the Jenga catchphrase
from Critical Role was preparation for you to
actually be a Jenga master.
LIAM: I surprise myself, let me tell you!
TALIESIN: We loved our Dread shirts and were like,
it's a shame they don't glow! And they were like,
next time. And we're like, man!
LIAM: I think this is Ivan van Norman's eye. I
hope it's his eye.
MATT: It looks about right.
TALIESIN: It's the door of the house, right?
MATT: Some eldritch horrors are more horrible than
others. All right, guys. Happy to be back. We
missed you. Sorry for the chaos. Bringing it down,
we finished our announcements. That means tonight,
we step into the world of Azeroth as we prepare
for tonight's episode of Critical Role.
[dramatic music]
MATT: And welcome back. So, as we bring ourselves
into this story-- I missed you guys.
JENNIFER: It's their fault!
MATT: It's okay. The Burning Legion has returned.
The world-conquering armies of the corrupt titan,
Sargeras, have assaulted Azeroth. The greatest
heroes of both the Alliance and the Horde have
gathered their resources to combat this
apocalyptic scourge. Traveling off to the Broken
Isles and to Argus beyond to fight for the
salvation of Azeroth, these heroes will be the
stuff of legend. While they're away, things are a
little slow down here in the Eastern Kingdoms for
you guys, as a band of friends seeking to make a
name for yourselves. The streets of Ironforge grow
dull with fetch quests and baking runs. Gilneas'
biggest torment is a terrible flea infestation.
After Stormwind holds a pet-racing contest, which
you each individually lose, you gather your
frustration and head east in search of real
adventure, trudging through a mire of
uninteresting quests and aid to local farm-hands
and wandering merchants. You've all amassed some
equipment to aid you for the new challenges ahead.
Although the patchwork sources leave your gear
somewhat mismatched in color and make. Bundle, you
in particular seem to take pride in your
lime-green robes that you were assured carried a
powerful enchantment.
TALIESIN: It's from a boutique!
MATT: Your troupe has now found your way to the
valley of the Red Ridge Mountains seeking solid
work, only to find the work boards empty and the
wild beasts that roam the surrounding landscape
well in the hands of the local guard. You all sit
within the Lakeshire Inn, within the village of
Lakeshire, two cups into your woes as you lament
your life choices and clashing attire. The warm
interior is rather vacant outside of your band,
the hearth empty with naught but a smoldering log
to combat the chill morning air. That's right,
you're two cups in for breakfast. The innkeeper,
Brianna, yawns and leaves as the bartender, of
fiery-orange, shoulder-length hair and mustache,
walks over to deliver your next round of breakfast
drinks.
LAURA: Sure is chilly in this place, huh? Woo!
Maybe you can add another log, there?
MATT: "Over here, in the fireplace?"
LAURA: Yeah, in that hearth.
MATT: "I'll throw one on. Okay."
LAURA: Thanks!
MATT: "Let me know if you want another round."
LIAM: This is a little weak. Do you have anything
stronger than this?
MATT: "I can go look, but I got to do the log
thing first."
LIAM: All right. Log, then grog, yes?
TALIESIN: If you have a menu of breakfast beers,
that would be most gracious.
MATT: "All right." He looks a bit scattered but
goes off to put the log in the hearth. So, as we
go around the table, if you wouldn't mind taking a
moment to describe your character as you appear at
the table.
TRAVIS: Yes! I am Lohkor Windfallow, paladin.
Keeper of virtues and righteousness. I am
devilishly handsome, and I don't play well with
others because of that devilish handsomeness. But
my skills are always for sale and my fellows seem
to appreciate my roguish good looks.
LAURA: You are quite handsome. Oh, hi! My name is
Greldamine Clypsol. I'm a gnome mage. I am short,
even for a gnome; I know. That's fine. I wear my
hair in a high bun. It's brown. I'm just the
biggest fan of Jaina Proudmore. I think she's just
the most amazing mage I've ever seen, you know. I
hear good things about her. She's so powerful
and beautiful. Sounds amazing, I hear. I don't
know, I haven't met her in person.
TALIESIN: I have to catch my breath. Okay. My name
is Bundle. I'm a dwarf. I've got a very, very nice
lime green robe.
LAURA: It's beautiful.
TALIESIN: Thank you, I'm very proud. I'm a priest
and I've been studying for quite some time.
Learning my trade, perfecting it. I'm a bit
behind. I mean, I've got some younger brothers
that are doing much better than I am, and
certainly they're succeeding more and going
further, and that's fine. I'm doing my best. I'm
taking my own pace. Going a bit bald and I'm
trying to do my best to bring it over, and it's
going into a-- it's not a great beard, but I use
the ham hocks to liven it up a bit.
TRAVIS: It's good. No, it frames your face very
well.
TALIESIN: And I feel like I'm making my way at my
own pace very well. More beer.
JENNIFER: I'm Aerwin Whiteclaw. It's been quite a
long time since I've been in this much company.
It's rather overwhelming. I am a night elf of the
rogue persuasion. I come from a long line of
rogues. I attempted to be rather more of a
businessperson and healer, but was quickly dragged
into the family business. I spend large amounts of
time alone, in the dark, by myself. I dress in
black. I prefer it that way.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: No reason to spend all that time by
yourself.
JENNIFER: Ready for another drink.
(laughter)
LIAM: Yes, my name is Quazirat Toluus.
LAURA: Quazirat Toes?
LIAM: Quazirat Toluus.
TALIESIN: All ten of them?
LIAM: All ten, yes. I am Draenei, wear all white
at all times, top and bottom, underneath and
front. Whole nine yards. I am simple man. I like
to test myself in battle for the glory of Argus.
Every day of my life for the glory of Argus. I
also like to sample the fine spirits of the realm,
and I am a big player of MMORPGs. I like to unwind
at night when I am done killing the Burning
Legion.
LAURA: What's your handle?
LIAM: It is LRJenkins1234.
LAURA: Creative. I like it.
MATT: At this point, the bartender comes by this
time with the next round of drinks. The one log he
placed in there is starting to catch a little bit,
but it's cold enough in the morning where it's
taken a little while. The smoke's billowing up,
bit of it dribbling past the top of the fireplace
and hitting, what you can see, is a casual stain
of gray that reaches the roof of the interior of
the tavern above it. As he sets it down, he goes,
"I'm sorry, I didn't mean to eavesdrop. But based
"on your conversation and attire, I can see that
you seem to be aspiring problem solvers. Is that
"right?"
TRAVIS: I guess so, that does describe us,
doesn't it?
JENNIFER: I suppose.
MATT: "Wonderful. Well, I'm the bartender here.
And my name is Wental. I happen to have a problem
"that's in need of saving, friends, and solving.
You see this inn, it's been in my family for
"generations, left to me by my late father. And
while it does keep me busy," and he looks around
to a very empty tavern around you, "extremely busy,
my passions lie elsewhere. My hobby, my greatest
"of loves, is being a smear monger."
TRAVIS: A what?
MATT: "A smear monger."
LAURA: That sounds great.
MATT: "A smear monger, a chandler, crafter of
light."
LAURA: Of course!
MATT: "A candlemaker!"
TRAVIS, LAURA, TALIESIN: Oh!
LAURA: What kind of candles?
MATT: "Oh, all kinds of candles: scented,
colorful, sizes, long wicks, short wicks."
TRAVIS: Explosive?
MATT: "No, but I haven't dabbled, either."
JENNIFER: Any black ones?
MATT: "Ah, that'll bring us to the crux of our
conversation. There were. I've been hoarding all
"of the oils and fats from the kitchen since I was
a boy, slowly learning to build a stock and keep
"it beneath my bed, and eventually moving it to a
shed offsite. Reading what books I can in secret.
"If my father knew my interests in candle making...
anyway." And you can see his eyes begin to well up
a bit and his hands are shaking. "I went to go to
my storage shed after buying a small homestead in
"Goldshire and hoping to open a shop at some point
in the future. It's all gone. All of it! Just
"gone! Every. Single. Candle I've made! Gone!"
LAURA: Even your fat stores?
MATT: "Well the fat stores are normally stored in
there, but they've gone bad since. I asked for it
"to be investigated, but the guard laughed at me.
They have no appreciation for fine candlework."
You notice, across the room, one of the other
women who are in there who's the local voyeur
chuckles under her breath and she eats her cold
toast and stays at the table. Wental shoots her an
icy dagger glance and back to you. "I ask, if you
would help retrieve my life's work, I would
"greatly make it worth your while. I have my
savings, which isn't much, about 520 gold pieces.
"And I could probably muster some armor that
matches."
LAURA: That'd be great!
MATT: "What do you say?"
LAURA: Do you have robes?
MATT: "That could be arranged."
TALIESIN: Doesn't have to match.
TRAVIS: Yeah, but we should present a united
front, though. I mean, people should be able to
see that we are a group.
JENNIFER: As long as it's black.
LIAM: As long as it's white.
TALIESIN: As long as it's lime green.
LAURA: I'm partial to purple.
MATT: "I'll see what I can do about dye colors.
I'll have to send away, possibly to Westfall. They
"have some good dyers there. But if you agree to
this, then the sooner we can get off the better!"
And he twirls his mustache with both of his
fingers, a nervous tick or an exclamation of
physicality. "Shall we?"
JENNIFER: I'll agree as long as you never do that
again.
MATT: "Very well."
TALIESIN: There was a fisherman who did like 25 of
those little red plants, but this sounds better.
LAURA: This sounds fun! Wental, you can count on
us! I jump on top of the table and raise my fist
into the air.
JENNIFER: I shrink into my chair.
MATT: He awkwardly reaches out and side fistbumps,
not sure what to do.
LAURA: Candles!
MATT: "I like her!"
TRAVIS: I'm sure this morning's fare will be also
a part of our arrangement?
MATT: "Sure."
LIAM: And I was going to ask for a couple bottles
of your best vintage to be added to the agreed
upon price.
TRAVIS and JENNIFER: Yes.
MATT: "Very well. I'll be happy to place it upon
your tab that will be wiped clean upon the
"retrieval of my candles."
JENNIFER: A steed or two. I saw something out back
that looked rather suitable.
MATT: "I'll see what I can do. I only have so much
I can do in the town, but let me try. Anyway." And
he rushes off. He comes back and he brings you two
bottles of wine, not the greatest. You don't get a
lot of decent import over here on Lakeshore,
unfortunately. It's a little out of the way.
LIAM: Will it mess me up?
MATT: "If you were to chug it now, most likely!"
LIAM: That's a deal.
MATT: "All righty. Follow me. I'll take you to the
shed. See if you can learn anything."
LAURA: Great.
MATT: So Wental guides you outside the Lakeshore
Inn, around the back and up past some bushes.
There's a number of trees that crest right against
the base of the Red Ridge Mountains, just above
the location of the inn. As he comes around, you
can see there's the one stable off to the side. He
goes, "I'll talk to them and see what I can do.
But to be honest, the stable master and me don't
"really get along."
JENNIFER: Just show me where he is. I'm sure we
can work something out.
MATT: "Very well. Should I take you to the shed
first, or do you need your steed now?"
LAURA: Maybe to the shed since it's close.
JENNIFER: We can go to the shed. I don't want to
make the small one run.
LAURA: Thank you.
MATT: "I don't mind. All right." And you see he
seems to have confidence around the gnome. And
then he gets really sheepish in the gaze of the
night elf who stares down and probably stands a
good six inches taller than him. So he leads you
up past this section to the base of the mountains
and you can see there's a really nice-looking shed
that's settled between the edge of the mountains
and a tree over there. It's closed, it's locked
up, there's chains. But as you walk up, you can
see that the actual lock has been broken and the
chains dangle off to the sides of the two doors
that open up into it.
TALIESIN: There's your trouble. You left it
unlocked.
TRAVIS: I think someone broke the lock.
TALIESIN: You're making assumptions, I feel.
That's a lot to just assume, just taking your
first look.
MATT: (squeak) He opens the front doors to the
shed and upon looking inside, you can see there
are shelves arranged. There are small crates that
have been pried open. Across the entirety of the
floor you see scraps of wax scattered here and
there, large spaces where apparently clusters of
it were set and have since been pulled. And it is
entirely empty and scraped of any possible
remainder of wax. And there's a sudden smell that
comes out, too. It could be a combination of
either rotting animal bits and/or some element of
fecal matter. It's hard to really pick out. But
it's not a pleasant interior.
LIAM: Are there any markings, footprints,
different toe patterns, any kind of clues?
MATT: "I looked everywhere and saw nothing. I'm
also a bartender and that's why I asked you guys.
"So if you want to have a look, please!"
LIAM: Yeah. I was actually asking the DM.
MATT: Oh, okay.
LIAM: Do I see, with my Draenei eyes, as I stroke
my chin tentacles--
LAURA: You have tentacles?! You have tentacles on
your chin?
LIAM: On my chin. I don't like to draw attention
to them.
TRAVIS: You don't need to. They're just there.
MATT: So are you getting to the ground?
LIAM: That's right.
MATT: Make an investigation check.
LIAM: Yes. I'm making an investigation check. I'm
rolling a d20. That's not very good. That is, hold
on! I've just solved the entire game. That's a
two.
MATT: You get close to the ground and there's a
lot of small bits of wax. And you start pulling
them together and piecing them, and you figure if
you spend the next couple hours, you can maybe put
together a very small candle.
LIAM: There were candles here.
MATT: You are correct.
TRAVIS: Quazi, you are astute, as always. Bundle,
would you mind checking the lock to see if
there's--?
TALIESIN: I take a look at the lock.
MATT: Make an investigation check.
TALIESIN: Oh, boy. Oh, wow.
TRAVIS: Oh, no. It's cold in here.
LAURA: Warm it up, guys!
TALIESIN: Seven?
MATT: Seven? The lock appears to have been broken
through blunt force, but you have no other
information you can draw from it.
TALIESIN: Lock appears to have been broken by
blunt force. I don't know.
JENNIFER: Let me have a look.
MATT: All right, if you want to go ahead and make
an investigation check as well.
LIAM: That's a good idea. Okay, that's better than
us. So you go from there to there, and add that.
JENNIFER: So it's 13.
MATT: 13? So as you start glancing around, first
things first. When you get closer to the ground
and elements of the doorway, you can smell in the
air, it's almost like a wet fur scent in the air.
And as you glance towards the edge of the shed's
opening in the mud and dirt that surrounds the
exterior, you can see faint foot tracks smattering
in different directions. Many of them. There's
multiple sets. Soled shoes, or boots of some kind.
But it looks almost like there's also a toe or two
protruding from the front. Smaller than a man's
feet. They lead away from the shed and then
further up the mountain range to the westward
direction.
JENNIFER: I've seen these before. It's been a long
time. It was very far from here. I hesitate to
name it. I'll leave that to the Dungeon Master.
It's my first game!
LIAM: You can also tell there were candles here,
yes?
JENNIFER: Yes. I can smell there were candles
here.
MATT: So, go ahead and roll a d20 and add your
intelligence modifier to this one. So, look at
your intelligence. Liam, want to help her with the
intelligence modifier?
LIAM: Intelligence modifier is up here, yeah? Five
plus--
JENNIFER: So, 13.
MATT: That's a saving throw.
LIAM: Oh, so intelligence check, you say?
Intelligence check? Well, then it's just that
plus-- where the hell is it? There it is.
JENNIFER: Ten!
MATT: Ten? Okay. You recall seeing tracks like
this before but the name is on the tip of your
tongue. You're not entirely certain what it could
be.
JENNIFER: The name's on the tip of my tongue and I
can't quite grab it. Can someone else grab it for
me?
TRAVIS: Yes. Let me see if I recognize these
tracks.
LAURA: Does anyone know that you make candles?
Other than your father?
MATT: "Well, he doesn't know yet. I was going to
open the store first and have him come take a look
"at it."
LAURA: Oh, okay. So you don't have any candle
enemies?
MATT: "I don't believe so. Not in this town. There
isn't a candlemaker, not anymore."
LAURA: And are your candles scented?
MATT: "Some of them were."
LAURA: Do most of them smell like animal fat?
MATT: "Yes, they do, by their very nature. But I
try best to add lavender to the batch and
"occasionally--"
JENNIFER: Lavender, you say?
MATT: "Yes, lavender."
LIAM: What about paht-pourri?
TRAVIS: We've discussed this. It's potpourri.
LIAM: You're dropping off the T.
TRAVIS: Well, it's just potpourri.
LIAM: You're fucking with me.
TRAVIS: No, for the fourth time.
LAURA: Were you going to track them?
TRAVIS: I'd like to try.
MATT: Make a survival check.
TRAVIS: Natural 20.
LAURA: Is that with your Grog dice?
TRAVIS: With my die!
MATT: You watch as the armored human paladin gets
low. His eyes suddenly spark! As he looks to the
left, looks to the right, looks down to the
ground, and, almost like a hound dog, begins
trailing this track curving around the shed into
the west as you guys slowly follow suit.
TALIESIN: This is why we pay him big gold bucks
right there.
TRAVIS: And because I'm handsome.
MATT: As you guys follow, Wental stays a few steps
behind. He seems excited, but also not sure what
you guys are going to discover and you can see the
tension rising in him. His shoulders are slowly
creeping up across the sides of his head.
LAURA: Yes, we're clearly much more experienced
fighters than you are.
MATT: "I completely agree. I hope." At this point
you catch up to your human paladin friend over
there and you find the tracks lead up to a large
cluster of bushes that are embedded right in the
base of the mountain range. They're thorny.
They're dry. It's a small bramble cluster. It's
about five or so feet up. It's a wide chunk and
you can see bits and pieces of it scattered across
the edge of the mountain range here. As you get
closer you can see some of the jagged edges of the
boosh have a faint-- A boosh. The boosh.
TRAVIS: Are you amused by the boosh?
MATT: You find the boosh rather amusing. On the
jagged edges of the bush you see faint elements of
a waxy residue that have been scraped onto some of
the thorns of the brambles.
LIAM: Probably unrelated.
MATT: Just beyond you can barely see a dark
recess, about four feet tall and about four feet
wide, behind the bush, that presses into the
mountain range.
TRAVIS: The tracks lead to this bush. If you see
just beyond there's a recess in the mountains.
LAURA: How big is the recess?
TRAVIS: It's like four-- what is it? How far
about?
MATT: Four foot wide and four foot tall.
LAURA: Oh. That's small for a human.
TRAVIS: Indeed it is.
LAURA: So I wonder if these creatures who stole
the candles are smaller than humans.
TRAVIS: My hypothesis exactly.
TALIESIN: Or they're prone to crawling.
LAURA: Oh, or that.
TALIESIN: They could be crawlers. That's some mean
crawlers.
JENNIFER: Gren-- Grel-- Greldamin?
LAURA: Greldamine. It's okay, it's a hard name.
Especially for elves.
(laughter)
JENNIFER: It looks like you could stand upright in
that hole.
LAURA: I could.
JENNIFER: Yes. It's another element we should
factor into our search.
LAURA: Should I go in? Should we all go in?
LIAM: You first, little one.
LAURA: Gladly. Can we move these thorny bushes out
of the way though?
TRAVIS: Absolutely. I start ripping the dried
brush out of the--
MATT: The brush is actually not attached to the
ground. It comes and pulls out of the way really
easily.
JENNIFER: Does he fall on his butt when he pulls
on it that hard?
MATT: He almost does. He teeters on one foot as
his sheer show of strength to tear them out
overcompensates and his armored self, being top
heavy as he is, he stands there and awkwardly
wobbles in place. And for a moment you see as the
bartender, Wental, swallows deeply out of the
choice of companions that he's hired for this.
LAURA: Wental, are you coming with us?
MATT: "Oh goodness no!"
TRAVIS: Are you sure? We have extra daggers and
all sorts of things.
MATT: "I have a job. It's busy. Lot of people in
there. I need to make drinks and breakfast. I
"hired you to do this for me. Please do this for
me."
LAURA: Of course, yes, don't worry.
TRAVIS: We will take care of this and be back
expediently. You can count on us!
MATT: "Wonderful, thank you."
JENNIFER: Please have dinner ready.
MATT: "Yes ma'am." You can't tell if he's crushing
or legitimately super frightened but, "Good
"luck!"
JENNIFER: One and the same.
MATT: So pulling the brush out of the way, you can
see this has been a deliberately-dug cavern that
recedes into the mountain and into darkness.
LAURA: Hello!
MATT: (imitates echo) It does echo a bit.
TRAVIS: Can you see in the dark?
LAURA: Yes, but I also have Light! And I send
Light down the tunnel. Can I do that? Can I send
Light down the tunnel or does it light up around
me?
MATT: Well, you choose an object to then light up
like it was a torch.
LAURA: Oh, what do we have on us?
TRAVIS: I have a torch. I have ten of them.
LAURA: Oh. Well we should probably just use a
torch then.
LIAM: There's also rocks on the ground.
LAURA: Oh! I'll pick up a rock and cast Light on
the rock! That was a good idea,
Whatever-Your-Toes!
LIAM: Yes. Is there room for our World of Warcraft
pauldrons to go into this space?
MATT: Four foot wide? At your size? Barely. It
scrapes the edges as you push inward, digging two
small grooves along the cavern.
JENNIFER: Let's send him first. Someone push him
from behind.
TALIESIN: Grease it up and he'll squeeze right in
there.
JENNIFER: There's candle wax around.
TALIESIN: Wax the corners and push him through.
LIAM: Either the small magic one or the sneaky one
should be going first, I think, yes?
JENNIFER: Well she can stand upright.
LAURA: I'll go first.
LIAM: All right little stinker, let's see what you
can do.
MATT: All right, so Greldamine, as you light up
the rock in your hand and it's giving off this
bright torch light, you hold it in front of you
and you walk right into it. As soon as you begin
to step into the chamber you can already feel
there's a faint cold breeze blowing from the open
world behind you into the chamber. You're drawn
deeper and deeper into the darkness within as it
begins to faintly grade into a descent. What's the
order in which you guys are traveling behind her?
LAURA: Oh jeez, this is so dumb that I'm in the
front.
MATT and LAURA: What do you mean?
LAURA: With my 37 hit points.
TRAVIS: You're so squishy!
TALIESIN: We're all a little squishy.
TRAVIS: To make you feel better I will be second.
LAURA: Okay.
TALIESIN: I'll go right in the middle.
JENNIFER: If you'd like a wall behind us, I'll go
after him.
LIAM: All right. Dramamine, lead the way.
MATT: As you continue delving deeper down this
cavern, the smell of damp earth seems to be ever
present as a recent rainfall has left a lot of
this path, the early portion of it, rather muddy.
Your feet slip and slick against the soft floor as
you occasionally have to right yourself against
the walls of the cavern, being careful as you push
deeper into this. Now after some time the path
comes to an abrupt halt where the floor seems to
drop down about five feet into a tunnel that opens
larger and wider, 15 feet below you, deeper still
into the mountain.
LAURA: Shh! Can I hear anything?
MATT: Make a perception check.
LAURA: Ooh! 23.
TRAVIS: Wow.
MATT: What little bit of wind is passing through
down into the cavern, you can hear what sounds
like a faint rock falling. Some scraping sounds
and a door slam, distant, below you, and distant.
JENNIFER: Might this be a good time for some
shadow melding?
LAURA: What is that?
MATT: It's up to you. You can only use it once per
short rest so keep that in mind. If there's
nothing currently around you can still stealth
whenever you want to.
JENNIFER: I'm inclined to stealth.
LAURA: Oh yeah, you can stealth.
MATT: Okay, so yeah, go ahead and roll a stealth
check.
JENNIFER: I'll be the stealth person. All right
so--
LAURA: We can all try to stealth right now if you
want to.
LIAM: It would be better because here's the thing,
even if you are supremely sneaky which you are,
I'm fucking bullshit with sneaking so we all have
to, you know, pull our weight.
LAURA: Maybe you'll roll a 20.
LIAM: We'll see how I do. Three!
JENNIFER: 28.
MATT: Your darker night elf complexion vanishes
into the shadows-- there you go. I love it.
TALIESIN: 15.
LAURA: 13.
TRAVIS: 13 as well.
LIAM: And I lied. Five.
MATT: That makes a difference. All right so, as
you guys all quietly look down into this small
cavern it drops down, you're looking over the
edge--
LAURA: Like five feet?
MATT: Like five, six feet down below you jump down
if you want to.
LAURA: Should we jump down?
LIAM: Yeah! They'll never see us coming!
(shushing)
JENNIFER: Put a sock in it. So I suppose I should
go ahead. I'm going to sneak ahead because I'm the
sneaky one in this one. All right, I'm sneaking
ahead.
MATT: As you guys all leap down into the tunnel
below you--
JENNIFER: Oh, oh! (grunt)
MATT: Okay. Said that, you all leap in afterward.
You go ahead and begin to sneak ahead a bit and it
switches back a bit and goes into a much more
steady decline in the direction of where you came
from below.
JENNIFER: Is it slippery?
MATT: It's actually much drier now. You're further
away from the cavern entrance, it looks like the
water--
JENNIFER: It's much drier here. I'm going ahead. I
smell something. It's very familiar, but my
intelligence is not as high as I'd like so I can't
remember what it is.
TALIESIN: Lavender.
LAURA: Ooh.
JENNIFER: It smells like lavender. It does, good
reminder.
LAURA: Does it?
MATT: You don't smell lavender as well--
TALIESIN: No? Never mind, that's just me being a
nuisance.
JENNIFER: I don't smell lavender, I take that
back.
MATT: But you--
JENNIFER: Stop it, I'm new.
MATT: You do begin to hear as you begin your
approach what sounds like faint rushing water.
JENNIFER: I hear rushing water.
MATT: And you see ahead as you're pushing
forward-- are you guys following behind her?
LAURA: Yeah, no, we're following, we're following.
MATT: So like, hanging about 20 feet or so back?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: Eventually the path begins to curve to the
left and you can see a faint source of light that
begins to emerge around the corner as you begin to
curve around.
LAURA: (whispering) What does it look like?
JENNIFER: (whispering) It looks like a long thin
ray of light. Vertical, I think. I've been waiting
to find out if I'm right.
TRAVIS: Are you making this up?
JENNIFER: I am, totally. Am I allowed? Am I
allowed to do that?
LAURA: No!
JENNIFER: Oh, I'll stop now. I don't know this
game yet.
LIAM: What happens is he will create the
environment and the things around you and you
interact with them and you roll dice occasionally.
JENNIFER: I'm going to go under here for a
minute.
LIAM: You're in control of your personality and
the actions you do in this world. He's the world.
JENNIFER: I don't know, do I see any light?
MATT: So as you coast around the corner go ahead
and make a perception check.
JENNIFER: Okay.
LIAM: There it is. Oh that's shnazzy. Yeah. What
is that?
JENNIFER: (counting) 18.
MATT: All right, so as you coast around the
corner, placing your hand along the edge of the
cavern you glance over and you can see the hallway
opens up into a much larger chamber of natural
stone formations and stalactites litter the roof
above you, the cavern top. There's about 20 feet
beyond this entrance, an underground river that is
stretching across from one side to the other
before diving in and vanishing beneath the rock
wall on the far right side. Crossing this small
recess where the water seems to be rushing, you
can see the occasional mist and spray from wayward
rocks that are breaking up the flow of the river.
Two rickety wood plank bridges that cross past it
are attached and nailed into portions of the rock,
and then right across, you can see the source of
light. There's a number of sources of light that
are slightly shifting on the opposite end of the
chamber. There's another platform on the other end
of the river where you can see roughly nine nasty
looking humanoid creatures that are clustered with
patches of fur on portions of their body. They
carry satchels and packs. A single, melting lit
candle rests atop each of their heads as their
light source in these dark tunnels.
LAURA: That's really cute.
MATT: You now recognize what was on the tip of
your tongue. These are definitely kobolds and they
appear to have been coming through a door that is
now closed and being locked on the opposite side
by one of them that is larger. They're carrying
these large sacks and they're all talking amongst
each other. You can see their features are
somewhat rat-like and their protruded snouts,
whiskers that shoot off to each side. They haven't
noticed your presence yet.
LAURA: How tall are they?
MATT: About three and a half, four feet?
LAURA: So they're taller than I am.
MATT: Mm-hmm.
LAURA: I put my rock out.
MATT: Okay, so your light source vanishes.
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: And we've been trailing the elf, so--
JENNIFER: Now we're in the clear, so I'm going to
step back.
LAURA: What should we do? How many of them are
there?
TALIESIN and JENNIFER: (counting) One, two, three,
four.
TRAVIS: Nine.
LAURA: Nine? There's about nine of them. Okay. Do
you think we could take nine of them?
JENNIFER: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Of course.
LAURA: Has anybody tried talking to kobolds
before?
TRAVIS: I haven't.
TALIESIN: I've never talked to one before.
JENNIFER: If our mission is to bring the candles
home, what would happen to the candles if we took
them out in a violent manner? Would they be
damaged, would that--
TRAVIS: Did we ask how many candles were missing?
Boxes of them.
LAURA: An entire shed's worth!
LIAM: I think it was more than nine so like ten
candles. Eleven, probably. We'll find out if we
kill them.
LAURA: I wonder if these are actual candles or if
these are old candles and they stole his candles
for new candles because the candles on their head
are wearing down, do you know what I mean?
LIAM: You just said candles a lot of times.
TRAVIS: Who's feeling particularly sneaky right
now?
LAURA: I can be invisible.
TRAVIS: That's right. Feel like journeying in a
little bit? Seeing what else you can see?
LAURA: Sure. Sure! I cast Invisibility on myself.
MATT: Okay. You watch as the outside of your
gnomish companion shimmers and then vanishes. You
find yourself invisible and you step carefully.
LAURA: Okay. I'm going to walk across the bridge
now.
JENNIFER: We can still hear you.
LAURA: Yeah. I'll be quiet once I get towards
the bridge.
TRAVIS: See if you can see any of the other
candles.
LAURA: I walk towards one of the rickety bridges.
MATT: Okay. Go ahead and make a stealth check with
advantage because you're invisible.
LAURA: Ooh. Yeah. 22.
MATT: Okay. As you carefully make your way over
towards the edge of the bridge you can see the
water is about a foot and a half, two feet below
where the bridge is and it's not rushing super
fast but enough where it's breaking the water a
bit, you're seeing a bit of spray and mist and you
see these nine kobold creatures across the way. It
looks like the one that was locking the door is
currently talking and giving instructions to the
others as you see the larger one is standing there
with this massive pack on his back that's filled
to the brim. All of them are carrying pickaxes to
the side, but he has the wicked, more strongly
built one. As he's pointing to them he's talking.
Make a perception check.
LAURA: Oh, natural 20! Ha!
MATT: Nice.
So you can hear faintly what he's
instructing is, "Stop complaining. We've gots to
"get these tunnels boom-booming before more cursed
people come. Now you, place there, you place
"there, me, I place everywhere else." And they all
begin to scatter a bit and make their way towards
the two bridges to begin to cross over in the
direction of you.
LAURA: Oh no! Oh god, and I start backing up
towards my companions. I run towards them and say
They're on their way over here! They're going to
blow things up! I think the big one has the bag of
candles on his back!
TRAVIS: You sure you heard blow things up?
LAURA: Yeah, he said something about blowing
things up!
LIAM: Where are you?
LAURA: I'm right here! I punch him in the knee. I
could've punched something else.
TRAVIS: We've got to stop them. There's nine of
them.
LAURA: We can do it!
TRAVIS: There's five of us.
LAURA: What if we take out one of the bridges
while they're on the bridge?! Cut the rope and
then some of them that are on the bridge will
fall!
MATT: While you're having this conversation two of
them have just now finished traversing the bridge.
LAURA and TRAVIS: Shit.
LAURA: Quick! Go cut the bridge!
TRAVIS: Go cut the bridge?
LAURA: Cut the rope on the bridge!
JENNIFER: Can I take them out while--
MATT: If you'd like to.
LIAM: This is the time.
JENNIFER: This is the time to take them out.
MATT: All right, so as they're having this
conversation you pull around the corner with your
hand crossbow and make a shot at the closest one
to you. You see one of the kobolds lumbering up,
he's reaching into his satchel and he's pulling
out a small rod of some kind. Go ahead and roll an
attack.
LIAM: All right. And it's at advantage because
she's hiding, yeah?
MATT: Exactly.
LIAM: Yeah, so roll it twice and take the higher
one. So it's a 17 plus your attack from the
crossbow is a 25.
JENNIFER: 26. 17 plus nine.
MATT: Oh that most definitely hits.
LIAM: Plus eight.
JENNIFER: Oh sorry, plus eight, sorry, yes, right.
25.
MATT: That most definitely hits. So go ahead and
roll damage on that with sneak attack damage.
LIAM: So the damage is a 1d6, so you roll one of
those cubes.
JENNIFER: One?
LIAM: Okay, three plus your sneak attack damage
which is at your level--
LAURA: Probably 1d6. 2d6 maybe?
MATT: It's 4d6. It's under the attack.
JENNIFER: There it is. 4d6.
LAURA: 4d6?! What level are we?!
MATT: Level seven.
LAURA: Oh shit.
JENNIFER: So I add ten. 17.
LIAM: Plus the five.
JENNIFER: So 22.
MATT: 22 points of damage. So, as that one crosses
the way it pulls out its rod and (grunting)
(arrow whooshing) (cry of pain) and goes straight down,
limp, drunk ET style, on the ground, slams face
first and is done.
JENNIFER: We need to get the other one now don't
we?
MATT: At this point, the one that just finished
crossing the bridge on the other side goes "Cera!
"Get up!" Walks over and kicks him. Then looks over
and sees you holding the hand crossbow and goes
(screaming).
TALIESIN: Do I have time to get one attack in?
MATT: I need you all to roll initiative.
(groaning)
JENNIFER: What's initiative?
LIAM: So we're seeing what the order is so roll 20
again and add this. And then keep that number in
your head. For a moment. You changed it, roll it
again.
JENNIFER: I saw what it was but--
LIAM: Well if you know what it was then keep it.
JENNIFER: I do know what--
LIAM: I can't read your die Jen! Yes, that's good,
that's 23. Okay.
MATT: 23?
LIAM: Just remember that. Why can't I roll well?
Okay.
TRAVIS: What did you roll?
LIAM: 11.
MATT: All right so we have 23, we have-- how do
you spell your character's name again?
JENNIFER: A-E-R-W-Y-N but it's I-N, either one.
MATT: Aerwin? Okay cool.
LIAM: J-E-L-L-O.
MATT: There you go. Perfect.
TALIESIN: 14.
MATT: So it's 20 to 15? Anybody?
LAURA: Oh.
TRAVIS: She had 23 right?
MATT and JENNIFER: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Oh, what was it?
MATT: 20 to 15.
TRAVIS: I'm 15.
MATT: All righty. And spell your name for me real
fast.
TRAVIS: L-O-H-K-O-R.
LAURA: Lohkor.
MATT: 15 to ten.
TALIESIN: 14.
LAURA: 13.
LIAM: 11.
LAURA: Lies. 12.
MATT: All righty and then--?
LIAM: 11. Quazirat.
TRAVIS: Quasimodo.
LIAM: Q-U-A-Z-I.
LAURA: I'm naming you Toes, because that's all I
can remember.
MATT: All right, cool. So top of the round as all
the kobolds now notice you guys clustered right
there at the entrance of the cavern, start rushing
over the bridge, their pickaxes out and the larger
one on the opposite side, seeing this, seems to be
preparing for something. What are you doing?
JENNIFER: I'm loading up the crossbow.
MATT: Okay, so you pull out another bolt, load it
up and staying there, and you're going to fire at
which one?
JENNIFER: They're all behind the one in the
front?
MATT: There's the one that just kicked the guy you
killed and there's two sets that are running
across the bridges currently over the water.
JENNIFER: I'm going for their leader.
MATT: Okay cool, so you might have to get a little
closer, you're about 40 feet away from him or you
can fire from now but you'll have disadvantage on
the attack. But up to you.
JENNIFER: I can move a little closer. I'll move,
hit and then move, right?
MATT: Okay.
JENNIFER: I can do that can't I?
MATT: You can do that, yeah. So you go ahead and
move forward your 30 feet, that'll get you into
a 30 foot range. You'll be almost in melee range
with one of the kobolds. Go ahead and take a shot
at the leader.
JENNIFER: And that's these? No.
LIAM: To hit you roll d20. So roll the roundy and
add your attack bonus for crossbow.
JENNIFER: 16.
MATT: 16 just hits. So you roll damage, it's not
sneak attack because you're not hidden.
LIAM: Yeah, so now you're just rolling d6, a cube.
JENNIFER: d6 cube. Which one's the d6? It's this
one! Okay, there we go.
LIAM: And add a five.
JENNIFER: Seven.
MATT: There we go, seven points of damage,
(grunting). They seem angry as it begins to reach
and fiddle with the back of his pack on his back.
You can use your bonus action to dash backward if
you'd like to back into the cavern entrance.
JENNIFER: Yes, I think that's most useful.
MATT: Okay so, after firing the kobolds are
rushing in and you back up, getting behind your
allies to protect you. All right, that brings it
to Lohkor.
TRAVIS: I don't know why we always try and do this
stealthily. I get the warhammer out and I'll reach
forward to the one and take a big swing right in
his face.
MATT: Go for it. This is the one who kicked his
friend trying to wake him up.
TRAVIS: 18.
MATT: 18 hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: That's 1d8. 13 points of bludgeoning
damage.
MATT: 13 points of bludgeoning damage. All right.
TRAVIS: I have another one because of extra
attack?
MATT: You do.
TRAVIS: Nice! 15.
MATT: 15 hits.
TRAVIS: Nice. And that is seven points of
bludgeoning damage.
MATT: All right. As you rush forward the first hit
hits him upside the chin. You see a spatter of
blood across the rock behind you. He gets back and
pulls out his pickaxe, his angry whiskered face,
you see fury in his eyes and you sink the hammer
into his face. He's like (cry of pain) (gurgle)
and he falls to the ground, dead.
TRAVIS: Yes! I turn to the rest of them and I say:
Let them have it! And I take off running into the
fray.
MATT: All right, great. As that's happening, you
running, the larger leader in the back who
finishes fiddling with his pack pulls a small rod,
holds it up to the top of the candle on his head
and you watch it spark, and lobs it in an arc over
to where you are. The kobolds stop running and
watch it going as it arcs over, except for two of
them that weren't paying attention and are
charging towards you as it (thudding) between your
legs, rolls a little behind you, and there's that
brief moment where everything slows down for but
an instance before it explodes in a cacophonous
explosion of flame and force. I need all of you to
make a dexterity saving throw.
JENNIFER: So that's the d20?
LIAM: So yeah, roll d20. Dexterity save. So what
you get on that? Ten plus that is here. Nine.
MATT: All right so, what did you get?
JENNIFER: 18.
MATT: Okay, that succeeds.
TALIESIN: Eight.
MATT: Nope.
LAURA: 18.
MATT: Succeeds.
TRAVIS: 16.
MATT: Just barely succeeds.
LIAM: And this is a save, not ability skill,
correct?
MATT: Right.
LIAM: Oh, that's big 11.
MATT: That's a failure.
LIAM: No. I don't think so.
MATT: All right so, Bundle and Quazirat, you guys
both suffer 18 points of fire damage.
LIAM: Seems fake.
MATT: The rest of you suffer nine points of fire
damage. And the two nearest kobolds who are
rushing in to go after Lohkor also explode into
pieces and are thrown behind you. You see them
running like (screaming) (explosion) and are
destroyed by their own dynamite. And you hear this
laughter at the back of the cavern. "Firework!" He
seems to be rather excited and given this bit of
fury inspirational boost from the carnage he's
caused. All right, that's going to end his turn.
He's going to stay right there at the edge.
Bundle, your turn.
TALIESIN: Everything hurts, one second. I'm
finding a thing--
TRAVIS: New class abilities. We're all like,
flexing in the thing that we've never played
before.
TALIESIN: I know, this is so difficult.
JENNIFER: At least I'm not the only one.
TALIESIN: I'm going to quickly cast Mass Healing
Word on everybody while I, not even get up, I'm
going to sit up and cast Mass Healing Word on the
group.
MATT: Okay, so go ahead and roll that. That's a d4
plus your--
TALIESIN: Oh, that's right it's auto. So, d4 plus
wisdom modifier. That's six.
MATT: All right, so everyone heals six hit
points.
TALIESIN: And I'm going to use my bonus action to
create a Spiritual Weapon.
MATT: Okay. What kind of weapon is it taking the
form of?
TALIESIN: A giant hammer that looks a little bit
like an anvil that's bigger than his hammer. It's
going to manifest right above the main kobold's
head ten feet up.
MATT: All right, so as it begins to apparate in
the sky, Lohkor, you look across and you can see
the hammer, slightly larger than your hammer,
apparate.
TRAVIS: Son of a Bundle!
MATT: It does take a swing at the leader, so go
for it. I believe when you summon, it gets to take
one hit.
TALIESIN: Does it get to take one hit?
MATT: Double-check.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I'll go for it.
MATT: Spiritual Weapon. Yep!
TALIESIN: That's 15?
MATT: 15 unfortunately misses. It swings, and you
can see the kobold look up as it sees your eyes
trace up and he goes, (growl). Sees it, (growl).
Leaps backward as it slams into the ground,
cracking the stone beneath and he dodges out of
the way. (laughs)
TRAVIS: Still with the performance issues, eh,
Bundle?
TALIESIN: I'm getting up! And I use my movement to
stand up and shake off.
MATT: All right, cool. Ending Bundle's turn,
that'll bring us to Grendlemine.
LAURA: Okay, it's Greldamine.
MATT: Greldamine, sorry! Reading my own
handwriting's a problem.
LAURA: Are any of them in a line? Are they on the
bridge still?
MATT: On the bridge there's three on each bridge
that are in a line.
LAURA: And then the big one?
MATT: Actually, no, at this point, there's two,
because two of them got blown away. There's two on
each bridge right now.
LAURA: Okay, and the big one, is he lined up with
a bridge, or is he between the bridges?
MATT: No, he's in between the two.
LAURA: Okay.
LIAM: On other side.
JENNIFER: Is Greldamine still invisible?
MATT: She is currently.
LIAM: What's the length of those bridge,
guesstimation-wise?
MATT: The bridges are about 20 feet across, 15 to
20. They're not super long bridges; it's not a
huge chamber.
JENNIFER: How many of them are left now? We were
down to eight.
LIAM: Five total: two on each bridge, big guy
other side. Big is relative term.
LAURA: Okay. For fear of damaging the perhaps bag
of candles on the big one's back, that would be
bad, I'm going to cast Burning Hands towards one
of the bridges with two of the things on it.
MATT: Okay! So you rush forward as two of the
surviving kobolds-- on the right or the left
bridge?
LAURA: The left!
MATT: Okay, so you run over to the left bridge
and, as the kobolds are rushing across with their
pickaxes out (heavy breathing), you--
LAURA: (screams)
MATT: You watch as her invisible form suddenly
appears, apparating as the illusion that has been
hiding her vanishes. As a flamethrower gout of
fire burns out from in front, engulfing both of
the kobolds. What's the saving throw on that?
What's your DC? Your spell DC?
LAURA: My DC is 16.
MATT: 16! No! Yes! One of them succeeds, one of
them fails.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: So, what's the damage on that?
LAURA: 3d6 fire damage.
MATT: So go ahead and roll 3d6.
LAURA: And it sets things on fire.
MATT: Yes. The bridge is definitely on fire.
LAURA: Nine damage.
MATT: All right, nine damage. Then one of them
takes four damage. Okay, so they're like, "Ugh!"
They pull back a bit, and you can see the edge of
their whiskers are curling in and burned. The
fur's seared at the edges. Some of them actually
have caught fire and a little bit of smoke is
pouring off. But the edge of the bridge that
they're standing on, that you're right in front
of, has definitely caught fire. And you can see
the two kobolds are now trying to figure out what
to do as they're stuck in the middle right now.
LAURA: I'm going to run away from the bridge and
hide behind Lohkor's legs.
MATT: You used your movement to approach the
bridge to cast Burning Hands.
LAURA: Oh, I did? Great! Can I move at all?
MATT: I'll give you five feet.
LAURA: I'll back up five feet.
MATT: (small steps). Their eyes are trained on
you.
LAURA: Shit!
MATT: All right, that ends your turn. That brings
it to their turn. So, as far as kobolds go, the
two that are on the bridge start rushing towards
you. I'm going to go ahead and see if the bridge
maintains its coherence for both of them. For the
first one it's fine. The second one it is not. So
the first kobold runs forward and it's going to
swing at you with its pickaxe. Because you were
damaged by another kobold, it gets a bonus to
damage.
LAURA: I was? Oh, I was.
MATT: From the explosion earlier. So, that is
going to be a 20 to hit?
LAURA: Oh.
MATT: I believe that hits, right?
LAURA and TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: All right, and you suffer ten points of
piercing damage as the pickaxe hacks into your
shoulder as it rushes past. The other one, as it's
running towards you, you see it pulling back its
pickaxe to follow through and try and attack with
its friend as the final ropes release. And you
watch him go (yells) and vanish into the water
below. You hear him (gurgles) as he gets carried
by the water current further down the river and
he's trying to swim upstream. He's currently stuck
in the middle of trying to figure out what to do
there. The other two rush across the other side of
the chamber, finish traversing that bridge, and go
straight towards you, Lohkor, because you're the
closest to them at this point. That's going to be
a 17 to hit.
TRAVIS: Misses.
MATT: You reach out and you parry off to the side.
The other one's going to go ahead and instead he's
going to-- That's a 22 to hit.
TRAVIS: That does hit.
MATT: So you go ahead and suffer six points of
piercing damage. The first one you deflect, the
second one hits you, jamming into one of the
plates, bending the armor, and hitting you in the
side. You feel your body tense from the severe
pain. But it's nothing, you've had worse.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Just not the face.
MATT: Quazirat, you're up.
LIAM: Is there a clear path between where I'm
standing and either bridge?
MATT: Well, one bridge is currently collapsed. The
one on the right you could run through, but you
would probably be getting attacked from both the
kobolds that ran across and are blocking the path.
You'd have to take an attack of opportunity from
both of them.
LIAM: Yeah, that sounds fun. I'm going to run for
edge of bridge on this side. How far is that for
me where I'm starting?
MATT: I'd say it's about 15 feet from you now.
LIAM: That's good. I like it. 15 feet is good. I
run towards edge.
MATT: Okay, so you run to the edge. You go past
the two kobolds. Are you just running past them?
LIAM: Yes.
MATT: All right, they both get attacks of
opportunity on you. The first one is-- Wow, the
golden snitch is working for me now. That is 21 to
hit.
LIAM: Sure, that hits.
MATT: That is seven points of piercing damage as
the pickaxe swings and snags you in the back of
the shoulder blade. The other one is a 17 to hit.
LIAM: No, eat shit.
MATT: That one scrapes across the back of your
armor and makes no effective impact. You continue
rushing across the bridge--
LIAM: No. I used 15 feet to get here. I'm going to
do my running long jump for 25 feet over 20 foot bridge
you describe to me and land on other side. And
move up to this asshole on other side.
MATT: Okay. You cannot jump further than your
movement speed, technically. So you run, you jump,
and you're getting right towards the edge there. I
would like you to go ahead and make an acrobatics
check.
LIAM: Oh, you think I would understand this
mechanic before this moment in my life at level
seven. What kind of check?
MATT: This would be an acrobatics check.
LIAM: Okay. Oh, not great at all. But I get to add
two because of Remarkable Athlete, so hopefully
that's enough. 14.
MATT: 14. You were prepared. You make your way
through the air, barely catch the edge of where
the other platform begins, and you roll over the
shoulder into it. And as you come to stand, you're
right there before the leader kobold who's there
with his giant pack there ready as he has another
one of these sticks that he's currently trying to
pull up to the candle on his head. What are you
going to do?
LIAM: I'm how far from him?
MATT: You're right up against him.
LIAM: Oh, well I'm going to take his head off. I
had a pet rat but I don't care. Here we go. Oh,
that's a one! But I have an extra attack, so I
will go again. Oh, that's so bad! That's a 12.
MATT: As you confidently grin, your massive
draenei body looking down upon this kobold, who
looks like he got caught with his hand in the
cookie jar, you swing wide with-- What weapon are
you using?
LIAM: I'm using greatsword.
MATT: This giant two-handed cleaver that swings,
and the kobold goes (hums).
LIAM: I'm going to attempt to embarrass myself
further and use action surge.
MATT: Okay, make two more attacks. He dodges both
of your swings.
LIAM: Colville, don't fuck me, Colville!
MATT: It's now laughing.
LIAM: 15 for the one.
MATT: 15 just misses.
LIAM: But this last one is okay! 17.
MATT: 17 does hit.
LIAM: Yes, finally!
MATT: He dodges the third one and goes, "You have
problem? Can't hit?"
LIAM: Oh Fievel, your troubles are just beginning.
That is ten slashing damage.
MATT: Ten slashing damage. You take a chunk out of
his shoulder. "This favorite shoulder!"
LIAM: Kiss my sword. The hilt says Leeron Jenkins.
Let's get this shit started!
MATT: Perfect. Ending your turn. To the top. It is
your turn, Aerwin. So there are now currently four
living kobolds. Well, one of them has fallen into
the river, who is currently beneath the water,
struggling against the current. There is one that
is partially damaged that is currently up against
and fighting him. Actually, no, two of them that
are up against fighting you and one that's up
against you.
JENNIFER: But this one also--
MATT: Yes, there's the main leader across the way
that he's currently up against.
LIAM: So, you attack this guy, you get sneak
attack damage because I am right up against him.
JENNIFER: Yes, I want to do that.
MATT: All right, so you're taking another shot
with your crossbow?
JENNIFER: Yes.
MATT: All right, so you load up another bolt. And
then aiming across the way. Making your way up
close to where the bridge is, you'll end up being
in the melee range of the one that's fighting her,
but you can still make the strike.
LIAM: Acceptable risk.
JENNIFER: All right, so I roll a d20?
MATT: Go ahead and roll your attack.
LIAM: What'd you get? Plus your crossbow--
JENNIFER: 19.
MATT: 19 hits, go ahead and roll damage plus sneak
attack damage.
LIAM: So, 1d6 to start, then you add the other
cubes. Okay, that's good.
JENNIFER: And then I add these guys? Okay. 18.
LIAM: Plus?
JENNIFER: 23.
MATT: As the kobold's still laughing after the
blows of your warrior friend swinging wide, It's
like, "It's fun, I take you with me! It's--" You
watch as a crossbow bolt slinks right into where
the top of the clavicle in the kobold's neck is.
It's reaching up to try and pull it out. Its
fingers look like it's going numb and it looks
hurt. It's holding on but it's hurt. That's a
nice, slick shot. So, you've made your movement.
You have a bonus action if you wanted to do
anything.
JENNIFER: Well, I'm right next to the one that's
attacking her, correct? I think I'll turn around
with the short sword--
LIAM: Nope, you cannot do that with bonus. But is
she up against any kobolds at the moment?
MATT: She's right next to one that's been fighting
her.
LIAM: Well, the best you could do with a bonus is
maybe to disengage. Which means get away from them
so they cannot hurt you. But you cannot hit again
with--
JENNIFER: Okay, I'll disengage.
LAURA: Yeah, leave me alone next to it, thank you.
Thank you for the good advice.
LIAM: That's good advice. Just dance back a little
bit.
MATT: So with the five feet of your movement left,
you go ahead and step away, using your bonus
action to disengage, carefully stepping from the
kobold as it's going feral right now, feeling
surrounded. That ends your turn. You're up,
Lohkor.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I am over these guys right next to
me. Warhammer! That is a 22.
MATT: 22 will definitely hit.
TRAVIS: That is 12 points of bludgeoning damage.
MATT: 12 points of bludgeoning damage. As it comes
down, the hammer slams into the chest area of one
of the kobolds that's harassing you. It hits him
and you hear this little squeak sound as the chest
cavity takes a very heavy blow. Still standing,
but it's hurt.
TRAVIS: Still standing, eh? Round two! That is a
25.
MATT: That definitely hits. Go ahead and roll
damage.
TRAVIS: Another 12 points of bludgeoning damage.
MATT: And with that you use the momentum of
pulling away to swing upward and from the
underhand to hit. It snaps against the bottom of
the kobold's jaw and you hear its neck (cracks)
from the impact and it falls onto its back as its
legs curl back into its torso. And it's done.
TRAVIS: With my bonus action I turn and point to
the last standing one: My eye sees you.
MATT: You swear you see a slight tinkle dribble
down its leg. All right, that ends your turn. At
this point, the leader over there who's glaring at
you goes, "No, Ham has to finish his work!" And
he's going to go ahead and grab one of the-- Yeah,
it regenerates. Rolled a five. He pulls another
what you recognize now to be sticks of dynamite.
And looking at his pack you can see his pack is
filled. It wasn't candles in that pack. It is
jam-filled with explosives. And he goes rushing
past you. You get an attack of opportunity on him.
LIAM: Oh good, yes. He's got lots of candles!
Yeah, that's good. That's 24.
MATT: That hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
LAURA: Chop his head off!
LIAM: I'm trying! It's a ten.
MATT: Ten points of damage. (yells) Takes a heavy
hit but continues rushing past the bridge area.
Then, as he's rushing, he lights it from the top
of his head and chucks it in your guys' direction.
As it lands, it detonates, taking out-- let's see
here. Damage-wise, everybody but you needs to go
ahead and roll a dexterity saving throw please.
LAURA: Oh no, this is bad.
LIAM: Okay, so you did quite good with 22, yeah.
TRAVIS: That's a one.
MATT: 21 points of fire damage.
LAURA: 15.
MATT: 15 just barely succeeds, so you take 12
points of fire damage.
TALIESIN: Yeah, no.
MATT: I said 21, right? Sorry, so it's ten points
of fire damage. 21 points of fire damage.
JENNIFER: 22.
MATT: Ten points of fire damage.
LIAM: Does she have evasion?
MATT: You do, so you take nothing.
LIAM: Zero! Because rogue is best class.
MATT: So you, seeing this coming, you jump
backwards, grab the kobold that's in front, and
use him to shield you from the blast. And he goes
(screams) and scatters into ash as it manages to
detonate and explode the remaining kobolds in the
area. So all the kobolds that were with him have
all fallen to the ground now, turned to ash, or
detonated in some way. And you can see as the
leader of them is catching his breath across the
bridge, he goes, "Oh no." And he glances past with
his long gaze, and you can look over at the other
kobolds that had their own small caches of
dynamite sticks, some of which have been lit by
the recent explosion, that are rolling towards the
rock wall where you guys entered.
TRAVIS: We've got to go! Double dash, all the way
out!
MATT: So you guys all start rushing towards where?
Off the bridge?
LAURA: Across the bridge, right?
MATT: All right. So, I need all of you guys to--
Let's have everyone roll an initiative check right
now since technically the combat here is finished.
We're going to do this as to see who can manage to
make it across before the explosion.
TRAVIS: It's going to be an early night.
TALIESIN: What's the check again?
MATT: Just roll initiative.
LAURA: 19.
TRAVIS: Four.
TALIESIN: God, why am I rolling so bad? Ten.
JENNIFER: 16.
LIAM: 14.
MATT: Okay. You were pretty much mostly fine
across the bridge. All of you go rushing past as
you see Lohkor going (huffing and explosion). You
see the whole room behind him light up. You can
see a silhouette. It's full-on movie style
explosion as you see it burn past him. You only
catch the edge of it, which is good, because you
then only suffer eight points of fire damage. But
you watch as the entrance you guys came through
falls and collapses, a series of boulders and
rocks, the opposite end of the chamber falling in
on itself. Part of the river, you can see the
kobold that's barely clawing its way out of the
water, (panting) "Huh?" (thud). A rock hits and
smashes him across the bank. Part of the river
fills in and you can see now the bank splashing
over and starting to try to make its way back. But
you guys are now on the opposite side of the
chamber. It's quiet. You all take a minute to
breathe, look at your wounds. You're a bit singed
around the way--
TRAVIS: I'm putting out the fire in my hair. I use
Lay on Hands to put out the fire.
LAURA: Oh, I forgot to do this. And I cast Mage
Armor on myself.
TRAVIS: Before. Much better than after.
TALIESIN: I'm going to maybe do a Prayer of
Healing. Also, technically speaking, I have
Disciple of Light, which means-- Would everyone
have gained an extra five points?
MATT: They would've, yes. Keep that in mind. Next
time. We'll say for now, you guys all would've
healed an additional five points of damage because
he is really good at healing as a priest.
LIAM: You want to take like five, or maybe even 20
minutes here before we go forward?
TRAVIS: I mean we're hot on the trail.
LAURA: Why do we need to do that?
LIAM: I don't know. You know, conserving energy,
that kind of thing. Let's go! You want to kick
ass, I can tell. Little one, let's go.
JENNIFER: I'm with her. I will now call her Small
and Brave. I'm with Small and Brave. SB for short.
TALIESIN: I can't do Prayer of Healing while we're
walking though, can I? It's just verbal.
MATT: Is it the ten minute one? You have to sit
still for ten minutes to do it.
TALIESIN: Ten minutes to heal everybody up a bit.
So that's 2d8 plus my spellcasting ability
modifier?
TRAVIS: That's not long enough for hit dice and
stuff though?
MATT: So roll 2d8 plus your wisdom modifier.
TALIESIN: Oh my god, really?
MATT: Double ones?
TALIESIN: Yep.
TRAVIS: You gave the golden snitch away, Taliesin.
This is the beginning of the end.
LAURA: Did he really?
LIAM: He tossed it at the DM.
TALIESIN: So that's nine points of healing to
everybody.
MATT: Still good. All of you guys heal nine
points. That's not bad.
JENNIFER: Okay, so we already added the five, but
we don't get the five?
MATT: Nine on top of that.
JENNIFER: Nine more on top of the five? Okay.
MATT: As Bundle finishes the Prayer of Healing and
you all feel your wounds begin to close and stitch
themselves together, you see a little bit of
movement at the edge of the banks. Between the
rock that had plummeted into it, you watch as a
tiny hand-- Climbing out of the water you see a
very bloodied, smashed, one eye swollen kobold.
LAURA: Can I use Firebolt at it?
TRAVIS: No! Don't you want to ask maybe what they
were doing down here, or what their plans might
be?
LAURA: Oh, I mean sure, if that sounds good to
you!
TRAVIS: I think it might be wise.
LAURA: I'm a rage monster. I just like to kill
things!
TRAVIS: I know that about you.
JENNIFER: That's why she's my new best friend.
LAURA: Go for it.
TRAVIS: Can I go over and pick it up by the back
of the neck?
MATT: (squeals)
TRAVIS: Hello, friend. Before I let one of these
fine people--
MATT: As he's scrambling right now, looking up at
the candle which is currently out because of the
waterlogged, it's like (whimpers).
TRAVIS: I know, a very sad face. Before one of
these fine people sends you to your maker, what
were you doing in here?
MATT: "Okay. Just, you friend, right? I work,
help!"
TRAVIS: Yes, friend. Much more work for you,
friend.
MATT: "Reeksus."
TRAVIS: Wicksis.
TRAVIS: Reeksus.
LAURA: You understand what he's saying? Because I
can't tell at all.
MATT: "We sent by great King Togwaggle. Togwaggle
send us to make bigger booms! Make better tunnels
"to people town!"
TRAVIS: Yes, I am aware of people town.
MATT: "King Togwaggle greatest, best of all
kobolds!"
LIAM: How are those tunnels coming? You've made
them, or making them?
MATT: "We made and make more, by the glory of
Rakanishu and King Togwaggle."
TRAVIS: King Togwaggle, is he here with you now,
close by?
MATT: He looks back towards the closed door.
TRAVIS: Back that way?
LAURA: Does the king have all of our candles?
MATT: "Lots of candles."
LAURA: Lots of candles. We should talk to him.
JENNIFER: How many people are with the king?
MATT: "People? No people."
JENNIFER: Sorry, how many of your kind are with
the king?
MATT: "King is not very kind either, but is good
king!"
JENNIFER: Are there many kobolds with the king?
MATT: "There is a few."
JENNIFER: More than there were here?
MATT: "Depends on the time of day."
LAURA: What about now?
MATT: "I don't know, we've been away for a
while."
JENNIFER: When do you eat? When do the kobold
eat?
MATT: "When there is food."
LAURA: I like him. Can we keep him?
TRAVIS: And what would we do with him?
MATT: "Do you have food to eat?"
JENNIFER: Do all the kobold eat together?
LAURA: I pull out some beef jerky and hand it to
him.
MATT: (messy chewing)
JENNIFER: There's more where that came from if you
answer the question. Are there more than those of
us you see here of the kobold?
MATT: "There are, but scattered. Dangerous
tunnels, find dangerous things. Wander. Avoid
"them! We do."
TRAVIS: Quazi, do you think maybe you could
convince him to show us safe passage?
LIAM: Safe passage, convince him? Oh, yes. Bring
closer.
MATT: (squeals) And you catch him as he throws
him.
LIAM: Your hands, what I like about them is
they're so little (bones snapping).
MATT: (yelps) Make an intimidation check. With
advantage for breaking his hands.
LIAM: That's a 17.
MATT: (screams and sobs)
LIAM: Okay, I can do this to you five more times.
MATT: "No, I only have two hands!"
LIAM: I can play this game all night long, little
man. So we need to get inside. We need to be, you
know, alive and not getting killed, so we would
like to keep you. She has lots of beef jerky, we
could feed you. But we can't have any, what did
you call these?
MATT: "Boom booms. Okay, I show you. I show you!
Don't break! No more arms left to break."
LAURA: Aw, heal him, please? His poor hands!
LIAM: Well let him earn it first, you know? Maybe,
20 minutes we're still alive, you have healed hand
and more meat.
MATT: "Okay. Put me down?"
LIAM: I'm not holding you.
TRAVIS: Yes, you are.
LIAM: You gave him to me? I like this guy. Pat pat
pat.
MATT: In the rush of combat, you didn't realize
that you were clutching him the whole time.
LIAM: Well, I went like this. I thought you were
holding him. You know, Dungeons & Dragons is funny
thing. Your mind's different from my mind. Who
knows what we're seeing? I drop his ass on
ground.
MATT: "We need to go through door."
JENNIFER: Should we secure him?
LAURA: If you want.
TALIESIN: We've got rope.
TRAVIS: Just so we make sure you don't break your
other hand, she's going to make sure that you're
secure.
MATT: "Okay."
JENNIFER: Do I need to roll something for that?
MATT: No, easy enough. He waits for you-- You have
rope on you?
JENNIFER: I do, I have rope.
MATT: Okay, so you go ahead and you bind him up
and you have a little leash that you're holding
him by. And he's like, "Okay. To the door."
JENNIFER: Can I pass her the leash since he's her
pet?
MATT: "Oh. Pet?" Greldamine.
LAURA: What?
MATT: You're having a kobold's leash handed to
you.
JENNIFER: Can I pass him your leash? Would you
like to have him as a pet?
LAURA: Oh, well, all right.
MATT: Broken, jagged teeth, spittle drooling
down.
LAURA: I don't think he's much of a pet. He's more
of a companion.
MATT: "Could you light the candle?"
LAURA: I will in a little bit.
MATT: (whines)
JENNIFER: Hearts next to it.
LAURA: What's your name?
MATT: "Reeksus."
LAURA: Reeksus. You got it.
MATT: "Open door!"
TRAVIS: Through the door then.
LIAM: And I kick him really hard in the ass. Lead
the way.
MATT: The door is closed.
LIAM: Lead the way.
MATT: "I'm bound! You made me put rope on it!"
TRAVIS: Is there a latch, a door knob?
MATT: There is a handle latch and it looks like
there is a lock mechanism to it.
TRAVIS: Hmm, a lock.
JENNIFER: Whose purview is this?
LIAM: That's you. You take look. Make sure it does
not explode on you.
JENNIFER: I don't see any wicks. I don't see
anything explosive.
MATT: Make an investigation check if you want to
check for traps.
JENNIFER: Oh! 25.
TALIESIN: What did you roll? Well, she rolled a
20.
LAURA: That's important.
MATT: Very nice. It's a lock mechanism. A
relatively simple lock. It is not trapped. So, you
could easily undo this with your thieves' tools.
JENNIFER: So I do something so I can do that?
MATT: Yep, so you roll another d20, and then add
your proficiency modifier and your dexterity
modifier.
LIAM: This plus this, so plus eight to what you
roll.
JENNIFER: So that is 14.
MATT: Easy enough. The door unlocks, opens a bit,
and beyond that is a tunnel of darkness. An
interesting smell hits you as you open it though.
Whereas inside here you have that damp,
hard-water, Pirates of the Caribbean ride smell
that's in the water chamber, beyond that as the
door opens this musty, almost mildewed smell hits
you. It's earthy, it's fresh, it's natural, but
it's definitely an underground, familiar smell.
JENNIFER: Why can we never encounter a field of
flowers?
LAURA: Should I light up a rock again?
TALIESIN: Oh, I can do it. So I pick up a rock and
light it up, and toss it in front of us. Just keep
kicking it down.
MATT: It lights up the chamber as it goes, and you
continue to walk and kick it as you push forward.
The walls begin to slowly glow the further in you
go. You begin to notice that, aside from a few
small crystalline areas, there are heavy bits of
fungus that are beginning to appear along these
chambers. Glowing green, orange, blue mushrooms
and clusters of fungal matter that are beginning
to give this faint luminescence to the interior of
the chamber. And you now very much understand
where the smell was coming from. As you begin to
curve around the right side of it, the tunnel
widens a little broader to about 15 feet wide. The
mushrooms begin to get larger and larger, some of
them four feet tall or bigger. You can see large
pillar stalactites and stalagmites are meeting in
the center where they give their own little
offshoots of fungus. But some of these are getting
very big and the pathways are getting a little
narrow to move past until, as you turn around one
of the right bends, the fungus is pushed around to
the point where it's a very narrow passage to push
through these fungal forests.
LIAM: I don't like mushrooms.
LAURA: They're quite tasty, actually.
TALIESIN: Could make a glowing salad of some
kind.
LAURA: Ooh, yeah. Hey, Reeksus.
MATT: "Yeah?"
LAURA: I give him a little bit of beef jerky.
Okay. Do you want to go in front of us and lead
the way to your king?
MATT: "Okay." And he carefully turns to his side
and thins up and slowly-- with disadvantage
because he's bound-- still effectively manages to
squiggle his way between the small path. And you
can see he knows it pretty well, through the small
cluster of dense tall fungus safely to the other
side.
LAURA: Is it bad to touch it?
MATT: "I would not recommend it."
LIAM: And the rope is still trailing from him?
MATT: Yeah, it's 30 feet of slack rope. It's on
the ground over there.
TRAVIS: If only we had some fire.
LAURA: Oh. Do you want me to set these on fire?
Because I have some. I mean, is it safe to burn?
What if it sets off a poison when they're on fire?
I've heard that burning mushrooms could get you,
you know--
TRAVIS: Eating mushrooms.
LAURA: Oh, it's not fumes?
TALIESIN, LIAM and TRAVIS: No.
LAURA: Oh! I wouldn't know. They don't allow that
kind of stuff at mage school. Okay! I'm going to
go through! Wait, am I going to burn it? I'm going
to get to the other side and then I'm going to try
to burn it. I don't want to burn Reeks. Okay. I go
to the other side.
MATT: Okay. Go ahead and make a straight dexterity
check, please.
LAURA: All right. Woo-hoo! What is that, 18 or 19?
18 plus dexterity. 21.
MATT: Following suit, you deftly follow the same
pattern and come out the other side, not even
touching any of the fungus with either side of your
armored shoulder pauldrons. Your mantle, I guess
it would be.
LAURA: Should I try to burn them now? What do you
guys think?
LIAM: Depends on what we think biggest threat is.
Touching mushroom, breathing mushroom?
JENNIFER: Should we test it first? Touch it to
test it to see if it affects us?
TRAVIS: I'm afraid they might release spores and
then become airborne which is why I only recommend
trying to burn it first.
JENNIFER: That would release a lot of spores.
LIAM: How far away can you cast that shit from?
LAURA: It's ranged about eight. I don't know what
that means.
MATT: Is this Burning Hands?
LAURA: No, Fire Bolt.
MATT: Oh, Fire Bolt? Oh, it's a pretty decent
range. Just a single hit, yeah.
LIAM: What if we all back up to our different
sides, yeah? Get back as far as you can and we'll
get way the fuck back. See what happens.
LAURA: And then I'll hit it because I can do
cantrips a lot, right?
MATT: Cantrips you can do as many times as you
want.
LAURA: Fuck-- I mean heck yeah! I'm going to do--
TRAVIS: They don't let cursing happen in mage
school either?
LAURA: They don't curse in mage school. I'm sorry
about that.
MATT: Yeah, they're real tough on that in
Dalaran.
LAURA: They smack your hands. I'll tell you that
much.
MATT: They wouldn't tell you but Madame had a
potty mouth.
LAURA: I'm going to cast Fire Bolt at the
mushrooms. That gives me 2d10 fire damage.
MATT: Yes, even with a singular bolt, the
mushroom's pretty big and it's not moving. It's
pretty easy to hit. You hit the first one a while
away and as it impacts you watch as the flames
burn up. Immediately the strange, subtle squeaking
sound releases as it shakes and shimmies. And you
watch as spores filter out and then ignite from
the nearby flames that immediately destroy the
cloud before it can emerge. And the fungus slowly
withers and crumples over.
LAURA: Okay, good! I do the same thing on all of
the mushrooms that are along the path.
MATT: Okay. One by one you create this pathway,
destroying the fungus on the opposite side. Are
you still holding the rope?
LAURA: Yes.
MATT: Okay. As the flames begin--
LAURA: But I went through, remember? I went
through and I'm holding the rope on my side.
MATT: Right. So as you're destroying these the
rope pulls a little taut to your side as you begin
clearing the path. And you look over and you can
see your friend is peeking around a rock. You can
see this glow on the other side of a boulder
around the bend where he's looking over and looks
back at you and is like--
LAURA: What?
MATT: (mutters)
LAURA: Hold on.
MATT: "Okay." The rest of you guys, there is a
path wide enough to follow through.
TRAVIS: We join.
LAURA: They're coming? Okay, I go over to Reek.
MATT: As you guys approach you can see the small
flickering of light shift suddenly and a dark
shape of a figure whips around from behind the
rock. You see a flash of cloth that floats open
and then drifts down to the side as an arm
uncurls. You can see immediately wide-shouldered,
a broad long trench coat that swings open to one
side, a clawed, familiar, slightly furred hand
holding it open as a brownish hat, wide-brimmed,
appears with its candle placed on top of the brim.
You see another kobold standing there looking at
your tied-up friend and the rest of you. And he
goes, "Hey! Hey! Want to buy a fungus?" As you
look on the inside of the cloak you can see these
little patchwork pouches of different gathered
mushrooms, orange, green and blue. "I sell, good
"price. Come. Buy."
TALIESIN: Well--
LAURA: Well, what do they do?
MATT: "Taste good! Ugh. Bad. Good bad. Fun!"
LAURA: I don't understand what he just told me.
LIAM: I mean, to begin with you're not alarmed by
us being here in the first place?
MATT: "I need to make money."
TALIESIN: Let's not look a gift horse in the
mouth. A gift rat. Orange?
MATT: "Orange fungus. Slight citrus-y taste. Weird
fuzzy sensation. 40 gold."
TALIESIN: And the other two were--
TRAVIS: What about blue?
MATT: "Blue fungus. 30 gold. Make for good
digestion tract."
TRAVIS: I'll take the blue one.
LAURA: You have that much gold?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: You now have a helping of blue fungus.
TALIESIN: What's the third?
MATT: "Green fungus! 25 gold. More of the onion of
fungus family."
LAURA: That's a good topping.
MATT: "Yeah!"
LIAM: I grab rope that is holding Reekcheeks and
bring him over. "You know this one?"
MATT: "He is strange one. Don't like him. I
don't-- kobolds stay away."
LIAM: Is he problem?
MATT: (whispering) "I don't know."
LAURA: You be nice to him!
TRAVIS: It's the-- they're real--
LIAM: I punch him in the eye.
MATT: (cry of pain)
TALIESIN: You only live once. Orange.
LIAM: You've got to keep them in line with tough
love.
TALIESIN: I take the orange.
MATT: All righty.
TRAVIS: Do I know anything about this blue fungus?
MATT: Make a medicine check.
LAURA: It's good for digestion I hear.
TRAVIS: 16.
MATT: 16, okay.
TALIESIN: Oh, 20.
MATT: Okay. So eating this fungus has a chance of
poisoning you, but also has the opportunity to
heighten your senses and perceptive capabilities
for a short time.
LAURA: Ooh, it's a gamble.
TALIESIN: How about mine?
MATT: So that's the orange one, you got the--
TALIESIN: I have the orange.
MATT: You've got the orange.
LAURA: Yeah, he got the blue.
MATT: He got the blue, sorry, yeah. So the blue
one has a faint possibility of poisoning you.
Sorry, you're the blue. The orange one is the one
you got. So you get the heightened senses, yours
has a chance of poisoning you as well and or has
the possibility of healing some hit points.
TALIESIN: Down the hatch.
MATT: All right, both of you make constitution
saving throws.
LIAM: Give it to Mikey, he'll try anything.
TRAVIS: Now, because you're next to me I have Aura
of Protection which is plus two to saves?
MATT: Yeah, it would.
TALIESIN: Oh, that helps because my constitution's
really low.
TRAVIS: Yes! 21.
TALIESIN: Eight.
MATT: Okay, so you're poisoned for the next hour.
The poisoned status means all of your
attacks are at disadvantage and your ability
checks are at disadvantage as well. So you have
advantage on all perception and investigation
checks for the next hour.
LIAM: Everything is crystal clear.
MATT: Yeah, your eyes dilate suddenly and I know
kung-fu.
TRAVIS: Yeah! Show me.
MATT: Bundle, you heal six hit points.
TALIESIN: I heal six?
LAURA: Ooh, at least it healed you while it
poisoned you.
TALIESIN: I'm also going to cast Lesser
Restoration and make the poison go away.
MATT: Okay. So the poison vanishes from your
system at which point the kobold, "Mushhuckster
"Max thanks you. Now off to find new ventures!"
Pulls the cloak in front of his head and darts
away on little ninja feet. Back through the
mushrooms and vanishes into darkness.
TALIESIN: It's weird he's selling mushrooms to
random people in caverns like that.
TRAVIS: I highly recommend the blue fungus.
LIAM: In another life, I would have hit that guy
before he said a single word. I would have dropped
his ass.
TRAVIS: Somehow I know that to be true about you.
MATT: At this point you hear a strange guttural
growl from the path that you were traveling near a
pillar of stone encased in mushrooms as from
around one back of it you see a shape of a large,
hunched, bestial dwarf ape-like creature standing
at about six and a half feet tall as its long arms
drag on the ground. It's drooling down its own
chest. You've experienced, most of you in particular,
this is a trogg, a large subterranean creature,
but this trogg is acting strange. It's giggling to
itself. (deep laughter) Holds the pillar and grabs
some mushroom and scarfs it.
LAURA: Oh no.
JENNIFER: Here we go.
MATT: (grunts) And he starts walking around the
edge, looks around the edge right to you, "It's
"real?"
TALIESIN, JENNIFER, and LAURA: No!
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
TALIESIN: Come on! Natural 20! About fucking time!
There we are! No!
MATT: "Too weird! I see things!" You see two other
large troggs come from behind going. They're
tripping balls. One of them is currently clutching
a long staff of purple and gold inlay and is
gnawing on it like a large lollipop. You can't see
the top because it's jammed in his mouth. They're
all looking at you going (laughing).
TALIESIN: I'm going to use Thaumaturgy to make us
all look really fuzzy, in and out, if I can do
that.
MATT: You may.
TALIESIN: Ooh!
MATT: No. Okay! They all stand there and watch.
(groaning) One of them picks his nose slowly.
TALIESIN: I hadn't thought this through.
LAURA: I use Prestidigitation and create light
flares around him.
MATT: One elbows one in the chin, the guy who was
holding the staff, he elbows him the chest.
(gagging) Pulls it out. You can see on the top of
the staff, it has these awesome, pointed purple
stones, three of them in a triangular pattern that
float, locked into place. (licking) Jams it back
in his mouth and begins chewing on it again.
TALIESIN: Can I make the staff look like it's made
of snakes or something? Can I Thaumaturgy?
MATT: Unfortunately, that's an illusion spell.
Thaumaturgy is very simple. It's a very faint
effect that wouldn't have an effect if they
weren't already tripping balls.
LAURA: If they're already tripping can we say:
Whoa, why are you holding that snake in your
hand?
MATT: Make a persuasion check!
LAURA: Please! Oh no, 11.
MATT: 11. He goes (gags). Pulls it out, looks at
it, "Hey, a snake!" and begins trying to bite
through. You watch as his teeth are breaking on
the metal.
TRAVIS: I'll cast Command on him and say: drop
that wicked snake!
MATT: Okay! What's your spell DC?
TRAVIS: 13.
MATT: He rolled a 13 minus one. This trogg is not
very wise. Drops it. You see he's putting his
tongue through his mouth and bits of teeth are
falling out of his lips and bouncing off of his
belly. (grunts) They're all currently entranced by
the movement and the lights that you've created.
JENNIFER: I'd love to collect the thing.
MATT: Make a stealth check to see if you can not
gather their gaze as they're currently entranced
by this.
TRAVIS: We're doing our best outside inflatable
people.
JENNIFER: 21.
MATT: 21. You slowly, subtly go beneath their
eyeline, slip out, and pull the staff away as
they're all still (gasping). One of them begins
picking his ear, pulls something out, and eats
it.
(groaning)
LAURA: We should back away slowly.
MATT: (farts)
TALIESIN: Oh, slowly. Okay!
LAURA: Reeks, if we leave them, will you keep
guiding the way?
MATT: "Behind them? The way is where they came
from."
TRAVIS: Quazi? Feel like introducing yourself?
LIAM: Good news, my brothers. We come from both
the future and the past.
MATT: All three of them (grunt).
LIAM: Let me tell you. Your fathers are proud of
you.
MATT: The two on the sides look in to the one in
the center who goes, "You know father?"
LIAM: I've been this fucked up before. Your
mothers love you and are proud of you!
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
LIAM: Persuasion, you said. That's 18.
MATT: 18? His giant, meaty, fur-covered hands clap
onto your shoulders of your armor and pulls you in
close. You can smell the horrible trogg breath
billow out across your face. Almost thickens the
air around you. It smells of rotting meat and a
multitude of terrible memories.
LIAM: And the deep secret is: You know that I am
you.
MATT: He releases you and takes a step back and
goes. (sobbing) And starts sobbing openly. The two
other troggs clap the side of his shoulders and
start sobbing, too. The three of them sit in place
and start having the most basic of existential
crises you could watch.
TALIESIN: Slowly making our way around the
existential crisis.
MATT: The rest of you make a stealth check. You
already made one. The rest of you make a stealth
check.
LIAM: Doing inches this way like an arc. And Papa
and Mama don't want you to hurt you! You have to
love you!
MATT: You get the sense they're picking up every
third word due to the limits of their language
comprehension. They're like, (grunting) "Love!
(grunting) Ove! (sobbing) Guh!" They're just
making guttural noises at this point.
LIAM: Give into it.
MATT: Make a stealth check, please.
LIAM: Oh, that's a 20!
MATT: As you guys slowly curve around the three
sobbing troggs, staff in hand, you exit through
the tunnel they had passed through. The fungus
begins to give way as the heat begins to rise
steadily once you traverse further into this
tunnel. You're holding the staff. As you're
walking, looking over it, a slow voice beings to
peek in seemingly from nowhere. It says, "Oh,
"wondrous. Another unworthy soul. I command you to
throw me into a river and be done with it."
JENNIFER: Hmm. First, you must tell us your
secrets.
MATT: "I require a wielder who walks the path of
power, fool."
LAURA: What's it saying?
JENNIFER: It requires a wielder who walks the path
of power, fool.
LAURA: Magic?
JENNIFER: I'm not calling you a fool, it's calling
you a fool. Magic.
LAURA: I do magic!
JENNIFER: Take him.
MATT: As you take the staff, it warms to your
touch. For a moment, there's an awkward silence
of: did she actually hear anything, or has your
friend been crazy the whole time you've been
traveling?
JENNIFER: Both.
MATT: A voice slowly echoes in, "Ah, you! You have
potential. A withered seed that could blossom into
"a tyrant of the arcane."
LAURA: Well, I'm pretty blossomed already, but
okay.
MATT: "Yes. You will do. I am Aluneth and
together, we will do great things." And that's
where we're going to take a break.
TRAVIS: Ooh! You've got sentient weapons in this
thing! The little gems are floating in a
triangle?
MATT: They're held aloft by some mystical power.
LAURA: Fancy!
MATT: I'll show you pictures of it.
TRAVIS: Nicely done! Your baptism is going well!
JENNIFER: Sorry about trying the narrative thing!
I was like: Oh shit!
MATT: No, it's all good! First time in, you just
figure it out. You're doing great.
JENNIFER: Oh, there's a wall there!
MATT: Thank you guys so much. We're going to to go
break. We'll be back in a few minutes. Rest, get
drinks. We have some fun stuff at the break for
you to watch. You get to check out, if you haven't
seen it, the song I sing for this expansion.
Pretty sure it's coming up.
LAURA: Notebooks in the store!
MATT: Yep!
JENNIFER: Where's the notebook?
LIAM: Show the Feywild!
TALIESIN: Now I want to do Russian now.
MATT: We'll be back here in a few minutes. We'll
see you then.
[break]
MATT: Welcome back, everybody. Before we dive in,
the winner of the Wyrmwood giveaway is
flashfletch33. So congratulations, flashfletch33.
Danoba will get your contact info and we'll get
that off to you ASAP. Also, I was just notified
that the chat had discovered: back when vanilla
launch happened, I was one of the people waiting
at the midnight launch of World of Warcraft
outside of a cold Best Buy in Irvine many years
ago, and started my long trek on the RP server
Silverhand at launch. I discovered today via
fatalcake23 in the chat that there is both a Vox
Machina and a Slayer's Take guild on the server I
started on, which is so weird and full circle.
Yeah, we used to play on that server.
TALIESIN: Yeah, you dragged me onto Silverhand!
MATT: Yeah, so that's kind of cool. So hi,
everybody on Silverhand and those guilds and
beyond.
TALIESIN and MATT: It's been a while.
LIAM: We are such fake nerds.
TRAVIS and TALIESIN: Totes fake.
TRAVIS: I just want to go deadlift right now.
JENNIFER: I aspire to nerd.
MATT: You aspire what?
MATT: All right. So as we come back in, you have
acquired--
LAURA: Yay! Should I read it out loud?
MATT: If you'd like to.
LAURA: I have acquired Aluneth. "This ancient,
extremely powerful staff was once owned by
"Aegwynn." Egwin. Agewin.
MATT: Sure.
LAURA: "The only female guardian of Tirisfal. This
staff carries a mind far more ancient than most
"things in Azeroth." My spell attack rolls gain a
+3 to hit. Whenever I deal damage, I deal two
additional hit points of force damage. That's
amazing.
MATT: As you're clutching the staff, as it speaks
to you in your mind: "Together, we will do great
"things. But you must survive. So: be smart. Stay
alive. And perhaps ditch these unnecessary
"dregs."
LAURA: They're pretty cool, actually. Well, some
of them.
TRAVIS: Who's cool?
LAURA: What?
TALIESIN: Well, I'm cool.
LAURA: What are you talking about?
LIAM: What are you doing? Did you eat mushrooms?
TRAVIS: You said "They're pretty cool."
LIAM: You were talking out loud to no one.
LAURA: Oh, no! It's the staff! It has a voice!
JENNIFER: What did it say? I heard it.
LAURA: It said that I'm really amazing and that
I'm going to do good things. I think that it's
like a really powerful weapon. It's like the kind
of thing you take with you for several levels at
least.
TALIESIN: How did we agree that you get the epic
loot drop?
TRAVIS: Staff of flirting.
JENNIFER: He wouldn't speak to me. I'm too tall.
LAURA: That's probably what it is.
LIAM: I think it's your own positive nature,
speaking to you from yourself.
LAURA: That's possible. My mama and papa are very
proud of me.
LIAM: I mean, that's up to you and them. I don't
know shit about that.
JENNIFER: Is he you?
LAURA: Is it a he? I don't know.
LAURA: Oh, him? Not staff. I'm confused.
MATT: Your perceptive Night Elf sense picks out
the air becoming more sulfurous as you progress.
You all begin to feel a bit uncomfortable in your
armor as the temperature gets warmer and warmer.
As this tunnel descends slightly and then comes to
an abrupt leveling point, you can see a faint
orange glow begin to fill the chamber before you
as the pathway opens up to a large, cavernous
dome. The floor of this new chamber is cracked,
with dark soot, and brittle, black rock. The room
seems to maintain its own atmospheric,
reddish-orange glow across the entirety of the
roof. Roughly 30 feet into this chamber, you get a
glance at the source of light as the rocky floor
suddenly drops off into a river of roiling, molten
magma. The heat at this point is extremely
intense, causing you to squint as you back away
from the edge. There's a series of pillars that
rise from the lava into platforms. In fact, it
looks like at one point, two wide stone bridges
that were perpendicular, meeting in the center,
once reached across this lava field, both from
where you stand and then one on two opposite ends
of this cavern, where you can see openings on the
opposite end to the right of where you are, and
then to the left, it appears a portion of it has
collapsed and closed it off. These bridges,
however, through time and erosion, have fallen in
parts. And to give you a visual perspective of
what you're glancing at, you entered from this
chamber. These are the existing platforms still.
The shaded elements represent ones that are down
in the lava, and resting there. There's a slight
alcove over here, there's a number of dotted bits
here and here, this appears to have collapsed, and
there's an opening here and an opening here.
You're currently on this platform.
TALIESIN: See, this would have been an appropriate
place to build bridges that are kind of iffy. Two
of them, even.
LAURA: Yeah. Hey, Reeks?
MATT: "What?"
LAURA: Which direction is your king?
MATT: "Uh--" And he bends forward and tries to get
one hand up, and the finger goes like--
LAURA: Hey, look! Your hands are working again!
MATT: "Ow!"
(laughter)
LIAM: Mind over matter.
MATT: "They mostly just let me through."
LAURA: Oh, Okay, well, we'll figure it out.
TRAVIS: Now, now, you know King Tagwaggle will be
very disappointed--
MATT: "Togwaggle!"
TRAVIS: Togwaggle will be very disappointed if we
are not brought before him.
MATT: "Wait. Across." And the finger, the broken
hand, tries to lift up. "Across. I remember! That
"way. That way to Togwaggle."
LAURA: Straight across?
MATT: "Yes."
TALIESIN: I want to take a quick insight check and
give him an eye. I don't trust this one. That's
not bad. That's a 16.
MATT: 16? Kind of hard to read. You get the sense
that something doesn't sit right with the way he's
saying it.
LIAM: Aerwin, do you see anything hinky in this
room? Anything off? Bad?
MATT: You can make a perception check if you
like.
JENNIFER: I'd like to make a perception check.
TRAVIS: Can I join her with my heightened senses
from my blue fungi?
MATT: You may. With advantage.
LIAM: What's that? Okay, that's 16, plus
perception.
JENNIFER: So, 23.
TRAVIS: 18.
MATT: All right. So as you both glance over, you
notice the part that's collapsed and taken down
that portion of the bridge, there is no way
through. It is completely sealed off. You both
notice simultaneously, on the central cross
platform in the center of the chamber, where you
see across the broken center there's a bunch of
scraps of metal. Empty shells of armor
plates that have been left there and have long
been covered in dust and soot. You notice with
your fair vision that the small alcove on the far
end of the upper corner that's down near the
surface of the lava, it appears to be two figures
lying down in the shadows there. You can't make
out much more detail than that, but there appears
to be two humanoid entities that are currently
resting on that platform.
LAURA: They're laying a trap. I'll bet you
anything.
JENNIFER: We need to get closer.
TALIESIN: With darkvision, could I see them?
MATT: At this distance, no. You'll probably have
to get closer to the central platform to get a
better view.
TALIESIN: All right. I'm going to try and go for
the central platform.
LAURA: Wait! But you just said there's a big pile
of metal in the middle, and two creatures hiding!
What if they're waiting to explode the middle?
LIAM: And we're standing here talking in this
chamber.
JENNIFER: Could I take some of my ball bearings
and go across? I have my ball bearings in my
pocket to trip them, and go across and try to get
closer.
MATT: You could throw them out in front of you to
try and see if it hits them.
JENNIFER: No, I'll have them with me in case I
need them as a defense. Can I sneak across to see
them?
MATT: Okay. So you pull out your small pouch of
ball bearings, hold them in your hand. Go and make
a stealth check.
LIAM: That's good. You're going to be good.
JENNIFER: 23.
MATT: That's not bad. You have to leap across to
get to the smaller platform that's going up,
because there are the breaks in it. What's your
strength? Ten?
JENNIFER: Zero.
MATT: Right, so maximum ten. So you get about a
10-foot jump across that way. It's about a 10-foot
jump to get to that smaller platform. You, keeping
low, using the balls of your feet, make a leap for
it, just catching the edge ever so carefully. If
you can make an acrobatics check to use your
momentum to tumble onto it.
LIAM: Acrobatics, you say?
JENNIFER: 12 total.
MATT: 12! Okay. You barely use your momentum to
not tumble backward towards the molten rock below.
Using your shoulder, you roll, and using your
momentum you come to the other side of that and
leap a second time towards that other side of that
platform. I need you to make one more check for
me.
JENNIFER: 13.
MATT: 13. All right. So you leap, tumble, and you
make your way across the platform. As you stand
there, looking around, you get a quick glance down
into that little alcove below as you take in the
circumstance. You see there, there are two
figures. They are armored, they are lying down,
and they are skeletal. They are long burned away.
The flesh is gone. They long died there. Either
they were trapped and couldn't find a way out and
slowly starved or dehydrated, but there's nothing
but a pile of their equipment, their weapons,
their armor, and bone. At this point, the floor
below you gently rumbles a bit, and you watch as
some of the metal scraps scrape across the ground
on their own. They leap up into the air and form
bracers, some sort of large, thick pieces of
armor, separate, as molten rock shoots up and
flame ignites, filling the center of the empty
armor into a large, elemental-like enemy made of
fire and magma within the armor. You watch as this
magma rager, appearing, giving this flexing roar,
goes charging towards you. What are you doing?
JENNIFER: Am I doing this?
MATT: Well, you're definitely not hidden from it
yet. You have to hide first.
JENNIFER: Okay. Strength is not my thing. I think
I'm going to run.
MATT: Okay. So you run back the opposite
direction, leap, head across the way. Go ahead and
make an acrobatics check.
JENNIFER: 22.
MATT: Fine. You spin, roll off your shoulder,
leap, a second time on the other side, and make
one more acrobatics check.
JENNIFER: 16.
MATT: Not a problem. You make it across to the
other side and you watch as this large, raging
elemental stops at the edge, scoots back, and
stands there, waiting, on the center platform.
JENNIFER: Well, at least now we know.
LAURA: That's intimidating. What about the two
things laying in wait? Were they setting a trap?
JENNIFER: They were skeletons. They were done.
They were dead.
LAURA: They were undead?
JENNIFER: They're dead.
LAURA: Just dead.
JENNIFER: They were regular dead.
LIAM: Well, that's iffy. You know. But also
tempting. Because what did they have when they
died?
LAURA: We should definitely check it out.
LIAM: I can chuck you over.
LAURA: But there's a giant flame monster.
LIAM: Well, yeah. First one thing, then the
other.
LAURA: How are we going to beat him?
TRAVIS: I could stun him.
LAURA: You think that would work?
TRAVIS: Might. We'd have to be fast. And no one
could fall.
LIAM: I'm not going to fall.
TRAVIS: Why did you think I was saying that you
would fall?
LIAM: You were staring straight at me.
TRAVIS: Was I?
LIAM: Oh, yes.
TRAVIS: One of us could fall.
LIAM: Now you seem sarcastic, because you're
rolling your eyes.
LAURA: I'm not very good at jumping, but I can
cast Fly on myself.
JENNIFER: (gasps) She is invisible. She has
invisibility.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I think we have to get to-- did you
trust Skeever?
LAURA: Reeks?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: Well... Hey, that's a good point. Reeks?
MATT: "Yes?"
LAURA: Why didn't you warn us about the giant
monster in the middle there?
MATT: "Sorry, I forgot."
LAURA: Did you?
MATT: "Yes."
LAURA: What happened to your voice?
MATT: "What?"
JENNIFER: Did they die from the monster in the
middle because they are on the far side? Or did
they die trying to get out that entrance because
it is not really an entrance?
LAURA: That's deep. Maybe they just fell, and they
couldn't climb back up.
TRAVIS: They had to have gotten there for a
reason, right?
LIAM: There are these big bruisers floating there,
staring at us.
MATT: Just staring at you, yeah.
LIAM: You can fly.
LAURA: Yeah!
LIAM: I have seen you do it so many times. Can't
you skirt the edge of this room and go over there?
You don't need to go through this guy.
LAURA: Over to the alcove?
LIAM: Sure, see if there is anything worth, you
know. This is what we live for.
LAURA: I can try.
TRAVIS: Fly fly away. Fly far away.
LIAM: I am not going, too much hassle.
MATT: "Be careful. It's dangerous. Big fire
thing."
LAURA: Okay. What did you say?
MATT: "Big fire thing."
LAURA: Yeah, how do you make him go back to
sleep?
MATT: "Don't let him know you came."
LAURA: Okay. Tell you what, Lohkor. Will you hold
his leash, please?
TRAVIS: Sure!
LAURA: I'm going to fly! I know exactly how to do
it.
MATT: You cast it on yourself. It's a
concentration for I believe up to an hour?
LAURA: Ten minutes!
MATT: Ten minutes. Even better.
LAURA: Sure, yeah, I'm going to fly. And I'm going
to try to go over to that little alcove and see
what happens.
MATT: All right. So you watch as the tiny gnome
suddenly takes off and begins gliding across the
roof of this magma area.
LAURA: And I'm giving the creature a wide berth.
LIAM: Look, Laura, you're finally doing it.
MATT: As you're doing it, you watch as the magma
rager stares and tracks her as she goes. And as
you head across the way, it shifts to the very
edge of the platform, almost tensing at the border
and watches as you slowly descend towards this
platform. As you come down, make a perception
check.
LAURA: 17.
MATT: Glancing, you look down. Yeah, they are
charred and long dead. The armor appears to be
burned away. There are a few pieces of equipment
that have lasted okay, although covered in black
soot. There's a couple of small satchels that are
left there and looks like they were back to back.
Just hoping for help or trying to find a way off,
and eventually, they expired.
LAURA: I'm sorry you had a tragic ending. I'm
going to keep flying around them. I don't want to
touch my feet to the ground, in case something
comes out of the ground. But I'm going to dig
through all of their shit and see what I can find.
MATT: Make an investigation check.
TRAVIS: Wow. One.
LAURA: Goodbye.
MATT: Okay. Glancing through, most of it falls
apart as you grasp it. The armor crumples and
falls apart as you touch the armor. The only thing
that catches your attention because it is the one
piece of equipment that is shining amongst the
rest, is in one of the sheaths. There is a blade,
that as you pull it out, it's got this beautifully
wicked metal that curves into a point at the end,
like a forked point. It's got a bit of an energy
pulse gem in the center of where the hilt is. And
as you reach over to look at it, it looks pristine
untouched by time. (burps) Pardon me! A little
effervescent tonight, apparently! The soot wipes
off of it cleanly.
LAURA: I hold it aloft. I found a weapon. I'll
bring it back over to you guys.
LIAM: I also talk to you.
MATT: At this point, Aluneth does whisper and say
"You've already found a weapon. This is of no use
"to you."
LAURA: I'm not going to keep it. I'm going to give
it away.
MATT: "Good. The sooner, the better." Goes silent.
You watch as, coasting over, blade forth, the magma
rager still tensing against the edge as she flies
overhead.
LAURA: I wave it towards the creature as I fly by,
but I don't get close enough to really do
anything.
MATT: Greldamine finally lands on the ground,
presenting the blade.
LIAM: What kind of blade? How big is this thing?
MATT: It's a longsword. It's big for a longsword,
but it does technically act as a longsword.
LAURA: Which one of you would like this beautiful
blade?
TRAVIS: I would like to see it.
LIAM: I would also, but I would do roshambo with
you.
TRAVIS: Yep.
LIAM: Okay. Best out of three, or just one time?
TRAVIS: One time. Throw on four.
LIAM: On four?! I have intelligence of eight.
TRAVIS: Throw on three.
LIAM: Throw on three?
TRAVIS: Throw on one.
LIAM: Why are you changing it on me? Let's do it
on two. We go one, two, shoot. Okay? All right.
One, two, shoot! Oh shit, two papers. We go again.
One, two, shoot! Give me that shit.
MATT: It's a very fine blade.
JENNIFER: What's the name of her sword again?
MATT: Aluneth.
LAURA: It's a staff.
JENNIFER: Sorry. Does Aluneth have anything to say
about where we are?
LAURA: Oh mighty Aluneth, do you have anything to
say about where we are?
LIAM: You seem very crazy right now.
LAURA: It talks, I swear.
MATT: The voice comes back in from the aether. "I
do despise these subterranean regions. I don't
"recognize where we are. This world has changed
quite a bit since I last walked its surface."
LAURA: Yes.
JENNIFER: How long since you walked its surface?
LAURA: How long since you walked its surface? I
mean, I know, I've heard about Aluneth before.
It's very ancient.
MATT: "Of course you have. I don't know,
generations."
LAURA: Long time.
TALIESIN: Could you fly over to the--
MATT: Do you wish to attune to the weapon?
LIAM: Hell yeah. I am attuned to nothing, so I
will attune to this.
LAURA: You want me to go over to the collapse?
TALIESIN: Yeah, lead the creature over to that
section.
LAURA: Oh, okay! I'm going to fly over to the
collapsed area, because I've still got a little
time left, right?
MATT: Okay, so you coast over to the collapsed
area.
LAURA: And I land. Now what do you want me to do?
TALIESIN: I'm going to try and cast Hold Person on
the creature.
LAURA: Wait, I'll wave my arms so he walks toward
me.
MATT: Make an intelligence check.
TALIESIN: God, it won't work on him, will it?
MATT: Yeah, so the creature heads over and it's
focused on you. What'd you get?
TALIESIN: I got 20.
MATT: 20. You get the sense that Hold Person
mainly affects small humanoid creatures. A large
elemental like this would not be held by a spell.
LAURA: Is an elemental considered a monster?
MATT: It's considered a monster.
TRAVIS: Creature, though.
MATT: So you discovered your weapon.
LIAM: Yes. This was made for me. Should I be
describing this to the table? Yes, this is called
Adventurefury, Blessed Blade of the Thrillseeker.
This weirdly pristine longsword is encased in
meticulous, almost gaudy, gold scrolling and
rune-like carvings that spell out phrases like,
"Carpe Diem", like your shirt with donut, and "You
only live once." You gain plus two to all attacks
and damage rolls made with this weapon. You are
immune to fear and, if you ever attempt to flee
from danger, you must make a wisdom saving throw,
DC 12. On a failure, you instead rush toward the
challenge in hopes of glory. YOLO!
TRAVIS: Yes! That's a great item!
MATT: It's Adventurefury, Blessed Blade of the
Thrillseeker.
TRAVIS: Oh my god! Damn!
LAURA: Is that an actual blade in the game?
MATT: (chuckling) No.
LAURA: Please make it an actual weapon in the
game.
MATT: It's an inside joke.
LIAM: For Argus and for LRJenkins1234.
TRAVIS: I could try to stun him if we all wanted
to make a break for one side or the other. I'm not
sure if it would work, so, any other ideas?
JENNIFER: Which side?
LAURA: Straight through, I think! I mean, that's
what Reek said.
TRAVIS: Wasn't Reek lying?
LAURA: No! He's very trustworthy.
JENNIFER: I think there's something on the other
side that we don't know. We need to know.
TRAVIS: I cast Zone of Truth.
MATT: Okay. What's your spell DC? Oh, 13, right?
Nope.
LAURA: Yay!
TRAVIS: Cheeker-- what's his name? Oh, right,
Reek.
MATT: "Reeksus."
TRAVIS: Do you really know the way back to
Tagwaggle?
MATT: "I do, yes!"
TRAVIS: Which direction is it?
MATT: "That would be (straining) right!"
LAURA: He lied to me!
TRAVIS: He did. I'm sure it's nothing personal,
though!
MATT: "I'm bad with directions!"
LAURA: He's telling the truth! Do you like us?
Aww. Do you like me?
TRAVIS: No, he has to answer.
MATT: "I endure you!"
LAURA: I'll take it!
MATT: I endure you.
LIAM: Hey, Shakira, do you fear me?
MATT: (panicked wimper)
LIAM: Good, that's all that matters. Let's go.
LAURA: I think I'm running out of my ten minutes.
MATT: You're getting down to the last couple of
minutes.
LAURA: I need to stand up and I need to fly away
from this place, or else I'm going to be stranded
on this side!
TALIESIN: You can land wherever we need to be.
LAURA: Yeah, that's what I'm going to do, but I want to
fly around to the other side.
MATT: Okay, so you coast around to this platform
over here and land on the opposite side of the
bridge. The magma rager spins and is flexing in
the direction of where you are.
TRAVIS: While the Zone of Truth is still active,
Bundle, what are you the most afraid of?
MATT: Make a wisdom saving throw.
TALIESIN: Oh! That's a 24.
MATT: Answer as you feel.
TALIESIN: Not you. Not even a little. You're so
soft and squishy.
TRAVIS: No, see, if it was a spider, then I could
take care of it for you. I don't want to leave you
in an awkward situation.
JENNIFER: Should we leave you two alone?
TALIESIN: No.
MATT: "Yes!"
TALIESIN: Well, you only live once.
LAURA: What are you going to do?
TRAVIS: Do it.
TALIESIN: I'm going to make a run for it. Fuck
it.
MATT: What's your strength?
TALIESIN: My strength is 16.
MATT: 16? That's easy enough for you. You run and
leap, big dwarven strong legs. You leap across. You
land on the center platform, at which point the
magma rager turns to face you. What are you
doing?
TALIESIN: I'm going to cast Sacred Flame, which I
know will do very little on him, but it might
temporarily irritate him. I'm going to run the
opposite direction.
MATT: Okay, Sacred Flame. So he makes a dexterity
saving throw. No, it's an action to do that.
TALIESIN: Oh, it's an action to do that? Should I
burn my action running?
MATT: To dash? You can, if you want to. Okay, you
go running as it goes charging toward you. It's
going to go ahead and attempt to make a
charge-slam attack. That is going to be a 23 to
hit.
TALIESIN: Oh my god, yeah, that hits.
MATT: Double ones on the attack, so only six
points of bludgeoning damage.
TALIESIN: I can live with that.
MATT: Six points of fire damage.
TALIESIN: I can live with that too.
MATT: As it slams into you, you immediately get
pushed 15 feet back into the air. You arc
backwards. As you're falling back, you can look,
you're edging toward where the central platform
where you were before you go to the middle one,
and off to the side where the lava is. Go ahead
and make an acrobatics check.
TALIESIN: God, if I have to do an action, I hope I
can get an action before this happens. Acrobatics
check, oh god.
TRAVIS: Why'd you give the Snitch back?!
TALIESIN: Because I'm an idiot! 20.
MATT: 20? You barely manage to catch yourself on
the edge and roll back up (straining) onto the
platform. The magma rager is right there staring
at you, its burning coal magma eyes angrily
staring at your dwarven form.
TALIESIN: So where am I now?
MATT: You are now currently right here in the
center, yeah.
LAURA: Oh, he ran backwards?
MATT: He slammed into him as he ran toward him and
pushed him back onto the middle platform. At least
he didn't fall in.
LAURA: Okay, I have an idea. Is he considered
fighting us right now, or is he just staring?
MATT: I mean, in theory, it can't seemingly do
anything at you from range, so he's waiting for
somebody to come to his platform. If you decide to
then assault him on the middle platform, there'd
be an initiative roll. But right now it doesn't
seem to have any means of attacking at range.
LAURA: Okay, then I'm going to cast Charm Monster
on the creature.
MATT: Okay. So this is your 4th-level?
LAURA: It is.
MATT: It rolled a four, so it does not succeed.
LAURA: Woo! You love us! We're really great! Let
us pass!
MATT: You watch as its intense expression toward
the dwarf slackens and it flexes its shoulders and
then roils back to the center platform and then
looks over toward you with a nod.
LAURA: Your mama loves you very much. Your papa's
very proud of you. Come on, you guys.
TRAVIS: Doesn't seem so scary! Across.
MATT: All right, so your strength, your strength.
What's your strength?
JENNIFER: Ah, zero. Or ten, sorry, ten.
LAURA: Nobody attack him, guys. If anybody touches
him, this is going to break.
MATT: Yeah, so the three of you make it across
fine without any issue. Go ahead and make an
acrobatics check for me.
LIAM: 20. Natural 20.
MATT: I'll let that go for all of them. With a
natural 20, seeing this happen and watching them
all dart across, you begin to do hand-over-feet,
full-on handspring-style leaping over the
platforms past the rager. You all make it over to
the side platform, meeting up with your mage
friend as the magma rager's still sitting there,
resting in the center, looking toward you for some
sort of an order.
TRAVIS: I did have Reeksus with me.
MATT: (screeching) (impact) He's being dragged and
slammed like some horrible, slow-motion yo-yo.
TALIESIN: I did a quick Cure Wounds back to 41.
LAURA: Can you talk, magma monster?
MATT: You hear it emitting some sort of sound, but
it sounds like a heavy bonfire and rocks banging
together.
LAURA: You know what friends do? They dance.
Friends dance with each other. We should dance.
MATT: So as you step up to the edge of the
platform, begin to gnome-dance, the rager--
LIAM: Is it the Warcraft dancing animation?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: There's this large elemental covered in
armor that's pseudo-getting down with this tiny
mage gnome on the edge of the platform as the lava
glows from underneath, uplighting him.
LAURA: I guess we can go, you guys. See you
later.
MATT: As you walk away, it slowly stops dancing
and goes back to rest in the center of the
platform. All righty, that was a unique solution.
TRAVIS: Reeksus, now that your lies are through,
lead the way. Quietly!
LIAM: We are problem solvers!
MATT: "Quietly is the key here! Shh!"
LIAM: Aw, I don't feel bad. Why is that?
MATT: "Big thing lives ahead!"
LIAM: Not Toddlewaddle? Something else?
MATT: "Togwaggle beyond. This is big dragon!"
LIAM: What did you say?
MATT: "Dragon!"
TRAVIS: I have actually not gone up against a
dragon. I just want to put that out there.
TALIESIN: They're not bad. Well, I mean, I hear
they're not bad.
LAURA: Have you ever seen a dragon in person?
TALIESIN: No, no. I mean, well, no. Well, no.
TRAVIS: Reeksus, one dragon? Just one?
MATT: "One dragon. Not too bad for you, right?"
LAURA: Have you ever seen a dragon?
JENNIFER: Yes. Well, my grandfather, he told me
tales of them, yes.
LAURA: Okay.
JENNIFER: We choose the shadows in the presence of
dragons.
TRAVIS: Yes, let's stealth for a minute.
MATT: As you guys press down through the darkened
grade, the heat subsides slightly. You feel the
breeze now, this pulsing breeze through the
tunnel, rhythmic almost, as you turn into an open
cavern, a magnificent natural pocket of geodes and
crystals, beautiful blue and green crystals
refracting patches of luminous fungus into these
faint kaleidoscopes that permeate the entirety of
this entryway. There's a visible exit across the
chamber and slightly to the left, where you can
see in the middle is a glittering mass, piles upon
piles of gold coins, punctuated by gems of all
colors peeking through this hoard. As you enter
and look about, it is more money than any of you
have ever seen. There atop this mound, you see
lying the gargantuan, curled form of a sleeping
red dragon, arms crossed, head resting there,
(snoring).
JENNIFER: Creature hasn't acted in combat yet?
LIAM: Yeah, but I have to share. Speaking in
accent, but out of game. As a former rogue,
boo-hoo, this one is asking me if assassinate is
good in this moment to get a special surprise
attack on gargantuan-sized dragon. Yes.
JENNIFER: He doesn't know I'm here.
MATT: It's true.
TRAVIS: Is she asking Quazi, or is she asking
Vax?
LIAM: You would almost definitely hit dragon, but
it would be like taking donut and hitting side of
Empire State Building. Absolutely you will hit,
absolutely. You will take off half of one scale of
dragon. I mean, you can do it. This is Dungeons &
Dragons. Do whatever you like, but I'm just
saying, the game will end in two minutes.
MATT: Technically, it's Kobolds & Catacombs.
JENNIFER: Point made.
LIAM: I am curious to see.
TRAVIS: It's still sleeping. What else do we see
in this--?
MATT: Make a perception check.
TRAVIS: Okay. With advantage still? Blue fungus
still?
MATT: You do, yeah.
TALIESIN: You're a fun guy.
TRAVIS: Thank you, Taliesin. 19.
MATT: 19. Glancing about, you can see that the
crystals across the room appear to have been
either naturally grown, or some have been placed
with some sort of faint, magical light behind them
that, when it refracts, it actually acts as a
light source within the chamber, almost
intentionally so to make the place prettier.
Looking throughout this large cluster of coins on
the floor, you can see broken bits of furniture
and decor, things that have been jammed into there
and bent slightly, like vases and sculptures.
Various pieces of art that are scattered in this
horde. What does catch your eye is there is a
beautiful, jagged-looking dagger with a series of
red gems across the blade, a chain affixed to its
pommel that is currently resting partially jammed
underneath one of the hands of the sleeping
dragon.
LIAM: Tempting, tempting.
TRAVIS: I bet he's a heavy sleeper.
LIAM: Yes. If anyone's going to fuck with that
shit, it's going to be you, but it's still a big
if.
JENNIFER: I'm in.
TRAVIS: Yes!
LIAM: I also have a question about this item that
I'm attuned to. Let's say that this one's not
crazy enough to grab dagger and we just want to go
by. This says that, if you ever attempt to flee
from danger, you make wisdom save. Does sneaking
by--?
MATT: Avoiding is different than fleeing.
LIAM: I just wanted to triple check. Part of me
thinks it would be hilarious to see me rush in,
but--
MATT: Oh, believe me, part of me thinks it'd be
hilarious, too. But distinctive; fleeing is
different. If the dragon were to be awakened and
engage you, it might be a different deal, but
slaying a sleeping creature is no glory.
LIAM and MATT: YOLO.
TRAVIS: Are there any other exits out of this
room?
MATT: Currently, from what you view, no. The rest
of the chamber appears to be the home to where
this dragon is. You do not see an exit and it
seems strange that a dragon of this size would
find its way in or out.
TRAVIS: Not to be a stickler for our contract, but
do we see any candles?
MATT: Looking around with your perception bit, you
glance around, and you can see there is a trail of
flecks of wax that lead across the left side of
the chamber into the exit where it goes. So it
looks like whatever has been transporting the mass
of candles went that direction.
LAURA: Great, there's the exit.
TALIESIN: I'm going to start making my way that
direction no matter what.
LAURA: Sneaking, sneaking. As stealthy as
possible.
MATT: Who's sneaking first?
TALIESIN: Sure.
MATT: Make a stealth check, please.
TALIESIN: That's all right. 19.
MATT: As you make your way slowly around the edge
of the chamber, carefully stepping gingerly on
your dwarven toes, with a sudden snort, it shifts
slightly. As it blows hot air from its nostrils, a
few coins glitter and come to rest. Stillness.
Your breath is held. Slowly you exhale as it does
not appear to have disturbed the dragon. You
slowly make your way the rest of the way across
the chamber and you're now standing at the archway
for the tunnel that extends beyond to the next area.
Who's next?
LIAM: I elbow the gnome and lip sync, and I say,
chain.
LAURA: No, no.
LIAM: I know.
LAURA: Don't do it! Okay. Are you going? Okay, I'm
going to try to go.
MATT: Okay, make a stealth check.
LIAM: You all need to go through because, you
know, I'm so big and heavy.
LAURA: Once you're through, and then she's got to
go last because she's going to try and steal that
dagger.
MATT: What'd you roll?
LAURA: 13.
MATT: 13, okay. As you slowly make your way
through, there's a slight shift to the dragon's
neck position as it turns (snorting). One eye
slightly opens and you watch as the interior
secondary lid flicks a little bit and a voice,
(grunting). And it instinctually lobs out a jet of
flame in your direction. I need you to make a
dexterity saving throw, please.
LAURA: Ten!
TRAVIS: That's a lot of dice.
MATT: You take 38 points of fire damage.
LAURA: Well, I'm unconscious! Oh wait, no. Okay,
wait, let me do my math because I have my Mage
Armor up, which means that my Arcane Ward is
active, which means I have 19 hit points on my
ward.
MATT: Which it takes those off first. Yes.
LAURA: Yes, so that means there's, how many? 38
minus 19. So 19 left. So I'm still alive!
MATT: So the dragon, after snorting haphazardly in
a brief moment of being roused from its slumber,
its dream, it goes back to sleep as the jet of
flame subsides. You look over and see this, what
once was a tightly- and well-placed-together bun,
is now a singed mat of scraggled gnome hair as the
mage stands there, covered in soot, little bits of
fire burning off the edge of the cloak-robe.
TALIESIN: I'm going to throw a Cure Wounds at that
to help with that.
LAURA: I'm going to stealthily run toward him.
MATT: You catch up with Bundle as he goes ahead
and heals. Go ahead and roll for that.
TALIESIN: You get 11 points back to help.
MATT: All right, who's next?
TRAVIS: I'll go.
MATT: Make a stealth check.
TRAVIS: That's a five.
MATT: All right. As you follow suit behind your
gnomish friend, clank clank, a couple of
footfalls hit and you hear how loud it is. You
stop. (snorting) Heck yeah, it's totally sleeping.
Two more steps. Clang, clang, clang! (snorting)
You hold still. Okay, it's fine. Two more steps.
Clang, shink! Your foot hits a small pot on the
ground, which breaks and shatters at the impact of
your armored foot. (grunting and whooshing) Make a
dexterity saving throw.
TRAVIS: Nope! Five again!
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: Let the dice hit the floor.
MATT: 35 points of fire damage.
LARUA: Oh jeez! Are you alive?
MATT: As this gout of fire slams into and burns
all of your flesh, it takes all personal strength
to not scream out in pain as the flames subside.
You're like, (gasping).
TRAVIS: Yeah, can I--
MATT: Are you still holding the rope that
connects?
TRAVIS: Oh, I was, wasn't I? I still had Reek.
MATT: Yeah, the rope is burned off now. Reeks,
while still bound, doesn't have a tether.
TRAVIS: Did he get smoked by the fire too?
MATt: No, because he was a number of feet behind
you. He's like, (gasping). But you can make the
rest of the way if you would like to.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I would like to. And can I Lay on
Hands, dump the rest of my hit point pool into--?
Okay.
MATT: And so the three of you are across now. It's
just the two of you and Reeksus.
LIAM: Okay. So you want to try to tangle with the
devil and try to take this blade?
JENNIFER: I do, I do.
LIAM: Hm. And what is the landscape like from
where they are to where we are, here?
MATT: It looks like most of it is either a small,
maybe eight- to ten-foot-wide walkway with bits of
furniture and gold that are pressed over there,
and a few small pillars that have nothing resting
on them at the moment, and along the curved wall
where everyone has been stealthing around. The
rest of the chamber is filled by hoard pile and
the dragon.
LIAM: Here's what I think. If I fucking move, big
noise, jig is blown. You need me to stay still. So
you do your thing and if it goes well, you go and
then I go. If things go bad, we all die together.
JENNIFER: Things go bad, can you run while I
distract him with my things going bad?
LIAM: You know, no promises. We'll see what
happens. Good luck.
JENNIFER: Here goes nothing.
MATT: Stealth check.
LIAM: Stealth, oh. It's a one. Does she have--?
She does not. Does she have what I had?
MATT: Are you talking about Reliable Talent?
That's a much higher level skill, unfortunately.
LIAM: Oh, too bad, so sad.
MATT: So as you approach and grab the base of the
dagger, you slowly climb up the coins and get your
hand around the hilt. As you tug, it's caught on
something. You're like, no, I don't know if this
is worth it. You pull again. It's caught on
something. Eventually, it comes free. Whew. You
glance up and watch as this large, yellow eye is
looking right down at you as a deep voice begins
to vibrate the ground. The coins jangle at the
sheer bass of its intensity. "Might I ask what
"you're doing?"
JENNIFER: I thought it was stuck in your hand. I
thought I would help.
MATT: "Well, allow me to help you." The arms
suddenly reach out and grab as it lifts its torso
back. Its head retracts as it inhales.
TALIESIN: Power Word Shield.
MATT: Okay, so you're using Power Word Shield on
her? Go ahead and roll up for that. You guys are
over there. What are you doing?
LIAM: LRJenkins1234!
MATT: What are you guys doing? This large dragon
is now rearing back. What are you doing?
LIAM: Running forward.
MATT: I need everyone to roll initiative.
JENNIFER: 16 temporary hit points? What does that
mean?
TALIESIN: It means add 16 that you're about to
probably lose.
LIAM: So you're there.
JENNIFER: 56, 62, 72.
LIAM: But this is where you're at isn't it? Or is
that where you're at?
JENNIFER: No, I'm right here, that's where I'm at.
LIAM: You shouldn't be there because you can't go
higher than that so now you add 16 to that and
that's where you are. So 45 add 16.
JENNIFER: 61.
LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: All right so, initiative everyone. 25 to 20?
LAURA: 20.
LIAM: 24. Oh shit, that was Vax's voice.
TRAVIS: Yeah, it was!
TALIESIN: Seven.
TRAVIS: 19.
JENNIFER: Do I roll for that?
MATT: Yeah, you do. Roll initiative.
JENNIFER: Oh god, four. You're done.
MATT: Four plus--? What's your initiative modifier
there?
JENNIFER: Initiative, my initiative is--
LIAM: Five plus whatever you roll.
JENNIFER: Nine. It's not going very well is it?
LAURA: This is going to go very badly.
MATT: What did you get Bundle?
TALIESIN: Seven.
MATT: Ooh.
JENNIFER: YOLO?
LAURA: We have candles to get!
MATT: So, top of the round is you. Quazirat. Are
you running to meet up with the rest of the party?
LIAM: Party? I'm running at dragon. Yes. I'm not
running from dragon. Couldn't if I tried now.
Well, maybe I could.
MATT: It's a small tunnel that everyone else is
standing at.
LIAM: Nah, I'm going to dragon. Yeah. First one is
17.
MATT: Nope!
LIAM: Of course not. Second one is 25.
MATT: 25 hits.
LIAM: Yes, it does. Okay so that is big damage,
16!
MATT: 16 points of damage as you strike, arching
your Adventurefury Blessed Blade of the Thrill
Seeker across the chest of the red dragon. It
scrapes through and you see a little trickle of
blood begin to spill from the little bit of scales
that you carved through. It's still inhaling and
seems to not even notice your presence.
LIAM: Oh buddy. Let's go!
MATT: All right, that ends your turn. Greldamine.
LAURA: I'm going to hide and not fight a dragon.
MATT: Okay, so you're retreating into the hallway
and hiding?
LAURA: Yeah!
MATT: You run deeper into the hallway. Are you
trying to make a hide action?
LAURA: Sure.
MATT: Make a stealth check. So you disappear into
the (screaming), into the cavern.
LAURA: Oh, I didn't stealth very well. Seven.
MATT: Okay, you feel like you're pretty stealthed.
All right, Lohkor.
TRAVIS: I run forward with my warhammer and I'm
going to take two attacks and I'm going to dump
Divine Smite into both of them.
MATT: Go for it.
TRAVIS: Smite. 22 for the first one.
MATT: That hits.
TRAVIS: And 16 for the second one.
MATT: Does not hit. So you don't dump the second
one, once you hit you Divine Smite. So you didn't
lose any spells.
TRAVIS: Okay. 13 plus-- what's Divine Smite? There
it is. 2d8. 25 points of radiant damage.
MATT: Nice. So as you run forward slam! Your
hammer hits right near the wound that was left by
your Draenei friend. As it impacts, there's a
flash of radiant energy and you watch as the wound
opens up ever so slightly more. The dragon's still
(inhales). Your second strike, you go to swing at
it and it hits the scales and the impact causes
your entire body to shake from the sheer force of
its armor against your impact. No effect. That
ends your turn?
TRAVIS: Yes, it does.
MATT: All right. The dragon rears back and
releases an entire burst of fire breath towards
all of you except for you. You're just out of
range because you ran. Everyone else, make a
dexterity saving throw, please.
TRAVIS: You have plus two because you're near me.
LIAM: What did you get, what is that?
JENNIFER: One.
LIAM: That's seven plus your dex but it's still
not great.
TRAVIS: Ten.
LAURA: Everybody rolled shit.
LIAM: Not me.
TRAVIS: You get a plus two, Liam.
LIAM: That's not bad.
TRAVIS: What did you roll?
LIAM: 22 total.
MATT: Okay. You take 24 points of fire damage.
LIAM: Ain't no thing but the chicken wing.
MATT: You failed on the save, but you still take
half because of your evasion so you also take 24
points of fire damage.
JENNIFER: Okay.
TALIESIN: Thank you for that cold resistance by
the way, that's really cool of you to put on this
character.
MATT: Dude, dwarves have frost resistance in
Warcraft, I'm sorry.
TALIESIN: I know, bring it.
MATT: What did you roll on your--
TALIESIN: Ten.
TRAVIS: Ten here as well.
MATT: Okay. So you take 48 points of fire damage.
TALIESIN: I'm out.
TRAVIS: Me too.
LAURA: Oh no!
MATT: You watch as both of them fall to the ground
unconscious--
LAURA: Oh, they're the only two that can bring our
people back!
TALIESIN: I've got a healing potion.
LAURA: I do.
JENNIFER: We still have to kill this beast.
(laughter and yelling)
MATT: With your time traveling, as minor as it may
be, when you're facing death in the face here and
you don't see much of a chance of victory at this
point--
LIAM: So these two are down?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: That ends the dragon's turn. Aerwin, it's
your turn.
LIAM: Get the hell out of dodge.
JENNIFER: We have to get them out, we have to get
everyone out.
LAURA: Tell them you're sorry.
JENNIFER: Sorry.
MATT: (laughs) You have two allies currently on
the ground. One that's right next to you which is
your big friend and--
JENNIFER: I need to help him. What do I have that
can help them?
MATT: You can try to grab and drag them if you
want to.
JENNIFER: I'm going to grab and drag them.
MATT: Okay. You grab them by the scruff of the
neck and begin pulling them across the way towards
the direction of where they are. The flames as
they pour through barely miss and begin to catch
fire. You're now inside an old mine shaft and the
archways have wooden supports in the mine shaft
that are starting to catch fire. So you're
dragging him through. You get him right to the
edge of the cavern using your movement and action
pulling him over there. The dragon's going to take
one swipe at you as an attack of opportunity. Oh
that is a 13. What's your armor class?
JENNIFER: 17.
MATT: One big swipe barely misses you overhead and
you hear the wind over top as you barely duck
below, drag him through the coin and get him to
the edge of the cavern. That's the end of your
turn. That's going to bring us to Bundle! Make a
death saving throw please.
TALIESIN: I'm cool.
MATT: All right, cool. You're up.
LIAM: Okay, this is bad. I'm stupid, but not that
stupid so I'm going to run towards these two, to
dwarf, yes? And use action to cram potion healing
into his mouth. Wake him up.
MATT: Okay. So you rush out, the dragon's going to
take a swipe at you as an attack of opportunity.
LIAM: Okay.
MATT: Actually, he already used a reaction on her,
yeah, so he cannot. So you go running, you get up
to Bundle's body, drag him the rest of the way so
now you have both their bodies at the edge of the
cavern entrance, the flames starting to curl in
this area. You put a healing potion-- What healing
potion is it?
LIAM: This is a potion of healing greater. 4d4
plus four.
MATT: Okay. 4d4 plus four you heal.
TALIESIN: 4d4 plus four (coughs).
TRAVIS: Just you, right?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: Quazirat, that's the end of your turn.
LIAM: That's the end of turn, yes.
MATT: All right. That brings us to-- unless
there's anything else you want to do.
LIAM: That was action. Wait, hold on. I will use
bonus action to do Second Wind on myself.
MATT: Okay, sorry, didn't mean to cut you off
there, sorry.
LIAM: No, that's fine. That's three, yes.
MATT: All right, that brings us to Greldamine?
It's your turn. The rest of your allies come in,
two of them being dragged in, burned and
unconscious. One of them slowly comes to
consciousness as the potion is applied and the
dragon is in the room behind roaring now. The
whole chamber shakes and quakes and you watch as
bits of rock begin to fall in the mine shaft that
you're in. What are you doing?
LAURA: Who else is still in the room?
MATT: All of your allies haven't quite caught up
to you, they're about ten feet away from you, but
they're coming into the tunnel that you're in.
LAURA: Ten feet away? He is?
MATT: Yes.
LAURA: I'm going to run towards him because he's
still unconscious, he's being dragged, right?
MATT: Correct.
LAURA: I'm going to run towards him, ten feet,
give him a greater healing potion, 4d4 plus four.
TRAVIS: Oh yeah, you roll that.
LAURA: No, you roll it.
MATT: Whichever, as long as somebody rolls, it's
fine.
TRAVIS: Oh my god, I can't grab it. Stop it.
This is the slipperiest dice ever. Damn.
12.
LAURA: Plus four. 16. And then I'm going to use
the remainder of my movement to run back into the
tunnel.
MATT: You go rushing back down the tunnel.
(yelling)
LAURA: (yelling)
MATT: That brings us to your turn, Lohkor. You
come to consciousness coughing from the vial of
healing potion.
TRAVIS: (yelling) Double dash!
MATT: Half of your movement to get up. Then you do
the rest of your movement and then dash. You go
screaming past your gnome friend. You haven't seen
a person in plate move so quickly. That ends your
turn. It is now the dragon's turn. To your luck,
the breath weapon does not regenerate. The dragon
is going to take swipes at each of you. That's a
24 versus you.
LIAM: Only hits a little bit, though.
MATT: Okay. And then against you. That's a 15.
JENNIFER: 17.
MATT: As both claws strike out to slam into both
of you down on the ground, you manage to dive out
of the way. You feel the impact behind you. You
almost don't get to your feet as you catch. You
turn around, though, and you see the arms and legs
splayed underneath the dragon claws of your
Draenei friend, Quazirat.
LIAM: Everything's going to be fi--
MATT: That is 15 points of slashing damage.
LIAM: Yes, okay.
LAURA: Are you still alive?
LIAM: Yeah, you know, always living.
MATT: There's no room in here to do a tail attack,
unfortunately. So it can't make that. That ends
the dragon's turn. Your turn, Jennifer.
JENNIFER: Okay. So I decide what we're going to
do?
MATT: All your friends are running out that way.
The dragon seemingly can't get into this size of
the chamber.
JENNIFER: I'm running.
MATT: You go bolting out there.
LAURA: Good thing you got that dagger, though!
JENNIFER: Yes!
MATT: You're holding the dagger like, "Yay!"
(yelling) You go running and you catch up to the
rest of them. You're bolting past the mage. Full
on double dash. You go past your paladin friend.
That ends your turn. That brings us to Bundle.
TALIESIN: I'm running. No, I'm out!
MATT: You go bolting, dwarven legs catching up to
the rest of them. That brings us to the top.
Quazirat?
LIAM: I'm going to flee from the dragon.
MATT: Make a wisdom saving throw.
LIAM: We'll see how we do!
TRAVIS: Oh shit!
TALIESIN: I'm so excited!
LIAM: It's a big 13!
MATT: Exactly? What's the DC on the sword?
LIAM: 12.
MATT: So you succeed!
LIAM: Let's get the hell out of here, you guys!
MATT: You resist the magical influence of the YOLO
that's thrown upon you by Adventure--
LIAM: Blessed Blade of the Thrill Seeker.
MATT: Adventurefury. Blessed Blade of the Thrill
Seeker.
LIAM: Eh, too much hassle! Go!
MATT: I believe he's wielding an adventure sword.
As you guys are bolting behind, rushing as fast as
you can, you hear the rumbling and the roar of the
dragon and the heavy inhale once more. As the head
begins to push its way into the cavern behind you,
the impact, the cavern shaking, you two who are
running the fastest notice before anyone else
does, the ground gives out beneath you. You both
go into a freefall as the strength of the ground
dissipates beneath your form. The rest of you see
this happen just as you reach the edge and you
watch as the tunnel is falling and collapsing
beneath you as you all begin to tumble down into
darkness. Right as that gout of fire is released,
you watch above you as you spin into shadow, the
flames completely engulf the cavern where you once
were. Strangely, the collapse saved you! As you
plummet down, whack! I need everyone to make an
acrobatics check to see if you can manage to
lessen the impact of the fall.
LAURA: Natural 20!
TALIESIN: Not a natural 20, but 20.
MATT: You take four points of bludgeoning damage.
TRAVIS: 14.
MATT: Four points of bludgeoning damage.
TALIESIN: 20.
JENNIFER: 19.
MATT: Four points of bludgeoning damage.
LIAM: 24.
MATT: Four points of bludgeoning damage. You guys
all managed to lessen the impact of the fall.
LAURA: What happened to Reeksus?
MATT: He is nowhere to be seen. Who knows what his
fate was. Probably very toasty.
TRAVIS: Can I Cure Wounds on myself?
MATT: Yeah!
TRAVIS: Cure Wounds!
MATT: Go for it. By the way, you now have that.
LIAM: See what you got. Ooh!
LAURA: Read it out loud!
JENNIFER: Kingslayer. Dagger. Artifact. Requires
attunement slot. One-handed weapon. Once
commissioned by the orc warlock Gul'dan for his
assassin Garona, this blade has seen many a death
at its hands. One of a pair, the other has been
lost to time. You gain +3 to all attack and damage
rolls made with this weapon. When you hit an
enemy, they suffer an extra 1d8 poison damage and
make constitution save (DC 14) or become poisoned
until the end of your next turn.
TALIESIN: That's mean!
LAURA: Attune to that shit!
JENNIFER: It was hard to get.
TALIESIN: Worth it!
LIAM: She needs 20 minutes with that. So we should
probably, you know.
LAURA: We could rest up.
TALIESIN: I'll do a Mass Healing Word.
LAURA: Do you want to? Or we could use our hit
dice. If we take a short rest while she attunes.
TALIESIN: We could use our hit dice, or I could
do, yeah.
LAURA: We might need that later.
TRAVIS: Yeah, do the hit dice.
MATT: You guys glance around the space you're in.
LAURA: Oh, yeah. We need to actually do that.
MATT: As you guys are having this conversation,
you look around. What faint bit of light you carry
with your torch light or the Light spell to look
around at the space around. You seem to have
slipped down into a small crevasse that is
partially broken open. You're hidden in this
small, collapsed portion where a lot of it is
filled with the loose rock. Beyond it, you can see
a flickering, orange glow. As you approach and
glance up the side, make a perception check,
whoever is at the front of that.
TRAVIS: I've got it. Advantage. Blue fungus! That
was crap all around. Nine. Ten.
LAURA: That's terrible.
MATT: As you come inside, you see a circular
chamber. More hexagonal, I guess. Stone-built,
constructed. Most everything else here has been
natural. This has some cavernous feel, but has
some structure to it. This entire chamber is
filled with knickknacks, gold pieces, random
boxes, collected odds and ends, and mounds of wax
ending in numerous lit candles. The entire
chamber: hundreds of lit candles. The most
romantic of chambers you've seen. Large, small.
This is the mass of where candle storage is for
this subterranean cavern network. That's all
you're able to make out from this point.
TRAVIS: Well, there's a shitload of wax ahead.
LAURA: Should we sit down and heal ourselves?
TRAVIS: Yeah. I think the coast is clear.
LAURA: Okay.
TALIESIN: Actually, I can do a thing that might
help. Where's the thing where I can make it so we
all get max healing no matter what?
MATT: That's a 3rd-level spell. That is--
TALIESIN: Beacon of Hope?
LAURA: No, I don't think you have it.
TALIESIN: It's Beacon of Hope. So I'm going to
cast Beacon of Hope on everybody so for the next
minute, I suppose it's just-- will this work for
hit dice?
MATT: Not on hit dice, no.
TALIESIN: Never mind.
MATT: Beacon of Hope is for spells and effects
that heal you. The hit dice is resting for an
extended period of time.
TALIESIN: We'll just do the hit dice. It's been so
long!
LIAM: Where are you at?
LAURA: All right!
TALIESIN: Wow, that was awful.
LAURA: I'm back, baby!
TALIESIN: Boy, I'm not.
MATT: As you guys are completing your short rest,
a new sound perks your ears as you're resting. You
all stop for a moment and listen. It's the sound
of a soft violin. Echoey. In the direction of
where the candles are being stored.
LAURA: Can I peek through the little thing?
MATT: (violin playing) Make a perception check.
LIAM: I don't like that music.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: I don't like it.
LAURA: 17 plus five is 22.
MATT: As you come to the edge and you glance past the
first few rows of wax and candle mounds, you can
see in the distance a number of piles of collected
unlit candles that line the walls. To the back of
this 30-foot diameter chamber, a large lump wax
throne stands, crowned with a dozen wide candles
all flickering as they wreathe a sitting, larger,
more rotund than average kobold, wearing leather
armor that cannot seem to contain his bulging
belly, now freed from the bursting leather plates
around his torso. A white, wild chinstrap beard
marks his chin line, as a large metallic crown of
cobbled golds, silvers, and iron adorn his head,
fused with a tall window lantern that shines
brighter than a lantern should. You see shifting
movement from within the lantern, like the light
source seems to be moving of its own accord,
almost alive. A smaller, elderly kobold stands
next to this wax throne with a tiny violin, and
he's playing music as the kobold king sitting on
the throne has his eyes partially closed,
listening. You see, through the shadows of the
flickering candlelight, amongst the various piles
beyond your vision, apparently other kobolds are
also in the chamber rummaging around, moving,
organizing, placing goods they've received. That's
what you see.
LAURA: How far away is the throne?
MATT: It's about 25 feet from you.
LAURA: (whispering) You guys, the king is right
there! Lots of other dudes in there too.
TRAVIS: Does the staff have any suggestions?
LAURA: Hey, Aluneth! Should we attack?
MATT: "If you feel confident in your power, then
destroy them and siphon their magic. Feed on what
"power they've got."
LAURA: Can I do that with you?
MATT: "Of course, my darling."
JENNIFER: What's he saying?
LAURA: Aluneth is saying: destroy them!
JENNIFER: Can you do that?
LAURA: I don't know.
MATT: "Can you do that?"
LAURA: Yeah!
MATT: "Then prove that you're worthy of my
gifts."
LAURA: Yeah! Should I do a Fireball at the king?
TRAVIS: Who's playing the violin?
LAURA: An old kobold next to him.
TRAVIS: I thought it was a little gnome?
MATT: It's a tiny, elderly kobold who's like
(squeaky violin music)
LIAM: I've seen you two in action. What if she
fires and you follow with fire?
LAURA: I'll let her do the first attack, because
you get assassinate, and then I'm going to
Fireball immediately after that.
TALIESIN: And I'll Sacred Flame as well.
JENNIFER: Am I assassinating the king? Should we
assess first the power of these other kobold
around him?
LAURA: Fuck it!
JENNIFER: All right, let's do it. Eyes on the
prize. Crossbow's ready.
MATT: Make a stealth check as you approach the
edge and begin to get to a place where you can--
JENNIFER: 19.
LIAM: No, it's not, it's much higher. 30.
MATT: You feel comfortable enough stepping from
the crack in the wall, and then diving below the
first row of large, heavy, wax mounds. You ready
your crossbow across your forearm, aiming it for
the king's soft under throat. As you prepare
yourself, the music comes to a halt from the
violinist, and the king turns to him. "Thank you.
This earthquake has made me ever so nervous." Do
you take your shot? You have advantage on your
attack, so you get to roll twice.
LIAM: That's cocked. So what's the higher one?
JENNIFER: 27.
MATT: That definitely hits, go ahead and roll
damage.
JENNIFER: That's this one?
LIAM: You're doing crossbow? 1d6. Roll a cube.
Three plus your sneak attack damage. And we're
going to double this when you're done, because
you're an assassin hitting in the dark.
MATT: It is considered a critical hit because he
is unaware.
LIAM: (counting) 37, because you're an assassin.
LAURA: Fireball!
MATT: (choking) It reaches up and turns as you
release the Fireball into the room. The violinist
starts playing again, looks back and barely pulls
the bow away and goes, "Oh no!" as the entire room
bursts into flame. Go ahead and roll your 8d6
damage.
LIAM: Every kobold is the best in this game.
LAURA: How many? 8d6? Oh jeez. 24.
MATT: Okay, so 24.
LAURA: Oh! Plus two! 26, because I'm attacking
with Aluneth.
MATT: Four of the ten kobolds in the room are
destroyed as the explosion hits. You hear a bunch
of screams in the corner as a number of them are
annihilated. As you can see, the throne itself is
melting in the wake of it. King Togwaggle. A three
does not make it. So that's 26 fire damage to him.
And the violinist is ashes. As the flames subside,
you watch as there's a kobold shaped skeleton
clutching a now burning violin that tumbles into a
pile on the ground. At which point, the other
kobolds jump out, damaged and burning looking to
King Togwaggle as he's sitting there, the edges of
his chin beard burning and curled up. He has this
giant shovel that he has resting at his side. And
he glances up at his crown and goes "Rakanishu, it
looks like company we has. And You! No! Take!
"Candle!" Slams the shovel onto the ground and
stands up. Everyone roll initiative.
TRAVIS: Oh my god. What the hell? What's
Rakanishu?
MATT: All righty. Wow, okay. So, 25 to 20,
anybody?
LAURA: 22.
TALIESIN: 21!
MATT: Oh wow, look at that!
TALIESIN: It finally happened.
TRAVIS: "Finally happened."
MATT: All righty. Then 20 to 15?
TRAVIS: 18.
MATT: 15 to ten?
JENNIFER: 13.
LIAM: Big ten, my man.
MATT: All right. Greldamine, you're up first. You
finished shooting the fireball, they're all now
pulling out pickaxes and going (yelling) and
they're all turning. They can see you and they can
see you and the rest of you, currently now
stuck in this hole in the wall right now. You're
all locked in this pincered position.
LIAM: Let's go, wee one.
LAURA: Okay, ooh. How close are they all to each
other?
MATT: They're all about 15 feet from each other.
LAURA: Fireball!
MATT: All right! Roll the damage. Togwaggle does
make his save this time.
LAURA: 34.
MATT: 34, all right. So that's 17 points of fire
damage to Togwaggle. And the rest of the kobolds
(explosion) (screaming). Annihilated.
TRAVIS: The one syllable protest!
MATT: Their pickaxes tumble off and some are stuck
into the stonework. Surrounding, beginning to melt
wax elements have now melted even further and are
now beginning to coat the ground with soft molten
wax. The entire chamber is now becoming a sticky
wax base.
LAURA: Oh. I may have melted all of our loot that
we were supposed to take back.
LIAM: It'll form back together though.
LAURA: Yeah, he's getting his wax back, that's the
important part! I am going to back away from the
little crack in the wall and hide against the
wall.
MATT: So you're now moving out of the crack of the
wall and moving into the chamber?
LAURA: No.
MATT: There's a giant, hexagonal, circular
chamber, and the small crack in the wall where you
guys were hiding.
LAURA: All of us in this teeny crack?
MATT: Yes. Except for you, you're actually outside
of it and by one of the mounds that is slowly
melting in front of you.
LAURA: Okay, I guess I will step outside of the
crack and try to hide behind a mound of
something.
MATT: Okay, so you dart off to one of the mounds.
You don't have any action to do a hide check,
unfortunately. Using it for cover, hopefully. That
ends your turn. Bundle, you're up.
LIAM: Everybody say crack as much as you can.
ALL: Crack!
TALIESIN: Just for fun, let's do-- where is it? I
keep losing everything I'm doing. I'm going to do a
very standard Guiding Bolt. And a Sacred Flame
attack. I'm going to go for a two-fer on the big
kahuna.
MATT: Those are technically both actions.
TALIESIN: Oh they're both actions? I thought it
was a bonus, never mind. This is so hard to do,
it's been so long since I've done this.
MATT: It's okay. Guiding Bolt?
LAURA: (singing) Guiding Bolt up the butt!
TALIESIN: I'll do a standard Guiding Bolt at this
guy, and see what happens.
MATT: Okay. Make a ranged spell attack against
King Togwaggle.
TALIESIN: Here we go, Guiding Bolt. That's a 19.
MATT: Plus?
TALIESIN: Guiding Bolt is a 25.
MATT: That'll hit, go ahead and roll damage.
TALIESIN: That's 4d6 radiant. Ooh! 16 points of
radiant damage.
MATT: Okay, and the next hit against him has
advantage.
TALIESIN: Yeah, the next hit against him has
advantage, and yeah, I'm going to give myself a
quick Healing Word as a bonus action because I'm
really low.
MATT: Okay. As a reaction, King Togwaggle's going
to go ahead and use Vengeance of Rakanishu. After
the Guiding Bolt slams into King Togwaggle, he
lifts up his giant shovel in his hand and you
watch as the interior of the lantern crown that he
has begins to brighten and suddenly your chest
bursts into flame. You suffer 14 points of fire
damage and you are considered on fire. Until you
spend an action to put it out, you're going to
take 1d6 fire damage every turn.
TALIESIN: All right. I am at 29 points of health,
that's okay.
MATT: All righty, so that ends your turn?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: All right, suddenly you watch across the
chamber which you hadn't noticed before, there is
a door that slams open and from the inside, from
what little of bit you can see it looks like some
sort of a latrine or like an open piss pot room.
Four kobolds start rushing out into the center of
the chamber, their feet getting stuck in the wax,
so they'll only be able to move at half their
speed so they can't get up to anybody. They take
their pickaxes and throw them! So they're going to
throw three at you and three at you. Technically
you guys would both have a little bit of cover
because you're behind those, so I'd give a plus
two to your AC for each of you. So the first three
against you. That is going to be a 16, what's your
armor class?
LAURA: I did Mage Armor, so I've got 16.
MATT: Correct, so with the plus two, it does not
hit. The first one is deflected off the armor. Oh,
that's going to be a natural 19, so that hits you.
You suffer nine points of piercing damage as one
pickaxe hits you in the chest, clavicle area,
you're like (grunt). The third one's going to
throw and that is a 19.
LAURA: That hits.
MATT: So you take seven points piercing damage
from a second pickaxe that jams you in like the
hip area, it falls out, but the wound's open. The
three against you. That's going to be a 15 plus
four, that's 19?
JENNIFER: I'm 17, I don't have any pluses, right?
LAURA: Plus two!
JENNIFER: Okay, so 19.
MATT: Plus two, so 19, so it hits you exactly. So
you take six points of piercing damage as one
pickaxe grazes you across the neck and shoulder.
It hurts, you can feel the welt picking up. Second
one is going to go ahead and strike you, that is
going to be an 11. So, no. That one you dodge out
of the way, and a third and final one is going to
come for you. That is a natural 20! As you dodge
out of the way and come around, there is one that
takes both hands (grunt) (whooshing) and as you
spin around to hear the scream it hits you right
in the forehead. That's a six, that's 12, plus
three. You take 15 points of piercing damage as
your head is ringing from the impact of the
pickaxe. Your vision blurs and doubles for a
second as you right yourself and clutch onto the
soft wax. You fall into a little bit, and pull
yourself out. That's going to end the kobolds'
turn, now it's King Togwaggle's turn. King
Togwaggle is going to rush forward, currently it's
only the three of you visible because nobody's
come out of the chamber yet. So he's going to rush
forward and get between the two of you and make a
shovel strike on each of you. So the first one
against you, that's a 27.
LAURA: Oh god!
MATT: I rolled a natural 19. You take--
LAURA: He's at disadvantage though, because I'm a
gnome. I'm very small.
MATT: No. That is 15 points of damage, as the
shovel hits you upside your head, and then
attacking you. That is a 16 plus eight, that's 24.
That hits you. That's an eight plus six, that's 14
points of bludgeoning damage.
TALIESIN: (groans)
MATT: Ending their turn, it now comes to you.
TRAVIS: Can I push out of the crevice and run at
King Togwaggle?
MATT: You push out and he's right there. You guys
are all clustered right on the outside so he's
easily within range.
TRAVIS: I can get right on him?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Can I use my Hammer of Justice, "Target a
creature within 15 feet of you to make a
"constitution saving throw against your spell save
DC or become stunned until the next round" on my
next turn?
MATT: Yes you can. All right, so. That is an 11.
What's your--
TRAVIS: 13! Yes!
MATT: So as you step out of the crevice, you
summon the radiant energy granted to you from the
divine, and you watch as this giant radiant
hammer, summoned from the sky, slams down and
strikes the top of King Togwaggle's head. The
crown goes off to the side for a second and he's
like (grunting). He can't make words, his bell is
rung. So he's stunned until the end of your next
turn.
TRAVIS: Yeah!
MATT: All right, that's your action. You're there
and you're up engaged with him. That finishes your
turn. All right, you're up, Aerwin.
LAURA: With stunned, if you hit him does it break
the stun? Or he's--
MATT: No, he's stunned, and attacks against him
have advantage and melee attacks against him I'll
double check, I'm pretty sure auto-crit.
TRAVIS: Do I get a bonus action with that crazy
move or is that it?
MATT: You do, if you want to use a bonus action.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I want to pour some Searing Smite
into it as well.
MATT: I'll let you do that, sure. Well, it's not
a melee weapon attack, I think, unfortunately.
TRAVIS: Oh that's right, never mind. That's what
it is, your call.
MATT: Stunned, incapacitated. Yep, so as an
incapacitated creature, yeah.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: So you guys, melee attacks are auto-crits on
him right now.
LIAM: Okay, and your buddy is there so--
LAURA: Dagger, dagger, dagger!
LIAM: Not hidden, can't do that, but you're still
going to get sneak attack.
JENNIFER: Dagger, I want to do the dagger.
LIAM: Yeah, you're going for an attack. Is she at
advantage because he's stunned and weird?
MATT: Yes.
LAURA: It's an auto-crit!
LIAM: So roll twice. Oh auto-crit, so you don't
even have to roll.
LAURA: Yeah you do, you have to roll to see if it
hits.
LIAM: Well, yeah you hit, 16 plus eight, so 24.
MATT: 24 definitely hits. I'm checking to make
sure I do this right.
LIAM: So you roll--
JENNIFER: 1d4?
LIAM: 1d4, which is the triangle, the pyramid.
Roll that. Okay, now you roll your-- four, good.
Roll these guys. Okay, roll those.
JENNIFER: Okay, all right.
LIAM: Holy shit, that's a good sneak attack.
JENNIFER: 22.
LIAM: 22, wait, you double it, because it's an
auto-crit, so 22, 44 plus the three, is 47.
LAURA: Plus the poison damage?
MATT: Plus a d8, which is doubled because it's an
auto-crit, so roll a d8.
LIAM: Oh, you have smoked this guy.
LAURA: Yeah, that one, that one.
JENNIFER: Five.
LIAM: Ten.
57.
TRAVIS: Jesus, 57 points?
MATT: So using the dagger you mustered from
beneath the dragon, you jam it right up into the
abdomen of King Togwaggle and while stunned he
goes (choking) and you watch as some of his brackish
blood (splattering) out of his mouth. He looks
hurt, but is very angry. While still stunned in
place, his eyes have locked in on you. You can see
the bloodshot look behind the whites. He goes,
"No. Take. Candle." Is that your turn?
JENNIFER: Is that the end of my turn? That's the
end of my turn.
LIAM: Yes, you can disengage as bonus action and
get away from him so he can't hurt you.
JENNIFER: I'll do that.
LIAM: Dance back.
JENNIFER: I'll dance back.
MATT: He's stunned, he can't even attack her. So
you move away from him. All right, so you pull
away, pulling the blade out from the wound which
now is like (dripping sound). Ending your turn,
you're up.
LIAM: How far away are other little guys from this
one?
MATT: They're about ten feet behind him, in the
center.
LIAM: Ten feet behind him? Then I will use my
whirlwind warrior class ability, and I will start
with the big man and move to his little buddies.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: Okay? So here we go.
MATT: So as an action you can make an attack
against each creature that you come adjacent to.
LIAM: So I'll start with him, yeah? So I get two
attacks because of who I am, that is 16? Not
great.
MATT: You don't get two attacks of part of this,
you get one attack against each thing you go
across.
LIAM: Okay.
MATT: So you get one attack on him.
LIAM: So am I at advantage because he's fucked
up?
MATT: Yes.
LIAM: Okay good. That's better, that's 24 to hit,
that hits.
MATT: That hits, go ahead and roll damage.
LIAM: Okay, here we go again.
MATT: And I'll say with your movement, moving
through you can hit four of the six kobolds.
LIAM: Okay great. 14 on this guy. Keep going?
MATT: So you're shifting on and you watch as
Quazirat suddenly grabs his blade and begins
spinning in a circle. You guys have to duck out of
the way as he carves into King Togwaggle, carves
through a bunch of the wax and begins burning into
the center of the chamber and cleaves through,
hopefully, four of these kobolds.
LIAM: Ever hear of Baryshnikov? Amateur. Do I roll
for attack on each one?
MATT: Yes, you do.
LIAM: Okay, here we go. First one, we get 18.
MATT: Hits.
LIAM: Second one, we get natural 20. Third one we
get one.
MATT: Nope.
LIAM: Fourth one we get 28.
MATT: Three of them hit, one of them is a
critical.
LIAM: Okay, so first one we get 18.
MATT: 18 damage?
LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: The first one you cleave the head off.
(squeal)
LIAM: Okay, so second one critical so eight, 16,
18, 24.
MATT: That one, the blade bisects him from hip to
chest and he stumbles forward to the ground in two
pieces.
LIAM: Oh buddy. And the last one, 14.
MATT: 14. That one the blade stops in his body and
he's like (choking) "Why?"
LIAM: Life comes at you fast.
MATT: (growling) All right. That ends your turn.
LIAM: Sure does.
MATT: All right. Greldamine, your turn.
LAURA: Okay. I'm going to try and take his crown
off his head since he's stunned.
MATT: Okay, what are you going to do, are you
going to grab and pull it off?
LAURA: Yeah!
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Oh wait, no! Can I use Mage Hand to do it?
Is that what Mage Hand does?
MATT: If you want to do that roll an athletics
check. Sorry, not an athletics, an arcana check to
see if you can manage to pull it off.
LAURA: 15?
MATT: 15. You watch as the crown comes off and is
now floating there as you're holding it with the
Mage Hand.
LAURA: I got his crown! I'm going to run across
the room with the Mage Hand following behind me
and start trying to bury it in wax on the other
side of the room.
MATT: Okay. So you're holding it in the air and
trying to dig a hole in the soft wax?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: That will end your turn, Bundle, you're up.
TALIESIN: It's going to take an action to put
myself out, I assume.
MATT: If you want to put yourself out.
TALIESIN: I would like to put myself out.
MATT: At top of the round, you do take three
points of fire damage.
LIAM: Stop, drop and roll.
TALIESIN: Okay.
MATT: You spend the round (yelping), putting the
fire out on you.
TALIESIN: Do I get a bonus action?
MATT: You do.
TALIESIN: So for a bonus action I'm going to cast
Spiritual Weapon at 4th-level, because I think
that gives me an extra d8 for spiritual weapon.
MATT: It does, yes.
TALIESIN: All right, so I'm going to cast
Spiritual Weapon.
MATT: And what are you summoning?
TALIESIN: I basically want to summon what is
basically a big chomping mouse trap.
MATT: (laughing) All right.
TALIESIN: I'm going to take a whack at the king's
head with a giant--
MATT: A divine mouse trap. It's beautifully
carved, from ivory it looks like. The silver
snapping mechanism, it looks like it was of elven
make. It has filigree on it. As it appears you
hear this chorus go (angelic singing) as it
prepares itself.
TALIESIN: I'm going to smack it right into him.
Does it auto-crit, if it hits?
MATT: It's advantage on the attack and I think
it'll be an auto-crit.
TALIESIN: Oh, it's also advantage on the attack. I
rolled a 17 plus--
LAURA: Well you could get a 20.
TALIESIN: Yeah, 23, but it's an auto-crit anyway.
LAURA: Isn't it? It's an auto-crit?
TALIESIN: He's still stunned. So that's 26 points
of damage. (snapping)
MATT: You watch as it snaps down and more blood
spills out. And you hear the snapping of a bone
and one eye closes in pain. He's still standing
there and is furiously awaiting his return.
TALIESIN: I'm going to back up a bit, with my
movement. And get a little bit of cover.
MATT: The four kobolds see you running by with the
crown gliding. They go "No! Rakanishu! Save it!"
and they all throw all their pickaxes at you. That
is 12? Misses you. First one hits soft wax. Second
one is a 24.
LAURA: Oh no!
MATT: So you take five points of piercing damage.
Make a concentration check.
LAURA: Oh, what a concentration check for the Mage
Hand? Okay!
MATT: I'm pretty sure Mage Hand is concentration.
We'll find out real fast here. No, it's not
concentration, it lasts for a minute.
LAURA: Okay good!
MATT: Just lasts for a minute. So that one you
took the damage. Third one, that's going to be a
17 plus four, that's a 21.
LAURA: Oh no.
MATT: So you take another four plus three damage.
That's seven points of piercing damage.
LAURA: I turn and look at it right as it hits me
in the face and knocks me out cold.
TRAVIS: Oh it does?
LAURA: (screams)
MATT: You fall to the ground and the axe
(pinging). There's a little trickle of blood down
your forehead as you hit the soft wax, which does
soften your blow.
LAURA: Oh, it cracks my glasses.
MATT: It does, one side is now shattered in a
spiderweb, as the crown clatters to the ground. As
it does the glass of the lantern breaks. All
right, that's the end of the kobolds' turn. Your
turn.
TRAVIS: My turn?
MATT: Yes.
TRAVIS: Hold real still for me (whoosh). Two big
attacks with the warhammer. I'm going to dump
Searing Smite into the second one.
LAURA: Advantage.
TRAVIS: Oh advantage, that's right. I mean they're
crits, aren't they?
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: So 18 to hit. 12 points of damage on the
first one.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: No, it's a crit. Double it.
TRAVIS: Oh yeah. 24.
MATT: Whatever the dice was you double.
TRAVIS: Yeah, oh I'm sorry, right. So 14 plus
five. 19.
MATT: 19, all right.
TRAVIS: 21. 21 again, and I'm dumping Searing
Smite into it. He does a constitution--
LAURA: 19.
TRAVIS: Yeah, sorry, what'd I say?
LAURA: 19 again, you said 21.
TRAVIS: Oh damn it. (laughing) Sorry.
MATT: How do you want to do this?
(cheering)
TRAVIS: Stunned, I walk up with the warhammer,
spin it in my hand, and do one, two, with the
second one arcing up with all that radiant damage.
Coming under his chin, trying to change the way
his pretty face looks.
MATT: And as you do, frozen in place you see the
neck muscles tensing against the magic, trying
desperately to fight his way back and as the
hammer swings up, the first hit clanks across the
jaw, which you see (crunch) break and go slack.
The second strike, as you hit the jaw slams
upward. You see teeth shatter from the sheer force
of the impact. As the jaw slowly falls slack, both
eyes are cross eyed, the forehead is pushed
inward, and he gurgles before falling onto his
back, onto the ground. Unconscious. And bleeding
horribly. All right, that end your turn?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: All right, at the end of your turn you
glance over and you notice the mage is down and
you watch the shattered lantern-- suddenly flames
are beginning to emerge and swirl. You see all the
nearby candle wicks that have been slowly burning
away from the heat of the room, the flames are
almost being drawn from the candles towards this
lantern and this flame that is growing in the
center. And you see all the kobolds are now going,
"Rakanishu, Rakanishu, Rakanishu." That ends your
turn. Aerwin, you're up.
JENNIFER: We need to get to safety for a minute,
and get everybody healed I think.
MATT: You have two outs here, there latrine room,
and there is the crack where you were in.
JENNIFER: Latrine room.
MATT: You go darting for the latrine room?
JENNIFER: Yep.
MATT: Okay, so you double dash around, leaping
over the body of King Togwaggle, leaping off of
the soft wax mound, out of the range of the
kobolds that can get a swipe at you. Dart into the
open latrine room, and as you dart inside, you see
a makeshift royal restroom, complete with a
terrible smell you'd expect from a kobold latrine.
There is a rickety wooden commode series, three of
these nasty looking, supposed to look nice but
aren't really nice at all kobold toilets. Even
dangerous to sit in, they look like they have
shards of wood and nails, jagged up. There is a
rushing underground river that vanishes through a
far wall. It looks like it's set up with the bars
to be almost like a bathing apparatus.
JENNIFER: (sighs) Man. Rushing river, bathing
apparatus. Can I duck in there to hide?
MATT: You could certainly try.
JENNIFER: I'm going to duck in there and hide for
a minute to get out of danger.
MATT: Okay, so you get into the water and you get
down into the rushing water. It's a pretty strong
current.
JENNIFER: All right.
MATT: So you can hold onto one of the rails
there, that can hold you in place. Okay, so you're
there, keeping low in the water.
JENNIFER: Do I have any more rope left? No I used
it. I could tie myself up to rest for a minute?
No, I'll just sit.
LIAM: You've got six seconds, that's what your
turn is.
MATT: All right, that brings us then to Quazirat.
LIAM: Right I see the little one go down, so I
start hoofing it in that direction and I plant my
hand right down on her little forehead and I use
Gift of the Naaru. And you get seven hit points of
life.
LAURA: Yay, I'm alive!
LIAM: But then I keep running past her as far as I
can go.
MATT: Okay. So you do that, you rush past, go to
heal her. Two of the kobolds that you struck last
turn that are in melee range with you swing out
with their reactions to take an attack of
opportunity.
LIAM: That's fine.
MATT: 20?
LIAM: Sure, that hits.
MATT: You take five points of piercing damage.
Other one. Oh that's a natural one. He swings
wide. You rush forward, between the two other
kobolds, intending to get to her, heal her, and
then continue to run. Which direction?
LIAM: Towards the latrine.
MATT: Okay, you go darting towards the latrine.
LIAM: Which is technically fleeing, so do I need
to make saving throw with sword?
MATT: You would.
LIAM: Okay good. No. That's not good. That's a
four. YOLO.
MATT: Adventurefury: Blessed Blade of the Thrill
Seeker calls to you. And this day, glory must be
found! YOLO, motherfucker.
LIAM: Bozhe moi!
MATT: All righty.
LIAM: But am I out of movement and I'm stuck where
I am?
MATT: You've healed her and then you spin around,
blade ready, and you're going to fight these
kobolds and whatever that fire thing is that's
growing.
LIAM: Yes, I am.
TRAVIS: Electric guitar in the background. (guitar
solo)
LIAM: I take the sword. (guitar solo)
MATT: All right, Greldamine. You come to
consciousness and watch as your friend spins
around with his giant blade and start laughing in
this face of this-- now you notice, swelling
elemental entity that is drawing fire from all of
the candles in the room and is growing by the
moment.
LAURA: Okay. I'm going to use Frost Nova and try
to target the fire element and the other little
things that are in the room.
MATT: Okay, all right. So that's a 20-foot radius.
You can hit all the kobolds. All right, so roll
3d6 cold damage.
LAURA: Ooh. 15.
MATT: 15.
TRAVIS: Constitution saving throw.
MATT: Sorry about that, microphone. And they have
to make a constitution?
LAURA: Constitution.
MATT: For the kobolds, what is the DC on that one?
Your spell DC?
LAURA: My spell DC is 16. Oh, did it go up? No.
MATT: No, 16, so that's a failure on the first
one. One kobold freezes to death, locked in place
as they're frozen solid. That one does succeed.
Next one fails with a one and this Rakanishu fails
with a six plus-- yeah because it's constitution
he doesn't have-- it's a plus four, so that's ten.
So you watch, first off, Rakanishu takes double
damage for that. Takes 30 points of cold
damage being vulnerable to the cold. You watch as
the fire entity (freezing sounds). The flames
slightly flicker and pull in there, and the ice
that's encased around it seems to create this orb
or sphere that's holding it in place. The source
of the fire that's drawing towards it seems to be
temporarily cut off and all but one kobold are all
locked by ice. One seems to break forth (growling
and snorting) "My candles now!" All right, does
that end your turn or do you-- you can still
move.
LAURA: I'm going to move, I'm going to run towards
the latrine.
MATT: Okay. Half your movement to get up from
prone because you were unconscious. So you can get
about ten to 12 feet. You rush over, you're about
maybe ten feet away from it. But you're making
your way as best you can!
LAURA: Are there any candles around?
MATT: There are dozens of candles.
LAURA: Still?
MATT: Yeah, I mean they seem softer and you can
see clusters of them, but yeah.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: All right, that ends your turn? That brings
us to Bundle.
TALIESIN: I'm going to Channel Divinity and
quickly throw seven points of healing at
everybody, and myself. Every little bit helps. I'm
going to, just for fun, take a swing with the
mousetrap at the giant flame beast to see what
happens.
MATT: Okay, go ahead and roll an attack on that.
TALIESIN: That's a 14?
MATT: 14? Unfortunately, as it goes to snap, it
hits the ice that's encased around it and can't
seem to break past. No effect.
TALIESIN: I'm going to turn and run to the
latrine. Aye! Then I'm going to turn around and
run.
MATT: Okay. So you go and run. You can get into
the doorway of the latrine to avoid the kobolds
that are still in place from getting an attack of
opportunity. All right cool, so you get there,
that's the end of your turn. The kobolds now are
there, only one of them can move. He's going to go
ahead and charge after you, who got back up and
swing at you. It's going to rush up to you, and
swing with its pickaxe.
That's going to be a 17 plus four. That's
going to be a 21. You take five points of piercing
damage. Are you still up?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: The other two are going to begin throwing
their pickaxes. They have a whole cluster of them
in their bag, and they're throwing them as best as
they can. One of them's going throw at you, and
then one more, because one of them died, is going
to throw at you. So against you, that's going to
be a 14.
TRAVIS: Misses! Sorry.
MATT: Against you, that's going to be a 12. You
guys are deflecting the pickaxes in the middle of
the air. Ending their turn, it is now Rakanishu's
turn.
LAURA: At least he can't move, you guys.
MATT: All right, so. Beginning of the round, the
ice breaks. His movement's still zero, so
Rakanishu cannot move, but you're watching as he
begins to gather the flames again from the nearby
candles. This is a burning fire elemental entity
made of pure rage and flame, and this flickering
voice goes, "Free! That foolish kobold knew not
what he had. I will be the new firelord!" And his
mouth opens, and you watch as all the flames begin
to pull out. All of the candles in the room are
snuffed as the flames are consumed, and the
elemental begins to grow bigger and bigger. As it
does so, everyone who's still in the room-- which
is you, you, and you're at the door, and you-- all
suffer one point of fire damage.
And then as part of his attack, he's going to use
his explode. (roars) And detonates in the chamber,
40-foot radius, so that's all of you.
LIAM: Is that a dex save?
MATT: Nope. All of you ignite. No immediate
damage, but you're all on fire. At the top of your
round, you take 1d6 fire damage until you take an
action or something to put the fire out. All
right, so that's the end of Rakanishu's turn. It's
your turn.
TRAVIS: (pained noises) I run forward.
MATT: Top of your turn, you take six points of
fire damage.
TRAVIS: I run forward with two attacks from my
warhammer against Rakanishu. That is 16?
MATT: Misses. You swing, and the flames seem to
dodge out of it. You hit air, as it seems to be
reforming its body to avoid the blows and then
going back into its semi-solid fire form.
TRAVIS: 23?
MATT: 23 hits.
TRAVIS: Ten and I will use my bonus action to dump
Searing Smite into this one. So that's an extra
five points of what kind of damage? I'm not sure.
I think it's fire.
MATT: Searing Smite? Yeah, that's fire damage.
That does nothing against a fire elemental.
TRAVIS: That was so smart!
MATT: So as the flames consume your hammer and it
hits, it devours the fire from the hammer.
TRAVIS: Well, cool. Good deal. All right, next!
MATT: (laughter) You still do weapon damage on top
of it, so roll that.
TRAVIS: It was ten points.
MATT: All right. Ten damage there. That ends your
turn. That brings us to you, Aerwin.
JENNIFER: I'm going to go after it with the
kingslayer. Try to take it out.
MATT: At the top of your round, because you're on
fire-- technically, you were low in the water.
Because you were low in the water, the flames,
when they begin to take form on you and begin to
engulf, you duck low and you would have probably
been unaffected. Water puts out the flames. All
right, so you let go of the pole, you rush back
into the chamber. You cannot get quite close
enough to hit him with a melee. You could throw
the dagger, if you want to, or shoot it.
JENNIFER: Oh, with the crossbow? Yes, I'm going to
do the crossbow.
MATT: Okay, so bolt in. Release it. Fire with the
crossbow.
LIAM: Is Lohkor adjacent?
MATT: He is, yes, so you get sneak attack.
JENNIFER: I'm going to add, because it's the
dagger--
LIAM: No, you're doing the crossbow, you said. You
can do the dagger.
JENNIFER: It's the dagger in the crossbow.
LIAM: You cannot fire it. You can throw the
dagger, or you can fire the crossbow.
JENNIFER: Throwing the dagger, so 30.
MATT: 30? That'll hit. Roll damage.
LIAM: So 1d4. Roll the pyramid, then roll your
four cubes. Add that all up.
JENNIFER: Eight, 11, 13. 16. Plus poison.
MATT: No poison damage. The elemental is immune to
poison, unfortunately. It's made of fire; there
are no veins for the poison to affect. The dagger
slams into the fiery torso, and you see a moment
of resistance as the blade carves into the flames,
then falls and clatters to the ground below it. It
seems like it did some damage. But it doesn't seem
to be reacting to the impact.
JENNIFER: So now, I daggered him. Can I shortsword
him?
LIAM: No, you can't do another attack. You can use
a bonus action--
JENNIFER: I'm going to back up.
MATT: You can dash back into the water, if you
want to. So you go back to the water. Holding on
there; the water's rushing below you. You can see
the water as it's rushing in, it's disappearing
into a small opening where the rest of the river
is disappearing towards. That ends your turn. That
brings us to Bundle.
TALIESIN: First thing I'm going to do is attack
with the Spiritual Weapon, as my bonus action, so
that's-- oh, that probably hit. 23.
MATT: Wait, no. I got the order wrong. Quazirat.
Hold onto that roll.
LIAM: Okay, so I'm on fire? Fuck it. I run, and I
attack. I shout: For Argus! And I run forward to
him, and I would like to attack-attack for my
attack, but then also use my recovered action
surge, so I'll hit this fucker three times. First
one is good. Don't distract me! Is 29.
MATT: That hits. You take four points of fire
damage.
LIAM: Fine. Is 17 for the next?
MATT: That misses.
LIAM: Okay. And last one-- oh, balls-- is 20.
MATT: 20 hits, and you suffer ten fire damage from
hitting him. You now see at the size that it's
gotten, hitting it with a melee attack does fire
damage to you by proximity.
LIAM: That's good shit, so here we go. First
attack-- oh, that's terrible!-- for ten? Second
attack that hits is 18, so a total of 28, all
told.
MATT: 28, all told. Gotcha. Okay, so as you're
slamming into it, the flames are burning your
skin, and you're wincing, swinging as hard as you
can, a few make purchase into its body, and you
can see it carving away. It reacts a bit from the
hits, but the giant jack-o-lantern fire grin
continues to swell and grow with its physical
size.
LIAM: It's all right. I hold my ground and block
my friends.
MATT: Okay, ending that, now it comes to top of
the round. Your turn.
LAURA: Are there any more kobolds alive?
MATT: There are three of them. Actually, yes.
There are three of them, but they're on fire. It
didn't distinguish. Everything caught fire in the
room, and there are three kobolds going, (pained
noises) as they're burning up. Rakanishu don't
give a shit.
LAURA: Okay, well, I'm going to cast Sleep at
2nd-level, so that gives me 7d8 worth of hit dice
to knock people out.
MATT: Okay, roll that.
TRAVIS: Whoa. Sleep.
LAURA: I'm thinking they're d6, but they're not.
(counting)
LIAM: Don't act surprised, Travis. We know you're
going to be a Sleep magician in the next
campaign.
LAURA: 34.
MATT: 34? Okay. You watch as the three screaming
kobolds (screaming, snoring). Smoldering as they
sleep on the ground. On fire. Really tired.
LAURA: For my movement, I'm going to run towards
the latrine.
MATT: You're still on fire, right?
LAURA: Yeah, and jump in the water.
MATT: You took four fire damage at the top of the
round.
LAURA: Okay, and I'm going to jump in the water to
put myself out.
MATT: The flames go out as you dive into the
water.
LIAM: They look so innocent when they're asleep
and on fire.
MATT: Bundle, now it's your turn. Sorry. You can
still take that attack if you want to.
TALIESIN: 23 with the Spiritual Weapon to hit.
MATT: Top of the turn, you still take six points
of fire damage, as you're burning.
TALIESIN: All right, that's fine. Let's hit this
thing with the mousetrap again. Plus my spell
attack bonus, so it's 16 points of damage.
MATT: 16 points of damage. As the giant divine
trap snaps on, you watch as it snaps through one
of the arms. The fire arm vanishes, as it seems to
sever it at the shoulder, then it reforms
afterward.
TALIESIN: Then I'm going to use my second Channel
Divinity: Preserve Life and put 30 points of
health into you to keep you awake, and I'm going
to take five for myself, then I'm going to run
into the latrine, as well.
MATT: Okay, so you dart into the latrine. You go
into the water. You manage to put the flames out
on you, and now you have three of you sitting in
there. There's enough room for maybe four of you
into this rushing-water area. All right, so you've
mostly clustered there. That ends your turn. The
kobolds that are sleeping, it's their turn.
(laughs) They all quietly expire as they smolder
in their sleep.
TALIESIN: Live by the candle, die by the candle.
MATT: And they are. They are their own candle.
Okay, so that finishes their turn. There are no
more kobolds in this chamber. Rakanishu is now
going to--
LIAM: I'm in his grill.
MATT: Both of you are. He's going to focus on you.
He's going to take two fire rakes at you. That is
26 to hit and 25 to hit.
LIAM: That almost doesn't hit, but it does.
MATT: You take 18 points of fire damage from the
first hit.
LIAM: Totally cool.
MATT: That's 21 points of fire damage from the
second hit.
LIAM: So 18 and 21? Cool. Let's find out what that
does. I'm not down, but-- okay, cool. I'm up.
MATT: Actually, technically? Sorry, those should
be an additional d6, because every round that he
consumes fire, he increases the damage he deals,
so an additional seven points of fire damage. All
right, cool. That brings us to the end of
Rakanishu's turn, who is going to begin shifting,
using the movement, which gives you guys both an
attack of opportunity. Is now moving towards the
latrine, where everyone's rushing towards. Both of
you guys get attacks of opportunity.
LIAM: 15.
TRAVIS: Jesus! Nope.
MATT: Both of you guys-- he's too fast, and both
of you swing your weapons and actually hit in the
middle of the air, and there's a spark, and you
both "Damn it!" at each other. Up to the top. That
brings us to Lohkor. Your turn.
LAURA: Lohkor.
TRAVIS: Oh, me! I run up behind and I hit it!
MATT: Go for it.
TRAVIS: 20!
MATT: Hits. You take three points of fire damage.
TRAVIS: Yay. I rolled the wrong thing. Six points
of damage. Second one. 16.
MATT: 16 misses. It goes wide.
TRAVIS: There you go. Cool. That's it.
MATT: All right, so you rush up and you're behind,
swinging. One hits, one misses. The heat is
intense now, and whatever facial hair you had is
now gone. Your hairline is beginning to burn away.
The hairs on your head are being singed off by
being this close to the beast. All right, that's
going to bring us to Aerwin, your turn.
JENNIFER: I need to get my dagger back. I'm going
to get my dagger back.
LIAM: Oh, you're picking it up instead of
attacking? That's your call.
JENNIFER: No, I want to attack. I want to attack!
I'm going to use the crossbow, because that's what
I have.
MATT: All right, roll for an attack.
LIAM: Plus, what is it, seven?
JENNIFER: Seven. 15.
MATT: 15? You go to strike, and it barely misses
it by a couple of inches and fires off into the
distant room, unfortunately.
JENNIFER: He's coming toward the latrine?
MATT: He's coming in that direction, yeah.
JENNIFER: I'm going to go around him to the other
side to prepare to come after him again.
MATT: Still inside the latrine?
JENNIFER: I'm not in the latrine. I came out of
the latrine to attack him.
MATT: I thought you backed back into it, into the
water.
JENNIFER: End of the last turn, I went back in,
right?
MATT: You threw it, then went back in.
JENNIFER: I didn't have to come out to crossbow
him, did I?
MATT: Not necessarily.
JENNIFER: I came out to crossbow him, and then can
I run across the chamber?
MATT: Sure, I'll let you do that. As you move past
him, he does get an attack of opportunity on you.
That's going to be a 23 to hit. That is 15 points
of fire damage to you as you run past.
LAURA: Oh no, unconscious?
LIAM: No, she's up.
MATT: That ends your turn. Quazirat, you're up.
LIAM: I think of my father, Leeron Jenkins, and I
run.
MATT: I like Leeron Jenkins. Offshoot bloodline.
LIAM: I run at him, and I attack again. Yeah,
okay. First attack is okay. It's 22.
MATT: That hits.
LIAM: Second attack is a 21.
MATT: Both hit.
LIAM: Okay, first time, we get 18. Next one, 16.
MATT: Okay, 18 and 16. All right. You also suffer
nine points of fire damage from the two strikes,
the flames beating into your face each time you
hit him.
LIAM: That is so cool.
MATT: All right, is that the end of your turn?
LIAM: Yes, it is. Still up.
MATT: Nice. Yeah, it looks like it's taken a
beating, but it's not looking super rough.
LIAM: Next round, for sure.
MATT: Now, your turn. Greldamine.
LAURA: With my magic wand of missiles--
LIAM: Sorry! I have a bonus action. I'm going to
use my Second Wind. Thank you. Go.
MATT: How many times can you use Second Wind?
LIAM: I recovered it. I used it once before, we
took a short rest, and this is the last time.
LAURA: With my magic wand of missiles, can I use
all my charges?
MATT: Sure.
LAURA: I'm going to use all seven charges in the
magic wand of missiles, and I'm going to try to
hit it.
MATT: All right, so that would technically be a
7th-level Magic Missile, which means you'd shoot
nine darts, so 9d4 plus nine.
TRAVIS: 9d4?
LAURA: (counting) 20.
TRAVIS: Uno mas.
LAURA: One more? 21 plus--
MATT: Nine.
LAURA: Plus nine?
MATT: 30 points of force damage. As you hold the
wand out in front of you, full-on anime missile
style, nine magic arcane missiles slam into
Rakanishu. As the impacts hit, Aluneth, in the
back of your mind, goes, "Yes, that's what I'm
talking about!" Awesome. And you're going to stay
in the water?
LAURA: Heck yeah!
MATT: All right. That's going to end your turn.
Bundle, you're up.
TALIESIN: I'm going to cast Spirit Guardians at
level three.
MATT: Spirit Guardians is still up, isn't it,
though?
TALIESIN: Spirit Guardians is different. You're
thinking of Spiritual Weapon. This is Spirit
Guardians, so if he's within 15 feet of me, that's
going to be a thing on his turn, if he's within 15
feet. Also, he's slowed by half. But I'm also
going to hit him with my Spiritual Weapon.
Mousetrap! Goddamn it. I miss. Can I have my die
back?
MATT: Nope. It's mine now. All right, that ends
your turn. It is now Rakanishu's turn. The flames
continue to swell even larger, and now there is a
flaming radius. Fire is now around him. You see
all the wax around him is beginning to burn and
bubble in the immediate vicinity. He's going to
make two fire rake attacks: one against you, and
one against you. Against you, that is an 18.
LIAM: Oh, I'm an 18 AC.
MATT: That hits you, just barely. And against you,
that is a 16.
TRAVIS: That misses.
MATT: All right, it misses you. You, however,
suffer 19 points of fire damage.
LIAM: Do svidaniya.
(groaning)
MATT: (impact) Falls to the ground, burning in
cinders. Still conscious, but hurting.
LIAM: Still conscious?
MATT: Not conscious, sorry. Still alive.
LIAM: Still alive.
MATT: All right, and with that, you watch as
Rakanishu begins to move into the chamber, and the
presence begins to light the commodes on fire. The
wood's beginning to burn. The entire area is now
in flames.
LIAM: Harry Potter and the Chamber of Pots.
MATT: You do get an attack of opportunity as he
moves away from you.
TRAVIS: That's a 24.
MATT: That hits. You suffer five points of fire
damage.
TRAVIS: That's nine points of bludgeoning damage,
and I'll put some Branding Smite into it, as well,
as a bonus action. Do I get a bonus action as a
reaction?
MATT: On a reaction, you don't, so you can't do
that. Nine points of bludgeoning. All right--
TALIESIN: Is he within 15 feet of me now? He has
to do a wisdom saving throw.
MATT: Okay. Natural 20.
(groaning)
MATT: Still takes damage, but it's halved, I
believe.
TALIESIN: That's 3d8. 12, so six points of radiant
damage.
MATT: Six points of radiant damage onto Rakanishu.
All right, end of the turn, top of your turn,
Lohkor, you suffer three points of fire damage
from the proximity of the fire aura. All right,
your turn.
TRAVIS: My turn. Two attacks against him. That's a
23, should hit, and the second one is-- no, that's
not a hit.
MATT: Okay, so four points of fire damage from the
first hit.
TRAVIS: Nine points of bludgeoning damage, and as
a bonus action, I'm going to put Branding Smite
into it, which is 2d6 radiant damage, and the
enemy glows bright.
MATT: I think he's pretty bright as it is.
TRAVIS: Four points of radiant damage.
MATT: All righty, got it. That ends your turn? All
right, so you rush up to him. All of you are
clustered in the commode, which is now in flames
all around. Aerwin, your turn.
JENNIFER: I'm going to shoot him with the
crossbow--
MATT: You're now on the other side of the chamber,
crossbow out. Go for it.
JENNIFER: 18. 26.
MATT: That hits. Roll damage.
LIAM: Is Lohkor adjacent? Okay.
JENNIFER: 1d6?
LIAM: Yeah, you hit, so a cube, plus sneak attack
damage. Four, plus these guys.
JENNIFER: 16. 21.
MATT: 21 points of damage. Okay, so it sticks in
the back, and you watch the flames, while growing,
it's starting to grow thin. The flames are growing
more disparate, and the connectivity of all this
fire is beginning to look like the mass is
lessening. The damage is starting to take a toll
on it. Are you going to stay where you are?
JENNIFER: I'll back up.
MATT: So you're even further away on the opposite
side? Gotcha. All right, cool. That brings us to--
make a death saving throw.
LIAM: Yo. I'm good.
MATT: All right. Greldemeyer, you're up.
LAURA: Greldamine.
MATT: Greldamine, sorry.
LAURA: It's fine. It's a hard name.
TRAVIS: Grundlemeyer.
MATT: Gwendelmere.
LAURA: I'm going to cast-- Grandlefarts!-- Sleep
again, at 2nd-level.
MATT: All right, go for it. Roll the dice.
LIAM: On the thing?
LAURA: Yeah. That's how many? 7d8?
MATT: 7d8.
LAURA: (counting) 25.
MATT: You watch as the flame begins to flicker a
bit, then die down to this tiniest little candle
flicker on the ground. And there, you see this
tiny flame that's wavering lazily. Room is still
on fire, and everything around it is awful, but
apparently, it was at a point where the Sleep
could take effect.
LAURA: Oh my gosh! You guys, grab as many candles
as you can, and let's get the hell out of here!
TRAVIS: Snuff that flame?
LAURA: I don't know! If you damage it, it wakes
back up. I'm not exactly sure how this thing
works.
JENNIFER: I have a waterskin. If it's that size
and sleeping, would that much water take it out?
LAURA: Let's grab all the candles we can. They
might all be completely melted.
MATT: Make an investigation check.
LIAM: About 20 seconds have passed. Should I make
another death save?
MATT: Yes, you should.
LAURA: Can somebody else please make an
investigation check? We're searching for candles.
TRAVIS: 16.
TALIESIN: Take 2d4 plus two.
MATT: You manage to find an armful of soft
candles. They're pushed together and mush now.
LAURA: Is there a bag I can shove some wax into?
MATT: You've got sacks. You quickly start filling
sacks. How long does the spell last for Sleep?
LAURA: It doesn't say. Oh, a minute.
MATT: Okay. You've got to hurry.
LAURA: Really quickly!
LIAM: What happened?
TALIESIN: Good things. We're running!
LIAM: Did I get him?
TALIESIN: Yes. We're running.
LIAM: What are we doing?
LAURA: Right as we're running out, pour the water
on him, and we'll jump in the latrine.
JENNIFER: Got it. It's done!
MATT: So you guys all rush into the latrine room,
and what are you doing?
JENNIFER: I have the waterskin. I'm going to pour
some water on this tiny flame and try to kill it.
MATT: All right, so you uncork it and pour the
water onto the flame. You watch the flame
(whoosh). It restores into the full Rakanishu
elemental. The room immediately, all the flames
brighten once more. What are you guys doing?
LAURA: Jumping into the latrine!
TRAVIS: Yeah, jump into the latrine, and maybe let
the raging current take us wherever.
JENNIFER: It goes somewhere.
MATT: The rushing river, you mean? Okay.
LIAM: Right, so we make a run, and I make a wisdom
save, and I fail, so I turn around and go back. I
drop my candles.
MATT: All of you guys dive into the water, letting
the water take you like a water slide, one after
the other, and you watch as Quazirat turns around
with Adventurefury, the Blessed Blade of the
Thrill-Seeker in his hand, and knows, "No, this is
your fate. This is your glory." And the last thing
you see before you all vanish into the water is
him scream and run towards the reformed
Rakanishu's elemental form.
LIAM: LRJenkins1234!
JENNIFER: Your father's proud of you!
MATT: So at this point, darkness takes over.
You're being rushed around the current. It's
battering you around at a rapid speed. Even those
of you with darkvision, things are coming by so
fast that you're only seeing things quick enough
before it impacts you. I need all of you to make a
perception check. If you have darkvision, you make
it with advantage.
TALIESIN: 19.
MATT: Success.
LAURA: 23.
TRAVIS: 16.
JENNIFER: 17.
MATT: 17? Okay, you all succeed, so you only
suffer three points of bludgeoning damage as you
guys are being battered around-- oh, you go limp
and unconscious.
TRAVIS: Oh, you do?!
JENNIFER: I only had two left.
MATT: All right, as you're being thrust around
inside, the river's carrying you, and you're
trying to hold your breath. The air escapes your
lungs. You guys all try your best to hold
together. You hit another sequence of rock. Using
your perception from before, you still only suffer
another seven points of bludgeoning amongst you,
so seven, seven-- actually, it would be half, so
three to each of you. Eventually, after a minute
or so, your lungs begin to burn from holding in
the air. What's your constitution?
TRAVIS: 16.
MATT: What about you?
LAURA: 13.
TALIESIN: 14.
MATT: Okay, so your air begins to escape your
lungs. You can't hold it anymore and you begin to
drown just as a light comes to you. All of a
sudden, the thrusting of water stops, and you're
all free-floating in water, and you all begin to
scavenge around for any sense of what's up, what's
down. The light is below you, the glow, and you
begin to right yourself and realize that that is
actually above. You look up, and it looks to be
there's a surface of water. You all begin to swim
up-- at least, those of you that are conscious.
You're struggling and drowning, and you limply
begin to float to the surface.
TALIESIN: Is she floating to the surface? I'm
going to follow her up, then.
MATT: Okay. Make a constitution saving throw.
TRAVIS: Is my plate mail a problem?
MATT: You have a high constitution, so you're able
to hold your breath longer.
(laughter)
LAURA: Ten?
MATT: Ten? You go unconscious and begin drowning.
LAURA: Does that mean I start floating?
MATT: You're scrambling under the water and go
limp and begin to slowly rise up, as well. Two of
them begin to rise up in the water.
LIAM: Rise up.
MATT: All right, as you guys break the surface,
(gasping) you glance around, gasping in the cold
air. The blue sky above you is nearly cloudless: a
welcome sight as you recognize the nearby docks
and humble buildings of Lakeshore, where you once
left. You apparently were jettisoned to the bottom
of Lake Everstill, and you're just around the
corner from where you started this venture.
TALIESIN: Healing Word, level two; Healing Word,
level three.
MATT: Okay, you come to consciousness. She's a
little worse for wear.
LAURA: Oh no. Do you have Revivify?
TALIESIN: If I use my Healing Word not knowing
that she was dead-- did I use my Healing Word not
knowing she was dead? Because I'm out of magic, at
that point, if I've used two Healing Words.
MATT: Make a medicine check.
TALIESIN: All right, that'll do.
LIAM: Also, did his spell reach three miles back?
MATT: No.
TALIESIN: Oh! 24.
MATT: 24? Glancing over as you begin to cast the
spell, you recognize the signs that she is not--
TALIESIN: Revivify on this one, Healing Word at
level two on this one.
MATT: Okay, I'll allow that. For the purposes of
this, you reach over, and from the cold shackles
of death, the spirit of Aerwin, who went on to
greet the goddess Elune, is pulled back into her
form as she gasps for breath back at the surface
and begins to paddle.
TALIESIN: Big dwarven punch in the face. Wake up!
MATT: The four of you slowly scramble and make
your way towards the shores of Lake Everstill.
Waterlogged and down one ally, you make your way,
beaten and bruised. So you have two satchels of
no-longer-soft candles, and you make your way
inside Lakeshore Inn, which has another patron
now, so business is booming. You see as Wental
turns around as you enter and goes, "My goodness,
"friends! You've returned! Oh, and a little worse
for wear, but where's your friend with the
"beard?"
TRAVIS: He died.
LAURA: He died getting your candles.
TALIESIN: You owe us lunch.
MATT: "I'm terribly sorry, but food can be
prepared. That's a shame. But did you get my
"candles?"
TRAVIS: Show him the bag.
MATT: As you dump out a solid rock of wax onto the
wooden table, he glances down.
LAURA: Those creatures, they had melted all of
your candles already. We saved as much wax as we
could for you.
MATT: "Let me go make some breakfast." As he
shell-shockedly makes his way towards the kitchen,
you all sit down, pull the wooden chairs out, slap
down on the table, water still dripping from your
armor and clothes. You sit there, grab whatever
half-drunk tankards you left as you exited, finish
them off, make eye contact, and think, "Man, can
it really be worse up on Argus right about now?"
And that's where we'll close today's game.
(cheering)
LAURA: Oh no, poor Toes!
LIAM: Will one of you please look after my WoW
account?
JENNIFER: Absolutely.
MATT: Thank you guys so much for playing. Thank
you, Jen, for coming and joining us.
JENNIFER: Thank you! This was so fun. Thank you.
Amazing.
MATT: Thank you guys for coming and joining us.
Thank you very much to Blizzard for working with
us and putting this together and letting us play
in Azeroth for a bit. Once again, please check out
the Kobolds & Catacombs expansion for Hearthstone
releasing on December 7th, and they're streaming
on the official Blizzard Twitch and YouTube on the
5th for their awesome Kobolds & Catacombs escape
room. Thank you guys, again. Have a wonderful
night, and is it Thursday yet?
(cheering)