MATT: Hello, everyone, and welcome to tonight's
pseudo, not-really episode of Critical Role, where
a bunch of nerdy voice actors sit around here and
tonight, maybe play a little bit of Dungeons &
Dragons. My name is Matthew Mercer and
unfortunately, we have a number of members who
were sick after our convention appearances this
last weekend, who couldn't make the game tonight
due to unfortunate circumstances. So with the
amount of people who couldn't make it, we decided
to instead not play this week and instead, do a
live Q&A with the questions in the chat room and
as well as questions that were put on Reddit, so
we'll get to those there in just a moment. And
then, when that's over, as decided recently, I'm
going to have a fun battle royale. I made a small
arena and the latter half of today's episode is
going to be Grog versus Keyleth versus Zahra
versus Kashaw free-for-all. See who stands winning
at the end of this show.
WILL: It's going to be such a slaughter.
MARY: I'm looking forward to the three minutes of
gameplay.
WILL: Exactly! It's going to be 90 seconds of
great fighting.
MATT: I cannot wait!
TRAVIS: Can anyone cast Hold Person or Friends?
WILL: I can. That's good to know! Okay, see, I wouldn't
have known that. Just like turning undead the first
time.
TRAVIS: I shouldn't have said anything.
MARY: Why did you say anything?
MATT: So that will be the second half of the show
after we take our midway break. Before that
happens, let's do a quick round of announcements.
First and foremost, I wanted to say thank you to
our Critters and fans that came out to Wizard
World Portland this past weekend. We had an
incredible turnout. Wizard World was very happy
and we're looking to possibly be doing more of
those in the near future. So we'll be able to see
other parts of the US, meet more of you guys we
didn't have the chance to that weekend. It's
wonderful to meet all of you, both at the con and
at Guardian Games out there. It was a great game
store. We got to hang out with a bunch of you in
person. But thank you so much for coming out and
visiting. We really appreciate it. Also today, I
put up on the Dungeons Masters Guild site,
dmsguild.com, a new order for the blood hunter
class. It's called Order of the Lycan. Which I
mentioned a little bit at Wizard World, but it's
essentially a blood hunter order that involves, as
part of a ritual called the Taming, they accept
the lycanthropic curse and through training and
honing their willpower and the blood magic that is
part of blood hunters' training, they can control
the curse of lycanthropy to a certain extent to
prevent themselves from going berserk, but still reap
the benefits as they transform into whatever
were-creature they choose--
TRAVIS: Were-creature?
MATT: I mean, there's were-tigers, were-rat. So
you decide which strain you're infected with.
WILL: A were-rat would be pretty damn cool.
TRAVIS: Can you change, or are you locked into
one?
MATT: No, you're locked to the strain of
lycanthropy you are, unless you get uncursed and
you get another strain.
MARISHA: Like half rat, half person.
TRAVIS: Like a big ass rat or you're like little
bitty?
MATT: No, you're like, big ass nasty--
TRAVIS: Princess Bride.
MATT: --Warhammer Skaven style. It's pretty rad.
Yeah, bigger than that.
WILL: I don't think they exist.
MATT: But yeah, it's on the DMs Guild site. It's
free. Go check it out, see if it's something you
guys want. Check it out. It's good. Also, another
announcement I want to make real fast, I'm saying
this because I've gotten 15 to 20 tweets a day
about it, for the Earthbreaker Groon fight last
week, it was intentional that the Quivering Palm
ability was held back. He was testing individuals
in the battle, not trying to go lethal or kill. It
was more of a tease for the actual ability. God
forbid they ever come across a not quite as
helpful or restrained monk in the future. But I'm
well aware. It was intentional. I should've made
it more clear that he was holding back in the
moment and I apologize for the confusion it
caused.
TRAVIS: Hold on. He was holding back during that
whole thing?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Cool. Awesome.
WILL: Somebody asked me about that too. I think my
response was, "What?" He keeps holding back! And
it's like, all right. I just want a good fight.
TRAVIS: Put my belly button with my spine.
That's holding back?
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: I love how that's part of the
announcements, though, you try to--
MATT: I'm just trying to quell it now, because
it's been perpetual and I'm like, I know. It's all
good.
WILL: It's a good fight!
MATT: It was a good fight. I love me some monks,
man. It was so great to bring a monk in there and
more hopefully to come, because there are those in
the world that are trained for different sets.
MARISHA: In fact, maybe now's a good time to
hearken back to your episode one announcement,
because it's been almost 50 since you've made the
announcement that you like to house rule a lot of
stuff.
MATT: Yeah. House rules, rules are fluid, you have
a good time. But don't worry about it. I know that
you guys want to see it come out in all its full
glory and that may still happen in the future. We
shall see.
MARY: You'll be a lycan-tiger monk or a lycan-rat
monk?
WILL: Wow.
MARY: Can you cross?
MATT: I mean, you could multiclass.
WILL: It sounds like something we would have on
ThunderCats.
MARY and MARISHA: Yeah!
TRAVIS: Snarf gets an upgrade.
WILL: Snarf-grade. Snarr!
(laughter)
TRAVIS: The quivering snarf.
MATT: The quivering snarf?
WILL: The quivering snarf.
MATT: That's a great romance novel descriptor. As
he lies there, his quivering snarf in the
moonlight-- All right. So that I think is all my
announcements. You guys have anything else you
want to talk about before we jump into the Q&A?
TRAVIS: This cookie's good.
MARY: Oh! Steve Blum and I are going to be at
CoastCon next weekend, not this weekend. The next
weekend in Biloxi so come on out and say hi!
WILL: Nice! March 17th, I will be in Toronto at
the big con up there. So that's going to be a lot
of fun. So come out Canada and come chill out. It
will be a good time.
MATT: Fantastic! Go check him out there. And me
and Marisha--
MARISHA: We leave next week.
MATT: We leave next week. We'll be gone from the
2nd to the 9th in Ireland. We'll be at a
convention at Kaizoku Con in Cork, Ireland
which--
WILL: Say that three times fast.
MATT: Kaizoku Con in Cork, Ireland, Kaizoku Con in
Cork, Ireland, Kaizuku Con in Cork-- no.
(screaming)
MARY: That was so close!
WILL: It's always the C take!
MARY: Yeah, you get cocky on the C take and you're
out.
MATT: That's a problem. But yeah, so there will
not be an episode next week because we'll be gone
but we'll be returning to the next proper session
which will also have the return of Will and Mary
as well to finish off that arc on March 10th, I
believe? So we'll be doing that. Anything else?
You good? Oh, that's right. And we'll be giving
away two copies of these books throughout tonight.
Brandon Sanderson's The Bands of Mourning. That is
not me on the cover as the Internet likes to
perpetually point out.
WILL: Can I say something? Because Brandon
Sanderson is my favorite author, bar none. These
books are incredible. They're amazing. You should
read everything he does. These are all from
Mistborn-- they start with the Mistborn trilogy.
They go from there. These are standalone novels
that take place after everything you knew about
Vin and everybody else. They are incredible so
these are a really cool prize.
TRAVIS: Laura says the same thing and I think it
was Kit Buss' art of those novels that we saw
first and we're like, oh, she's an amazing
artist!
MATT: Yeah. Thank you, Brandon Sanderson for
bringing us our main artist on Critical Role! So
yeah, we'll be giving these out throughout the
show tonight--
MARISHA: Along with those giveaways, with
Lootcrate I did an Espionage nail-wrap tutorial
and Jamie hooked me up and gave me a few Critical
Hit nail wraps. Yeah, you can go see how easy and
awesome it is. Actually, someone asked me at the
Con this weekend if I was a paid sponsor, like
paid promoter for Espionage. And the answer is no.
Ashley Johnson and I actually, legitimately,
really love their products and are huge fans. I'm
just a legit fan. I think I tweeted the link
yesterday. I'm going to go tweet it out and go
check out Espionage Cosmetics. They're great.
MATT: Do it.
TRAVIS: Those go on your nails?
MARISHA: I have some on right now.
MATT: They can. You can certainly try.
WILL: Is that what those are? So that's not
paint?
MARISHA: No, that's not paint. They're these.
They're nail wraps and you stick them on. They're
like stickers and you put clear coat on them and
they last two weeks.
TRAVIS: No, they don't!
WILL: No. I don't deserve it.
MARY: You could demonstrate on Will.
MARISHA: I could, yeah. I could. You want to
demonstrate? I need a nail file.
WILL: You're going to need more than nail file.
Some kind of a big thing.
TRAVIS: (chainsaw sounds)
MARISHA: I demonstrate in the tutorial. But
they're really great! And actually do make some
for dudes, as well. They make some that are like
gender neutral.
WILL: Okay. I'm not a big nail-guy, but all
right.
MATT: I'm not either, but I've worn before.
TRAVIS: It's gender neutral. Is it really for
dudes?
MATT: It's for everybody. Yeah, Marisha.
TRAVIS: Come on.
MARISHA: Yeah. Semantics. All right.
MATT: All right. So that being the case, the first
half of this evening is going to be a general Q&A,
guys. We're going to be poring through the
Reddit, we're going to be trying to keep up with
the chat room to answer what questions we can, so
feel free. If you see something come by the chat
room on the side there, guys, if you caught
something that seems like a fun question to
answer, feel free to jump out and take it if
somebody's in the middle of explaining--
TRAVIS: Are you serious? That thing moves like The
Matrix screen.
MATT and MARY: I know.
WILL: I just like, Matthew, you're dreamy.
RYAN: We're pasting a lot of questions that come
up.
MATT: Great.
TRAVIS: Oh, there's an emoji thing!
MATT: Ryan will be helping with this.
MARISHA: So good.
MATT: There it goes.
MARISHA: Hey, where's Wendy? We could bring Wendy
out.
MATT and MARY: Yeah. Where's Wendy?
RYAN: I'm going to go get her.
MATT: We're going to pull her real fast, see if
you guys say hi to Wendy. She is one of our
official Critical Role artists. She did all the
artwork for our fantastic story of Vox Machina
pre-stream video and for the show.
MARISHA: She also did all the art for the Winter's
Crest Festival.
WILL: Yay!
MARY: She's wearing the best t-shirt ever.
(cheering)
TRAVIS and MARY: Hi Wendy!
MARISHA: We're getting a chair for you. Here you
go, scooch up a little bit.
MATT: Ryan! You want to start throwing questions
out?
RYAN: I have to frame her up and then I can do
questions.
MATT: Perfect! In the meantime, I'll start with
some--
MARISHA: Do it all at once, damn it!
MATT: Some of the Reddit questions we have ready
to go. PregosFearStaircases on Reddit.
ALL: PregosFearStaircases?
TRAVIS: Can we just talk about how that's the best
name I've heard all day? That's amazing!
MARY: Better than Bonertown?
TRAVIS: Well, Bonertown's a classic.
MATT: What does the PCs do for prep? I notice dry
erase markers for temporary hit points. Do they
lay out their spell cards or have them typed up on
one page? What do you guys do to prep for a game?
TRAVIS: Well, there's many hours of meditation and
reflection that goes into what Professor Grog is
going to do next. Or you can tattoo "impulse" on
my forehead; that would probably be it.
MARISHA: Does it need to be that clear? Nothing.
Yeah, how do they mean?
MARY: Do you go through your spells and stuff?
MARISHA: Clearly not.
WILL: You guys also know them so well by now that--
We're learning, so we're there going like-- most
of my prep is calling you and saying, "What can I
do at level four?" That's what I do because we
watch you guys and it's like, "All right, they
know everything." I didn't know any of this stuff.
You know it better than I do.
MARY: I feel like I'm cramming for an exam. It's a
constant school nightmare of, "I'm not wearing
"pants and I didn't study!"
WILL: "And there's a dragon in front of me and I
don't know how to kill it!"
MARY: Hellish something!
MATT: The classic school argument.
WILL: Exactly!
MARISHA: I guess I sometimes try and go back and watch
the end of the last episode so I can remember
where we were.
WILL: Like Breaking Bad?
MARISHA: Yeah!
WILL: Nice.
MARISHA: I also have all my spells on little
cards. I've got a few spell references: I've got
the book, cards, and spreadsheets. I have dry erase
markers and my notebooks, endless notebooks. I've
become the token party notetaker of the group.
TRAVIS: You're very organized.
MATT: And every now and then we still get a Wind
Walk. as much as we prep, we still sometimes don't
get it right.
MARY: The question was for the playable
characters, but how much time do you put in?
MATT: Per week, I put at least as much time in
prep as we do playing. So from like three, four
hours plus a week into prepping for each one of
our games. That involves, not just prepping for
that session, but also writing ahead, planning for
future elements that might tie into events, seeing
how things that happened last session will affect,
ripple down the line, and trying to make sure that
I'm not completely caught off-guard. Not that it
ever helps; I'm always completely caught
off-guard. But it makes me feel better and sleep
at night during the week.
TRAVIS: It's kind of great because we have this
endless resource of people who are going to let
you know when you miss or forget something. So
it's like, what's the point of prepping because an
hour after the show I have 500 people going, "You
might have forgotten about that!" Yep, never even
thought about it.
MATT: It's like having a wave of Clippy the
paperclip. "Um!"
MARISHA: "Uh, by the way!"
MATT: It looks to me like you're trying to use
Reckless Attacks!
WILL: Did you mean Quivering Palm?
TRAVIS: To be clear, I like that it is there, so
please keep it coming otherwise I might not
remember any of that stuff.
MARISHA: See, I have a bunch of people shouting
spells at me that I should do, that I may or may
not have learned because druids work-- do druids
work like clerics where we learn spells at the top
of the day? Do clerics work like that?
MATT: Yeah, same way where you choose the ones you
have memorized, prepared and then you can choose
from that list.
TRAVIS: How many do you get?
MARISHA: Like 17.
TRAVIS: 17 spells?!
MARY: But you can only choose between how many per
day?
MARISHA: Well, I can choose 17 that I have total,
and then I have four 1st-level spell slots, three
2nd-level, three 3rd-level, three 4th-level, two
5th-level, one 6th-level and one 7th-level that I
can use. So, theoretically, I could learn ten
level four spells, but I only have three slots
that I can use of those ten. So I have 17 spells
that I can learn that I can pull from my entire
list, which is like 100 spells, but I have to
balance it out. So I have four 1st-level spell
slots that I can burn, so I try to pick three to
four first level spells that I learn at the top of
the day. So when people are shouting at me over
the internet going, "Keyleth, Polymorph Trinket!
"Polymorph him!" I don't necessarily have it
learned. I have to learn every time at the top of
the day.
TRAVIS: You also don't hear them.
WILL: I did, because I had Wil Wheaton going,
"Turn undead! Why aren't you turning undead?"
Because I don't fucking know what that means! What
are you talking about? That's what I had. That was
my prep. You have the whole internet. I had him
yelling at me.
MATT: Now, that's my high school nightmare. Wil
Wheaton in my ear the whole time.
MARY: Stop rolling ones. Oh.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MARY: Sorry, Wil. I love you.
MATT: All right, so see if we can find another
question coming up here.
MARISHA: I saw someone ask if Wendy was going to
play with us.
WENDY: That is up to you guys.
(laughter)
MATT: Good to know. It's an interesting balance
for the show, because for Critical Role, it's the
story of Vox Machina. I'm trying to not turn it
into a guest-of-the-week show. This is why I'm
very sparing with storylines and bringing guests
in. You guys I brought in for the Slayer's Take,
and this was the right time to bring you guys back
for a bit. We'll have a couple more guests coming
in next month, it looks like, but I don't want to
make it too constant. We may have you in as a
guest in the future. It may not be very soon, but
it's good to know that you're interested.
WENDY: I would be honored.
MATT: Okay. Yeah, we will have guests
occasionally. Occasionally, because this is the
story of the core party.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
WILL: It should be. It's the way it should be.
MATT: We could do a spinoff with guests only or
something. I don't know.
WILL: We're already talking about it. You guys
have Thursday nights. We'll pre-you. We'll do
Wednesday night, and we'll have our own show.
It'll be fine. Just the two of us going, "I don't know."
MARY: "I don't know. I burned my three spells. Can
we wait an hour? I need a short rest."
WILL: And Wil's voiceover going, "Turn undead!"
MATT: There's no dungeon master.
WILL: There's no dungeon master at all!
MARY: That's all I remember: Hellish Rebuke. What
a day! I'm out.
MATT: That would be amazing.
MARY: We're going to get a home game.
WILL: We have other friends that really want to
play, so we're going to start playing, probably
getting a game together a week, and it's some
interesting people that want to join us.
MARY: If we can get one of them to get in town for
longer than a day.
WILL: We've got some cool people that want to join
our little club, so you guys have definitely
inspired us, which is good.
MARY: So much so that Liam has said, "Can we come
and watch?"
WILL: That's going to be fun.
MATT: Let's see. This is an interesting question.
From Raquem on Reddit: Do you or anyone ever get
tired of this being broadcast and wish you could
go back to your more personal game? While a lot of
good has come out of Critical Role in terms of
exposure, do you find the invasive nature of the
internet to be difficult to handle? Would you have
a problem saying, "Okay, we're done now. Thanks,
"Geek and Sundry. Thanks, everyone, and see you
later."
That was our fear when we first started the show,
and it was a very real fear, because taking
something that's so personal to us and putting it
on the internet is one, a risk; two, a danger,
having the internet come out and set fire to it
and tell you that your fun is wrong.
WILL: Your fun is wrong! I want that shirt.
(laughter)
MATT: I don't speak for everyone here, but while
that was our fear, in practice, I'm pleasantly
surprised that was never the case. The community
that's sprung out of this is so supportive and so
positive. Even the exceptions are people that are
passionate enough to want a voice and to feel
involved. There's not the hate that we were
expecting from it, and it hasn't really changed
how we play the game or our experience with it. We
enjoy it just the same. It may not be as close
physically, and the map proximity to the players
is something we're still working on getting
better, but other than that--
WILL: That's a question I would have, then. You
guys play Dungeons and Dragons, and it's a ton of
fun, and everybody's having a great time, but at
your core, you're all entertainers. We're all
entertainers; that's what we do. How much of any
of it has changed because now there's an audience?
Everything changes when there's an audience.
There's an audience, and you're entertainers.
That's what you do.
MARY: Or do you forget about it? At this point,
forget that the cameras are there, and you--
MATT: That's more the case. If there was a live
audience, it's hard not to, and as a stage
performer, you draw energy from the audience, and
it's a mutual sharing.
WILL: You do for the cameras, too, though. You
might forget that the cameras are there, but you
always forget that the cameras are there while
knowing exactly where the cameras are. That's how
we are as performers. The cameras are gone, but
you know exactly where you have to look. I've
totally forgotten that the camera's there, but I
know it's right there.
MATT: It's become a layer of it. I wouldn't say
it's impeded or changed our experience. At least,
not for me.
MARISHA: We seem to become more committed, maybe.
We try not to dick around in between. At home,
we'd go, "Hang on, I've got to go. Can we take 45
minutes for a break?"
TRAVIS: Did we? I think those were some pretty
marathon six-hour sessions. We would break off for
whispers.
MATT: But there would be catching up on shit you
did during the week.
TRAVIS: We were pretty slap-dickish when we were
playing, and I think we've carried that through
pretty nicely.
MATT: This is true.
MARISHA: I think we were pretty selfish in wanting
to entertain ourselves.
TRAVIS: That's true. It's weird, because Sam's
such a great improv person, Liam's got crazy
theater experience, so everybody knows to honor
moments, when to be quiet, when not to. The timing
is such a great thing among the cast. We're all
friends, so there's no trying to figure each other out.
MARISHA: I feel like all that was there before the
show. That was all there.
MATT: It's a lot of luck that we had those
relationships beforehand, and making that momentum
in the game before we put it on camera. What
things may have changed have been so minimal by
comparison that I haven't noticed too much of a
difference, personally.
WILL: I was saying, it would be a cool experiment
to have you dungeon master a game with a group of
people that have never played before.
MATT: I've done it. On camera.
WILL: That would be really interesting. It's like
being on any other cast, where after a while, you
know what your fellow cast member's going to do.
In a certain way, you know what's going to happen.
It'd be interesting where it's six people who have
never met before: go.
TRAVIS: That was like that D & Diesel thing,
because he had played years ago, but Chobot and
Dan were new to it, and when you sit down and
you're happy-go-lucky about it, and you drop into
your dungeon master thing, people are like, "Oh
shit, this is real."
(laughter)
TRAVIS: It's the perfect tone-setter.
MATT: That will be one of my shining moments of my
entire career, was looking over at Vin fucking
Diesel, this burly Fast and Furious guy.
TRAVIS: Tiny arms.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: He sat down. It was like, (thuds).
MATT: I shook his hand when he got there. I was
like, "Hi."
MARISHA: I still remember the camera guys were
like, "All right, Diesel, sit in frame." He was
like (thud) and the camera guy's like, "Let me
just scoot the camera back a little bit, adjust
"the focus."
MATT: That was the defining moment, watching that
arrive. He was so nice and so cordial and so much
fun and open to it, and then he sat down, and as
soon as we started, looking over and seeing this
burly man turn into an eight-year-old--
MARY: Completely. And you could see it on camera.
It was amazing. And then to see him slowly and
eventually come out of that shell and gain
confidence and remember what it was like to play
this at his age now.
TRAVIS: Those criticals didn't hurt, either.
MARY: No, it was so awesome!
MATT: His luck was ridiculous. We only had 25
minutes to play that game, which they cut down
from an hour when we got there. I was like,
"okay!" I was so afraid he would roll shitty and
have a terrible time, but he rolled really well,
and I was like, "Yes, thank you."
TRAVIS: Thank you, RNG Jesus.
WILL: I also have to say-- I don't know if you
actually saw the movie-- it was fun.
TRAVIS: Yes!
WILL: It was fun! It really was. I watched it two
nights ago. I had fun.
TRAVIS: First five or ten minutes, I was like,
"this is going to be a great movie."
(laughter)
WILL: They made a movie just for me.
MATT: Travis, do you and Laura even break into
character at home during stressful situations to
lighten the mood?
TRAVIS: Shit, no. Laura is already rolling her
eyes enough at Grog that if I tried to be that
stupid at home, she'd be like, "Fucking stop." She
wouldn't let that fly. We talk to each other in
weird voices, almost never our own, but if I tried
to talk as Grog, I would get dragon eyes of death.
I'd get smarter real fast.
WILL: I would like to slap you. Roll a dexterity
saving throw.
MARY: Feel better, Laura.
MATT: Hope you feel better. Ryan, do we have any
burning questions in the chat room?
RYAN: I have eight pages.
MATT: Do you want to toss one out? Toss one out
there we can maybe tackle?
RYAN: I can also just give you the damn thing.
MATT: Also viable, but I like hearing your voice.
TRAVIS: Lob it. Softball that bad boy.
RYAN: Red Sea Logos: does the positive outweigh
the negative on the internet? Does it make it
worth it? Because we love you guys. I'm assuming
they're referring to comments from people and the
community that have been developed. Does the
positive outweigh the negative?
MATT: Far. Far far far. The negative is so
comparatively miniscule in comparison to that
positive energy that you guys continuously
generate. Not just around the show, but this
entire Twitch channel and everyone that works hard
on it. It's been overwhelming. That was my biggest
fear, that the internet was going to come in and
go, "No!" and stab me in the chest. Don't do that,
please. No. I've already answered the question
from my perspective. It's been so overwhelmingly
positive.
TRAVIS: It's really such a weird thing to be
positive all the way across, and if you're not, we
mute you.
WILL: I still want the "your fun is wrong" shirt.
Your fun is wrong.
MARISHA: Even the people who get heated or upset,
they're getting heated and upset at our imaginary
characters that we made up in our heads, so at the
end of the day, it's still working. We're still
affecting them.
MATT: You guys are so invested in the play time to
have this much passion to yell about.
MARISHA: It makes them feel that.
MARY: Think about the effect that it's had
creatively on people. Let's talk to Wendy about
that. Come on, the artwork has been-- and the
fanfiction?
WILL: There was some fanfic this morning. I was
like, "What? Wait a minute, he's doing what? Why
"is he naked?!"
MARY: What am I doing with my tail?
WILL: Seriously, she's using her tail.
MARY: Who's driving? Okay. But in terms of
artwork, it's unbelievable.
WENDY: And your characters come to life so well,
and the world that you've painted is so vivid, so
it's easy to doodle it out.
TRAVIS: It's so great.
MARY: Wendy doodles.
MATT: It's not just artwork, too. There's people
that have produced incredible musical tracks, many
of which I've actually incorporated in our in-game
soundtracks. People that have sent fanfiction and
have gotten into writing heavily, some of them
because of the show. People tell us, "I haven't
"written in 15 years, and after watching the show,
I'm working on a new novel." It's much bigger than
us, at this point.
WILL: That's cool, though. That's what you want.
That's when everybody's imagination takes over,
and it goes to a whole other level. The same thing
happens with fantasy baseball. It's that kind of
thing. It started with a bunch of people around
the table, then everybody takes it and do whatever
they want.
MATT: It's music. It's doing what you love and
inspiring other people to do what they love, and
there are many people that inspired me to do this
and things before this, and it's great to continue
that chain, to do honor to those that inspire me
to continue to do the things that I love, and
hopefully continue that chain.
MARISHA: Beyond that--
TRAVIS: No, sorry. I had an art question.
MARISHA: I know you guys, you were saying you talk
with Kit and Meg all the time, and we were having
the conversation not long ago. All of our official
artists thus far, one's in Los Angeles, one's in
the UK, in London, one is in-- where's Joma?
MARY: The Philippines.
MARISHA: The Philippines. The other's in the
Philippines.
MARY: And Viktor is in--
MARISHA: He's in Sweden. All of our official
artists have been on different continents, which
is crazy.
MATT: Mikandi's in the Middle East.
MARISHA: Yeah, Mikandi's in the Middle East.
That's right.
MATT: We have people all over the world. It's
incredible. And people creating their own
adventures and sending us pictures and stories
from their own home games, and art of their
characters. It's so cool!
MARY: Anything that spawns that kind of creativity
is amazing.
WENDY: Creativity spawning creativity. Sorry.
TRAVIS: If you come up with a sketch, do you ever
stop and start and stop and start, or is it what
hits the page is eventually what comes up? We see
so much art, and rarely do we ever go, "No, that's
"not how I saw it." We're like, "Yes. Also yes!"
WENDY: I know sometimes I'll be watching and
sometimes I sit there and wait for a really cool
moment to come up, and then, "Bam! There it is.
I've got to get that down." My job is to put what
happens visually, so it just comes to me, I guess.
Sometimes it doesn't work. I'll sketch something
out, and it doesn't look right, so I'll have to do
it again, but what I put up, yeah.
TRAVIS: It's so cool. It's like a crystal ball.
WILL: One of the things you guys have also done,
in a weird way, is you've given people permission
to do this, if that makes any sense. I've talked
to certain people who have been like, "Yeah, I've
"played D&D forever, but we don't really talk about
it." Literally, people are like, "We don't bring
"it up; we don't talk about it. It's our thing.
There's six or seven of us. Nobody really tells
"their friends about it. We just do our thing." And
now, we watch that show and we talk about it! It's
permission to go, "Yeah, we nerd out. It's the
greatest thing in the world, and it's so much
"fun!" I think a lot of it is you guys doing that,
where it's a show.
MARY: It's improv. I never knew what it was! The
first time I played was here, and I was like, "Oh
"my gosh! I studied this in grad school and
college. It's improv."
WILL: With wizards.
MARY: With wizards!
WILL: It can't get better than that.
MARY: Can I do it? Sure, roll. Okay. So then
there's gambling.
(laughter)
MARY: Yelling at my dice! It's craps and improv
and amazingness.
MATT: It feels like-- I mentioned this at
Portland-- it feels like being part of Fight Club.
I was going through TSA when we were coming back
from Portland, Oregon. I'm going through TSA, and
the guy comes out with the laptop, because it gets
picked up from the side, and the guy has the
gloves on, and he pulls it off and looks at it and
hands it back to me and goes, "Here you go. Also
"had to stop your buddy Scanlan earlier." I was
like, "What?" And I go back, and Sam, who had
already gone through, tells me that yeah, he had
some of his checked, and the guy hands it to him
and goes, "Your bag, Scanlan Shorthalt."
(laughter)
MATT: People all throughout the world that sit
down and watch the show, and they keep it all
secret and put little comments off to the side,
and it's incredible.
MARISHA: And two days later, the Hollywood
Pantages tweeted, "Scanlan just walked the red
"carpet."
MATT: Yeah, the Hollywood Pantages.
MARISHA: The Pantages. Whoever runs social for
Pantages watches Critical Role.
MATT: So hi, if it's you. I had a bartender at the
Echoplex when we were there for Booty LA one
night, and I went to order some drinks, and he
goes, "Sure. Do you play Dungeons & Dragons on the
"internet?"
MARISHA: Which is very jarring when you're
drenched in sweat, and you're like, (untz untz
untz). Someone's like, "D&D?" and you're like--
MATT: It was awesome.
MARISHA: I feel really sober now.
WILL: That's cool.
MATT: Next question. Are there any you've chosen
there?
MARISHA: Someone asked: would you recommend
playing a game with friends or finding a group
made up of strangers?
MATT: You can go either way. I would recommend, if
you haven't played before and have any level of
self-consciousness about it, try and find friends
and people you're comfortable with to try it out
for the first time. If you don't find that much of
a social problem with engaging new things with
people you don't know, you can definitely give it
a shot, and if it turns out not being your thing,
if it's at a premade game with strangers, then you
can go back and try and find friends to play, and
if your friends are like, "I don't know how D&D
works," send them an episode of Critical Role.
TRAVIS: Yeah. There's a guy we know that plays at
Emerald Knights, and I forget what night they have
D&D nights--
MATT: Wednesday nights.
TRAVIS: Wednesday nights. He showed up a couple of
times to play with one group, and then he hopped
in some rando group and was totally nervous about
it, but he was like, "It was the best game I've
"ever played," because nobody knew him or what he
was going to do, so he was free to make these wild
choices and be totally nuts. He was like, "It was
exhilarating!" I'm like, "D&D night was
"exhilarating?" He was like, "Yeah, man! It was
great!"
WILL: There's a place right near us that does
stuff like that. Fire & Dice, right near us.
TRAVIS: We're coming.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Hello! Are you open?
MATT: That's a good question. Someone asked, how
did you guys decide on the name Critical Role for the show?
I think that was actually a Liam suggestion,
wasn't it? You and Liam were doing a few on that
one.
MARISHA: We had a text thread going. We had a few
different options that we were floating around.
MARY: What were the other ones?
TRAVIS: d20 Turds.
WILL: Prego Fear Staircases.
(laughter)
MATT: Nothing But Doors. Doors Forever. I can't
remember some of the ones we had, but Critical
Role was the one that seemed to best encompass who
we are, where we come from, and it plays in with
the RPG theme, but also role-play, and us being
actors who play roles for a living. It put
everything together what we were, so that one
stood out.
MARISHA: I think Charisma Save was being tossed
around, but someone else already had that.
MATT: There's a lot of RPG-based names that
already exist! Strangely.
MARISHA: We were trying to do something around
Dice Box, or Dice Tube or something.
(laughter)
WILL: We did Andrew Dice Play for a while. That
wasn't working.
TRAVIS: Everybody gets a pop and do the glasses.
MARISHA: We had a few different ones. I have an
art question, so while Wendy is here, from
Carbacca. Hey, Matt and the gang: What scenes do
you think you could describe or even act out--
that's not going to happen-- from before the
stream that you would like to see drawn by us
crazy fan artists, because there would be no "new
mewments"-- no new moments this week.
MARY: No nude movements?
MARISHA: No nude movements.
MATT: No, Twitter has proven that wrong.
MARISHA: Artists need something to draw.
TRAVIS: Pre-stream?
MATT and MARISHA: Pre-stream.
TRAVIS: I have one. So one of the first pranks
that Vax pulled on Grog was we were sleeping
around a campfire, and in the middle of the night,
Vax went over and wrote "dork" on Grog's forehead
with a piece of charcoal from the campfire, and
when I woke up-- we might've been drinking while
we were playing. When we woke up, I look in my
goblet in-game, and I see the reflection, and I
said, "Who wrote Kord on my face? ...Krod?"
(laughter)
TRAVIS: In character. Can't even spell it
backwards.
MATT: It's so good.
TRAVIS: It was one of the first ones, and off went
the prank war.
MATT: There was that. And I remember, named after
that, you guys purchased an ox at one of the small
towns on your way out to Emon. It was near
Westruun. You purchased an ox that was useless,
and you named it Dork the ox.
TRAVIS: We were going to use him as a sacrifice.
WILL: Dork the ox?
MARISHA: And we tried to interrogate him, because
we were hoping he would know stuff--
MATT: Speak to Animals. The ox was just like--
MARISHA: He was like, "I'm a cow. I don't know
shit."
MATT: It was similar to you interrogating the cows
in the later episode. You learned so much from the
first time. As you started to travel, because Dork
doesn't travel very well, Grog took it upon
himself to find a way to cram him into the bag of
holding, which took a series of strength checks
and tensile checks to see that the bag didn't
burst in the process.
TRAVIS: It's like in Hermione's handbag.
MATT: He wasn't a huge ox, but he was still
growing up. Managed to push him in there, and this
was also the sad lesson when they reached the next
town to realize that the bag of holding does not
have a perpetual air supply, and that was the end
of Dork the ox.
TRAVIS: Dork was toast. We pull him out. This
giant carcass fell out.
WILL: Poke holes in the bag for Dork.
MARY: At least you ate well that night.
TRAVIS: I was like, "Oh shit!" And we butchered
him, and we put him back in little pieces, but
then we also learned that the bag of holding is
not refrigerated, so three months later, I pull it
out, and this gelatinous ooze comes sliding out.
We're like, "Has it coated everything else in
"there?"
"Let's say no."
MATT: Oh man. What are some other great moments
from pre-stream?
MARISHA: Two years' worth.
MATT: The most serious one was Pike's death.
MARY: That's what I was going to say.
MATT: Pike being killed in the throne room. I
think your artwork in the pre-stream video,
wonderfully done with the shadow against the
wall.
TRAVIS: We were not expecting that.
MATT: Yeah, that was the glabrezu, the treachery
demon, getting the killing blow on Pike as the
whole party watched on and crumpled to their
knees.
TRAVIS: Yeah, Ashley literally pulled her shirt up
to her eyes, and Laura sat under the table
MARISHA: Yeah, in the fetal position.
TRAVIS: They were both crying, and the rest of us
were in shock. What? We do what? What happened?
MARISHA: It was really sad. We always remember the
time we discovered the magic carpet, too, because
that was so good. It was so epic. Allura's tower,
which we've seen now happen on game, right, her
tower implode?
MATT: Well, Allura's tower has a specific magical
defense, where it can crush itself into a small
extra-dimensional space and then rebuild itself.
However, the recent attack on the tower was not
part of the defense mechanism. That was Vorugal
actually destroying the tower, so what you saw
recently in Emon was the end of Allura's tower,
which is unfortunate.
Great question here, and this pertains to you and
technically, you. Romance between player
characters is not something you see in a lot of
games. This is by Gore Ax on reddit. Liam said in
an interview that he approached you first about
the possibility of adding romance to the game.
What advice did you give to him or would you give
to DMs and players about that subject? Also, since
you knew about Vax's interest in Keyleth months
before Marisha, did that ever create an awkward
moment that you had to play dumb about it?
Interesting question. I think romance in game is
an interesting storytelling facet. I think it's
been a phenomenal thread in our game, and it's
driven a lot of great character moments, and it's
brought some needed realism to both Vax and
Keyleth's relationship. It's been really cool.
You do have to be respectful, and you have to make
sure that the game group is mature enough to
handle that. That would involve one, talking with
the players and the DM before it happens. In this
situation, Liam talked to me without talking to
Marisha because he wasn't sure if he wanted to
pursue it or not. He just wanted to make sure it
wouldn't be weird for me, and as we're actors, and
we trust we understand the separation between
character and ourselves, that was never an issue.
I was very comfortable with Liam.
But not all games will be like that, and some
people might have jealousy issues, so you want to
make sure before you even pursue anything like
that that you talk to everyone involved and make
sure that it's cool. It's not necessary, and it
can be a really cool facet if everybody treats it
like that.
And romance doesn't have to be a very melodramatic
thing, either. It could be an element of the
flavor. It could be a flirtation you carry on and
is an off-camera thing that gets mentioned here
and there. It doesn't have to be that you sit
there at the precipice of a cliff declaring your
love for 30 minutes while the other players gag
themselves in the corner.
WILL: You could just kiss her and leave. That's
what I did. Kiss her and walk out the door.
MARISHA: Cowboy in the sunset.
WILL: By the way, I probably should've asked you
about that. Do you mind if I kiss her and then
leave?
MATT: No, it was a great moment! I knew you were
leaving.
(laughter)
WILL: Exactly. I knew you were out.
MATT: It's cool, too, because some romances
succeed and become a cool driving moment for the
character to try and protect the one they care
about. Many romances fail and end up leading to an
interesting tension between the characters. I'm
excited to see where this goes, because it could
go either way. There's been a lot of interesting
perspectives here. What I like about your guys'
romance is it's very realistic in the sense that
it isn't an immediate grasping each other, and
it's perfect. Both of you are broken people, and
you're both trying to still figure out whatever
this is, and Keyleth's very unsure, and you're
both feeling out the circumstance in the midst of
this apocalyptic chaos. I find it fascinating.
WILL: And then Kash comes back in the middle to
add a little-- that's how life works! It's
absolutely how life works, though.
MARISHA: Because you know Kash was Keyleth's first
kiss, right?
WILL: Yeah. It's one of those things.
MARY: And it doesn't have to be this bang, bong
thing. The most beautiful moment, I think, was
when he knocked on your door and said, "I don't
want to be alone tonight." And one of my favorite
pieces of art came out of that, of "You are my
sun." That was so beautiful and encapsulated that
moment so perfectly, without having it hot and
heavy or anything else. Just two lonely broken
people seeking solace.
MATT: Everyone's like, "Oh, are they going to go
and bang?" I'm like, "No." Not where they are as
people. They're both so hurt and feeling so sad
and alone that they need that comfort of somebody
else there to hold them. That artwork, I felt, was
a great encapsulation of that.
WILL: That's the thing that amazed me about
watching you guys and how into your characters you
guys got. The last episode we did, when we're all
in the bar and they're having a drink. We finish
the episode, and Liam went, "Man, we needed that."
And it was like, "With everything going on, we
"needed to sit at a bar, and we needed to drink. We
needed that." You could tell. Everybody gets into
what's going on. It's really cool.
MARY: And then we watched Scanlan cause
diarrhea--
WILL: And the snarfed quivering palm technique.
(laughter)
MATT: I like that. If you guys see any questions,
by the way, that you want to reach out and grab,
feel free to. Or we could look through some of
these papers.
RYAN: There's a question for Wendy that someone
sent. By Toruya: What class would she play if she
were to join?
WENDY: Well, in a game that I'm playing already, I
play a druid, and her name is Clover.
MARISHA: Clover's so cute.
WENDY: She's a faun. That's what I would play.
MATT: That's awesome! Clover's awesome.
MARISHA: Travis, what is yours and/or Grog's
favorite kill that you've had?
TRAVIS: (Grog voice) They're like your children.
You can't really pick one.
(laughter)
WILL: It's going to be Kashaw in about an hour.
TRAVIS: I think the one where he bit the tongue
out of the mouth and then tore it out. That was
pretty good. The gorier the better.
MATT: You bask in the glory of those so well.
TRAVIS: I do. I get so happy when it's a blood
shower.
MATT: This question here: Matt, does anyone in the
game have a deck of many things? No. And if I can
help it, they never will.
WILL: Write down where we can find that!
MARY: Deck of many things.
MATT: Oh, good luck, guys. Deck of many things is
what you throw in the game when you're bored and
want to get it over with.
TRAVIS: That was the charity game, right?
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: I have someone here saying, how detailed
are our notes? She just says, how detailed are
your notes? I don't know if she's asking Matt or
us. Why don't you go first?
MATT: My preparation is pretty-- a lot of my notes
are narrative points and bullet points. I'll
choose whatever locations they might possibly go
to, I'll list what NPCs are there and what their
current circumstance is. I will then bullet-point
important bits of information that NPC might know,
based on certain topics that are relevant to the
current storyline, and have that there for quick
reference. A lot of it's shorthand, to remind me.
A lot of it looks like a broken-down report that
you would send to some company somewhere. It's a
structure of information for myself. It's very
loose, because I don't want to feel like I'm
reading a page too often. There are certain scenes
I want to set properly, and I'll write those in
advance and go back and forth, but for the most
part, I'll outline basic notes and points the NPCs
would know, and then based on what you guys do--
WILL: Do you ever do specific dialogue? Like, I
have to put this line in.
MATT: Every now and then, if it's a very key
character moment and the story lends itself and
there's a good possibility that someone will ask
about it. There's many things that don't get asked
that the NPCs never mention. Maybe that'll come to
light down the line. For more important NPCs or
very specific story beats, I will write out lines
of dialogue to make sure that I don't miss any
important information and to make sure that I
don't end up leading the players astray
accidentally, because when you're improvising off
the cuff, sometimes stuff comes out and you're
like, "Oh shit. What'd I just say?"
MARY: Accents and everything else, I was just
thinking, the notes you have to keep for making
sure you get the right voice.
MATT: That's the other thing, too. Whenever I
create an NPC, I'll note a texture and timbre of
their voice. I'll put "gravelly, low-key, haughty
and full of himself, Cornwall." Make note of the
texture and dialect I use, if any. That way, I can
get something ballpark of what they were before.
It's not going to be perfect, and I'm sure if you
line them up, you'd be like, "Oh, it's changed
"over time."
TRAVIS: What did you write next to Victor? Crazy?
WILL: Mad Hatter.
MATT: Victor, I didn't have to. Victor was created
on the spot.
WENDY: Really?
MATT: Yeah. And since then, I had to write down,
"fucking crazy old guy." Prospector, I think is
where it came from. Very much that (Victor voice)
crazy old prospector type thing. That realm.
MARY: I was going to try to mask of many faces of
Vanessa, and I turned to Travis and was like,
"What accent did Vanessa have?" I totally forgot!
I can't sell it if I don't have the accent.
TRAVIS: I was like, Spanish?
MATT: She's eastern European.
RYAN: This question has come up several times, so
I figure it should be asked. It's by Villager26,
Valkyr Parable, and Gaica. Has there been a
storyline that hasn't been or cannot be explored
now that the campaign's on stream? If so, can you
tell us about it? Also, was there a failed version
of the campaign before Vox Machina, with the same
group. Like, you guys tried it, you had different
characters that didn't work and you had to reboot
it.
MARISHA: TPK'd?
MATT: No, actually. This group, Vox Machina was
its first time coming together in this world I
created. It's been created over time with the
campaign. I didn't go out to build the setting to
build the whole world. It was a one-shot, and I
built a town. I built Stillben. Then as we turned
from a one-shot into a campaign, I began
expanding, and now it's become much bigger than I
anticipated, and I'm perpetually fleshing it out
over time. But yeah, there was no failed earlier
attempt per se.
MARY: Didn't Taliesin have a different character
and he rerolled?
TRAVIS: Very first game, right?
MATT: Very first game, he had a character, and he
couldn't make it for the next few games. It was a
dragonborn paladin, and then he couldn't make the
next few games, and when he was able to, his
schedule opened up for the next one, I was like,
"Do you want to play the same character?" He was
like, "I want to try something different." And
then Percy was born. That was where you guys found
him over in the Umber Hills.
TRAVIS: Which is great, because when he was
playing that dragonborn wizard, sorcerer?
MATT: Paladin.
TRAVIS: Paladin. He knew everything. He saved us
from dying in that first hour and a half. We were
fumbling around like a bunch of blind morons, and
you could see him biding his time. I wish we had
video of it so I could go back and see if you gave
him a nod, like "go ahead and save these
"jackasses." He was like, "I would like to freeze
this gear and move this and shift that," and
everything stopped, and we're like, "We're alive!"
Just because of Taliesin.
MATT: Yeah. I will say, there aren't any dead
story threads from pre-stream. It's hard to equate
what that would be; the party went where they
went. There are many different facets of the world
that they didn't come across.
MARISHA: It's like trying to argue past timelines
that never existed.
MATT: I'm sure there are things that might answer
your question that I can't recall.
MARISHA: I'm sure I have a bunch of unborn
children that will never happen.
MATT: That got weird.
MARISHA: I don't know why I said it.
WILL: I just kissed her, dude!
MARY: That's a powerful kiss, man.
WILL: Just grab my medal, hey. That's what all the
slices on the arm are. No.
MATT: This is an interesting question. From
Sanderf90 on Reddit. Which NPC that Vox Machina
encountered became a lot more important than you
first expected? We know Clarota wasn't supposed to
join the party and Victor came out of thin air.
Are there any examples where a character you
didn't expect became far more important? Gilmore.
MARY: Gilmore, yeah.
MATT: Your Gilmore was phenomenal. Ryan's Gilmore
was awesome. He was a merchant in Emon that I had
created that had a fun personality, and I fleshed
out his background a little bit, and I thought it
would be a fun character that they would
occasionally come across, but after that first
encounter, it turned into a full discussion, he
and Vax began to build this relationship, and you
guys kept going back to him as your go-to purveyor
of magical goods in Emon. Then the investment
became more attached, and then as it progressed,
he became a central NPC, which I'm really happy
about. I love Gilmore. He's such a great
character.
MARY: I can't wait to see where he goes, to be
honest. I'm really looking forward to seeing it.
I'm as big a fan as you guys are of the show, and
it's not just because you guys are my friends. I'm
invested in these characters. It's such great,
compelling storytelling. It really is. Bravo to
all of you guys. Plus, it's really fun, but you
also get invested in these great characters. It
was hard last week to not hear about certain
characters and go, "Oh my-- oh. I don't know
"them."
(laughter)
MARISHA: Going off that, Maelyn in the chat asked
if there was any more background for Gilmore.
MATT: Yeah. There's plenty of background for
Gilmore. Since he became a central character, I've
fully fleshed out his backstory. We'll have to see
if it comes to light.
MARISHA: And going off that again, StormShadow17
in chat asked, Are we more attached to these
characters because we made them from scratch and
they didn't come from a script?
MATT and MARISHA: Very.
TRAVIS: Yeah, totally.
MATT: There is something to be said about-- as
actors, you're handed roles, and you work as a
collaboration with a production team to tell a
story, and all of you craft it together. You're a
facet of the machine. There's something about
creating from scratch a character's personality,
strengths, weaknesses, and then stepping into
their shoes and developing them and seeing
whatever their potential is for good or evil and
seeing it through in that imagination-based body
of theirs that is so much more personal and
connected that any role I've played. A lot of NPCs
in this game are closer to me than any character
I've played in a video game.
WILL: I also think you get the benefit of time
here, which you don't with a lot of roles you
play. A lot of roles we do, it's like, "Oh, when
did you play that role?" It was two Tuesdays ago
for three hours; that's when I played that role.
Whereas this, you're building it out, and you
become your character. It's the difference of when
you start a show, they're writing for you, and
when you really get to know the character, then
they're writing to you. You know what I mean? So
you guys have that awesome benefit of time, so you
really become your characters. We have recording
sessions, and even long-running shows, you might
record once a week for three hours for four
months, and that's it, and then you're on to the
next character.
MARY: Yeah, but somebody else is making your
choices for you. In this, you make your own
choices. You make your own mistakes, you've got
your own success, and everything else, so it is
from you guys and what the character is learning.
WILL: When you came to me and were like, "Would
you like to come on the show?" It was like, yeah,
great. And you're like, "All right. Who do you
want to be?" What? "Here you go. Who do you want
"to be? Let's build it." You sat at my house. I'd
assumed Matt's going to come over for a
half-hour.
MARISHA: Well, my prom in eighth grade--
TRAVIS: It's all therapeutic.
WILL: I thought he was coming over for a
half-hour. We were working for five hours. "All
"right, roll." Dude, this is the greatest. It was
awesome.
MATT: Which plays into a great question someone
else asked in the chat room. I can't remember who
it was, unfortunately, but they asked: For Will
and Mary, how did you guys come up with your
character backstories?
MARY: Oh. I'm obsessed with the moon and astral
geography and everything else, so I knew I wanted
that to have a very important part in her story,
and then to be honest, I had never played Dungeons
& Dragons, so I looked at the group, and I was
like, what does everybody have? We've got a
sorcerer, we've got a druid, we've got gnomes,
we've got bards. I went on the internet and was
like, what's-- oh, a tiefling. Oh, a warlock. That
still is a spellcaster; I knew I wanted to cast
spells, and I thought, a tiefling. That's not on
the show. Let's do that, it's really cool. Looked
at the design and everything else, and then make
it as tragic as possible, because that's always
good. Everybody's got a terrible childhood. And we
do, but I love the image of her first time being
outside was at night after this castle, and
looking up at the moon and having it sing to her
and save her life. That's the moment when she came
to life the first time ever is that moment. And
then she throws rocks at it. No, I'm kidding.
WILL: Yeah, I don't know. The name Kashaw was one
of the main characters in a story I wrote when I
was 16. He was the bad guy. He was the bad
brother, so originally I was sitting there going,
"I guess Kashaw could work." And then it changed
the whole character, then you and I sat down and
talked, and once you and I talked for a while, as
a writer, I then went, "Here we go." We've talked
about this, since Laura's the same way. I love
fantasy so much that once you get one little
nugget of an idea, then you start building a
world, and the story goes from there, and what
happens if we go this way or that way. And then
it's the little things. Different-colored eyes
having a whole story and the scars all have a
story, and you can build from every little thing
you do.
TRAVIS: It's like the ultimate character
customization screen at the beginning of a video
game. It's unlimited.
WILL: Side, quick thing. You guys do a lot of
video games. Isn't it the greatest when you're the
voice of the you character, so you can make it
look like you and it's your voice? It's the
coolest thing ever. I'm the only one in the world
that can do this!
(laughter)
MATT: It's really cool until your character dies a
horrible death, and you're like, "I'm going to
"take a walk."
WILL: It's so funny. I love that, though.
TRAVIS: Your own death.
MATT: On the topic of backstories and tragic
backstories, I will say, there is no more
dangerous occupation in any fantasy world than
being a parent, because everyone's an orphan.
(laughter)
MATT: If you have a kid, you're counting your days
down until a demon or orc comes and kills you and
burns your village.
WILL: Yeah, I guess it's rare. I created this
character. His life's great. Parents have been
married for 75 years. This is great, man.
MARY: They're funding my quest.
WILL: Yeah, taking a year off from college.
MARISHA: It's my bar mitzvah money.
TRAVIS: We do need to have one guest that's got
the silver spoon and has never suffered tragedy in
his life. We need a super optimistic person.
WILL: Everything will be fine! Come on! We can
befriend the dragon.
WENDY: Almost Clover, but not quite. Almost. Does
have the tragic backstory.
MARY: Parents still alive?
WENDY: Everyone's dead.
TRAVIS: Everyone's dead!
MATT: Just me and the DM. No NPCs.
MARISHA: A friend of mine, Eric Campbell, who's
been on the stream a few times, in his current D&D
campaign that he's playing, he's playing a guard
from Whitestone-- in our world-- who saw Vox
Machina come in, do these heroic feats, and is
like, I want to be like those guys. But he's got
parents, a nice background. He's going to hit the
road because Vox Machina inspired him, and then
find out how fucking terrible and awful it is.
He's real excited to be broken and beaten. He's
trying to be optimistic and a hero--
MARY: I got a care package from Mom and Dad!
WILL: It's their heads! Oh my god!
TRAVIS: What's in the box?
ALL: What's in the box?
MATT: I saw a question in chat. Someone asked if
the loss of the magic carpet was intentional, and
making it difficult to enchant. It was not
intentional. It was a particular danger in the
room to any of the players. It was unfortunate
that rolls--
MARISHA: The carpet took the brunt.
WILL: You saved me, though. Thank you.
MATT: The carpet took the brunt of it.
MARISHA: That's right! I feel really bad for you
guys, because Liam and I were like, "No!" And
you're like, "What the fuck is wrong with these
people?"
TRAVIS: We were in the other room. We were outside
in the studio.
WILL: There's the delay, so 30 seconds after it
happened, you heard from the other side of the
room, "No!"
MARISHA: You could feel the pain twice, like it
happened twice.
TRAVIS: You did it on purpose.
MATT: No, I did not do it on purpose!
TRAVIS: I'd like to roll insight. It's all good.
MARY: He's telling the truth.
MATT: It made it so much easier for you guys to
get from place to place when you had that magic
carpet.
TRAVIS: We flew over the Underdark. We flew over
the whole encampment and stuff.
MATT: It was cool. It had a lot of utility.
TRAVIS: Now we're going to die quicker.
MATT: These things happen. Let's see. For the
cast, what predictions about where the story was
going did you make that turned out to be
completely wrong? Or did you have any theories
that turned out to be spot-on?
TRAVIS: Clarota was a bitch!
MARY: You never trusted him from the beginning.
TRAVIS: I said it, but half the party was all
about it. I wrote it four times.
MARY: I remember when you guys went down into that
cave, and I was like, this is totally random, and
everybody said, "Don't do it!" And down you went.
I thought, "How much of this was planned? Was
"there somebody there in the first place?"
MATT: There was. I didn't expect them to ever
encounter it for the next four or five sessions,
let alone have it go so positively. It was going
to be an encounter, but they managed to roll
socially in a way that convinced Clarota not that
they were friends, necessarily, but to the
betterment of his survival to infiltrate and
manipulate.
TRAVIS: I thought the Briarwoods were both
vampires and somebody was going to turn vampiric.
I'm not going to say it was an easy fight, but I
thought somebody was going to be on death's door
legit, not just because of the ziggurat's
anti-magic zone.
MARY: Laura was.
TRAVIS: That was after-- was that because of the
fight, or was it because of the ziggurat?
MARY: No, Vex was before you guys went to
Whitestone. Wasn't it?
TRAVIS: Going down to one? That was down in the
ziggurat.
MARY: No, it was outside the castle. She cast
Finger of Death.
MATT: She's done it twice.
MARY: She's done it twice. Before you guys got the
carriage driver. I think this is right. Finger of
Death and Laura was two points away from dead.
WILL: You're already up. Your fun is wrong. Your
fun is wrong! (laughs) I want one of those. I call
that.
MARISHA: Do you want to answer that question?
MATT: This is a good question, because this comes
up often. Will Cooper, @willmortis asks,
@matthewmercer, how open are you to ideas and
suggestions from us about allies for Vox Machina
to encounter? I'm careful, because it is my game
world. I have a very specific layout as to how the
things in the story ought to go. If I do intend to
possibly in the future put this content out for
you guys to utilize, I have to be careful with
copyright stuff and not using too many outside
ideas because then it gets a little tricky. Plus,
a lot of people that have submitted stuff have
been like, "Hey, I have an item I'd like for
someone to use. It does plus six damage and gives
"them the strength of four gods." Okay. That's
cool, yo.
TRAVIS: What's wrong with that? Give me that
thing.
MARY: You have it. It's called Bacon.
MATT: Or I'll get NPCs that have a 14-page
backstory that is fun to read, but the focus is on
the players. I'll try to bring in what I can. So
instead, we've done a couple of circumstances
where we've incorporated NPCs that fans have
submitted as part of a contest, and we'll start
hopefully doing that more as the year progresses.
There will be opportunities for that, and you're
more than welcome to send stuff in. I don't have
time to read everything, unfortunately; my free
time is gone forever now, and I accept that, but
we'll have contests and stuff and incorporate
stuff for fans. We've had fans that we've lost due
to illness or circumstances in the past that I've
incorporated into the game. We've had fans who
were sick, and we've brought into the game as
NPCs, as well, and we've had contests in the past
and hopefully do more of those in the future.
As far as how open to it? I'm careful, because it
is still my game, and I don't want it to be too
much of a door I open, where everyone throws
everything and I no longer have control over it,
and I have very specific balancing ideas, too. But
there will be opportunities.
WILL: You're right, though. It's one of the
reasons why legally, your favorite television
show, you can't go and write a script for it. They
can't read it, because then if it shows up later,
then they can say, "Hey, I wrote that." It's one
of those things that it's a cool idea, but you do
have to be careful when you're building your own
world that it's just yours.
MATT: Yeah, if I ever intend to try and release
anything in the future, like a campaign setting,
which I would love to. The question comes up
often. I have to be very careful about that.
That's the largest reason.
WILL: He's not being uncool. He's being totally
prudent. You have to, though. It's important.
MATT: There will be opportunities in the future.
MARISHA: And a lot of the players get that, too,
and we're on the same path. What, do you not get
that, Travis?
TRAVIS: Laura texted me and said my pulled-up
pants look weird like that.
MARY and WILL: Wow.
TRAVIS: It's hot in here! I was pulling the pants
up.
MARY: I thought we were waist-up!
WILL: I'm sorry. I'm also about to get married, so
the idea of live-stream nagging is amazing to me.
Wow.
MATT: (shushes, whip crack)
TRAVIS: You don't know what it's like living with
a dragon.
WILL: Could you make a masculinity throwing save?
MATT: That's an eight.
TRAVIS: Advantage? Two!
WILL: That's awesome. I love that. She's
hysterically funny. "Your rolled-up pants look
"weird."
MATT: Preciously Insane on Reddit asks whether
Matt has ever had to discard any cool ideas
because of the players going in an entirely
different direction or because he felt it wouldn't fit
in the world. Often! But I hold onto them
because that could come into a one-shot in the
future, or if it comes back around in the story,
they return to the same place, they continue that
thread, possibly, and like I said, if I ever end
up wanting to release a setting, it would be a
cool thing to put into the world that even if Vox
Machina never encounters, you guys can in your own
games. So yeah, I hold onto it all. Not everything
gets caught. It's part of the fun of the
randomness of the game is you never know where the
players are going to go. I'll put a lot of effort
into maps and threads, and be like, "All right,
cool, so today, they're-- where are you going?"
TRAVIS: I loved it in the pre-stream games, you'd
show up with these two bags and five or six maps,
and I remember there was one night, a six- or
seven-hour game, where no maps were put upon the
table. You were rolling them back up, and I was
like, "Were those for tonight?" You were like,
"They were going to be." And we didn't go any of
those places.
MATT: It still happens here, often. But that's
fine.
MARISHA: My favorite was still when we snuck in
the back door of the Clasp the first time, and we
were like "Knock-knock. Oh, hey, Clasp leader.
Hey. What's up? We're here to decapitate you." And
we didn't plan any of that and you're like, "Oh,
you walk in? Let me start drawing real quick." And
starts drawing things. He's like, "Clasp leader is
there." It was good.
TRAVIS: Off the cuff.
MARISHA: Oh no, it just went dark. It's another
one going off that. Ivar @mistbornelite asks, how
often do we strategize outside the game? Which is
never, really.
TRAVIS: Strategize?
MARY: But do you think about it during the week? I
remember going, "Well, we ended that, and we've
"got frost giants coming up. What can I do?"
MARISHA: It's impossible not to think about it.
TRAVIS: I really wanted to look to see what their
traits are and stuff, but I can't.
MARY: I didn't do that. I didn't cheat--
TRAVIS: I wanted to cheat. I'm saying I wanted to
cheat.
MARY: I was like, "I really want to find out about
white dragons." But no, I did think about what
could I do?
MARISHA: I'll do that. Honestly, I think more
often than not, I'll be like, "Goddamn it, Percy
"totally had the last word. I should have said
this."
WILL: Oh, you're doing the drive away from the
fight!
MARISHA: I should have done this.
WILL: The Jerk store called, and they ran out of
you!
MARISHA: And I'll be like, next time!
MATT: To be fair, Taliesin is the master of the
one-liner bookend. He throws out some of the
best-- he'll wait for the perfect moment, and
then, "I'm sorry." (boof)
WILL: But there's a genius to that. Being able to
button a scene. There is a genius to that.
MARISHA: But I'll spend the week being like, "Next
time I see Percy, I'm going to give him a piece of
"my--" And it never happens.
MATT: What you guys were saying about the creature
stuff, don't forget, in-game, you can research
creatures that you know you may encounter out in
the world to learn about what they do, and you
can, depending on how well you research and retain
the information, learn things like weaknesses or
what type of abilities they have.
TRAVIS: Me, research? He ain't going to read.
MATT: You have a problem with that.
TRAVIS: But if it has pictures.
WILL: I asked you about that, because you were
bringing me back, and I said, "Look, I haven't
"been able to watch the show lately. What should I
know?" And you were the first person to go, "You
"know what? You're in a whole different part of the
world. You shouldn't know anything going on. So
"come in the way you came in before. They're coming
to you, so you shouldn't know what was happening."
I was like, "Okay. Yeah, that makes more sense." I
wanted to research and you were like, "No. You
"don't need to."
MATT: For instance, in the game, Laura has a very
strong knowledge of dragons; that's been her
favored enemy for a long time. You guys could
spend time and really delve into what threats they
pose beyond your encounters, and who knows what
you might find.
MARY: Exactly. Working for the Slayer's Take, how
much time have we had in the library after
encountering a rakshasa or the dragon. How much
time have we had to do our rakshasa--
WILL: You and I talked about a bunch of that stuff
coming back in, where we all met up, and we were
there 20 minutes before Matt got there.
MARY and WILL: What have we been doing?
WILL: What was the last mission we were on? We
came up with a backstory for each other, for our
relationship.
MARY: Why we're together.
WILL: Why we're friends, and why we've hung on,
and all that kind of stuff. Friends, all the
people on the internet. Just friends. But yeah, I
love that stuff.
MATT: Any other questions burning right now?
MARISHA: Travis, do you think Grog is unable to be
corrupted by Craven Edge due to his lower
intelligence? You're too dumb to be corrupted?
TRAVIS: I don't even think Grog thinks the sword's
trying to corrupt him. He's just a chatty sword
that for some reason talks to him. That's it. He
got the battle-sound lightsaber at Target, and it
talks.
MARISHA: Is Grog convinced that it's in his head,
and it's like Wilson and Tom Hanks in Castaway?
TRAVIS: I think he thinks it's just loud enough
for him to hear, so he's always like-- I have no
idea how that sound actually works.
MATT: I wasn't expecting you guys to retrieve
Craven Edge from the corpse. I wasn't expecting it
to be kept, and I definitely wasn't expecting it
to be handed to you, and now I'm so excited to see
where this goes.
TRAVIS: You didn't think we'd keep it?
MARISHA: He told me later he thought we'd throw it
into the acid with everything else.
TRAVIS: Fuck that noise. I'd throw Percy in if he
tried to do that.
MARY: I'm still waiting for the Calvin & Hobbes
mashups of Grog and Craven Edge. I put that out
there.
TRAVIS: I wasn't equipped for that shit in the
monk pit. That was unexpected. I had trouble
putting baby down.
MARY: Baby didn't want to be put down. You're not
picking up a flaming hammer instead of baby.
MATT: Interesting question from duetempte in
reddit says, how do you balance combat around six
to eight PCs, especially one- or two-enemy boss
fights? Best fast answer as I can. When you have
that many players, you have to keep running
quickly. Taking initiative is a huge thing. For
initiative, when I ask from top to bottom in
chunks of five. 25 to 20? 20 to 15? And what I do
is write the players' names down in the order, and
then if an enemy falls into that order, I'll write
it in the column to the right of it, staggered. It
almost looks like a back-and-forth line so I can
tell one column are heroes, one column are
enemies, and I have them in the order that they
show up in initiative. That way it's very easy,
very quick to write down, and visually it's easy
for me to reference who's up next. But for
balancing? You don't always want to give something
more hit points, because that means it's going to
take longer. With a lot of players, you still want
it to be around long enough to be a challenge. I
recommend increasing damage it deals, because it
doesn't mean you have to have as long an
encounter, but still have that threat of serious
danger. Not crazy damage, but scale the damage it
deals. A lot of creatures have legendary
resistance and legendary actions, which are very
helpful.
MARISHA: That's some bullshit. It's such
bullshit.
TRAVIS: You get three per round or something?
MATT: Oh my god, you're seven players. That's
fair.
MARISHA: It sucks when you're like, I'm going to
burn this 5th-level spell, and it's going to be
fucking amazing, and it can't fail, because the
spell says-- oh, legendary resistance. Oh.
MATT: So sorry. Maybe don't start off with all
your powerful shit.
WILL: Wow. You know what would help? The deck of
everything, or whatever the hell that thing is.
MATT: No.
MARY: Wand of healing. Do you guys ever go home
and have moments of contention about what occurred
in the game?
WILL: I'm so glad that was the question. I thought
it was going a different way. I'm so glad that was
your question! I've got to be honest with you. I'm
glad that's where you went.
MARY: Do you ever role-play Gilmore?
WILL: That's what I was waiting for! Do you ever
go home and have moments of contention? I was
like, thank god.
MARISHA: What was that tweet that we got that they
tagged you, me, and Liam in it, and it was like,
"God, Vax's voice is so sexy. Hey, Marisha, do you
ask Matt to do Vax's voice for you?" I was like--
out of everything; out of all the fan art, fanfic,
now you done made it weird. That's the line
right there. We found it.
MARY: But did stuff happen in the game and do you
have to take moments of breathing, or do you
realize it's just a game?
MARISHA: Only a few times. Getting the polearm in
the face, I was like, really? All three attacks on
Keyleth?
MATT: You can barter with an NPC. You can't barter
with the DM.
MARY: What!
WILL: (whip crack)
MARY: Did you hear that? I hear that one, too.
MARISHA: So many whips in the atmosphere. Not too
bad, though. Every game, we have people being
like, "Oh shit, Matt's sleeping on the couch
tonight!" And I'm like, no, it's fine.
TRAVIS: That doesn't happen at your house? When I
almost smacked Trinket and he ran through the
minefield?
MATT: You deserved that.
TRAVIS: Generally, everybody laughs, and when you
clean it up, you're like, "Man, that was fun."
She's like, "You never do that again." "Oh shit,
it's just a game." She was like-- and went
upstairs. "Babe, I love you!"
MARISHA: I love it so much.
TRAVIS: Imaginary bear. "What?" Nothing!
WILL: Totally real.
MARY: Start doing bear sounds downstairs.
TRAVIS: (bear-like) Grog is okay.
MATT: A two-part question; I want to answer a
couple of these. PseudoX1 on Reddit writes, with
some enemies that Vox Machina has faced, every
once in awhile, a PC gets one-shot by something.
Do you plan on one-shotting someone when they come
up against these enemies to provide a challenge,
or is it a side effect of the monster?
All the ones they've come across have been actual
side effects of the monster, like the banshee.
That's what they do. It's a nice way to bring in
challenge, especially when you have certain
players that are really resilient. Every now and
then, it's nice to remind them that not all
attacks just do damage. Some of them snuff you
out. It's a cool dynamic to it, because it
immediately turns the tide of the battle to not
only intense danger, even if it's not a very
powerful creature, to survival as well as being on
the aggressive, which is great. It adds tension to
it. Other part of the question: when listening to
players monologuing with each other, you look like
you're staring into their souls. What is usually
going on in your mind during those? I'm
remembering Nick at Night reruns, usually. Dick
van Dyke Show.
WILL: You've got (sings Meow Mix jingle).
MARY: (flatline sound) A nice 1K tone.
MATT: Someone please edit that, and at one of
those moments when the players are monologuing, my
brain going off on the Gilligan's Island intro.
TRAVIS: When you were monologuing, I actually
leaned over to Laura or to you and was like, "He
"hasn't looked down yet," because you were
explaining the history of the world, and we're
always looking for a little bit of-- and come back
up, and you were up here the whole time. I'm like,
"He's a god."
MARY: It was such an amazing monologue.
TRAVIS: It was insane! It was six minutes!
WILL: It was the history of the world!
MATT: I was afraid it was going to be boring. I
didn't realize I was going to be telling you guys
the whole-- and that was the condensed version.
WILL: I love that, though. Oh, he's talking about
how the world was created.
MARISHA: It's creation myth time.
MARY: It's like Greek mythology. We've got all of
it up until--
MATT: You guys never got to the point where you
inquired about the creation myth of Exandria and
what the Second Spark was, the Penance, and all
these other terms you've come across at points in
the game. It all plays into that world, and that
might be unveiled more as time goes on, as now
you're looking for the Vestiges, which do tie into
previous time periods. But yeah, as soon as you
guys started inquiring about it, I was like,
okay!
TRAVIS: We do go back and watch those things,
though, because there's no way some of us catch
that the first time around. You're a good
note-taker, but I'm like--
MARISHA: Even so, though, I'm generally scribbling
hot words, because I can't get it all. Oh, that
seems important. Key points.
WILL: I scribble them wrong. I was home later that
night going, "What's a vestibule?"
TRAVIS: The vegetables of the portents.
WILL: We're looking for vegetables. What's going
on?
MARISHA: Someone said, Matt, how hard was it to
decide to destroy the city of Emon after you spent
so much time to build it? Additionally, how early
in the story planning did you decide to destroy
the city, and what caused you to take that route?
MATT: That's a great question. It was very
difficult. I'd spent a lot of time developing and
fleshing out this entire city, and I'd set the
stage for it a long time ago. I didn't quite know
the form it was going to take, I just knew that
the Chroma Conclave, depending on events that
transpired and the return, which was going to
coincide with-- I know I had a two-year window of
Winter's Crest festivals. I was keeping tabs on
that. That was when they were going to be
signifying the release of Thordak from the Fire
Elemental Plane. It just so happened that Emon
became so central to the campaign at that time,
and based on his previous experience being sealed
by the adventuring party that now largely
incorporates themselves with the Council of
Tal'Dorei, that would be the first place to
strike.
And it's not just Emon. They're hitting a lot of
other targets of major power that have some
history with members of the Conclave, and it was a
tough decision, but it made sense driving forward
for the story. It brought together a moment where
players themselves, their characters were starting
to wonder what their purpose was. It was a really
great crux moment. Unintentionally! I had this
whole story arc looming, and the characters were
hitting interesting points of having an
existential crisis of what is it that's holding us
together? What is our purpose? And I was like, "Oh
"my god, this is going to be perfect. This is going
to be perfect! Boom!" And dropped it. It was so
good.
MARY: The minute Vax said, "I don't know what
we're doing. Why are we doing this?" All of a
sudden, I was like, "You did not plan that out." I
seemed at that point that you said to Liam, "Just
"plant that, because the bomb's ready to drop."
MATT: That whole conversation, I'm sitting there
going, "Just give me 30 minutes! Just give me 30
"minutes, man. It's coming!" It was so great. It
was very hard, but as a writer, sometimes to
really elevate the stakes of a story, which is
what you want to do when it continues like that,
you want to elevate the stakes and bring
everything back to a core, central focus and make
everyone feel the gravity of what's to come, you
have to destroy something that you love, and Emon
happened to be the gem of that time.
MARY: Plus, they were getting complacent. They're
all on the council, they've got a nice keep. It's
all lovely.
MATT: You've got to mix things up a little. I was
glad to bring that two-year seed to bear. It was
fun.
MARISHA: That's crazy. Two years.
MATT: What was your favorite PC that you've played
as?
MARY: Victor!
MATT: PC, like when I've actually played a game.
Actually, my friend Jason Bender, who's a game
designer, he ran a game years ago where I played a
dwarf fighter, my first time playing a combat
character in a D&D game. I was always casters
before that. I played a dwarf fighter named
Grimthorne, which I actually incorporated into
Exandria as the dwarf that ran you guys through
the brawlers' league. That character is my old PC,
Grimthorne. He was a fun, brash character.
TRAVIS: He was our manager, right?
WENDY: The wheels are turning. Oh yeah, that guy.
MATT: Yeah, shaved dwarf with no hair on his body,
and most of the dwarves shunned him for that
purpose.
TRAVIS: He took us through that tournament,
right?
MATT: Yeah, he took you through the brawler's
league tournament, yeah, where Scanlan summoned a
pony and you cut it in half to intimidate the
other team, and it worked.
TRAVIS: I didn't just cut its head off. I smeared
its gore all over us and we started screaming like
crazy people.
MATT and TRAVIS: Like you do.
MARY: Wow.
WILL: Fair enough.
TRAVIS: You know you've done well when Mercer's
eyebrows go up, especially like-- oh.
MATT: Did Percy's demon get stronger with every
target on the list that he killed? Maybe. Also,
what would have happened if he killed all five or
six, counting Cassandra? I don't know. I guess
we'll never find out.
MARISHA: He does this all the time. I don't even
know anymore.
MATT: But glad you're paying attention.
TRAVIS: What did you say?
MATT: Nothing.
WILL: Why'd you write "kord" on my head?
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Kord. I mean, krod. (moans)
MATT: Let's see. What are your favorite snacks or
drinks that you like to be gifted at conventions.
MARY: Apparently, beer!
WILL: Be careful how you answer this. I said
Twizzlers once as a joke, and everywhere I go now,
I get Twizzlers.
TRAVIS: I get bags and bags of Reese's Pieces, and
I like them. I don't drink them.
MARISHA: I would say, good note, though: please
don't bring us weapons at cons. Don't gift us
weapons.
WILL: Important safety tip.
TRAVIS: We've got to fly with them.
MARISHA: We've got to fly, and we have a hard time
getting them home.
WILL: Bet TSA likes that.
MATT: Yeah, we had a few great weapons gifted to
us at this recent convention, which were wonderful
gifts, and thank you guys for those, and we had to
go through Wizard World and find a way to ship
them back to us for that purpose, and it was a
whole--
WILL: (blade scraping) Yeah, I'm in seat 1A.
(laughter)
MARY: Sir, your warhammer is flaming. Could you
put it out?
MARISHA: There's no smoking on the aircraft.
MATT: Somebody at the con gave Taliesin a
Pepperbox replica, with an actual spinning barrel.
A very small one, but a Pepperbox replica. He was
like, "This is really beautiful. Oh god. I'm not
"checking luggage." So he took it in two pieces and
put them separately in there in the hopes it
wouldn't be a problem. Sure enough, TSA stopped
him from going through. He had to fill out all
this paperwork. Spent 30 minutes. This is the same
TSA where the guy recognized me and Sam, so I walk
over to check up on him, and the guy goes over and
goes, "Oh, of course it'd be Percy." And he helped
actually explain to TSA what it was and that he's
not trying to hide a gun through. We actually had
a Critter as part of TSA that was helping Taliesin
not get arrested for trying to carry a
150-year-old firearm.
WILL: Do you mind proving you're Percy? Roll a
d20.
TRAVIS: They take you into the mirrored room, and
it's like--
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Am I going to jail or walking out?
MARY: That's right!
MATT: I will happily run an improvised one-shot to
not go to prison.
TRAVIS: I saw there was a person that was asking
about, do we have too many magical items? I think
it's important to say that you told us that we can
only have three.
MATT: Three attuned.
TRAVIS: Attuned to us, yeah, so we don't walk
around and be like, "Oh, I'm going to use this."
MATT: You guys have been collecting magical items
for over three years now. That's the thing. They
have a number of them, and a lot of them are
circumstantially helpful. I try not to give out
too many. You only really get one major upgrade
every six months or so, or somewhere in that
neighborhood. I try to make it more special so
when you do find one, it's a cool thing. If you
give out too many too quickly, few have the
impact, and it's not really awesome when you find
something new.
WILL: You guys tend to have a lot of stuff. I
remember the last game, Laura's like, "No, 750
"knick-knacks," and we're all like, "Oh, okay.
Knick-knacks." And she's like, "No, it's written
"here. He told me I had 750 knick-knacks." Tons of
stuff.
MARY: Who's got the skull? Where's the skull?
TRAVIS: Oh, I found out where it was, because Vex
is a sneaky bastard.
MATT: Vex was the last person to have it.
MARY: Vex was the last person to have it, okay.
MARISHA: She hid it, I'm pretty sure.
TRAVIS: She didn't hide it. I rewatched the
episode.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: I missed it the first time! I miss a lot
of things the first time. I missed Percy doing the
shadow thing.
MATT: That was so beautiful. That worked out
perfectly.
MARY: Do you know what math is?
MATT: Someone's asking, Tophlitz on Reddit asks if
I was part of the Black Rock City cuddle puddle.
TRAVIS: What?
MATT: Burning Man. Yes, I was. Good to hear from
you. That's really cool. It's a Burning Man
gathering event. It's really cool.
WILL: The Black Rock City cuddle puddle?
TRAVIS: Cuddle puddle.
MARY: Are you guys dressed as rabbits?
MATT: No, that's the Billion Bunny March.
MARISHA: Not to be confused--
MATT: This is a bunch of strangers all getting
together and cuddling and hanging out and telling
stories.
MARISHA: Whereas the Billion Bunny March is a
bunch of strangers dressing up as bunnies and
protesting The Man.
TRAVIS: How often do you rewatch episodes? Only if
I feel like I missed something important. But
normally, that's a character choice, too. But I
don't catch shit.
MATT: I'll rewatch beats of previous episodes as
I'm preparing for the next one to make sure I
remember all the details of how it ended and try
to pick up from there. Try. Doesn't always work,
but I try. And to remember NPC voices.
MARISHA: Good question. Marisha, are you going to
Awaken Trinket someday? No! I'm not.
MARY: What does that mean?
MARISHA: No, and that's my Quivering Palm
question, is "Are you going to Awaken Trinket?"
No. I can't, actually. Trinket is literally too
smart for me to awaken him, and if I ever did, it
would mean that Trinket could theoretically be
like, "Oh, what? You've been my master this whole
"time, Vex? Well, fuck this shit. I'm out." And I
don't want to ever do that, so no!
TRAVIS: I wouldn't ever do that.
MARISHA: It's her bear. It's Vex's bear.
MARY: What does that mean to awaken?
MATT: It's a spell that druids have. Creatures
that have certain low-level intelligence, you give
them human intelligence and the ability to speak
and converse. They essentially become NPCs.
MARISHA: Do we want to read it?
TRAVIS: How smart is Trinket?
MATT: Trinket has an intelligence of four. Smarter
than the average bear.
(groaning)
TRAVIS: That's so low-hanging, and you-- It's
running down the jowls.
MATT: And yet, it is 100 percent accurate.
TRAVIS and MARY: It is.
MARISHA: The target must either have no
intelligence score or an intelligence of three or
less.
MARY: And what is Grog's intelligence?
TRAVIS and MARISHA: Six.
WILL: He says proudly. Six.
TRAVIS: I remember when we were rolling the
character and I rolled it, and it was some awful
roll, and you're like, "Your intelligence is six."
I was like, "Yay! What's that mean?"
MATT: I cannot implore you guys enough to really
embrace low stats as a character. It's such a
wonderful distinguishing trait for your
roleplaying capability. I'm disappointed when a
player doesn't roll anything lower than a ten. I'm
like, oh, man. What a missed opportunity. I
absolutely adore, as a player and as a DM, rolling
at least one or two low stats, because it really
exemplifies all sorts of crazy shenanigans you're
going to get into in the future.
WILL: That totally gave me my character, because I
didn't know what I was going to do. Did I want an
accent? I had no idea. And then I rolled a nine
charisma, and I was like, he's a dick.
TRAVIS: Yes! Awesome.
MATT: Which also, I want to point out, is another
great example. Both you and Keyleth are great
examples of characters that have low charisma. A
lot of people equate charisma to physicality and
appearance and beauty, and that is one way to do
it. For some people, they look like the kind of
person you would listen to or follow. Very
politician-like. They have this spirit to them,
and this visual perspective. You guys are
relatively attractive characters, but
personality-wise-- not you, your D&D characters.
WILL and MARISHA: Oh. Sure.
TRAVIS: Yeah, you two are total trainwrecks.
MARY: Keyleth is fucking hot.
MARISHA: That's why we do voiceover!
MATT: Exactly.
WILL: I've got the body for voice over.
MARY: And a face for radio.
MATT: But a perfect example. Kashaw has such an
abrasive personality that even the most average
individual is more likeable in general, despite
your appearance, than Kashaw is. You rub everyone
the wrong way, and that's the perfect way to play
a nine-charisma character.
WILL: It was so much fun to play that, and also,
it's one of those things where he does things
where it's this great juxtaposition where he's a
dick, and he tried to intimidate the last time.
He's got a minus-one for intimidation, so he's
like, "How's your family? This isn't going to
"work." It's like if I tried to intimidate
somebody. Not going to work. All right, sorry.
TRAVIS: How's your family? They're doing well.
MARY: Thanks for asking.
TRAVIS: The boy's in soccer.
WILL: It was so much fun to let the numbers
dictate. I wasn't used to that, so yeah. It helped
the character.
MATT: Someone asked here, Matt, have you ever
considered dwarves with not-Scottish accents?
Yeah. I love the Scottish brogue. It's my favorite
dialect of all, and so I revel in the chance to
utilize it, and I've grown up around fantasy
tropes of the Scottish dwarf. The Kraghammer
dwarves are definitively mostly Scottish. They
have some variations in there. There's some West
Country. There's some that fall out a bit. Dwarves
in other regions would probably have different
dialects, so if ever you guys travel to other
regions and meet other regional dwarves, perhaps
there will be variations. Let's see if they have
any other ones. We've got time for another ten
minutes of questions before we'll take a short
break, and we'll come back for our battle
free-for-all.
MARY: Zahra doesn't know about Percy and Lillith.
TRAVIS: She doesn't?
MARY: Nope. Zahra got a letter from Lillith saying
that she had an interesting time with the guys in
Emon, but she didn't name names. Lillith is not a
kiss-and-tell.
WILL: Kashaw is.
(laughter)
WILL: Telling everybody what just happened.
MARY: She told me about the world itself, but not
specifically--
TRAVIS: What happens to Vox Machina when everyone
reaches level 20, or something like that?
MATT: Oh, that's a good question. I'm foreseeing,
currently, the campaign has probably another good
year, little over a year, before everyone were to
reach max level. I don't know if we'll get that
far. There is a definitive arc to the story, and
it will progress to the point where the heroic
deeds of Vox Machina-- hopefully, whoever survives
to that point-- will be battling deities, and not
just worlds, but also realm-saving circumstances.
At which point, there will come a moment where the
story comes to completion, whether it be through
the fall of Vox Machina and the next wave of
heroes that rise up to try and take that place, or
they will complete their goal, become the heroes
of the land, and fade into the sunset to pursue
whatever their epilogue-based storyline is, which
you guys would help to write.
MARY: They come back through the wardrobe, and
they're kids again.
MATT: In which case, I would like to start a new
campaign with the new level-one characters you
guys would create, probably in the same world,
after the events of the first campaign. There
would be elements of the universe that you've
affected with your choices.
MARY: Lycan rat.
MARISHA: I was going to say, were-rat.
TRAVIS: Have you ever made a character that went
to level 20, anybody that's played before?
MATT: I've had a campaign that went close, but not
quite.
TRAVIS: What do you mean "not quite?" Meaning you
stopped playing?
MATT: Meaning we stopped playing, because adults
get busy and lives scatter.
MARISHA: Was that the Ravenloft campaign?
MATT: The Ravenloft campaign ended at 15, and the
previous campaign ended around 15, as well.
TRAVIS: Deities?
MARY: There's some spells that you only find on
another plane.
MARISHA: Eventually, we go god hunting.
TRAVIS: God hunting? Did you see the size of that
dragon back there? We're fucked next to that
thing.
MARISHA: Ghostbusters-style god hunting.
WILL: Are you a god?
MARISHA: If someone asks if you're a god--
MARISHA, MARY, and TRAVIS: You say yes!
MATT: TiamatZX asks: Question for Mary. What are
your thoughts on the friendship between Vex and
Zahra?
MARY: Oh. Wouldn't you like to know? Maybe you'll
find out. I think Zahra has not had many friends
in her life. I'll put it that way.
WILL: Neither has Kash.
MARY: Yeah, and those that she does have, the few
she holds very dear, and I don't think that level of
devotion has any idea-- it's a level of passion
that goes beyond the plane of physical,
attractive. There's an attraction to someone's
soul, and I think that's what she feels.
WILL: I think Kash is the same way, where it's
almost confusing to be with somebody that you
actually care about.
MARISHA: Keyleth feels some of that. It's a weird
feeling sometimes.
MATT: Quick question to answer here, since I get
questions about house rules a lot. Why did you
choose to make inspiration-- the normal one, not a
bardic one-- a d6 instead of the default
advantage? That was partially because there are a
lot of abilities and situations that give you
advantage already in the game. I felt it would be
a tweak where you could, in theory, combine the
two. I like the disadvantage and advantage system
a lot. I think it's one of the best things they
did in 5th edition to streamline combat and get
rid of a lot of the floating modifiers that I felt
bogged down combat in other systems. I felt like
this was a way to incorporate it where those that
could still get advantage and consistently get
advantage, based on how they play, would still be
able to benefit from the inspiration die. Mind
you, because there's a bard in the party, and such
a good bard, I don't feel that I have to throw it
out there too often. You guys are pretty
self-sufficient in giving your own inspiration.
WILL: That's amazing, watching him.
TRAVIS: Isn't it? If you want to talk about
genius, we've got genius doing storytelling. I've
asked him. I'm like, "Do you come to the show with
two or three songs in your pocket ready to go?"
And he says no, because he's a cappella-- Mensa
level, from college, right?
MARY: The fight song, come on.
MARISHA: He has the limericks. He's been writing
down the limericks. That's been a very new thing,
though. He'll be like, "I've been listening to Top
40 more recently." That's pretty much all he said.
He's like, "I'm trying to listen to the radio
more."
WILL: It's amazing to sit there. Damn.
MARISHA: He's crazy. He's great.
WILL: Totally awesome.
MARISHA: It's all that UCB training.
MARY: I'm pretty sure I saw him and his sister
Eden in Les Mis when they were in it on Broadway.
WILL: Oh, who hasn't been in Les Mis on Broadway?
TRAVIS: Let's wave a flag over some furniture.
WILL: We can't eat bread! Okay, I get you. Come
on. Take your prison time and shut up.
(laughter)
MARISHA: His story, by the way, at this Wizard
World panel.
MARY: Oh, it was amazing.
MARISHA: Yeah, if anyone hasn't seen the Wizard
World panel, he has a story of him as Gavroche
falling off the barricades, and it was in the
middle of the Miami riots, back in the day, and he
went to the hospital and was like, "I fell off the
barricade." He's all smudgy.
TRAVIS: The doctor's like, "You were on the
barricade?"
MATT: This little kid.
WILL: He's dressed like a French peasant. "My god,
boy, what the hell were they doing to you? Why are
"you still harmonizing? My god."
MARISHA: You have to watch him tell it, though. We
can't even do it justice, but it's great. It's a
good story.
MATT: Let's see. We've got time for a few more
questions, and then we're going to take a break
and come back for the free-for-all.
WILL: Oh my god, I've got minutes to live.
MATT: Yes, you do.
MARY: It's going to be so exciting!
MATT: Interesting question. Matt, have you ever
gotten a TPK or killed most of the players in the
party? Yes, actually. In the last campaign I ran,
the players went into the Shadowfell, and in this
particular world, necromancy had been banned and
outlawed for a hundred years, so undead and the
whole idea of undead creatures largely was
folklore. No one saw them. People thought they
were old wives' tales to keep kids in from
outside. And so when they actually went to the
Shadowfell, they were unprepared, wandered into a
tomb, and were surrounded by ghouls, and as
opposed to focused, targeting down, they decided,
"Each of us take one!" and kill them off. Well,
then three of the five were immediately paralyzed
and were torn down, and two of the remaining party
members, one of them started screaming while the
other grabbed her and pulled her out as they
watched the three other party members be devoured
by the ghouls that were there.
MARISHA: Remember how when we were fighting the
banshees, they have an ability where they can
touch you and you're down? Ghouls have a similar
ability where they touch you and you're paralyzed,
and you get canned. So if you split up, the divide
and conquer technique is probably the worst that
you could use against ghouls.
WILL: Backs to each other.
MARISHA: Yeah, pretty much.
MATT: In that circumstance, they lost three party
members in one battle that were eaten. They
watched them be eaten in front of them.
MARY: Oh, that's awful.
WILL: Now what do you do? Quick question. What do
you do? You're playing with seven players and you
put them in a situation where four die. How do you
come back next week with the three that are left?
MATT: What I do is in that time period, I would
get with the players that lost characters--
MARY: Why is he pointing to you?
TRAVIS: I don't know.
MATT: Because you're there! I would see if the
remaining party members had options in which to
attempt resurrection at their disposal, see if
that was successful or not, preferably before the
end of that session. If any of those were not
successful and the players were lost permanently,
then over the next week, I would meet with the
players that lost characters to have them create
new ones, probably a level lower than the lowest
member of the party--
WILL: And meet up with them?
MATT: And meet up with them, and find a way to
incorporate them in the story where they would
then become a member of Vox Machina going forward.
It's what I've done before, in the past. There is
a detriment to losing your character. I do bring
you in a level lower. Not starting at level one,
because that would be stupid.
WILL: You also lose your character.
MATT: Exactly.
WILL: Horrible.
MATT: That's how I would do it. That's how I will
do it.
(groaning)
MATT: (cackles) All right, each of us pick a
question to finish this off, if we can. I'm sorry
if we didn't get to your questions. This is a lot
of questions here tonight, and not a whole lot of
time. We have record of these; I'll try and answer
them on Reddit later.
TRAVIS: Somebody asked if I could re-pick the
people that went into the Earthbreaker Groon pit,
would I do it? No. A, I didn't understand what you
were actually asking, because he was speaking in
such a poetic way, and I was trying to give you an
intense struggle. "Shit, I'm missing all of this.
"I don't know what he's talking about." And you
were like, "Who are your blah-blah-blah muses?"
And I was like, "My muses? Pike. She's not here.
Shit. In case we fight, who's good? Oh, Vax has
"daggers, and Scanlan's my pal." And we jumped down
and they're like, "Oh, we're fighting." And I was
like, "Fuck!"
WILL: The second he got pushed into the pit, I saw
your face go, "Aw, shit."
MARISHA: I misunderstood the question.
WILL: All the blood drained from your face.
TRAVIS: The first five minutes, I was going
through my mind, how it would have gone if I had
picked other people, but I wouldn't have changed
it for a second.
MARISHA: It was great.
MARY: Vax and Scanlan.
TRAVIS: It was so great.
MARISHA: It worked beautifully.
MARY: Oh, will we see Salty Pete and the gang
again?
MATT: I don't know.
MARISHA and MARY: I don't know.
MATT: One of the members is up in Seattle now, and
another member only occasionally comes on for
another game. Maybe! It was fun. Definitely a
unique experience doing that. If we have another
Extra Life-type stream like we did, because that
was very successful, and we had a good time with
it. As much as it was a gamut for me to run, with
you guys helping with the story-- deck of many
things-- if it happens again, I would love to have
them all back, so we'll see if we can get them and
schedule them for it. I hope so.
MARY: Oh, that was good. Somebody said, what color
dragons would you all be?
MATT: What color dragons would you be?
MARISHA: In real life or our characters?
MATT: Let's say in real life.
MARISHA: In real life?
MATT: I can't answer a character question. All of
them! No.
MARISHA: Red.
TRAVIS: Ain't those the bad ones?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: You would be a bad dragon in real life?
MARISHA: That fire-breathing, man. Fire dragons.
WILL: "You'd be a bad dragon?" That was such an
earnest question.
TRAVIS: I was expecting more from you.
MARISHA: A chromatic dragon, just peaced-out--
TRAVIS: Whatever, Voldemort. Shut up.
WILL: She Who Must Not Be Named.
TRAVIS: I'd be a gold dragon.
MARY: Would you be a gold dragon?
TRAVIS: I'd call myself Kanye.
MARISHA: So influential.
TRAVIS: I'm a wordsmith. You're welcome for my
existence. I'm an influencer.
MATT: I'm going to make you play that if we ever
do a one-shot.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: I'll start smiling and then go--
MATT: There you go.
WILL: I've got a good question from Twitter. How
open were you for me to create my own deity as a
cleric?
MATT: I was very open.
WILL: You were suggesting to make one up if you
want to make one up. I don't know how other DMs
run the game, but you were very open to suggestion
and here's what you could do, and let me help you
a little bit here, but it was more "what do you
want to be?" and you guided me, as opposed to
"this is what you do, and here's how you build
it."
MARY: You encourage that. I was like, I've done
research and I want to do this. You're like, "No,
"don't pick anything that's established. You run
into problems with people nitpicking what you got
"wrong about the lore and everything else. Make
your own." Which was so wonderful.
WILL: They always say write what you know.
MATT: Tailor it to the rules. So for you, your
whole moon deity worked well for the Great Old One
pact because it was an entity that is outside of
the pantheon and you don't truly understand the
nature of where it comes from, just from the sky.
It was a perfect tie-in to that. And with you, I
didn't want to define anything, and I said, "You
can choose from the existing pantheon of the
"world," and I laid those out for you, and I said,
"You can create your own deity, but understand
"that based on the current rules that it would
probably be a much more confined belief system; a
"god that doesn't have the same following of the
others. Thus, why it's a receded worship than
"other gods."
WILL: Which then guided the backstory of how
nobody's ever heard of Vesh, and there's one
person that knows who she is, and that's Kashaw.
MATT: It worked out perfectly.
WILL: It worked out great, so yeah, it was very
cool.
MARISHA: I had a question scroll by, and forgive
me, I didn't see the name of who it was, but they
were asking about being a female playing D&D in an
all-boy group and how you break that comfort
level. Luckily, I think, especially now with the
resurgence of D&D, the boy's club aspect that
might have been surrounding it is definitely
slowly starting to get broken. D&D should never be
a gender-specific game at all. It's tough. It's
also where you grew up and where you're located
and the part of the country. I know, growing up in
Kentucky, I didn't have access to anybody,
especially other females that would want to play
with me. But yeah, if you feel uncomfortable, I
try to remember that it's probably a little bit of
them feeling uncomfortable on their end, as well,
so try to be open-minded to that, and I think
you'll get used to it, but there's not supposed to
be gender specifics. And guys, we have a ton of
our players that like to RP girls. We're all
actors. Maybe the best way if you're a female in
an all-guy group, fuck it, make a male character,
as well.
MARY: Or be the strongest, most feminine
role-playing character that you can be.
WILL: I'm sorry, I should mention that the guy who
asked that question was @paleheathen, whose
picture is actually with you and Laura.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I like him.
MATT: Good question. I will say, too, I've played
with many players that have created characters
that are across sex. Male players who made female
characters and vice versa. You see me play female
characters all the time. It's not a defining facet
of the character.
MARISHA: Female should never be a personality
trait.
MATT: Yeah, exactly. It can guide elements to it
down the road, but you want to create an
interesting character who just happens to be male
or female. I know some people have some weirdness
or they're not comfortable trying to play someone
of the opposite sex, and that's totally fine, but
you'd be surprised how cool it is sometimes to
jump into the character that's so different from
what you're used to and see how one, it can be a
very freeing experience from a role-playing
standpoint, and you might learn a lot about
yourself.
MARISHA: Actually, there's a really great video
that's on YouTube that someone linked me to this
past week, and it was from about three years ago
before the Fine Brothers milked this format, and
it was boys, a group of ten-year-old boys playing
Dungeons & Dragons with a group of girls for the
first time. Did you see that? Yeah, and it was
great, and I love kid logic, because I feel like
it really simplifies what we're all actually
thinking on its purest form, and all the boys at
the end of it were super mature and were like,
"Oh, this is great." They were like, "The girls
"were really bloody and violent. I thought they
would puke at the blood. I didn't know that girls
"could be that violent." I'm like, yeah, man. So I
feel like the kids realizing that there really is
no separation is quintessential, how everyone
feels.
WILL: It's also a flat-out awesome improv
exercise.
MARY: It really is.
WILL: It really is, to play the opposite sex, for
no other reason that it's really cool to open up
and be free.
MARISHA: And ultimately, to be 100 percent honest,
I really enjoy people who have implemented
Dungeons & Dragons in elementary schools as
teaching mechanisms, and there have been a lot of
people who've used it for kids who have social
imperatives or social awkwardness things in real
life.
WILL: I deal with anxiety, so I know exactly what
it's like to deal with that kind of stuff.
MARISHA: Yeah, totally, and I think it really does
teach you empathy on a different level, and you
really can put yourself in the shoes of someone
else that you're probably nothing else like.
Keyleth has taught me a ton. Playing Keyleth has
taught me a ton because I don't really consider
myself anything like her in real life, so playing
something super empathetic, she's taught me a lot,
and I think everyone can learn from that. That's
my tangent. I'm done.
MATT: One more question. This one's come up quite
a few times from different people. Someone's
asking about balancing encounters for creatures
that could easily take down one member of the
party but would also be difficult to fight for
another-- that would be a good challenge for one
member but would completely annihilate another
person in the party. How to handle that. How does
the party handle that? That's a great point of
tension in the battle. If a player knows that
they're squishy, their tactics should revolve
around learning how to stay away from that
creature that could probably take them down very
quickly, and it's the tougher members of the
party's responsibility to try and get between them
as much as possible.
WILL: That was Sam last week. He's the first one
who said that. He's like, "I don't fight, so I'm
"going to sing and run this way."
MATT: So yeah, you want to incorporate aspects of
a battle that will be a challenge across the
party, but you also want to make sure that you
don't tailor every enemy specifically to a player
all the time, like "This guy's a barbarian. He has
a lot of good resistance, so I'll build a creature
"only for him," and then go for this character.
Find a good challenge for the overall party and
let them figure out the mechanics. Sometimes
they'll run really well and combo their abilities
together like a well-oiled machine, and they'll
completely annihilate the encounter. Sometimes,
they'll do the entirely wrong tactic that they
should, and end up walking away, limping, going,
"That was bad. That was very bad." Sometimes, it
will go really poorly and they have to run. That's
the good thing, too. I always scale on the level
of making the encounter difficult, as opposed to
too easy, if you've done a few encounters that the
party has steamrolled, because if it gets too
hard, you can insinuate, you don't have to stick
around. They could always come back later with a
better plan if the first plan failed. In fact,
some fun battles are the vengeance ones, where
things didn't go so great the first time, but
going back with the knowledge you have now, you
set up an ambush or find a way to use the terrain
to your advantage next time.
WILL: Real quick, do you have to be real careful
that you don't pick on one specific person too
much, like you keep attacking one character?
MATT: It depends on the creature or monster that
they're fighting. If it's a beast-- if it's a
creature that is driven by instinct and isn't
super intelligent, it will go after whatever is
either the easiest and nearest kill or the thing
that apparently right now poses the biggest threat
to it. I try to think of the creature's mindset of
who it would go after, so if the battle begins and
all of a sudden the healer does something really
crazy and flashy and hurts the enemy, it might be
going after the healer for a while.
If it's a really intelligent creature, especially
if it's a well-trained combat veteran that knows
the strengths and weaknesses of different classes,
once a few rounds of combat have shown who
specializes in what, he may tell his team or
whoever he's commanding to focus down the healer
or the support class that's changing the tide of
the battle. If they know the barbarian's going to
resist the most damage, they'll ignore him for
now, take out the things that are supporting him
and keeping him up, and then we'll worry about him
later.
It's based on the intelligence of what they're
fighting, and I think for me, that's a lot of fun.
Sometimes it doesn't work out. Sometimes the party
comes up with a really cool plan and my really
awesome, interesting battle gets steamrolled. But
you know what? The players earned that victory.
I'm not going to fight and change numbers behind
the screen just because I wanted it to be cooler.
They earned that victory. I'll give it to them.
TRAVIS: So glad we're not fighting him tonight
because I just got infinitely more nervous.
WILL: I'm sensing you'll be fine.
MATT: All right, guys. It is 9:00. We're going to
take a short bathroom break, and then we're going
to come back here and see which one of these fools
is going to be the final standing fighter.
MARY: Place your bets!
WILL: I've got ten dollars on everybody but me.
[break]
MARISHA: --cock.
MATT: Welcome back, everyone. So, we're going to
see how this works out. Thank you, Marisha. So,
for the purposes of this, everyone's going to be
level 13, so bringing both Kashaw and Zahra up one
level. I need you guys to both roll additional hit
points right now, which we'll add to your
character at the moment. So d6 for you. For you,
it'd be a d8, I'm pretty sure.
TRAVIS: Are you playing as Gilmore?
WILL: This is my eight, right?
MARISHA: That's a ten.
WILL: Five.
MARY: Four.
MATT: Four, plus your constitution modifier, which
is two. So yeah, that's 83. What'd you roll?
WILL: I rolled a five.
MATT: You rolled a five plus, what's your
constitution modifier?
WILL: 16. Oh, plus three.
MATT: Plus three, so eight. So, add eight to your
total hit points, for the purposes of this
battle.
WILL: So I am at 108 for this battle.
MATT: Oh wait, warlocks may be a d8. Let me go
check this again. I'm used to the sorcerer stuff.
Let me see here real fast.
TRAVIS: I'm going to do what Laura would do and
warm up this d20. Shit. Fuck. That's the same
number!
MATT: Yeah, a d8! I'm sorry, reroll it. I'm not
used to you warlocks.
MARY: What if I roll less than a four?
MATT: Well, I'll let you keep the minimum.
MARY: I rolled a three.
MATT: We'll let you keep the four. It's my fault.
MARY: Oh, thank you.
WILL: Have I been killed yet? I'm surprised I'm
not dead yet, to be honest with you.
TRAVIS: We haven't started.
WILL: I thought I was killed. My bad.
MATT: All righty, so. Since your proficiency
bonuses have also gone up, don't forget that your
spell attack, your spell DC, and your physical
attacks all go up by one. For this battle.
WILL: So, my spell attack goes to plus ten and my
spell DC goes to 18.
MATT: 18, correct.
TRAVIS: This set is amazing, by the way. I'm so
excited by it.
MATT: This is my first time using Dwarven Forge
sets, which I've always wanted to. I was a
Kickstarter supporter when they first did the
dungeon tiles. I was stupid and didn't get them
pre-painted. Never making that mistake again. So
I've dry-brushed all of these with white to make
them look decent. I hope to use more Dwarven Forge
stuff in the future, for our game, because it
makes for some really cool, dynamic-looking sets.
So. Just so you guys are aware, for this battle,
this open pit here in the center is an open pit.
It falls into darkness. You don't know what's
below there.
TRAVIS: What are you talking about? Really?
MATT: Yeah, this is an open pit.
WILL: So Grog, push everyone. Push Grog into the
open pit.
MARY: It's an open pit? How deep is it?
TRAVIS: You don't know. "It falls into darkness."
So it's deep enough.
MATT: You'll have to go and make a perception
check next to it so you can see.
TRAVIS: What if there's a giant trampoline down
there?
MATT: Could be.
WILL: Has anybody thought about the idea of
meeting in the center and talking things out?
TRAVIS: I would like propose a pre-game handshake.
(under breath) I will throw all of you in.
MARISHA: Instead of violence, we can solve this
with rock paper scissors. It'll be great.
WILL: There was something you said about a
7th-level spell?
MATT: You and Zahra both get access to a single
7th-level spell casting. Also, you have access to
all the equipment you have on you, except for
healing potions. Each of you only has one superior
healing potion.
WILL: And what does a superior healing potion do?
MATT: 8d4 plus eight.
TRAVIS: Okay, all right.
WILL: 8d4 plus eight. You'll have to explain to me
exactly what that means when I need it. Now, do we
need to pick our 7th-level spell now?
MATT: I would prefer for you to. I mean, you have
a couple prepared, but you have to choose which
one you use in combat.
MARISHA: So my armor, with spell resistance, I've
got advantage on spell attacks against me? I can
get saving throws? My armor that has spell
resistance?
MATT: You get advantage on your saving throws,
yes.
WILL: I think I know what I'm going for my
7th-level.
TRAVIS: I'm ready to die.
WILL: Seriously? Are you kidding me?
MARISHA: Oh my god, this is so nerve-wracking, you
guys.
MATT: All righty, guys.
MARY: I'm very afeared now.
WILL: I got my 7th-level, I think.
MATT: All right, folks. I would like all of you...
to roll initiative! For the sake of this guys,
because I forgot my bag of side minis, which is
really stupid of me, the part of Kashaw will be
played by this rather buxom dwarf cleric. The part
of Zahra will be played by this red-coated Percy.
So you guys can keep track on that. All right.
MARY: I suck big balls and I cannot lie.
MATT: You know you have advantage on initiative?
TRAVIS: I rolled it twice and they both suck.
MATT: As all of you are suddenly and
instantaneously transported by some omniscient
entity, you find your feet slamming into the stone
ground of what appears to be some pit, a hundred
feet recessed into the floor of some indeterminate
location. The walls and the floor are built of
ancient stone. You see each of you placed behind a
wall with just enough visual across the top to see
that the other of your band are there across from
you. In the center lies a darkened pit to some
unknown distance of depth.
MARISHA: Grog?
TRAVIS: This is nice stone!
WILL: Z?
MARY: Over here!
MATT: Looking up into the sky, you can see the
blue sky, clouds drifting above, but too high to
reach. You hear a voice rumble up from around you,
going, "Now, show me who is your champion." So,
initiative! 25 to 20, anyone? 20 to 15? (giggling)
15 to ten?
WILL: I have a 14. Oh wait, I'm adding my
initiative? Where's my initiative? Front, there we
go.
MARISHA: You have plus two.
WILL: Okay, so I'm a 16.
MATT: 16? All right, so Kash is up first. Five to
ten?
TRAVIS: Ten.
MARISHA: Oh, I have 14.
MATT: 14.
MARY: Ten!
MATT: Grog and Zahra, who has the higher dexterity
between the two of you?
MARY: Plus one.
TRAVIS: Probably not me. 15?
MARY: Oh, dexterity? Ten.
MATT: All right, I'll say Grog is going slightly
faster than Zahra. All right. Based on that, Kash!
You're up first. What do you want to do?
WILL: I want to get my papers I'm already losing!
MATT: You're right over here.
WILL: Yeah, I know. Yeah, I want to move closer to
Grog, I guess.
MATT: Okay. You can grab your mini.
WILL: Now how far can we move, here?
MATT: Well, your speed is, I believe, 30, so you
can move six square spaces.
WILL: Maybe that's not the best plan.
MATT: Whatever you want to do, buddy.
WILL: If I can stay away from him, the better. You
know what? I'm actually going to make my way
around here. So, six squares? I'm going to get
right here and I want to check out the room and
the giant pit, which I am now apparently in front
of.
MATT: Okay, so go ahead and make a perception
check.
WILL: That's the d20?
MATT: Yep, d20 and add your perception skill.
WILL: That is a seven and, where's perception?
Plus four. But it has advantage.
MATT: Okay, so roll again.
WILL: Now it's two. Four. So great.
MATT: Okay, so you look down. What little bit of
light is making it down, you can see, vaguely, the
bottom of the pit. About 15 feet down, ten to 15
feet, so it's not a huge drop. You do see there is
texture to it, meaning it's not a flat surface.
There is something down there that probably, at
least it doesn't look like it would happily accept
your body plummeting into it.
WILL: Ah, it is not feathers. I'm sensing that's
going to come back to suck at some point.
MATT: All right, is there anything else you want
to do for your turn?
WILL: No, I'm good for now.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: Going to get straight into this, I guess.
I am going to cast Call Lightning at 5th level.
MATT: Call Lightning at 5th level? Okay. You guys
all of a sudden feel the hair on your body and
your beard drift up, almost like gravity suddenly
has no impact on the moment, as the smell of
crispy ozone hits the air. Above you, you can see
clouds gather out of what was once a blue sky. You
hear in the distance the rumble of thunder.
TRAVIS: Looks like rain!
WILL: I'm not dressed right for this. Look at the
size of her breasts.
MARY: Use them as a shield, Kash!
MARISHA: Then I say, I'm really sorry about this,
you guys! I think this is an alternate reality,
though, and we'll be fine if we just get out of
this! I can go ahead and bring down a spell,
right? Or no, yeah, I can the same time.
MATT: Yes you can.
MARISHA: I'm going to go ahead and hit Kashaw
because I can see him through my little window.
WILL: Suck.
MATT: All right.
MARISHA: I get 5d10, right?
MATT: Yeah, 5d10 points of lightning damage. I
need you to make a dexterity saving throw.
WILL: That's a d20 again? Four.
MATT: Plus your dexterity?
WILL: Three.
MATT: All right, I'm going to say that's a fail.
So you take full damage from Keyleth, at this
point.
WILL: And it's how much?
MARISHA: Sorry, Kash! 5d10.
WILL: Never should have kissed you.
MATT: That's a terrible roll. You're lucky.
MARISHA: That is a really terrible roll. 17, and
another one.
MATT: 18. You take 18 points of lightning damage
as a bolt of energy slams out of the sky like an
elemental hammer, hitting you and causing you to
hold yourself against the wall, directly to the
back.
MARISHA: And then I take my bonus action to turn
into an eagle.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: (eagle sounds)
WILL: I tried to check out the room a little bit,
first, see what was up.
MARISHA: Fuck that shit! Shit's getting real!
MATT: So a giant eagle, or just an eagle?
MARISHA: Giant eagle.
MATT: All right, since I don't have your polymorph
figures with me--
[no audio until 2:17:40]
(Matt scatting)
WILL: Do I have to tell you my 7th-level spell
eventually?
MATT: Whenever you want to use it.
MARY: Ooh, surprises.
WILL: I'm using a 7th-level Run Away spell.
MARY: Run away! That's my favorite.
OFF-SCREEN: They can hear you right now, but now
they can't see you. We're working on it.
MATT: But now they can hear us?
MARY: Kash, put your pants back on! Oh no!
TRAVIS: Is that a beholder coming out of the pit?
MARY: No, no, not a beholder! Don't eat Grog!
OFF-SCREEN: Program glitch. You're doing great.
[no audio]
OFF-SCREEN: They can hear you. They can't see
you.
MATT: Okay.
MARY: They can see Grog, but they can't hear
Matt.
WILL: Now they can't hear or see either of you,
but they can smell you all.
MATT: For those who were paying attention,
Keyleth, after casting her 5th-level Call
Lightning, turned into a giant eagle and then flew
80 feet up into the pit.
MARISHA: Fly away!
TRAVIS: Can you move diagonal squares?
MATT: Yeah you can. This is getting interesting.
Well, in the meantime, we shall see if we can get
this to work. RIP, sound? Oh no!
TRAVIS: One plus one, plus two, plus one.
WILL: Can I ask a question? While she is an eagle,
is she considered a creature now? Can she be taken
control of, if she's an animal?
MATT: That's a good question.
MARY: Because you use Polymorph, right?
MARISHA: Beast shape.
WILL: Could you use Geas on her?
MARISHA: I keep all of my mental stats.
MATT: Oh, a creature? Anybody's a creature.
WILL: Okay.
MATT: Any entity is a creature, whether it be a
monster or a person.
TRAVIS: It says we can see the board, but not you
guys?
OFF-SCREEN: Yeah, they can see the top-down right
now, but the shot right here doesn't have audio
for some reason. We're fixing that.
MATT: Can they still hear us and see the top down?
Okay, well then never mind! Let's get this
running! We'll stick with this. All right, that
ends Keyleth's turn. Grog?
TRAVIS: I would like to go into a frenzied rage. I
would like to move ten spaces. Right there.
MATT: All right. As a note, if you are raging and
you don't take damage or deal damage, you lose
your rage.
TRAVIS: Oh. So, should I maybe move first and then
rage?
MATT: Or not rage, if you're not going to do
anything.
TRAVIS: Oh. I'm very calm as I run from this spot
to here, preparing to rage.
MATT: Okay. Good to know.
TRAVIS: Shit, I don't think I ever knew that. You
learn something every day.
MATT: Yeah, if you fail to hit something or get
hit, which happens very rarely for you anyway, the
rage drops. Something to remember.
TRAVIS: Hit a little kid in the area if I have to
attack something. C'mere, boom!
MATT: All righty, so, if that's ending your turn,
Zahra, you're up. You see the eagle of Keyleth
take up after calling a bolt down from the
heavens.
MARY: You're beautiful, darling!
WILL: Good, now kill her!
MARY: All right. I would like to cast, because she
is within range of 120 feet, I'm going to do the
combo of Eldritch Blast, a cantrip, plus an
invocation of Agonizing Blast.
MATT: All right, so the invocation goes on that.
Are you casting that first?
MARY: Pardon me?
MATT: Meaning, the eldritch invocation just
happens on top of the Eldritch Blast. Did you have
another spell or bonus ability you wanted to do
beforehand, or not?
MARY: No, I think I'm going to save it, because I
realize that casting Hex actually takes up one of
my spell slots, does it not?
MATT: Yes, but you can always move it to different
targets if one falls.
MARY: Yes, I know.
MATT: Okay, good to know. All right, so, Eldritch
Blast firing against, all three against--?
MARY: All three against Kiki.
MATT: All right, what's the range on Eldritch
Blast?
MARY: 120 feet.
MATT: Yeah, she's definitely in range. All right,
what's the AC of your eagle?
MARISHA: 13.
MATT: 13, all right. Go ahead and roll three
d20s.
MARY: All right, do I get a spell attack bonus?
MATT: You do, plus 12. So don't roll a one. Roll
three times.
MARY: Roll three of the d20s?
MATT: That's a hit. That's a hit, and third one?
19, that's a hit. Go ahead and roll three d10s and
it's plus seven to each of them. There you go. So
17 points of damage.
WILL: Hurts, doesn't it?
MARY: 17, plus--
[intermittent audio]
MATT: --13, so 33. A total of 33 points of
damage.
MARISHA: Okay, well, that brings me, zero to my...
33 so that's nine points.
MATT: Did you drop form now?
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: Okay. First off, make a concentration check
for each one of those hits. It's a constitution
save.
MARISHA: I have a ring. So 14?
MATT: 14. Roll again? So you have to beat ten on
each one.
MARISHA: Ooh, no. Eight.
MATT: Eight? So as you're hit with the first
agonizing blast, it slams into your form and you
keep yourself in the air. The second one hits you
again. This time, the clouds disperse as your
concentration is wrecked from the blast. The third
one finally hits you, losing your form. You
transform back into a druid and immediately
plummet 80 feet to the ground.
WILL: And you don't have the big breasts to block
you, like I do!
MATT: So that's 8d6 falling damage.
OFF-SCREEN: We're back!
MATT: We're back? All right! Hold on. You take 28
points of fall damage as you fall down into the
pit, smack! Slamming into the stone ground. Your
bell is rung for a moment as your eyes have a hard
time focusing around you. You can feel the blood
beginning to pour down the side of your head from
the impact of slamming into the stonework.
MARISHA: Oh, bad idea. Okay.
MARY: Just a warning, don't hurt Kash! Just a
warning! Don't hurt him!
MATT: All right, Zahra, anything else you want to
do with your turn? Stay there?
MARY: No, I think I'm fine.
MATT: Kash, you're up. I'd say, actually, Keyleth,
you are prone on the ground because you fell that
height.
WILL: Can I see her, or no?
MATT: Yeah, you can see her, barely, around the
side.
WILL: I don't like Grog right behind me. That kind
of scares me a little bit.
TRAVIS: But I'm so stealthy!
WILL: Maybe he doesn't see me! I'm going to give
myself a little protection here and I'm going to
cast a 4th-level Guardian of Faith.
MATT: Okay.
WILL: I'm going to get a little help in an area
here, if I can.
MATT: Certainly. 4th-level Guardian of Faith.
WILL: And apparently the range is 30 feet and it
lasts eight hours. So if I hang near him,
hopefully that'll be helpful.
MATT: So any creature hostile to you that moves to
a space within ten feet of the guardian for the
first time on your turn has to succeed or take
damage. All right. So you choose an unoccupied
space within range and it occupies that space. So
where do you want it to remain?
WILL: Can I move first and then cast it?
MATT: Yeah, if you wanted to.
WILL: All right, I'd like to move back to kind of
where Grog was. So I'm going to go (counting) so I
end up about here. I'd like to cast the Guardian
of Faith right here, in front of this little
window.
MATT: Okay, I'm going to go ahead and use this
piece of popcorn here as the guardian.
WILL: He guards me and is wonderfully crunchy!
MARY: He smells so good!
WILL: That's my, yeah, so for right now I'm good
and I feel a little bit protected.
MATT: Keyleth, you're up.
MARISHA: Oh, me again? Already? Oh my god. Okay,
well, I stand up.
MATT: Uses half your movement.
MARISHA: I'm going to go ahead and throw a Call
Lightning up again, this time at 4th level.
MATT: Okay, the clouds re-form.
TRAVIS: What the shit. This is like Seattle.
WILL: Rain again? What, are we in London?
MARISHA: I think I've got a bit of a view on Grog,
kind of know where he is?
MATT: Ah, barely.
MARISHA: I can see Kash, though, right? Sorry,
Kash! (lightning crash) Right on Kash again.
MATT: All right, I need you to make another
dexterity saving throw.
WILL: And that's the 20 again, right? Come on,
come on. Eight, plus what? Dexterity? Plus two,
ten.
MATT: Plus your save, which would be more. Yeah,
you still failed. So 4d10 lightning damage to
Kashaw. That's better. 29 points of lightning
damage as another bolt streaks down, slamming into
the ground.
MARISHA: I'm going to use my bonus action to do a
Cure Wounds, or sorry, Healing Word at myself,
just at first level.
WILL: Okay, so I take 29 points of damage, is that
what you said? Eesh. 61 already.
MATT: All right. Keyleth? That's Keyleth's turn.
Grog, you're up.
TRAVIS: I would like to perform a little community
outreach and I would like to run. Frenzied Rage!
MATT: That's your bonus action, okay.
MARISHA: This is the shit of nightmares. I want
you to know that.
TRAVIS: I would like to look at Keyleth and go,
Hi! And attack.
MATT: This blur of grey and black comes streaking
around the corner as you see the foam frothing
from Grog's mouth, running toward you, Craven Edge
out of its scabbard.
MARISHA: Keyleth friend! Keyleth friend!
TRAVIS: 26?
MATT: Hits.
TRAVIS: 14?
MATT: 14 misses.
TRAVIS: 24.
MARISHA: Hits.
TRAVIS: 21.
MATT: 21 points of slashing damage.
TRAVIS: It was the third one that hit. 18.
MATT: 18 points of slashing damage.
TRAVIS: And she needs to make a constitution
check.
MATT: Two of them.
MARISHA: 18 would bring me to 40. Right?
MATT: 40. All right, so roll two constitution
saving throws.
MARISHA: Ooh!
MATT: Succeeds with both! 18 and 16! You hear the
voice creeping in your face go, "Come on, take her
"life! Give me her strength!"
TRAVIS: Well I'm working on it! Shit, relax a
little!
WILL: I love the fact, I'm sorry, I have to point
out that we're being guided by Mumm-ra. Which is
kind of awesome, I'm sorry.
MATT: Ancient spirits of evil. All right, so, that
ends your turn Grog. Zahra, you're up.
MARY: Can I move first so I can get Kiki and, so
sorry, my darling--
MATT: Where are you going?
MARY: I'm going to go toward Keyleth so I can get
her in sight.
MATT: You can see her there.
MARY: All right. I'm going to cast--
TRAVIS: Just do it!
MARY: Finger of Death.
TRAVIS: (shrieks) Does she have that?!
MATT: She does now!
WILL: Oh shit! Don't look at me!
MARY: I look like Percy, so No Mercy Percy.
TRAVIS: Do you have to roll for it?
MATT: Hold on, hold on. Okay.
TRAVIS: Well fuck the foreplay, let's get on with
it.
MATT: Constitution saving throw. It is a spell, so
you would have advantage on the roll for your
armor.
MARISHA: Oh, that's good! That's good. 17, that's
good for the first one. And a natural one! So I'll
take the 17.
MATT: All right, plus three? So you make the save.
You take half damage. Go ahead and roll 7d8 plus
30.
WILL: 7d8 plus 30! What?!
TRAVIS: You have that?
MARY: Just today. I don't know, I woke up! I may
need your help.
MATT: Chat room: "Well, that escalated quickly."
TRAVIS: 16? You're having me help you with math.
That's four. One more.
MARY: Grog and Zahra do math.
MATT: So you take 30 points of necrotic damage.
MARY: Plus 30? Oh yeah, that was 60.
MATT: Yep, 60, and half that. So you take 30 and
you're still up, at ten hit points, as a beam of
greenish necrotic death streaks across this
battlefield, slamming into your side unexpectedly
from behind as you're staring up at the horrible
form of Grog raging in front of you. You feel most
of your vitality sucked out of your body
immediately. You glance over your shoulder and see
Zahra around the corner going--
MARY: Slightly possessive of Kash, sorry! I'm so
sorry! You're too beautiful!
MATT: All right, Kash, you're up. Unless you
wanted to move still.
MARY: No, I'll stay there.
WILL: I think, wait, I have to see how close I can
get. I'd like to move first. My guardian is going
to stay there. I could stay there and ride it out,
let them fight it out. Seriously. Scanlan's
tactics. I'm going to move closer to the battle
here. So I'm going to go (counting). Wait, wait.
Hang on.
TRAVIS: Oh, into the pit! You die!
WILL: I guess it doesn't matter where I go, I'm
still not going to be able to see her, am I?
TRAVIS: There's a window. Is there a window, Matt,
or is it supposed to be a wall?
MATT: It's a window.
TRAVIS: Through the window, to the wall! To the
sweat drops down dragons' balls!
WILL: So can I see her?
MATT: Just so you're aware, that didn't use a
spell slot. No, because it's part of the mystic
arcanum ability. You get to use that once without
spending a spell slot.
WILL: Wow, that's a good spell. So can I actually
see her, then, through said window?
MATT: Keyleth? You could, yes. But she would have
three-quarters cover. If it has a spell attack
roll, she would get a bonus to armor class.
WILL: I'm still going to try to give her, if I can
see her from there, a 5th-level Flame Strike.
Okay, so that's what I'm going to do.
MATT: Okay.
WILL: She came out swinging! I was like, hey,
let's check it out!
TRAVIS: I was coming over to say hi and then it
was like, (explosions)!
MARY: You totally frizzed my hair with that
fucking lightning, so. Bad hair day is all Zahra
needs.
MATT: It's a ten-foot radius, so you're getting
this area? So I need both of you guys, Grog and
Keyleth, to make a dexterity saving throw.
MARISHA: Dexterity save?
MATT: Yes.
MARISHA: Nine plus--
MATT: You have advantage because spells.
MARISHA: So excited! Ooh, that's much better. 20
total.
MATT: 20? That would do it, so you take half
damage from this.
TRAVIS: 15.
MATT: I believe your DC is 18, so no.
MARISHA: What are you hitting me? Oh, you're
firestorming us?
MATT: Flame Strike. So roll 8d6, because it's half
fire and half radiant damage.
WILL: 8d6? Is this the six? Yeah, where is it? I
don't have-- yes I do. So eight. You mind if I
borrow these?
MARISHA: What does the cover grant you? What's the
three-quarters cover do?
MATT: It helps give you a better armor class, but
it doesn't help you against radial spells.
WILL: Come on, daddy needs to cook a druid. Here
we go. (counting) If it's on critical role? All
right, so there's 16... 30.
MATT: 30. You roll two more.
WILL: I roll two more, sorry!
MATT: So there's an incredible roll. 39. So, 18
points of damage. You take 39 points of fire.
Keyleth is now currently unconscious right there.
WILL: Try fighting now!
MARY: First kiss my ass!
MARISHA: Anything I can do to fix myself while I'm
out?
MATT: No, you keep making death saves until
hopefully you'd roll a 20 and maybe stabilize.
Well, if you roll a 20 you, fuck. I have to
remember the roll. You come back to consciousness
with one hit point.
MARISHA: But I have to roll a nat 20. Other than
that, that's it? Oh man.
WILL: You started with Lightning Striking me!
That's not something you forget! Yeah, that's my
turn.
MATT: Keyleth, I need you to go ahead and roll a
death save.
MARISHA: Yeah, totally. Nope.
MATT: All right, so that's one failed save. Go
ahead and mark that off. Grog, it's your turn.
TRAVIS: I would ask a question. Is there any way I
can move just up against the wall so that Keyleth
and Zahra are in a straight line?
WILL: Oh, that's not a good sound. That's a bad
question.
MATT: Oh, not really. I mean, depends on what you
want to do. If you're trying to ricochet Keyleth's
body--
TRAVIS: No, I have the Javelin of Lightning, but
it only works in a straight line.
MATT: Yeah, you'd probably have to hit one or the
other.
MARISHA: I'm also on the ground.
TRAVIS: I'm going to hit Keyleth on the ground.
MATT: You're going to hit Keyleth on the ground?
TRAVIS: Yeah, isn't she down on the ground?
MATT: Yeah. You can separate your moves and your
attacks. You can hit, then move, then hit.
TRAVIS: I'll hit her once and then move. I'm going
to pimp slap and run!
MATT: Okay, because it's a melee attack within
five feet, it's an auto-crit which is an immediate
two death saves. How do you want to do this?
(yelling)
MARY: Oh my god! What?
MARISHA: Come on, come on. All that pent-up
aggression you've been wanting to get out.
TRAVIS: I pick up Craven Edge over my head. Seeing
her there, unconscious, I turn my head away, turn
the point down, and go, whack!
MATT: And with that, you hear an attempt at breath
and a slight gurgle as your eyes are closed as you
draw the blade. You hear a satisfying, "Yes,
delicious. Two more, Grog."
TRAVIS: I'll do my best. Do I get an extra attack
after I make my move, because I killed someone?
MATT: Well, you have your bonus action attack
anyway because you have your frenzied rage, so you
still have your movement and two more attacks.
TRAVIS: All right, I would like to move to Zahra,
please. I would like to do like Joaquin Phoenix
and swing away. Yeah, Joaquin Phoenix in Signs?
See, and swing away? Grabs the bat and he beats
the shit out of the alien? I would also like to do
reckless attack on these.
MATT: All right, not great weapon master though?
TRAVIS: No. Reckless. Advantage, and whoever's
fighting me gets advantage. 24 is the first one.
MARY: Yeah, that hits.
TRAVIS: 18 is probably going to be good enough. 27
on the second one.
MATT: Both hit. You only get two attacks on her.
TRAVIS: Oh, that's right.
MATT: Yeah, because you killed Keyleth with one.
WILL: While she was unconscious! While she was
down and unconscious, awesome.
TRAVIS: Ten, 18 for the first one.
MATT: So 18 points of slashing damage.
TRAVIS: 12. 20 on the second one.
MATT: So 38 points of slashing damage against you,
Zahra. I need you to make two constitution saving
throws.
MARISHA: Grog off the leash is a bad day.
MATT: Yeah man, you guys' best bet was probably to
gang up on Grog, and you guys let him stick
around. This is going to be rough.
MARY: What do I need to do?
MATT: Roll a d20 twice, adding three each roll. So
that's a fail. Second one again? Success. So your
strength goes down to ten as Craven Edge saps a
strength point from you. You get a plus one to
your strength, which brings you up to 18, I
believe? So currently you get a plus one to hit
and damage on all your attacks.
TRAVIS: A beautiful thing.
MATT: I believe that's the end of Grog's turn,
because you can't do much else? Zahra, you're up.
MARY: I would like to tell Grog how much I love
him.
MATT: Don't forget, as a reaction, before your
turn ends, if you wanted to use your Hellish
Rebuke?
MARY: I know, but do I want to let it all go now?
MATT: It's either that or have him cleave your
face off next turn!
TRAVIS: It's always an option! Face slits are
always in!
MARY: Out of nowhere, a voice comes to me and
says, "Use Hellish Rebuke!" And so, as a reaction,
I shall.
MARISHA: Now I'm envisioning Grog's Rhinoplasty.
MATT: Make a dexterity saving throw.
TRAVIS: 19.
MATT: He succeeds, so he takes half the damage.
Roll 2d10.
WILL: Come on, you can do it, Z.
MARY: 14.
MATT: So he takes seven points of fire damage to
Grog.
MARISHA: God, he is made of meat and hit points.
WILL: Made of meat, hit points, and shame.
MATT: What are you at right now, Grog? He's at 134
hit points, guys.
MARY: Fuck you.
MATT: Seriously, Grog has rolled some of the best
hit point rolls I've ever seen in my life, and
then he took the toughness feat. And has a
constitution of 20. It's stupid.
WILL: So we can't kill-- Dude.
MARY: I know. Witch Bolt is a concentration, so I
can't Hex him, is that correct?
MARISHA: Whenever he fails that save on Finger of
Death, that's fucking--
TRAVIS: Tell me she only has one of those a day,
right?
MARISHA: One for free, without burning a spell
slot.
MATT: It's one of those things where, if it's a
concentration spell and you're not using it to
concentrate, Generally, just a one-off thing, I'll
allow you to concentrate on two things at once if
you use it as a one-off spell. So I would say, if
you wanted to Hex somebody and then do a Witch
Bolt but not have the concentration effect, I'd
allow that.
MARY: I don't know what that means.
MATT: What that means is, as long as you're not
maintaining Witch Bolt, I'll let it not override
Hex because you're just doing it as a one-off
spell.
MARY: Okay, but what if i want to keep it going?
MATT: Then Hex would not overlap with it.
MARY: I'm going to Witch Bolt Grog.
MATT: It is also a ranged spell attack, which
means you have disadvantage to hit him with it
because he is right in your face. You can step
away from him to try to do it.
MARY: I'm going to Hex him. If I Eldritch Blast am
I still at disadvantage?
MATT: Same thing, disadvantage on blasts because
he's right up in your face. You'd have to get away
from him to do that.
MARy: All right, I'm going to use my Cloak of the
Bat and fly away from him, but he gets to whack me
then, doesn't he? All right. Wait, let me, is that
considered an action?
MATT: Well, it depends on what the ability is.
MARY: Cloak of the Bat allows me to fly at will.
MATT: All it does is give you flying? So you don't
turn into a bat form, it means you can just fly?
So you can do that.
MARY: And then do I still get to cast something
afterwards?
MATT: Let me pull up the book real fast.
WILL: Like a kid at Christmas over there!
TRAVIS: No, I'm not getting excited about anything
because if Christmas is any indication, shit can go
south. I got a remote control car! (crashing)
(crying) I got a Nerf football!
MATT: You can choose to fly 40 feet. It's not
an actual action to use it, so you can do that.
That'd be your movement.
MARY: I'd like to do that and cast Evard's Black
Tentacles.
TRAVIS: What?! Whose?!
WILL: You'll find out!
MATT: Are you going to cast that first and then
go?
MARY: No, I need to get out of there before.
MATT: Okay, so Grog you get a swipe at her.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I do. Do I get advantage on my
recklessness?
MATT: Yes. Though technically, he does have
reckless attack on him, so you could attack him
without disadvantage. I forgot about that. So if
you wanted to hit him with a spell, your
disadvantage is canceled out by the advantage
you'd have on him because he used reckless
attack.
MARY: I'm not sure I understand that.
TRAVIS: You roll once instead of having to roll
twice and take the lower. Because you have
disadvantage, but I gave you advantage, so they
cancel each other.
MATT: So it's a regular roll if you wanted to stay
where you are.
MARY: He's still going to cleave my face off next
turn.
MATT: Yeah, but he won't get a bonus attack of
cleaving. Up to you. If you want to take the hit
to the face and run away?
MARY: I'm going to take the hit to the face.
MATT: All right, make an attack, Grog.
TRAVIS: 15 was the total of the second roll. I'm
sorry, so that's 24.
MATT: That hits, roll damage. Where do you want to
fly?
MARY: I'd like to fly over here.
TRAVIS: 21.
MARY: Fuck you.
MATT: 21 points of damage to you.
TRAVIS: And a constitution save.
MARY: Not yet. And I'd like to cast Evard's Black
Tentacles. Would you like to hear the
description?
TRAVIS: In explicit details.
MARY: Squirming, ebony tentacles fill a 20-foot
square on the ground that I can see within range.
For the duration, these tentacles turn the ground
in the area into difficult terrain. When a
creature enters or is affected for the first time,
the creature must succeed a dexterity saving throw
and take-- it's not too much damage. A creature
that starts its turn in the area is already
restrained. Basically, you're restrained.
TRAVIS: I'm restrained, okay.
MATT: This'll be the markers for the area. This
whole area is filled with dark tentacles.
WILL: And he can't go anywhere.
MATT: It's difficult terrain, which means every
five feet step you take it costs ten feet of your
movement.
TRAVIS: So my speed is halved.
MATT: Yep.
TRAVIS: Shit.
MARY: Do I get anything else?
MATT: That's your action. If you wanted to use
your bonus action to drink a healing potion?
MARY: That's what I'd like.
MATT: Go ahead and do that. You heal 8d4 plus eight.
TRAVIS: She needs to make a constitution saving
throw.
MATT: That's right, yeah. So that's 14. Roll two
more. 19 plus eight. So you heal 27 hit points.
That's the end of your turn. Kash, you're up.
These black tentacles.
TRAVIS: Come join the party, it's like an anime
nightmare in here.
(laughter)
WILL: It's tempting. What's also tempting is my
Guardian of Faith that's still over there waiting
for me.
TRAVIS: Orville Redenbacher?
WILL: Yes! He will protect all. No.
MARISHA: Orville!
WILL: I think right now while he is trapped
there--
MATT: That is eight plus three. That is a failure;
you lose another strength point.
MARY: Can I use luck?
MATT: If you have luck, yeah!
MARY: 15.
MATT: Yeah, never mind! It doesn't happen.
WILL: It is getting down to the nitty gritty. He
can't move now, which is--
MATT: That you know of, unless he makes his save.
WILL: Oh, well that's disappointing. With the way
he's rolling tonight, I'm guessing he'll make the
save.
TRAVIS: So I have to make a save to move, or it
just halves my speed?
MATT: At the start of your turn, you have roll to
see if you're restrained and take damage.
WILL: I think I got to hit him hard right now
while he's away from there.
TRAVIS: No! Look, she's right there in the open
world.
WILL: I think I'm going to use my 7th-level
Firestorm.
MARISHA: Yeah, you will!
MATT: Are you using it on both of them?
MARISHA: Yes, you are.
TRAVIS: You don't want to do that.
WILL: Yeah, I think I probably should.
TRAVIS: Think about all the poor tentacles that
just came to life.
MATT: That's true. It might knock her
concentration and lose the tentacle spell.
WILL: I imagine it might lose the tentacle spell,
but again, with the way he's rolling, I imagine
he's going to make his saving throw.
MATT: The point is, I guess, from a technical
standpoint, if you just hit him, the tentacles
will stay up. If you hit both of them, it'll
probably knock her down, but you lose the
tentacles and he'll be able to come after you next
turn.
WILL: Okay, then I want to do the one where he'll
go back after her and keep me alive and well,
which is what I'm guessing is going to happen.
MATT: It's up to you. You can go after them both
and take her out right now, probably. Your call.
Whatever you want to do.
WILL: I don't want to take her out right now,
because then it's just me and Grog. I've got
nobody who's helping me out.
TRAVIS: You might not get this chance again. I
mean, we're both right there.
WILL: How many hit points do you have? 309? How
many are there? 7000 hit points? You're at what?
TRAVIS: 134.
WILL: And you're at what? How many do you have
left?
MARY: I'm sorry, I didn't hear you. I didn't quite
hear you.
WILL: "My hit points are so low, I can't hear
anymore."
MARY: My hearing is gone. Apparently you lose
hearing. 57.
MATT: She looks hurt.
WILL: You know what, one thing at a time. I'm
going to go for Grog right now and I want to make
sure she holds her concentration on the
tentacles.
TRAVIS: I expected more.
WILL: You're still going to be like, "Oh my god,
it's the biggest hit I've taken all night! I'm
"down to 120."
MATT: As you're currently dealing with all these
dark, arcane tentacles that are sprouting out of
all the stones around the ground, a beam of light
seems to descend from the sky for a second as it
turns to a dark red crimson and bursts around you
in a giant inferno of searing divine energy.
WILL: Hey, how you doing! Boom!
MATT: It curves around and incinerates the remains
of Keyleth.
MARY: Bye, Kiki!
TRAVIS: Sarah Connor style!
MATT: Go ahead and make a dexterity saving throw.
TRAVIS: Oh wow, really? That's 21. It's a 19.
Dexterity saving, right? Yeah. Plus two.
MATT: So you take half damage from that. Go ahead
and roll 7d10 fire damage.
TRAVIS: 7d10?!
MATT: That's what she did to take out the
wyverns.
WILL: Are these d10? No, those are d8. So I got,
these are all d10s here, right? Nine. Does anyone
have one more? I have six. I need one more. There
we go.
TRAVIS: Why would I give him mine? I see a ten. I
see two tens.
MATT: 43 points of fire damage. You take half of
that, so 21 points of fire damage.
WILL: That's like nothing! And then for the rest
of my move, right? I'm going to run back to my
spiritual guardian and be like, what's up? That
was my 7th-level spell and nothing! We barely
touched him!
MATT: Keyleth smolders. Grog, it's your turn.
TRAVIS: I'd like to try and break free of the
tentacles of love.
MATT: Go ahead and make your dexterity saving
throw.
TRAVIS: It's 14.
MATT: 14 is a failure. You take 3d6 points of
damage. Could you roll that, Zahra?
WILL: Just keep tagging him, Z!
MARY: I'm trying, darling. I'm trying.
TRAVIS: What kind of damage, there, Matthew?
MATT: This is bludgeoning, so you take half the
damage. So he took four points of bludgeoning
damage and you are restrained currently.
Restrained, to specifically read you what it does,
your speed becomes zero, so you cannot move.
Attack rolls against you have advantage, and your
attack rolls have disadvantage. You now have
disadvantage on dexterity saving throws.
WILL: And you're still going to beat us all.
TRAVIS: I don't know, it's not a good thing.
MATT: So Grog, what are you doing?
TRAVIS: I'm turning toward the black tentacle
dealer, right, and I'm giving her the bird. No, I
would like to take the Javelin of Lightning and
throw it at Zahra.
MATT: Okay. Let me see the card? You don't have to
roll for it, it's each creature in the line. It
turns, as you see, Grog, the tentacles, turn
around, and throw something toward you, all of a
sudden it sparks with electrical energy and
streaks toward you like a bolt of lightning
horizontally. I need you to make a dexterity
saving throw, Zahra.
MARY: 12.
MATT: That's a success, so you take half damage.
Roll 4d6 lightning damage, Grog.
TRAVIS: Eight.
MATT: So you take four points of lightning damage
as the javelin streaks past you and skids across
the stonework behind, sending a few sparks, and
then falls to the ground, its energy used. All
right. Ends your turn, Grog? Zahra, you're up.
MARY: Right, so I've still got Witch Bolt on him,
yes? Is that what I used last time?
MATT: No, you used Evard's Black Tentacles.
MARY: Oh, I used Evard's Black Tentacles, which is
technically a concentration. It is. So I shall
use-- is Eldritch Blast? Can I do a combo of
Eldritch and Agonizing again, using my cantrip and
invocation? Or is that considered concentration?
MATT: Well, let me see. Agonizing Blast isn't a
cantrip, it's an Eldritch Invocation which gives
you the benefit on top of your Eldritch Blast. So
yeah, you can do that three times. That's your
cantrip, and you can do that, yeah. So all three
against him, or do you try and aim for your buddy
over there?
MARY: No, we've got to try and take out our giant
friend.
TRAVIS: I feel so loved.
MARY: It's a compliment. So that plus the
Agonizing, yeah? It'll still hold the
concentration?
MATT: Let me see the Javelin, what it does? Yeah,
I don't know what you guys are talking about. You
guys are really weird. Oh, and because it is four
damage, go ahead and roll a constitution save to
maintain concentration on your tentacles.
MARY: Ten.
MATT: Ten's enough to keep it, so the tentacles
stay. Thank you for the reminder, guys. So you're
doing all three against Grog? All right, roll with
advantage on each roll, because of his reckless
attack.
MARY: So it's 1d10 plus seven.
MATT: Go ahead and roll that twice. A nine, roll
again.
MARY: A nine.
MATT: All right, so that, what's your AC?
TRAVIS: 19.
MATT: 19, it does hit you because you have plus 12
on that attack roll. So roll for the second one.
That's one hit.
MARY: 11.
MATT: And roll again? That hits again. Roll for
the third one?
MARY: 14.
MATT: Roll again. See if it gets a crit.
MARY: Natural 20!
MATT: Two hits and a crit. All right, so let's go
ahead and roll that. So that's one plus seven, so
that's eight points of damage.
TRAVIS: Bludgeoning?
MARY: What's the plus 11?
MATT: No, it's force damage. That's to hit, not
damage. Plus seven that. So that's eight points of
damage. Second one?
MARY: Five?
MATT: Five plus seven is 12 points. And then this
is the crit.
MARY: Four.
MATT: So that's eight, plus seven is 15.
TRAVIS: So 35. Can I use my Stone's Endurance to
limit that damage?
MATT: From the last one? You can, totally.
WILL: Got an answer for everything, don't you?
TRAVIS: No, shut up. So that's 14. No, 15.
MATT: Okay, so the last critical hit does
nothing.
TRAVIS: Okay, great. So 20 total.
MATT: So as you hit him with the final hit, it
slams into him and he puts his chest out, pumps
it, takes the blast and it seems to disperse
across his muscled form to no effect.
MARY: Oh, it looked so good going in, too!
TRAVIS: Still pretty good. You actually burned off
the baby oil on these pecs.
WILL: That's what that smell is! All right. Let's
see if we can keep hitting him.
TRAVIS: I mean, look guys. Share and share alike.
WILL: I'm going to move a little closer to him.
TRAVIS: (whispering) Yeah, come closer.
WILL: So let's go there.
TRAVIS: Leave that guardian alone. He doesn't need
to come.
WILL: He can't come. He'd like to, but he can't.
He just hangs out there.
MARY: He's eating popcorn the whole time, enjoying
the fight.
WILL: But he looks awesome. He is, he's guarding
me just in case. He's a place to run back to if I
need it. I'm going to do another level five Flame
Strike. Yeah, because I can do two level-5s,
right? It's better than raising the dead. Doesn't
seem apropos at this moment. I would have raised
you, but you're ashes and you blew away. My bad.
MARISHA: Yeah, thanks. Matt had to go into
detail.
WILL: How do you think everything's going,
Keyleth? Oh, you're just ash.
MATT: All right, so, against who?
WILL: "Against who!"
MATT: All right, make a dexterity saving throw
with disadvantage, because you are restrained.
TRAVIS: 16.
MATT: 16, not enough. That's a failed save. Do 8d6
damage against Grog.
WILL: Where are the d6s now? Eight?
MATT: As you're being held back by the tentacles,
all of a sudden you see another streak of divine
energy come from the ground as flames erupt from
beneath you. Your vision becomes nothing but
fire.
TRAVIS: Not this again-- argh!
WILL: I have seven here. Here we go, come on. Aw.
Argh! 21, and then one more. Come on. 26.
MATT: So 26 points of fire damage.
WILL: To drink my potion, do I need to be able to
move?
MATT: It's a bonus action in my games, so don't
worry too much about that.
WILL: I'd like to drink my potion, sir. What do I
need? 8d4 plus eight, is that right?
MATT: Don't forget, you have your danger
sensibility. Roll another dexterity saving throw,
to be safe. It's things you can see, like spells
and traps.
TRAVIS: It's a nine.
MATT: Nah.
WILL: So I can drink my potion?
MATT: Sure. 8d4 plus eight. So you're up next,
Grog. Know what you're going to do.
WILL: (counting)
MATT: Shitty rolls!
WILL: Awful rolls. So 22.
MATT: All right. Grog, I want you to go ahead and
roll a constitution save real fast.
TRAVIS: I don't like the way you're asking. Ooh,
11?
MATT: 11. As the flames subside, you take a moment
to take in the damage you've taken. There's a
familiar smell, a smell you've smelled once before,
when Trinket ran across a series of lightning
traps: the smell of burnt hair. As you reach up,
you find your chin clean.
(yelling)
WILL: I took Grog's beard!
TRAVIS: No! What have you done!
MARY: Seppuku with Craven Edge!
WILL: Kashaw the cleric takes Grog's beard! I want
to see that fan art real bad! That is the end of
my turn, sir, because I already moved out here, so
I can't move back.
MATT: Grog, you're up.
TRAVIS: So I have to break free of the tentacle
trap, right?
MATT: Yeah, top of the turn, I need you to try and
break free.
TRAVIS: Son of a fuck! No, I have advantage on
dex, right?
MATT: You are restrained currently. Let me double
check really fast to make sure we have the
specifics, here. We haven't used this spell
before.
TRAVIS: Wienerschnitzel!
MATT: Okay, so, you take another 3d6 bludgeoning
damage because you started your turn restrained in
the tentacles. So do another 3d6.
MARY: Oh, that's better. 11.
MATT: So you take five points of bludgeoning
damage. Round it down. You have to use an action
to make a check to try and break free of it.
TRAVIS: Well, I would like to do that.
MATT: All right, go ahead and make a strength or
dexterity check, your choice.
TRAVIS: Oh, well, I have advantage on both of
those because I'm raging and I have danger sense.
19, that's good. What am I talking about?
Strength! Thank you! Yeah, 26.
MATT: All right, not a saving throw. A check.
That's still enough. You break free of the
tentacles. Break free using your action. You still
have your bonus action and your move, though you
can't move quite as far. Which way are you going?
You've got two targets right now.
TRAVIS: I know. I'm going to go towards, ding dang
dong, Zahra.
MATT: All right. (counting) You can just get up to
her with your barbarian speed.
TRAVIS: And what do I have left?
MATT: You have your bonus action still.
TRAVIS: Just my bonus action. I'll take my potion,
my superior potion, because I can't attack
anybody. Can I grapple or anything like that?
MATT: You can attack with your bonus action. You
have frenzied rage, remember?
TRAVIS: (inarticulate yelling)
MATT: Up to you!
TRAVIS: Awesome. Yes, let's do that. Let's attack
her.
MATT: All right. Go for it. Is this a reckless
attack?
TRAVIS: Yes. 26.
MATT: 26 hits, go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: You piece of... (counting) 21! In your
horned face!
MATT: 21 points of damage to you, Zahra. And a
constitution save.
TRAVIS: Oh, 22 points of damage, because I forgot
to add.
MATT: I need you to make a concentration check, so
roll another constitution save. Oh, that's a
failure. The tentacles vanish from the scenery as
the spell disappears. Bye, kernels! I need you to
make another one from Craven Edge. That is another
failure. You lose another strength point. You're
now a strength of nine, and you gain another plus
one, Grog.
TRAVIS: Plus one to attack and damage?
MATT: Well, plus one to your strength. What is
your strength at, now?
TRAVIS: Now it is 19.
MATT: So no bonus yet. Next time. All right, that
ends Grog's turn. Zahra, you're up.
MARY: All right. My question is, with my dark
staff, does this expend a spell slot?
MATT: No, it's from the staff itself.
MARY: Okay. Then I will cast Witch Bolt from my
staff at 5th level. That leaves me with one charge
left.
MATT: Okay. Using almost all the charges in that
staff. You still have to make a ranged spell
attack, which right now would be at disadvantage,
but he attacked so it would be a straight roll. So
go ahead and do that, roll a d20. That's a nine
plus your spell attack, which is 12. 21. What's
your AC?
TRAVIS: 19.
MATT: It hits. That's 5d12 points of lightning
damage against Grog. Five, because she did it at
5th level.
MARY: 21 plus 20. These two, it was the nine and
the 11. 41.
MATT: 41 points of damage to you, Grog. Lightning
damage. All of a sudden, up in your face, she
holds her staff in her front, closes her eyes, and
a blast of dark lightning hits you.
MARY: Don't taze me, bro! Sorry, love!
TRAVIS: It's okay, I'm going to kill you soon.
MATT: Zahra, is that the end of your turn? You
still have a bonus action.
MARY: I have a bonus action. What do I do with a
bonus action? If I move, does he get--? Meh.
MATT: That's Zahra's turn. Kash, you're up.
WILL: Okay, so I have a question here.
TRAVIS: Yeah, you can jump in the pit.
WILL: Can I? Great. Kash goes, I'm out. Taps out
and jumps in the pit. If Will was in the UFC, same
thing. You mentioned at the beginning of the
battle that we are now on a different plane,
correct?
MATT: You are out of your normal vicinity, yes.
WILL: Okay, but are we on a different spiritual
plane, do we know? I have a question.
MATT: You also know that you can cast lower spells
at a higher level if you wanted to.
WILL: I know, but my question is, I have a
wonderful Banishment spell, which is, if we're
from a different plane, I can Banish him, and if I
can hold the spell for up to a minute, he can't
come back. So can I banish him from the battle?
MATT: What's the range on it?
WILL: 60 feet, but I haven't moved yet.
MATT: Yeah, if he fails the save, you can banish
him for a period of time to another plane.
WILL: But that's the thing, according to the
spell, if we're not from this plane, he can't come
back. It's not just a period of time. He doesn't
return.
MARISHA: Oh, like, you're going to banish him? Oh
my god, do this. Send him to bizarro world!
WILL: Because we started, you said, we look up and
we're in a place we didn't know. It seemed like
we're in a different plane. So if I send him
back?
MATT: Technically it would be the same plane. It's
just in a different timeline.
WILL: Okay, so then he can return? Damn.
MATT: If you were fighting in the Hells, yeah, it
would send you back to the Prime Material Plane
and he would sit there.
WILL: Okay, so then it doesn't make any sense,
then.
MATT: It takes him out of the fight for a while,
but it's your call.
TRAVIS: Yeah, take me out a bit. You two talk it
out.
MATT: What are you doing, Kash?
WILL: I don't have a Flame Strike left. That's my
problem. I'm running out of spells.
MATT: With a 6th level, you could Flame Strike
both of them if you have one left of that.
WILL: Oh, I do have a 6th level.
MATT: Which would do more damage. It's your call.
WILL: But then she's going to die too!
MARY: (whispering) I have resistance to fire.
WILL: Well, then that's what I'm going to do. I'm
going to use a 6th level and I will do a 6th-level
Flame Strike on him.
MATT: I was just shooting it out there!
WILL: No, it's a good idea! I want to Banish him.
I wanted to be nice and go away for a while, but
he won't, so let's drop a huge thing of fire right
on his face. So we're going to do a 6th-level
Flame Strike right now.
MATT: All right, so that's 9d6 points of damage to
each of you. Do you want it to be radiant or fire
damage more? It's split into two types of damage,
so do you want to do more radiant or more fire
damage?
WILL: What hurts more?
MATT: They both hurt the same, although she's
resistant to fire. So fire or radiant, what are
you going to do? Just say one or the other.
WILL: I'm going to do radiant.
MATT: So roll 5d6 right now. I need you guys to
both make dexterity saving throws.
TRAVIS: Which I have advantage on.
WILL: 5d6, come on. I've been rolling crap here.
Let's go. Ones! Everywhere! Three ones. 13.
MATT: So you take 13 points of radiant damage that
is not reduced. You take 13 points of radiant
damage. Then roll 4d6 more.
WILL: Come on, come on. No whammies! Big money, no
Wheatons! Come on!
MARISHA: Oh my god, so many Wheatons!
MATT: 13 again. So you take 13 points of fire
damage.
TRAVIS: That's not reduced by making the save
throw?
MATT: Oh, you made the save! Both of these are
halved. Sorry, I forgot about that. You take half
of it, so you would be at, it was 13, you'll take
six points of damage.
WILL: I'm rolling like crap tonight. It was rough!
It could've been a huge strike.
MATT: All right. That ends your turn?
WILL: Yeah, it ends my turn. Oh wait, I haven't
moved yet! Can I move back to my guardian?
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: I still imagine that it's a giant,
floating popcorn kernel.
MATT: Grog, it's your turn.
TRAVIS: Right, okay. I would like to attack Zahra
and see how that does with the first of my three
attacks.
MATT: All right, make your first strike. With
advantage?
TRAVIS: Yeah. 23.
MATT: Her AC's 14. That hit.
MARY and MARISHA: (singing) So never more shall we
see you again.
TRAVIS: 21.
MATT: 21 points of damage.
MARY: Bye-bye, I'm out.
MATT: Zahra falls unconscious. I need her to make
a constitution saving throw.
WILL: Come on, Z!
MATT: You roll a d20. Okay, so she succeeds. You
are unconscious now, on the ground, bleeding out
as the blood that you draw from the blade you can
see seeping into the outside of Craven Edge. Grog,
what do you want to do? She's unconscious at your
feet, and you see Kash in the distance rushing
near a wall.
TRAVIS: No, I hit her again.
MATT: Roll with advantage, twice.
TRAVIS: 28?
MATT: That hits. It's an automatic crit, so you
lose two death saving throws. Mark those off. You
don't roll damage, she just lost two death saving
throws. She's on the edge. You have one more
attack.
TRAVIS: Is this my bonus action or one more
attack?
MATT: This would be your bonus action to attack,
yeah.
TRAVIS: And I can still move? I would like to run
behind the wall over here. Can I down a Superior
potion?
MATT: You haven't used your potion yet, right?
Yeah, you can do that. It's not d6s, it's d4s. 8d4
plus eight. This is getting intense.
WILL: It's not getting intense! It's a matter of
time before he comes over and kills me!
MARISHA: You've done really well.
WILL: Yeah, because I'm just running away.
MARISHA: You are kind of taking the defensive
route, which is great.
TRAVIS: 28 points.
MATT: All right, so you heal that up. Zahra, it's
your turn. I need you to make a death saving
throw.
TRAVIS: Fail it. Fail it, baby. Fail it for me.
MARY: 16.
MATT: That's a success, so mark a success. That
brings us to Kash. It's your turn. You have an
unconscious Zahra over there that you could finish
off, or toss a distant heal if you wanted to bring
her back. Or go directly after Grog and try and
bring him down.
MARISHA: There might be a cushy water bed in the
pit. You don't know.
WILL: We're sensing it's not a water bed in the
pit. I don't know, technically, but we're
sensing it is. I'm at 83, so I don't have to heal
yet. You know what? I'm going to move closer to
Grog. I've got to start doing some damage. Let's
move. I want to be able to see him. I want a clear
line of sight on him if we can. Do I have a clear
line of sight?
MATT: No, you'd have to move over here to get a
clear line of sight on him, really. You could move
that far, but then you're outside of your
guardian, which you can do if you want.
MARY: (chicken noises)
MATT: So what do you want to do?
WILL: I want to get as close to Grog as I can.
I've got to start doing some damage. He's going to
fuck me up the next round, but I have to be able
to.
MATT: You can get there.
WILL: And can I see him pretty well?
MATT: You can see him all right.
WILL: All right, and I can cast them at higher
levels, correct? So I guess that I'm going to have
to do some damage. I've used my 7th, I've used my
6th, and I've used all my 5th. I have two fours
left, so I would like to cast Spiritual Weapon,
but at a level four.
MATT: Yeah, you can do that.
MARY: (coughing) Heal Zahra.
WILL: My heals are sore! I'm running out of
things.
MATT: Okay, so you create a floating Spiritual
Weapon.
WILL: And I think I can hit him twice with this.
MATT: I will make this little kitten your
Spiritual Weapon. Where do you want to put it,
within 60 feet?
WILL: I want to put floating death kitten right in
front of him.
MATT: All right, little tiny floating death
kitten. So, all right. You have a spirit weapon, a
giant cat bludgeon, summoned by Vesh, and dark
energy pours off of this floating cat. (cat yowl)
Every impact.
WILL: And now, taste Mittens!
MATT: All right, so go ahead and make a melee
spell attack. Roll a d20 twice and add plus ten.
Take the higher one and add ten.
WILL: 28.
MATT: That hits. Go ahead and roll, is it a 4th
level? Okay, for every two levels, so it takes 2d8
plus five damage. Roll that twice.
WILL: 16.
MATT: 16 points of force damage, so it's not
reduced.
WILL: Mittens is death!
MATT: (cat noises) You're being bludgeoned by a
somewhat ethereal-looking dark energy kitten.
WILL: That's right. Who hits you and then goes--
(swipe noise)
MARY: Plus, Grog's allergic.
WILL: And now it says here that I can then, as a
bonus action on my turn, I can move the weapon up
to 20 feet and repeat the attack against a
creature. Again. Okay, so, I want-- Mittens, baby!
Let's move around the other side and hit him
again! Can we float him around the back or, I
guess it doesn't really matter.
MATT: Go ahead and roll again for the attack.
2d20.
WILL: 2d20. 12, seven.
MATT: So plus ten, it still hits. Go ahead and
roll 2d8 plus five.
WILL: Five, seven. 12 plus five, so there we go,
baby.
MATT: 17 points of force damage.
TRAVIS: I had exactly 17 hit points left, so I
would like to use my relentless rage.
MARISHA: Oh, he does have that!
MATT: Yep, this is where things get real
interesting.
WILL: Yeah, what exactly is happening? Damn you,
Mittens!
TRAVIS: I have to make a DC 10 constitution saving
throw. If I succeed, I come back to one hit
point.
MATT: Yep. Barbarians.
WILL: Hey, buddy? I hope you fail. Just want you
to know that.
TRAVIS: That's a 21.
MATT: So you are back at one hit point. That ends
your turn, Kash?
WILL: Yeah, I'm done!
MATT: Grog, it's your turn.
TRAVIS: Can I stalk toward Kash?
WILL: Slowly and menacingly? Hey, buddy!
TRAVIS: How big are you?
WILL: Oh, shit. I'm guessing 6'8", 280? No, I'm
probably not huge, I would imagine.
TRAVIS: Can I attempt to pick up Kash and throw
him into the pit? Like, grab him and sumo-Greco,
whoom!
MATT: You know what? Go ahead and make a grapple
check. Roll an athletics. You can roll athletics
or acrobatics.
WILL: Is it 20? Let me see which is higher. Oh, I
don't have anything. Are these dex? Because I
don't have anything here.
MATT: Which is higher, your strength or your dex?
Probably your strength, so roll a d20 and add--
WILL: Yeah, my strength is higher, but my
acrobatics are two.
MATT: What's your athletics? Three. So roll a d20
and add three.
WILL: 19.
MATT: What'd you roll?
TRAVIS: 18.
(exclaiming)
MATT: So as you go to grab him, you get your hands
on Kash and, as you begin to try and pull, all of
a sudden Kash's eyes go jet-black and you see this
burst of dark energy around as Vesh comes in to
protect the one cleric follower. As that happens,
your hands are forced off of his form. You still
have a bonus action.
TRAVIS: I do, huh? Can I try it again?
MATT: No, it's an action to try and grapple.
TRAVIS: So I could attack? Oh, motherfuck. And
intimidate is an action? Okay, yeah, I'll attack
him.
MATT: Great weapon master, or not?
WILL: It sounds like you're helping him.
MATT: I've helped you!
WILL: Well, there's a difference! I suck!
TRAVIS: You have a high AC, right?
WILL: I do. Wait, high AC? The attack bonus? No,
my AC is 20.
TRAVIS: Oh fuck, no great weapon master. Well, all
right, yeah. Let's try it. This one, great weapon
master, reckless attack. Plus, okay. 26 minus five
is 21.
MATT: 21 hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
WILL: Okay, wait now. I have a question, too,
because I also have a Ring of Protection and a
Sentinel Shield.
MARY: That's all wrapped up, I think.
WILL: Does it? Okay.
MATT: I'm double-checking, I'm trying to remember
if grapple is--
TRAVIS: 35.
MATT: So 35 points of damage?
TRAVIS: 35 points of damage and a constitution
save.
MATT: I'm double-checking one thing, because I'm
trying to remember if grapple is an action or an
attack.
WILL: Are you still at one?
TRAVIS: (high-pitched) Yeah! Just one!
WILL: Your voice! (high-pitched) I could tell you,
but yeah!
TRAVIS: I'm kind of one-eyeing it.
MARISHA: If you get through this with one hit
point--
MATT: You also have an additional attack, because
it only takes one attack to attempt to grapple. Or
you could attempt another grapple. Your call. Do
you want to grapple with your second attack, or do
you want to hit him again?
TRAVIS: I'll just hit him again.
WILL: What was the first damage? 35.
MATT: Great weapon master, or not?
TRAVIS: Oh yeah. Oh, it rolled over from a 20! Son
of a bitch! Okay.
WILL: Oh, this sucks. I can't do the math.
TRAVIS: No, that won't hit. Aw, it rolled over
from a 20!
MATT: So, as the first strike comes down with
Craven Edge, striking across the armor, it splits
and beneath you can see the red crimson already
spilling inside. Make a constitution saving throw.
d20, add your constitution modifier. Two, I
believe, right?
WILL: Yes. Four! Oh no, wait, I'm sorry. Three.
MATT: It's a failure! So he steals one of your
strength. Your strength goes up by one.
WILL: So my strength goes down?
MATT: It goes down to 16. Doesn't make a huge
difference. So, the second strike comes down
across with Craven Edge. This time, you put your
shield up, and you can feel the weight of it
almost pushing you off your feet, but it streaks
across the armor, no impact. That ends Grog's
turn. Zahra, make another death saving throw.
WILL: Come on, Z!
MARISHA: Roll a nat 20!
MARY: 19.
TRAVIS: Oh, it rolled over from a one, oh my god.
MARY: It sure did!
MATT: Two failures, two successes. Kash, you're
up.
WILL: I have one more 4th-level spell. I would
like to do another 4th-level Spiritual Weapon.
MATT: It would replace the other one.
MARISHA: Yeah, Mittens is still up.
MATT: You can use your bonus action to send
Mittens there and do another regular attack, or a
spell if you wanted to. Your call. It's a bonus
action. However, you do need to make a
concentration check for the damage you took last
turn. What was the total damage of that attack,
again?
WILL: It was 35.
MATT: Total damage, 35? Half of 35, that brings it
to, we'll say 17. Roll a constitution saving
throw.
WILL: And it has to be over 17 to see if Mittens
is still in the game? Come on, Mittens! Eight.
MATT: Nope, Mittens. So Mittens vanished from the
impact, but you can cast it again if you want to.
WILL: I can cast it again, though, and still hit
twice with it, can't I? Okay, so I'm going to
bring Mittens back. Hi, baby! So that's the last
of my 4th-level spells, okay.
MATT: Hold on, let me check one thing really fast.
Spiritual Weapon, checking one thing here. Just to
make sure. Lot of stuff happening really fast.
Spiritual Weapon is not concentration! My
apologies. So, you don't have to do that.
MARY: Mittens lives!
MATT: I look over and see Travis going like,
concentration check! I'm like shit, right! I need
to stop doing that. Mittens can move 20 feet and
repeat the attack.
WILL: Is she 20? Let's get Mittens over there.
MATT: Roll 2d20.
WILL: 2d20, come on! 16.
MATT: 16 plus your spell attack, that'll hit. Go
ahead and roll. Even at a minimum, Grog, I need
you to make another constitution check, with a DC
of 15 now.
TRAVIS: Yep. Yes! 28.
MATT: 28. Still at one hit point, Grog takes the
hit, almost goes down and then comes right back up
at the feet, angry.
WILL: Okay, so can I attack again?
MATT: You can use your action now to do something
else. Only a bonus action can do that. So now you
have your action. You could hit with your spear,
or you could do another spell if you wanted to.
TRAVIS: Now it's 20? (singing) Living on a
prayer!
WILL: He's going to pick my ass up and throw me
somewhere.
MATT: You still have your action. What are you
going to do?
WILL: But I could also run back to my guardian.
MATT: You could, yeah. He'll get an attack on you
if you run.
WILL: I think I'm going to have to hit him with my
spear, which has six points of nec on it, right?
Yeah, let's do that.
MATT: All right, roll 2d20, adding ten to each
hit. So go ahead. I'm sorry, adding nine.
WILL: 18.
MATT: Roll again.
WILL: Four.
MATT: Yeah, so you hit it. The damage hits. I need
you to make another constitution saving throw. DC
of 20, buddy.
TRAVIS: That won't do it. That's a 14.
MATT: (chuckles) How do you want to do this?
(yelling)
TRAVIS: Wait, don't I get saving throws and
stuff?!
MATT: Well, in theory, he could finish you off
next round.
TRAVIS: (stammering) All right.
MARY: Severe allergies.
TRAVIS: That's true. Severe allergies.
WILL: So is this a straight-up attack with the
spear?
MATT: This is your dark spear, the Shadow Spear.
WILL: So he walks over to Grog standing in front
of him, and he looks him up and down. You are the
biggest individual I've ever faced in my life. See
ya! Right through the chest!
MATT: As the Shadow Spear pierces the front of
your unarmored chest, it goes sticking out the
back of your torso. At that moment, you can see
his eyes go dark once again as the spear itself
sends this cold wave through your body, the
necrotic enchantment on the spear sucking the life
from you. You watch as Grog reaches out, grabbing
it, but his muscles wither and atrophy within a
matter of seconds, his face going sallow, his
entire life force drained into the spear as you
withdraw it from his body. The now extremely
malnourished, shriveled body of Grog crumples to
the ground with a cracking sound of bones against
stone. You hear in the back of your head, now, a
voice that says, "You've proven yourself worthy.
Lift me. Become my new master."
WILL: Can Kash do something here?
MATT: Yeah.
WILL: He reaches down, picks up the blade, and
says, I've already had one dark master. Throws it
in the pit.
MATT: (blade spinning through air, impact)
I need you to roll another death saving
throw.
MARY: Two.
MATT: Two. And with that, you hear in the distance
this small (exhale).
(laughter)
MATT: As the last of Zahra's life force expires
and her body disappears.
WILL: There can be only one!
MATT: There was a slight chance you would have
rolled a 20, and it would've been great if you
woke up and went--
TRAVIS: What are you at?
WILL: 43.
MARY: No, he would've taken me out.
WILL: 48.
TRAVIS: Man. You're sitting pretty.
MARISHA: Wow.
(cheering)
MARY: That was amazing.
WILL: That is ridiculously exhilarating. It was
cool.
MARY: So much fun! Thank you.
MATT: Well done, guys. That was really
interesting.
TRAVIS: You all wake up in your bed and go,
(gasps). Oh man.
MARISHA: I had a terrible dream! You were there,
and you were there, and you were there.
MARY: And you weren't there, but I felt you there,
and you were evil.
MARISHA: I hope I never get on Grog's shit list.
WILL: I though you were going to chuck me into the
pit.
MARISHA: Oh, by one point.
TRAVIS: I thought you were lower. I should have
done another grapple check, but hey.
MATT: It's okay.
MARISHA: And the maiden voyage of the Dwarven
Forge.
MARY: Yeah.
MARISHA: It looks so great.
WILL: Kittens and popcorn!
MATT: I'll remember to bring my proper minis next
time.
MARY: Keyleth should feel very complimented that
we felt the need to take you out first.
WILL: Talk about coming in swinging. My god.
MARISHA: Falling through the sky as a dead bird.
MATT: So yeah, the pit, if anyone would have
fallen in there-- you saw the texture in the
bottom-- it was a cluster of undead that would
grab and pull down and devour. Every single turn,
you'd have to roll to try and get out of the
grasp. If not, you'd be restrained and be taking
3d10 points of damage every turn.
MARY: Isn't there a spell that lets us control
undead?
MATT: There are spells like that, yeah.
WILL: I have a question, because one of the things
I was going to do, but then it looked like I
wasn't going to be able to-- if you take control
of a creature, you can't then have them do
something that will commit suicide, right? So I
couldn't have taken control of Grog and gone: jump
in the pit.
MARISHA: Well, is jump in the pit considered
suicidal?
MATT: Which spell is this?
WILL: Geas.
MARY: What if you suggested to him, Grog, I saw a
cask of ale down in the pit. Go get it!
TRAVIS: I'd jump in there after that.
MARISHA: I want to get into some Kilgrave shit.
MATT: Geas isn't a direct-- you don't command them
to do a specific action; you tell them to complete
this task for you and they're compelled to do it
and if they resist it they take damage. The moment
you send someone on a suicidal impact, the spell
immediately breaks.
MARISHA: But would "Hey, explore the bottom of
this pit" be considered a suicidal action?
WILL: You still know you're sending him to a
suicidal mission, though, right? So wouldn't that
essentially break the spell?
MATT: Possibly, but you could be like, "hey, I
need you to focus your attacks on Zahra," then he
could choose to do that or try to resist it and
take the psychic damage.
MARY: Could I have used Mass Suggestion to go:
"Guys, there's ale or something in the pit. Go
"find it."
MATT: It would've been a hard sell. With a really
low saving throw roll, a player could have been
compelled to lose a round to inspect, but it
wouldn't have been like "Yeah, sure!" and then
dove in.
WILL: Man, that was fun.
TRAVIS: That was really great.
MATT: Also, don't forget to check your casting
times, as well. I don't know what the Geas casting
time is.
WILL: Casting time's one minute.
MATT: Yeah, that would not be a combat spell.
Every round in combat is six seconds, so that
would have been a spell you could do outside of
combat.
MARISHA: What spell?
MATT: Geas.
MARISHA: Oh, right.
TRAVIS: Nicely done, Matt. Nicely done, Kashaw!
(applause)
WILL: I'm just a healer!
TRAVIS: I guess you can put one more notch on that
arm now.
WILL: Hitting the deck, though. My god. Mittens.
TRAVIS: El gato es diablo.
MATT: Cool. So yeah, depending on if some point
down the road, we have the opportunity, like the
break after a major story arc when we run another
one of these games, but with the entire Vox
Machina party, which would be fun. That would be a
ways off, but you saw this was fun to do. We'll
try that sometime.
WILL: I'd like to think as reigning champion I'd
be allowed to come back to defend my title.
MARY: You can think that as long as you'd like.
TRAVIS: We'll free up our own Summer Slam.
(laughter)
WILL: Oh, that's awesome.
MATT: And a great example of the power of warlocks
being nasty, the survivability of barbarians being
ridiculous, although it was you versus three magic
casters, which was not a good fight, but even
so--
TRAVIS: I was getting blasted.
MATT: And even so, it came down to quite literally
one roll, because if that hadn't taken you out,
that last spear hit, if you would have survived
that saving throw, you would have had three
attacks on him next round, and with great weapon
master, two of them would have taken him down.
WILL: Crazy powerful stuff. Running away is really
helpful at times. Sometimes, concession is the
better part of valor.
TRAVIS: Black tentacles.
WILL: Holding him there.
MARY: My suggestion to Travis was two of you both
jump into the pit, and then I lose my saving throw
and nobody wins!
(laughter)
WILL: It's just that voice going, "Guys?"
MATT: That's amazing. Guys, thank you so much for
coming.
MARY: Feel better, Laura and Liam.
MATT: Yeah, seriously. There will be no actual
session here. Me and Marisha will be out of town;
we're going to be at Kazuku Con in Cork,
Ireland. See you guys there. There will be no
show. There'll be stuff going on. They'll have
content here that they're going to decide on who to
show here, so keep an eye on the social media
platform to tell you what to look forward to in
our slot next week, and we will return for the
next session of Vox Machina's adventures on March
9th.
MARISHA: Do we have any giveaways that we need to
announce? Giveaway winners?
MARY: We have so much stuff to give away.
MARISHA: I know, there was so much stuff to give
away.
RYAN: Yeah, let's do a giveaway.
MARISHA: Yeah, sure. Giveaway.
WILL: You've got the Brandon Sanderson books.
MARISHA: Brandon Sanderson books and nail wraps.
RYAN: We were so enthralled with this that we
forgot to do our jobs.
(laughter)
WILL: That's when you know it's a good game! That
was really cool.
MARISHA: What was the book called, again?
TRAVIS: Two nuclear clouds. (explosion) Oh, that
sucked. Shit! (explosion)
WILL: It wasn't until the last move that I was
like, "Oh, right. I'm carrying a spear."
MARISHA: I feel like it was that scene in Sleepy
Hollow in the end, where the lighthouse is on
fire, then Grog walks out of it. That's what I
envision.
WILL: The last one was awesome.
MATT: All right, so you guys jump in there to see
if we have a winner here momentarily. I can see
you guys being active in there, which is awesome.
MARISHA: Be active! Check out The Bands of
Mourning. And Espionage Cosmetics! They have nerdy
makeup. Nerd makeup. It's a thing.
MATT, MARISHA, and MARY: You guys.
MARY: I really wanted to make Keyleth my willing
zombie slave.
MARISHA: That would have been really cool.
MARY: If I'd killed her with Finger of Death, she
would've come back as my zombie slave.
TRAVIS: You're dark, sister. I like it.
MARISHA: That took me down half my hit points.
MARY: Also what?
WILL: She also knits!
MARY and TRAVIS: Crochet!
MARY: Yes, lots of crochet.
WILL: Man, that was fun. When's the last time you
played as a player?
MATT: D&D?
WILL: Yeah.
MATT: A friend of mine, Matt Colville, who's the
writer for Evolve at Turtle Rock Studios, he had
me and Marisha and Liam and our friend Frieda down
to play a one-shot down at his studio back in
September.
WILL: Was that fun to not have to worry--
MATT: It was great! I missed that.
MARY: What were you?
MATT: I was a tiefling paladin. Oath of Vengeance,
named Marduun. It was fun.
TRAVIS: Oath of Vengeance named Marduun?
MATT: Paladins choose oaths as their variations,
and I was Oath of Vengeance. It was fun. That was
the last time, the only time I've played a player
character in D&D in years.
WILL: That must be fun.
MARISHA: Do we have a winner?
TRAVIS: Do we have a name? What?
MARY: I have no idea. Corbin? Corbin? Ow! It
hurts!
WILL: It's always something! A bomb, or something!
I mean it.
(laughter)
WILL: Corbin. Corbin!
MARY: I quit smoking. I have no fire!
MARISHA: This is pretty great fan art that came
out recently.
MARY: Is it Mittens?
MARISHA: It's all of us as the characters sitting
around a table.
MARY: Oh my god, that's amazing! Wendy, you're in
this.
WENDY: Oh my god!
MARISHA: I'll show it to Travis.
MARY: Who drew it?
MARISHA: It was--
WILL and MARY: It was the dukes!
MARISHA: @blupervillain. Diepod Travers.
MARY: Well, hey, @blupervillain. Thank you.
MATT: @blupervillain made an awesome art piece of
our table arrangement in here. You guys should
check it out. It's awesome. Well done. All right!
MARISHA: Do we have a winner of the Brandon
Sanderson book?
RYAN: Almost.
TRAVIS: Almost? Stretch. You've got to go, right?
MARY: I've got to go.
WILL: Check out the shirt! Now taste Mittens.
RYAN: A-K-A-Y-E-S.
MATT: Akayes. A-K-Y? A-K-A-Y-E-S. You are the
winner of the giveaway at the end of the show
tonight. Congratulations.
MARISHA: Critical Hit and book and maybe a few
other things. I don't know. There's always a
hodgepodge in the giveaways.
RYAN: We'll do the next one a big Critical Role
giveaway. We've got the book and Espionage
nailpacks and other stuff.
MARISHA: Cool. I'll bring it back.
WILL: When I'm done reading it.
MATT: All right, guys. Thank you so much for
coming and watching. We'll see you in two weeks.
Tune in next week to see what they have to fill
the slot for us. It should be a lot of fun. Yeah.
MARISHA: Yeah!
MARY: Yay!
MARISHA: Bye, guys!