MATT: Welcome to tonight's episode of Critical
Role, where a bunch of us nerdy-ass voice actors
sit around and play Dungeons and Dragons. This
evening, we're about to dive into our final game
of the year before we go away for the holidays,
and then return in the new year to begin our new
campaign. So tonight, instead, we're going to have
the members of Vox Machina who could be here--
unfortunately, Ashley is still in New York. Laura
is busy being at the Video Game Awards because she
was nominated for Best Actress. So we're sending
all the awesome, positive thoughts her way and
wishing her luck. And we all knew Vex was going to
go out in the first half anyway. That's not true.
But we miss you, Laura. We do have a sponsor
tonight. We have, for this fantastic episode,
Marvel Puzzle Quest returns to sponsor an episode.
Thank you so much, Marvel Puzzle Quest! Sam?
SAM: Guys, for the sponsorship opportunity, I know
that I have this habit of doing a bit, doing some
comedy at the top of the show, and it's all funny
and clever and brilliant and all that. But today,
I'm just going to do it serious. This is a serious
sponsor and they need our serious, unadulterated
attention. So I'm just going to read the copy, I
swear to god. Okay. Our sponsor tonight is Marvel
Puzzle Quest. Recruit all your favorite Avengers,
from Black Panther, Captain America, (fart noise)
Iron Man, The Hulk (fart noise), Black Widow, and
more! (extended fart) Create a super-villain dream
team and recruit Infinity Gauntlet-wielding Thanos
to wage your own war! (excessive fart noises) Mix
and match to create the ultimate team of three,
and battle it out in Match Three War! (squeaky fart)
Marvel Puzzle Quest is available on iOS,
Android, Amazon, and Steam. Download it now for
free. (so many fart noises)
MATT: God, Sam, holy shit.
SAM: I just read the copy!
MARISHA: Your own joke broke you.
TALIESIN: What episode is this?! How many episodes
did it take to finally get to this?
TRAVIS: Marvel Puzzle Quest gets the best stuff.
MATT: We have officially hit that level in our
game.
TALIESIN: We have steamed the shark.
LIAM: You've got to be careful. Marvel Marketing
is going to start stealing from your bucket of
tricks. We're going to see trailers with farts.
MATT: All righty. So let's see. Other
announcements? We have a quick one tonight, I
think.
MARISHA: There's the charity stream with Satine on
Saturday. The Roll20 dealio that she's doing is
this Saturday, all-day D&amp;D for charity.
MATT: This is actually a continuation of a charity
event that Satine's been running for years, where
me and her first played D&amp;D together years ago.
She asked me to be a charity DM and me and Keith
Baker ran games at Meltdown, years ago. So it's an
awesome group, awesome games. Please check it out.
Support it if you can.
MARISHA: That was the early days of streaming RPGs
online, before it was a thing.
MATT: Yeah, it was rough. But it was fun. It was a
good time. So yeah, check that out. Next Thursday
will be our big wrap-up. We've been asking
questions of the community. There's been a lot of
really great questions. So we got through as many
as we possibly can for this episode next Thursday
to answer a lot of questions about the campaign,
the world, things that went unanswered,
curiosities that you may have been holding on to.
The ones that we didn't get to, we might carry
over into the first week of the new year or
something. We'll figure it out. We want to get
through as many of these as we can, but we have a
large bulk of them coming to you next Thursday in
this time slot. So check it out next week! Let's
see. Any other announcements you guys want to
bring up?
TRAVIS: Laura would pull my lower lip over my head
if I didn't say that the beautiful Critical Role
notebook is in the merch store. It's gorgeous. I
don't hold it up and Vanna White it as nice as she
does, but it's in there. Laura and I will be at
SacAnime in Sacramento the first week of January.
January 5th through the 7th, I think it is. We'll
be in Sacramento.
MATT: Also, me and Marisha are both happy to be
hosting with the folks who make Gwent. If you're
familiar with the Witcher, they have their own
card game.
LIAM: You don't like Witcher, though.
MATT: Yeah, I'm not a fan. But we're helping host
their upcoming Gwent tournament next weekend,
Friday and Saturday. I can't really say the
specifics of it because they're going to announce
it on their own time, but it's going to be fun.
Somewhere in the Europes. But yes, we'll be there.
We'll have information on our Twitters and social
media if you want to follow and check out both
Gwent. We're streaming tomorrow morning, actually,
our last stream of us getting prepped, and we're
meeting with a bunch of guys in the community that
are showing us the ins and outs of some of the
factions and decks. So if you're like us and up
early tomorrow on Twitch, we'll be there. We'll
figure out all of the information on Twitter. All
right. Anything else, guys?
TALIESIN: Did podcast get updated, or did that not
happen? It may not have.
MARISHA: It's coming.
TALIESIN: Comic book issue three is available.
It's beautiful. And there's now two playlists out
because I didn't announce my playlist last week.
Percy's playlist went out and now there's a Vex
podcast.
MARISHA: I'm working on it. I started writing
today.
TRAVIS: I don't have one because it was going to
be all death metal, followed with nursery rhymes.
TALIESIN: I would like to know what kind of death
metal you're into.
TRAVIS: Technonic.
MARISHA: Also, big deal. This is a big one.
Talking about merch. This is a true story. We
found a bunch of extra David Mack posters that we
autographed and signed as hold-over, in case
anything was damaged or shipping was messed up.
Yeah, in case life happened. So we signed about a
hundred extra and we magically found them the
other day. So your last chance--
SAM: Can you tell me where we found them?
MARISHA: It was somewhere, I think, literally in
the boiler room.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I was about to say, it was
probably the boiler room because that's where shit
goes and vanishes. We are kind of a mess on
occasion, this is true.
MARISHA: No, we're a web company. We wouldn't be a
mess.
MATT: Individually and as a collective fumbling
our way through existence day to day.
MARISHA: But anyway, they are in the store right
now. This is your last chance. If you're like, "Oh
"no, I saw them!" But only a hundred-- and they're
gone. So yeah, last-minute Christmas present for
anyone who was looking for something.
LIAM: Marisha and I came out in another episode of
Madness. Some more improvised gameplay with
blocks.
MARISHA: If you're not watching it, holy crap. Go
watch it.
MATT: Awesome. All right. I believe that brings us
to the conclusion of our announcements. And
finishing that up, let's bring us to tonight's
special Level 20 Battle Royale episode of Critical
Role.
[dramatic music]
MATT: Welcome back, as apparently Sam transformed
into his ultimate, final form.
SAM: The King of Egos.
MATT: How many is this?
TALIESIN: It's Sams all the way down.
SAM: There are six pictures of me, plus me, so
that's seven. Lucky seven.
MATT: Seven Sams, that's your name for the night.
Seventh Sam-urai. So folks. Not long--
SAM: Wait a second. You're doing a story? I
thought we were just going to kill each other!
MATT: There's a narrative.
TALIESIN: Let him paint his picture.
LIAM: Have you met Matt?
MATT: Not long before you finish your preparations
for the final battle with Vecna, you all spent an
evening going to rest with unease and as sleep
took you, a vision fills your mind. Groggily you
come to, wiping the insides of your eyelids,
trying to find some means of grasping the scenario
around you. As unfamiliar smells of stale water
and crushed stone begin to fill your sinuses, the
light blearing into your vision, you slowly focus
to look around you and find a strange assortment
of structures in the vicinity. And there above
you, cracking through the clouds with a thunderous
boom, you see a cloaked figure descend from the
heavens, hands held aloft, palms up to the sky as
bolts of energy arc around its form. As it slowly
drifts, hovering above this central tower, the
sconces of flame below burning with embers that
drift up with the wind and vanish. The cloaked
figure spins around, revealing the face beneath
the hood, a well groomed, beautiful, familiar
beard and his perfectly combed hair.
SAM: Oh, I feel better now.
MATT: One side of his body contains unique armor
with a series of spines of metal seemingly
protruding into his arm, as if to keep it in
place.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Amazing.
MATT: As he spins around, making eye contact with
the five of you members of Vox Machina, his voice
billows out, "You've come again. And here you are,
and since you're here I think it's time that you
"show me what you've got. Show me what you've got!"
With a thunderous clap he vanishes. You see a
singular column of green energy left behind where
he stood, that now rests upon the top of the
pillar. You watch as these two disparate towers on
two ends of the battlefield begin to slowly spin
as energy crackles throughout them. You look
around the field for any sort of view of your
opponents and all you see are your friends, and
you know in that moment that this is another
challenge from the Great Colville, to show who
amongst you is most powerful.
MARISHA: Not again.
LIAM: But if we know that in advance.
MATT: His voice cracks out from the heavens, "Roll
initiative."
MARISHA: Wait, do we have time to precast?
LIAM: No.
MARISHA: To do like a little--
LIAM: Take your precast and shove it in your ass,
Keyleth.
SAM: Like you need something else.
LIAM: You need an edge on us all?
MARISHA: Yes, I do! It's not my fault that my
character's awesome.
LIAM: Using my first luck of the day at the top.
SAM: Can I inspire myself on this roll? I forget,
it's an ability check.
MATT: It's an ability check, yeah.
SAM: I will inspire myself.
MARISHA: Can I give myself an inspiring leader
speech?
MATT: No.
LIAM: That's ten minutes.
MARISHA: Come on, you got this, come on, come on.
You can do this, you can do this.
LIAM: I'm one luck down.
SAM: One inspiration down.
MATT: I'm checking real fast here, hold onto your
numbers for a moment.
LIAM: In my luck box. One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven.
SAM: Wait, wait, that's too many.
(laughter)
MATT: Which can include yourself.
SAM: Shit, I forget what Mythcarver does.
TRAVIS: You've used it twice!
MATT: I'll put it this way, does everybody have
something they wish to prepare before the battle?
TRAVIS: I would like to rage.
MATT: And as a note, whatever potions that you had
on yourself that are healing potions, are out of
this battle, as you check your contents of your
pockets.
TRAVIS: I mean, not really. I want to rage, that's
it.
TALIESIN: The only thing I can think to do is I
would want to already have my Boots of Spider
Climbing activated and my Diplomacy charged.
MARISHA: How about, instead of a speech, can I
cast Freedom of Movement on myself?
MATT: Sure.
LIAM and MATT: Wings are already out.
TRAVIS: Do you want to cast freedom of movement on
me?
TALIESIN: We get to pose before the battle right?
MARISHA: I think I'm the only one here, I don't
know, I can't.
MATT: As you take in the gravity of the situation you
can see a small sparkle around you as a
containment field marks the exterior of this
battlefield both around and roughly 80 to 100 feet
in the air.
TRAVIS: 80 to 100 feet?
MATT: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Find out the hard way.
TRAVIS: I won't. I ain't going up there.
MATT: Initiative orders. 25 to 20.
SAM: (laughing) Everybody.
TRAVIS: Oh, wow.
SAM: Everybody but Kiki.
SAM: 21!
MARISHA: I rolled pretty good, too.
TRAVIS: 20.
TALIESIN: 24.
MATT: All right, so we have currently Percy at 24,
Scanlan at 21, Grog at 20.
LIAM: 19.
MARISHA: Also 19.
LIAM: Oh, fuck you. Give it to me. She doesn't
need it.
MARISHA: Bullshit! Bullshit! Fucking Mr. Sneak
Attack!
LIAM: (laughing) What are you talking about? You
are the clear winner of this game!
MARISHA: Don't say that! I've lost all of them!
MATT: I would like you both, right now, to roll a
dexterity check. Roll a d20, add your dexterity
modifier.
TALIESIN: He may have to burn another luck.
LIAM: Nope.
MARISHA: Just my modifier, my straight modifier?
MATT: Yep. Because technically you're on the same
initiative, but I can't have you doing your
actions at the exact same time. This is to see
who's slightly faster.
MARISHA: I rolled a 15, for 17 total.
LIAM: 32, motherfucker.
SAM: Jesus! That's your wife!
MATT: Wait. How'd you get 32?
LIAM: I rolled a 19, my dex is a 13.
MARISHA: That's your saving throw.
MATT: That's your saving throw, it's a dexterity
check.
LIAM: Still higher than you.
MATT: Still higher.
LIAM: 19. It's a saving throw?
MATT: No, it's just an ability check.
LIAM: Oh, okay.
MATT: You're fine, you beat Keyleth.
MARISHA: Learn your character sheet,
motherfucker!
(laughing)
MATT: So there is a burst of speed and Vax is ever
so faster than Keyleth. His dextrous capabilities
edge her out of the initiative order, so Keyleth,
you're taking up the rear.
MARISHA: I was so stoked about my 17.
MATT: I know. With that, as those two towers are
currently crackling, Percival, it's your turn.
TALIESIN: Wow, it's been a while.
SAM: I don't know how to play this character
anymore. I've totally forgotten everything I can
do.
MARISHA: This is the last time we're going to play
these characters.
TALIESIN: I'm going to run into this room and I
want to see what's inside this building.
MATT: All right. So you rush around. That's about
as far as you get with your movement. Looking
inside, you see a large cluster of sigils carved
into the ground with crystals sticking out and
it's this low pulsing purple energy. Make a
perception check, actually.
TALIESIN: All right.
LIAM: Castlevania teleport mode.
TALIESIN: 23.
MATT: 23. You notice a small groove of similar
pulsing kind of purplish-blue energy that runs
from the circle and out of the chamber, which is
this line here. And then you also barely see on
the edge what appears to be an archway, a door
that is built that has a slight shifting barrier
of mist where the archway is.
TALIESIN: I'm going to spend the rest of my action
moving into the archway of mist.
MATT: You move into the archway?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: Okay, and with that you move here.
TALIESIN: How much movement do I have left?
MATT: That's where it puts you.
TALIESIN: All right.
MATT: And having revealed those two elements of
the battlefield. Going to leave those two open for
the time, but there is a roof up there about ten
feet tall. End of your turn?
TALIESIN: Mm-hmm.
MATT: Okay. Scanlan, you're up.
TALIESIN: You don't see me.
SAM: I'm going to turn invisible.
MATT: Okay, you cast Invisibility on yourself.
That's your action.
SAM: And I'm going to pick a direction to run in.
I don't see anybody. I'm going to pick a random
direction. That's right. I'm going to run to the
right. Is this a door that I can get in?
MATT: That is currently a door.
SAM: Currently a door?
MATT: Meaning it is a door.
SAM: I'll run over that way. I only go 25 feet. Or
25 things.
TALIESIN and MATT: 25.
SAM: And bonus action I can't dash, right, no?
MATT: No. You're not a rogue, buddy, no. Sorry.
SAM: I don't know. I've never dashed!
(laughter)
MATT: However, you are currently considered
invisible.
TALIESIN: Do you have a thingy for that? I have a
cake.
MATT: It's been a few weeks since we played and I
left my markers at home. But that's okay. That
cake means you're invisible. It's an invisibility
cake. All right, finishing Scanlan's turn. Grog,
you're up.
TRAVIS: Raging, can I run around the side of the
tower that's closest to you towards the door of
this little Superman shaped-- yep.
MATT: 30, you're at the door.
TRAVIS: Can I use siege to knock the fucking door
open?
MATT: Go ahead and make an attack against the
door.
SAM: Are we hearing things? Can we hear the crack
of wood?
TRAVIS: 20.
MATT: 20, go ahead and roll damage. You now hear a
thunderous roar, Grog's voice billowing out from
the air not too far from you across a moat-like
pond of clear water that surrounds the vicinity of
the central tower. With a smashing sound, you see
wood splinter off into the air.
TRAVIS: A d4 for the fit hands or with the axe?
MATT: With the axe.
TRAVIS: Oh, shit balls ass, sorry. Nope, that's a
ten. Eight plus--
MATT: This is the Bloodaxe?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: Bloodaxe is a d12.
TRAVIS: It is, right, I was using the sword before
that.
MATT: Yeah, d12. What did you roll?
TRAVIS: That's an eight on both of them, plus--
Sorry, been a hot minute. 23.
MATT: 23, double eight? Yeah, the door is
destroyed. It's blown inside, the hinges kind of
(squeaking sound) and what little bit of the door
still remains kind of breaks off and slams into
the ground, and revealing the interior of this
chamber, the door now open. It is empty except for
a singular chest sitting in the far corner from
you.
TRAVIS: Do I have any movement left? What did I
end on, 40?
MATT: That was 30, you still have 20 feet of
movement.
TRAVIS: Can I make my way to the chest?
MATT: Yes you can.
TRAVIS: And it's not a bonus action to open said
chest, right?
MATT: Nope, that would be an action.
TRAVIS: I'll stay in my room!
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: Can I shut the door-- the door's gone.
(laughter)
MATT: At this point, both of the towers-- the
sparking energy arcs outward and nobody's in the
vicinity, so no worries there.
SAM: Oh boy!
MATT: You watch as energy sparks offward and hits
the other structures nearby and then eventually
pulls back into the towers and the glow is slowly
building once more. Vax, you're up.
LIAM: Okay, I am sending you something. I'm going
to use a bonus action to hide.
MATT: Okay, roll a stealth check, please.
LIAM: Sure. Nobody can see me, right?
MATT: Not at the moment.
LIAM: Okay, that is a 27.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: Here it comes to you. And I've charted this
right, I think.
MATT: You're on deck, Keyleth.
SAM: Are we playing Battleship now? Are you
sending him moves? Is this what's happening?
LIAM: Yes.
MATT: Okay, Vax vanishes into the shadows of the
field. Let's see here.
LIAM: Feel me?
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: Okay.
MATT: That your turn?
LIAM: Oh, shite. Yes it is.
MATT: Okay, ends Vax's turn, Keyleth, you're up.
MARISHA: Hey, question, clarification on
blindsight?
MATT: Yes?
MARISHA: I was going to look it up. You're blind
but you can still see through you being awesome?
MATT: Is this in reference to a creature?
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: Blindsight means that they either don't use
their eyes to see and as such Blind doesn't affect
them.
TRAVIS: Oh, like the worms and stuff.
MATT: Yeah. Creatures without eyes, such as
grimlocks, grey oozes, either it's naturally blind
and can see without having to use the eyes or if
it's ever blinded it doesn't affect it.
MARISHA: Okay, so I wouldn't be able to see
through Scanlan's Invisibility with blindsight.
MATT: Not with blindsight, with tremor sense you
would still feel him running across.
MARISHA: That's what I was getting clarification
on. I am going to cast Sunbeam at 6th level,
and--
MATT: Where are you casting it?
MARISHA: Sunbeam. Myself.
MATT: Right. It creates a beam when you cast it.
MARISHA: As an action I get to create a beam,
right?
MATT: Correct, but when you initially cast it you
create a beam so if you want to fire at wherever
and it's gone, that's fine.
MARISHA: Okay. Well then, how about this? I want
to peek around this corner over here.
SAM: My tremor sense hears her moving.
MARISHA: Do I see Percy?
MATT: Yeah, you very plainly see Percy.
MARISHA: Okay, then I'm going to do Sunbeam.
TALIESIN: That'll do.
MATT: All right. First blood. Other than the door.
Which, to be fair, is the most Vox Machina opening
thing to destroy.
TRAVIS: This is for 115 episodes, you bitch!
MARISHA: Did I destroy the door? Is that what
you're saying?
MATT: No, Travis did earlier.
TRAVIS: You didn't destroy everything!
MARISHA: Sorry, I checked out.
(laughter)
MATT: All right, Percy, I need you to make a
constitution saving throw, please.
TALIESIN: Constitution saving throw. This is
magical, isn't it?
MATT: Yes, it is.
TALIESIN: So I get advantage on this.
MATT: You do.
MARISHA: Is that versus my spell level?
MATT: Yep, your spell DC.
TALIESIN: What's your spell DC? Oh, okay,
constitution saving throw.
MARISHA: It's pretty high.
TALIESIN: 25.
MATT: 25, I think that saves.
MARISHA: That hits, so you are not blinded but you
do still take the damage.
TALIESIN: How much damage?
MATT: Half as much damage.
MARISHA: Half as much. 6d8 radiant. (counting) 33
damage total.
MATT: 33 damage. Half that. You take 16 points of
radiant damage.
TALIESIN: I'll take 16 points of radiant damage.
MARISHA: And then I use my bonus action to turn
into an earth elemental. I still have a little bit
of movement, right?
MATT: You do.
MARISHA: I'm going to use the rest of my movement
to peek back around there.
SAM: How big is that thing?
MATT: It's considered a large creature.
SAM: Is it taller than the roof?
MATT: No. Because about ten feet tall, it's about
as tall as the roof. But you do see Keyleth come
out of the side, blast a Sunbeam-- Your line of
sight over there, you barely see her rush around
the corner, fire this beam of energy, and then
(whooshing) into an elemental and then curl around
the way.
SAM: Nice! Just going to crack my knuckles then.
MATT: Ending Keyleth's turn, Percy you're up.
TALIESIN: I'm going to hop right back through that
door, and take a right out that door and start
heading back out that-- yeah, right there, and
then I'm going to use the rest of my-- to cast
Silence. I'm casting my silence ball, I am now
completely quiet.
SAM: Except for tremor sense.
TRAVIS: Where'd he go?
MATT: You don't know where he went.
TRAVIS: Oh, he's off the map? Oh, there he is.
(laughter)
MATT: So Percy has Silence on him, Scanlan, you're
up.
SAM: Okay. Shoot! I saw her. (to Marisha) I saw
you!
MARISHA: I saw you!
SAM: Let's see here, 25 feet gets me to either
here or here, right?
MATT: I mean, 25 would put you-- almost.
SAM: But I can't get somewhere where I can see
her.
MATT: Not at the moment, it doesn't look like. You
know where she went, but you don't see her.
SAM: As I walk, I will try that door, see if it
opens. Does it open?
MATT: You walk up to the door, and you're going to
try it?
SAM: Yeah.
MATT: No, it's locked.
SAM: Then I'm going to keep going and get to
here.
TALIESIN: That's as far as you can go.
SAM: You said 20!
MATT: 25.
TALIESIN: Five, ten, 15, 20, 25. To the door.
SAM: I thought you said I could get to either here
or here!
MATT: Little gnome feet.
SAM: Okay, I will use my action to cast Minor
Illusion and it's going to be Scanlan's voice
coming from right here behind where she can't see,
singing a little song.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: Minor Illusion I don't think is
concentration, right? It just says one action.
MATT: Do be aware--
LIAM: Heads up guys, my only chance of surviving
to the halfway mark of this game--
MATT: Invisibility ends when you cast a spell.
SAM: Oh, when you cast any spell.
MATT: Any spell.
SAM: Ugh, shit, I always do this!
MATT: I know.
LIAM: My only chance of survival to the halfway
mark is hiding, so Matt and I will be doing a
little bit of texting this evening so I can
telegraph my moves until somebody spots me.
TRAVIS: Totally dick pics, right?
LIAM: Yeah-- no! That's crazy!
MARISHA: Right under the table. Live dick pics.
SAM: Then I will save my action until I see
someone, I guess.
MATT: What are you holding your action then?
SAM: No! No, sorry Matt! Sorry! I'm new to this
game! I'm going to use my action to dash, right? I
get more movement!
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: I go back here.
TALIESIN: Five, ten, 15, 20, 25!
SAM: Out of sight of her.
MARISHA: Do I get any--
MATT: Does your earth elemental have tremor sense?
Make a perception check.
SAM: Yes, yes, it's all happening.
MARISHA: 15 total.
MATT: 15?
MARISHA: No, 16. That makes a difference.
SAM: Do I make a stealth check or something?
MATT: No, because you went your full movement, so
yeah, no. She senses you.
SAM: Okay. Does she have pinpoint accuracy or just
know the general direction?
TRAVIS: She's made of earth.
MATT: She has a pretty good idea. So you don't see
him and as you're looking around you sense the
ground (footsteps). Something's there. Something
just moved behind that other building.
MARISHA: Feels like about 45 pounds. Oh, sorry, 75
pounds. Four-foot five... That seems tall.
TRAVIS: I don't have the deck, by the way. No
deck.
TALIESIN: I would hope so.
TRAVIS: Why? I mean, technically it's before the
Vecna fight but it didn't make the portal.
MATT: From a story, it's before because I needed a
reason for Vax to still be there, but I wanted to
make sure that everything was there. Yeah, tremor
sense, 60 feet. Yeah. All right, so that ends
Scanlan's turn.
SAM: She knows where I am?
MATT: You don't know that. You're like, "Aw, I'm
so slick! Nobody knows where I am!" She's like--
"There." All right, and finishing Scanlan's turn,
Grog. At this moment, the energy in those two
circles begin to (vibrating). Percival, you glance
over the back of your shoulder and you see a burst
of bluish-purple energy fill the entire chamber.
MARISHA: The inside circles?
MATT: Inside this entire room fills purple. It
washes past you. You feel warm but no damage,
nothing.
TRAVIS: Nothing?
MARISHA: I don't trust that.
TALIESIN: Can I say, Woo, that was close! Do I
hear myself?
MATT: Yes.
TALIESIN: Damn it! Fuck!
TRAVIS and MARISHA: Oh no!
MATT: And that's all you saw.
TALIESIN: Well, that makes life a little more
complicated.
MATT: Grog, your turn.
TRAVIS: All my spells. Can I open le chest du
mysterie?
MATT: You may. You use your action to open the
chest and reach inside. You get yourself a Potion
of Superior Healing.
TRAVIS: Yes, sweet. Great. I have my full
movement, right? Can I come out of the room and
start making my way toward this area?
MATT: Sure. 50 is about right here.
TRAVIS: That sounds great. And this is a solid
column? There's no way in there?
MATT: It is solid, but there's no roof on it. It's
an open cylinder, almost like a small cylindrical
bunker. It's about six feet tall.
TRAVIS: Okay, so you could--
MATT: Yeah, you could use it for cover or use it
to hide. The other ones, though, with the towers
on top, are solid. Even though they have windows
there, imagine those have no entry. They're just a
platform for the towers generating electricity.
Does that end your turn, Grog? All right, that
brings us to Vax.
LIAM: Well, you didn't-- I asked a very specific
question and I need an answer. Yeah. Before I can
make a call.
MATT: All right. There are stairs that spiral up.
LIAM: Aw, great. Thanks.
SAM: I've never seen someone so disappointed at
stairs before.
MARISHA: We've got an idea of where he is.
LIAM: Yeah, that's why I threw the phone down.
MATT: I'm sorry. This works for a certain point
before I'm like, all right.
LIAM: I know, I know. That's my magic power. Some
people turn into monsters, some people hide.
SAM: Your magic power is your wit.
LIAM: All right, hold on. I'm doing my fucking
move!
TRAVIS: Wait a minute. If you die, do you come
back 30 minutes later, naked, out of the woods?
MATT: 24 hours, yeah. But he still loses the
Battle Royale.
MARISHA: I was going to say, does he win the
battle? Just waits?
TRAVIS: Walks out naked. Lord Colville is like, "I
am pleased."
LIAM: Coming at you. Okay, that's what I'm doing.
MATT: Okay, got you. All right, that ends Vax's
turn. Keyleth, you're up.
MARISHA: Oh, shit. I want to go, hm. Bink, bink.
Oh hey, Scanlan! (laser noise)
MATT: You're going to Sunbeam the gnome?
MARISHA: I'm going to Sunbeam the gnome.
MATT: Scanlan, as you're sitting there hiding--
SAM: She cannot see me.
MATT: This giant earth elemental comes around the
corner, that you know to be Keyleth, and looks in
the general space you are and fires a beam in the
direction where you are. And it's wide
enough to hit you. So you gather, in that brief
moment before you get completely enveloped by
burning, radiant energy, "Oh shit, she knows where
I am." Make a constitution saving throw, please.
SAM: Can I Counterspell that?
MATT: Yeah you can.
SAM: Okay, I will Counterspell that at level
four.
MARISHA: Wait, but I've already cast it. It's a
concentration spell.
MATT: That's true. No.
SAM: It just happens?
MATT: Yeah. You're right. Thank you for reminding
me of that. Yeah, make a constitution saving
throw.
SAM: Constitution saving throw! First blood. 22.
MARISHA: Fuck! Yeah, you save against it.
MATT: Okay, so you're not blinded.
SAM: Great, that's good.
MATT: And you take half damage.
TALIESIN: But he becomes visible, right?
MATT: No. Once we get the damage in, he has to
make a concentration check.
MARISHA: 27 plus five, so 32.
MATT: 32, so 16 points of radiant damage and I
need you to make a constitution saving throw, with
advantage because you're a war caster.
MARISHA: He already did. Oh no, wait. Oh,
concentration.
SAM: Another 22.
MATT: All right, you're fine. You maintain
concentration on Invisibility. All right.
MARISHA: And I'm going to use the rest of my
movement to go--
TALIESIN: I have lost two of my most powerful
weapons already in one round.
MARISHA: I'll go there.
TALIESIN: Damn. It's okay, but I've lost two of my
most powerful weapons already. Shit.
MARISHA: What did you lose?
TALIESIN: I lost my Spider Climbing and I lost my
Silence.
MARISHA: Oh, your Spider Climbing is gone too?
That sucks.
SAM: But your most powerful weapon is your wit,
just like Liam!
LIAM: I'm just trying to live to intermission.
Come on.
MATT: So Keyleth, is that your turn? All right,
you moved around that way. Top of the round. Oh,
you do have a bonus action still, yeah.
MARISHA: No, I don't have anything to do. Never
mind.
MATT: Percival, you're up.
TALIESIN: Man, okay. I have 30 bits of movement.
I'm irritated. Can I make it to that door? No, I
can't make it to the door in one round, can I. I'm
going to-- shit, this is awkward. I've seen what
those things do already and I know they're about
to do it again.
TRAVIS: The first time it was after me and the
second time it was right before me.
SAM: Why is this so stressful?! We already beat
the bad guy!
MATT: But now you're beating the ultimate villain:
yourselves.
TALIESIN: There is nothing good I can do. I'm
going to start making my way over here and try and
make it to against, not quite to the door, but to
the wall.
MATT: 30. You get to about there with your
movement.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I want to be one over.
MATT: Yeah, so one over this way?
TALIESIN: Because I know that thing's got a
radiant kick.
MATT: Okay. All right, that's your movement.
TALIESIN: And then for my action--
MATT: You do, as you turn the corner, glance over
and you see a large earth elemental around the
corner, stomping within visual range.
TRAVIS: If you also want to see something pretty,
you look behind you, girl. I'm sitting over here
flexing.
MATT: That's true, and you do see Grog across the
water that way.
TALIESIN: Okay, I'm going to spend the rest of my
movement, then-- oh fuck, there is no good thing.
That door is locked, I'm sure it is.
MATT: Well that's 30 feet right there.
TALIESIN: Well I have an action still. Since I'm
here, I'm actually going to take a few potshots at
Keyleth for fun.
SAM: Yes you will! First blood!
MATT: So you have four attacks.
MARISHA: Are you going to say that every time
someone gets hit?
SAM: Yes.
MATT: Which weapon are you using?
TALIESIN: I'm using Bad News because the distance.
First shot is-- I'm actually going to do a deadeye
shot to gain advantage. Actually, that's not fun.
Yeah, deadeye to gain advantage. Here we go for
that. And that crits! So I'm going to use that
crit. I'm also going to drop all of Cabal's Ruin,
the entire run of Cabal's Ruin into that.
SAM: Oh, shit! All right, it's begun.
MARISHA: Might want to save your shit, but all
right.
TALIESIN: Cabal's Ruin is best used early. He
knows why.
LIAM: Sam, your face folded in the shirt is
terrifying. It's better flattened out, but with
four folds in it? Terrible.
TRAVIS: I like that right nipple coming through.
TALIESIN: Actually, that's technically, those are
not d12s. These are d12s. I really should have
four of these, but I'll do two and remember to-- I
have to double all these dice, so here we go. Time
to be a real jerk.
MATT: Well, Taliesin, here's the weird thing.
Cabal's Ruin currently has no effect.
TRAVIS: Oh, you got fucking smoked by the purple
shit!
TALIESIN: Would that have emptied it?
MATT: It currently lays against you like a normal
cloak.
SAM: You don't know. You don't know!
MATT: But you still get the shot off so you can
roll damage on that.
TRAVIS: Oh my god.
LIAM: Yeah, I don't know. I'm in this building
over here.
SAM: Oh, are you?
LIAM: Yes.
TALIESIN: Okay, that's fine.
TRAVIS: I need to keep living in those places. I
don't know what it does, though.
TALIESIN: That's 27 points of damage.
MATT: Piercing damage? Which, non-magical, you're
resistant to.
TALIESIN: Whole theory of that was to throw Cabal
into that.
MATT: So you would take 13 points of piercing
damage for the first hit.
TALIESIN: That is irritating.
MATT: You still have three more attacks.
TALIESIN: I'm going to use one of those attacks to
reload.
TRAVIS: How many points, Keyleth?
MARISHA: 13.
SAM: Ooh, first blood!
MATT: You watch (gunshot). You see bits and pieces
of the outer-shelled armor of the earth elemental
fracture and spiral off. Minimal impact.
TALIESIN: All right, and then I'm going to take
another shot and reload. This will be third and
fourth attack, shot and reload. At Grog! Because
that was disappointing. And I'm going to do a
push-back because I'm curious to see what happens
when he-- I think that'll almost get him to hit
the edge.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: So let's see what ten feet does to him.
Yeah. I'm just curious. You're near the edge,
sorry. Nothing personal. That's 28 to hit.
MATT: I'm pretty sure that hits. Go ahead and roll
damage.
TALIESIN: Oh, that's not bad at all. You're fine.
That's 15 points of damage and you move ten feet
away from me.
MATT: Okay, so as you take half that because
you're raging, you get pushed five, ten into the
barrier. Make a constitution saving throw.
TRAVIS: 30. 18 plus 12.
MATT: Okay, so you succeed. So you take-- that was
a very balanced roll. Like, six, six, six! Two,
two, one. 23 points of force damage, halved. 23
would be halved, so 11, and you do not get pushed.
As it slaps you into it, it slams into your back
and you feel it forcing you away from it at a much
harder rate than you were forced into it, but you
manage to hold firm on the ground and not get
pushed forward.
TRAVIS: Into the water?
SAM: Or whatever that substance is.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: All right. So that's your turn. Scanlan,
you're up.
SAM: I'm up? Okay, knowing where she is with my
tremor sense and just having seen her walk through
there--
MATT: You watched her walk around.
SAM: I'm going to peek around the corner and I'm
going to, even if it kills my Invisibility-- oh
wait! First I'm going to bonus action heal myself.
Healing Word.
MATT: Okay, this will break your Invisibility. So
level two?
SAM: Level two, yeah. Why not.
MATT: I just assume at this point. So 2d4 plus
six.
SAM: Ooh, four and a four! Okay, that's 14. I'm
back up. For my action, I will start singing.
(singing) If you want my body and you think I'm
sexy, baby then start to dance! (normal) And I
will cast Irresistible Dance on her. Through the
Hand Cone, by the way.
MATT: So hearing Scanlan's song, Marisha, there is
no roll because it is irresistible. Your earth
elemental form begins tapping a heavy stone foot.
(impacts) You start turning into your own version
of STOMP, a one-elemental show. Slamming into the
ground to the beat, maintaining it although he
stopped singing, you're feeling it. Hold on, let
me see here. Let me check one thing.
SAM: I can't even find it in the book.
MATT: Let me check one thing just to be sure
because she's an elemental and that may or may not
have an impact on this.
SAM: I can't find it in the book. Is it not in the
book?
TALIESIN: Irresistible Dance. It might be in the
new book.
MATT: All right, yes. So you are not immune to
charm, so you're fine. So you can't move.
SAM: Oh, she can only move.
MATT: That's true. So on your turn, you have to
use all your movement to dance without leaving
your space. So you're unable to move from that
spot until you get rid of the spell.
MARISHA: Can I do the Locomotion and do a
traveling dance?
MATT: You can, as long as it's in that space. So
you can do a little box-slide into that five-foot
square and you're fine.
MARISHA: How long does this last?
MATT: It lasts until you spend an action to try
and make a saving throw to resist it.
MARISHA: I have to spend an action?
MATT: Yeah. You also have disadvantage on
dexterity saving throws while this is happening.
So you can't move. You still have your action and
you can still cast spells from it, but until you
spend an action to try and make a saving throw--
MARISHA: What kind of saving throw?
MATT: This would be a wisdom saving throw.
TRAVIS: What if someone hits her?
MATT: Doesn't matter. So Scanlan--
SAM: I'm going to use whatever movement I have to
hide again behind this little--
MATT: Okay, that's about as far as you can get.
Okay, that ends your go? Top of the round. Grog,
you're up. The torches at the base of the tower
begin to flare up and then (explosion). You watch
as all the space around the outside of the tower
radiates with burning flame, affecting nobody. But
you get the sense that there are elements to this
field you have to use to your advantage or avoid
altogether.
TRAVIS: Good to know. Fire death.
MATT: Grog, as you see this flare burn around you
and then dissipate, it's your turn.
TRAVIS: Oh God, I was like, what? I'm sorry! Can I
use my action and dash to run all the way over to
this spot, please? Great. And that will--
SAM: Where are you going? She's pinned down, dude!
We need you over here!
TRAVIS: That will complete my turn.
MATT: Vax, you're up.
LIAM: All right, here it comes. Boop!
MARISHA: Jesus. Such a fascinating game.
LIAM: You guys are fucking dicks. I chose rogue.
This is what I can do! That's it! I don't have any
other shit I can do! This is it. I am defensive!
TRAVIS: You haven't even been touched yet.
TALIESIN: All of us have taken a little.
LIAM: Raven Queen take me. Okay.
MATT: So that's what you see.
MARISHA: Give it time, dude.
MATT: You're on deck, Keyleth.
LIAM: Good, good. Am I out of stuff?
MATT: No, you still have your action.
LIAM: Okay, this is real quick. I just have one
last note.
MATT: Okay. Got it. All right. Keyleth, you're
up.
MARISHA: Okay, I don't see anyone.
MATT: Nope. Scanlan is making you dance and then
goes like, do-do-do! And disappears behind the
pillars.
MARISHA: In my, what is it called?
MATT: Irresistible Dance.
SAM: Otto's Irresistible Dance.
MARISHA: In my Terran language I say, You fucking
asshole! And as I'm dancing I'm going to try and
make my wisdom saving throw because I can't do
anything else.
MATT: Go for it.
MARISHA: Don't fuck me, Gil! You totally fucked
me! No, wait! No, you kind of fucked me. What's
seven plus 14? 21.
MATT: The DC is?
SAM: 22.
MATT: 22, you do not succeed.
TRAVIS: You got high wisdom, yo!
MATT: You're just grooving out!
LIAM: Just stand there and hang out until three
hours of this game are up.
MARISHA: Question. Because it's cast on my
elemental form, if I switch wild shapes, will it
go away?
MATT: Only one way to find out.
MARISHA: Okay. I'll use my bonus action to turn
into a fire elemental.
MATT: As your form shifts into that of a moving,
grooving fire elemental, you continue dancing in
place. But now it's less STOMP and more really
smooth, soft rave dancing.
LIAM: It's like at Burning Man.
MATT: Essentially. That ends Keyleth's turn.
Percy, you're up. Percival, the cloak: the energy
returns to it. You feel the boots solidify back in
place and no sound.
TALIESIN: That will do. I'm going to run around to
the door.
MARISHA: It only knocks it out for a round? Or for
when it's turned on?
MATT: All magical items, all effects, it seems.
TALIESIN: I'm going to snap.
MATT: No sound.
TALIESIN: All right. Is the door open or is the
door not open?
MATT: The door's closed.
TALIESIN: I'm going to use Animus to open the
lock.
MATT: Okay. Make an attack with it.
TALIESIN: Don't fuck me, that's 29 to hit.
MATT: Yeah, no, roll damage.
TALIESIN: I assume the door cannot take psychic
damage.
MATT: The door doesn't take psychic damage.
TRAVIS: Are you sure? You've got a big vendetta
against doors.
TALIESIN: 17 damage to the lock.
MATT: You fire, no sound. The door opens with a
creak, no sound. The chamber within reveals a
chest in the corner.
TALIESIN: I'm going to run in, shut the door. It's
going to be an action to open that chest, isn't
it? Okay. I'm going to hide behind the door, so if
it opens.
MATT: You hide off to this side, waiting.
TALIESIN: I'm just being careful.
MARISHA: I have a question. Would Freedom of
Movement negate the dance spell? It says, "For the
"duration, the target is unaffected by difficult
terrain and spells and other magical effects can
"neither reduce the target's speed nor cause the
target to be paralyzed or restrained."
MATT: Technically, it's not reducing your
movement. You're just spending your turn dancing
in place.
MARISHA: Damn it!
TRAVIS: That's amazing!
MARISHA: I love this DJ!
MATT: This spell is worded apparently to just
skirt around Freedom of Movement. You can move,
you just don't want to. You're Flashdancing in
there!
LIAM: Best fiery running man ever!
MATT: That ends Percy's turn. Scanlan, you're up.
SAM: I become an ancient brass dragon. True
Polymorph is not a concentration spell, right? It
just happens.
MATT: True Polymorph is concentration.
SAM: So she would stop dancing?
MATT: Correct.
SAM: Then I'm not going to do that. Shit.
MARISHA: You know what? I'll take that!
TALIESIN: I'm not going to be a brass dragon! I'm
going to be me.
MARISHA: Enjoy the show, Scanlan!
SAM: Sorry, Matt, sorry.
MATT: That's okay. The brass dragon figure goes
back on the table.
SAM: You have an ancient brass dragon at the
ready?!
TRAVIS: Of course he does!
TALIESIN: Have you seen his office? It's basically
brass dragons.
MARISHA: Technically my office, so it's an even
stronger statement.
MATT: Sorry. It's getting better! No, it's not.
SAM: Well, in that case, I will-- poo.
MATT: Do you shake it out of your pant leg?
LIAM: Rabbit pellets.
SAM: I want to roast her! She's pinned down, man!
We got her right now, guys, this is it!
TALIESIN: We can't hear you.
MATT: You do all have the earrings in!
TALIESIN: But I certainly can't hear him.
TRAVIS: Oh, we do have the earrings in?
MATT: Yeah, you've got everything you have.
TRAVIS: Oh we can talk shit while we play?!
MATT: Yeah, you can!
TALIESIN: I can't hear anything you say.
TRAVIS: I'm going to teabag you when you're dead.
MATT: Scanlan, what you got? Grog, you're on
deck.
SAM: I will say, though the earrings, She's open,
let's kill her. Trust me, I won't kill you if you
get close.
LIAM: "That's the thing, though, guys, I'm a
really good liar."
SAM: I'll lean out and Lightning Bolt her.
MATT: Go for it.
LIAM: Is this out of the dick?
SAM: Of course. No, I'm sensitive to the plight of
women. I will do it in a gentle bow.
MARISHA: You just m'lady lightning struck me?
LIAM: Tip of the hat.
MATT: M'lightning bolt. It is the m'lightning
bolt.
(laughter)
MATT: And thus, a class begins to percolate in my
head. Scanlan, 8d6.
LIAM: We peaked at the 35 minute mark.
MATT: The Bardic School of White Knighting.
LIAM: The m'lightning bolt. Artists, I've never
asked for anything specific. But now.
SAM: 26.
MATT: I need you to roll a dexterity saving throw
with disadvantage because you're dancing.
MARISHA: This is so great. No, that was a natural
one. So I take it. How much was it?
MATT: 26 points of lightning damage to your fiery
form.
SAM: Do elementals maintain their damage level? If
she goes back to stone, does it halve the damage
that it had?
MATT: No.
SAM: Damn!
LIAM: Get it out of your head that you're going to
win. Just have fun on the ride.
SAM: If we're all over here, we can do it!
TALIESIN: It's like a rollercoaster where you know
that they haven't finished the last ten feet of
track.
TRAVIS: He's just going to come out from wherever
he is and help you right now.
SAM: She's there, man!
LIAM: You all are going to die, and I'm going to
come out and embrace my girlfriend and let her
kill me. That's how this game is going to go.
MARISHA: You would do that for me?
LIAM: Let her think that.
(laughter)
MARISHA: That's true love, right there.
SAM: I'm going to turn back behind there.
MATT: You're just boop! Okay, that ends your turn.
Top of the round. Grog, as you are coming around
the way, you see a familiar sparking of lightning
energy as the two lightning towers blast off a
radius of lightning energy. But no one's in the
radius to be affected by it. That brings it to
your turn.
TRAVIS: I would like to smash the door with my
bloodaxe.
MATT: Make an attack.
TRAVIS: Yeah, either one of those.
SAM: In the distance, do we hear another door
breaking?
TRAVIS: 21 points of damage.
MATT: You do. Another heavy hit right after the
bolt of lighting dissipates over the horizon, you
see splintered woods as an axe swings over the
range of the nearby roof of that building. You
hear an angry goliath yell as the door is
sundered, opening to the chamber within.
TRAVIS: May I entrez-vous, please? I will end my
turn.
MATT: All right. Vax.
LIAM: Coming at you. It's so good. I'm going to
win on this move. Okay.
TRAVIS: I'm going to mime it.
SAM: I'm single-handedly first blood-ing over
here! I'm first blood-ing everybody!
MATT: Scanlan is playing the exact opposite as he
did as Taryon in the last one!
SAM: Yep!
MARISHA: Switching masks.
TRAVIS: Are you writing a paragraph?
LIAM: A short one.
SAM: Dear Matt, check this box if you like me.
MATT: Okay, so that ends your turn. Keyleth,
you're up.
MARISHA: Give me this shit! I want to save from
it! Natural 20!
MATT: And with that, you have your movement back.
SAM: Oh no.
MARISHA: (grunting)
TALIESIN: You still have movement and a bonus
action.
MATT: Yep.
MARISHA: Bink! Do I see Scanlan?
MATT: You do.
MARISHA: (laser noise)
LIAM: Did you just make that noise?
SAM: Yeah, what's that noise?
MARISHA: Sorry. Sunbeam!
MATT: No, you don't have another action because
you used your action to resist the spell.
MARISHA: Oh! I have a bonus though. I will use my
bonus to go back to earth elemental.
MATT: Which, previously, Keyleth had two elemental
forms before she had to make a short rest.
20th-level Keyleth has just transformed into her
third form.
LIAM: Zero fucks.
TRAVIS: Does that mean she can go earth elemental
again, or is that it?
MATT: At full health. You get the sense now, and
you've heard of such rumors in your research as a
bard, that certain powerful archdruids can wild
shape as many times as they want.
MARISHA: This is open, right? Can I do a big old
jump into it? I do that.
LIAM: Sphere of Annihilation!
MATT: All right, that's your turn.
MARISHA: Don't fuck with me like that! I took you
seriously for a good two seconds!
TRAVIS: One little marble you didn't see.
LIAM: That's the biggest disappointment you have
tonight. You did all right.
SAM: Are there doors on that thing?
MATT: Percy, you're up. No, it's a solid wall
about six feet tall, which you can see Keyleth
peeking over the top a little bit.
TALIESIN: So I'm going to open that chest.
MATT: All right, you open the chest and you
acquire a potion of superior healing.
TALIESIN: Thank you. And that's how many feet?
That's like five. So I can now, I have a little
bit of movement to leave. Ten, 15, 20. So I can at
least use 20 to get to that corner there. Yeah,
toward me. There, just there. Do I see Scanlan or
is he still invisible?
MATT: No, he's not invisible anymore. You see
him.
TALIESIN: Oh, so I see him right there? I still
have ten feet of movement after that. Cool. I am
going to shoot Scanlan.
SAM: Nice.
TALIESIN: I'm going to shoot Scanlan. Let's use
Bad News for-- actually, let's use, oh this'll be
fun. Let's do Animus, sharpshooter, and deadeye,
just for fun. Animus, sharpshooter, deadeye.
SAM: I will Cutting Words this first shot.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: I can't hear him.
MATT: Well, and you're further than 60 feet from
him, I think, actually. Yeah, so it wouldn't
work.
TALIESIN: Animus, sharpshooter, dead shot. Oh,
you're so lucky that didn't crit. 28 to hit.
MATT: 28 to hit.
TALIESIN: That's 1d10 plus 1d6 psychic, plus I'm
going to-- eh, not on this one. This is shot
number one. So that's, oh, that's terrible. I'm
glad I did not. That's nine points of damage plus
one point of psychic, so that's ten points of
damage.
SAM: Are you adding these up? Because I'm not.
MATT: You take ten points of damage.
TALIESIN: For your next shot--
MATT: You don't hear anything. All of a sudden--
TALIESIN: You take 20 points of damage because
that was sharpshooter. 20, excuse me.
MATT: So you take 20 points of damage and the
(impact and grunting). And you glance over your
shoulder and you can see across the way, there's
Percival, gun up, but you've heard no gunfire.
TALIESIN: Next shot. Same thing. Also didn't crit.
You're very lucky. That also hits. That's 29 to
hit and then the same thing, 1d10 plus 1d6 plus
18. 26 points of damage.
MATT: 26 points of damage.
TALIESIN: And I'll do the same thing one more
time.
SAM: I'm the wrong target!
TALIESIN: Natural 20! You've just been critted.
And I'm going to drop all of Cabal's Ruin into
this as well. So that's (counting) 40 points of
damage and now the 10d6 lightning damage. Does
that get doubled or does that stay normal?
MATT: Lightning damage also gets doubled.
MARISHA: Oh, those were good rolls, too!
TALIESIN: Plus 33 lightning damage on top of
that.
MATT: 33 is doubled, so 66 points.
TALIESIN: 66 lightning damage on top of that.
SAM: On top of what? I'm not adding your shit.
TALIESIN: 41 plus 66.
SAM: How is it 41? It was 40 before.
TALIESIN: Was it 40? 40 plus 66.
MATT: So 106 points of damage from that shot.
TALIESIN: 106 points of damage on that shot. Oh, I
get my grit back on that, so that's nice. Ten.
Cabal's empty. And for my final shot, (evil
laughter).
TRAVIS: You know we kind of need Scanlan to take
down Keyleth, right?
SAM: It's all good. This is how he wants to play
it.
MARISHA: Come on, believe in yourself, man.
SAM: Taliesin's been trying to do this for
months.
TRAVIS: Don't make Taliesin get up at 5:30
anymore. It's not good for anyone.
LIAM: This might push you toward chaotic good.
TALIESIN: For my final shot, I'm going to reload
and hide.
MATT: Okay. You reload.
LIAM: Full action to hide?
MATT: Well, he's not actually using a hide action.
He just goes into a chamber.
TALIESIN: It's going to take him so long to get to
me. And if I get within ten feet of him, there's
nothing he can do.
MATT: So Percival, that's the end of your turn?
Scanlan, you're up. You watched this earth
elemental dive into the tower right next to you in
this open space. You get shot the fuck up. You're
covered in your own blood and you watch Percival
in the distance slink out of sight. And you're
hurting bad.
SAM: Yeah, I am. Mm, don't have lots of good
options. Oh boy.
TALIESIN: I beat him up for you.
MARISHA: You did. Very much so.
TALIESIN: So you're either going to kill him next
round or he's going to do it to you.
SAM: Bonus action, 2nd-level Healing Word. Uh-huh,
got to get back in the game.
TALIESIN: Roll that d4.
SAM: Five plus six, 11 points. Yeah.
MATT: There you go. Heal up 11 points of damage.
Hey, it all adds up.
TALIESIN: I'll make it go away again.
SAM: Let's see here. What to do?
TALIESIN: That was so pleasing.
TRAVIS: 106 points!
TALIESIN: One shot! I did three shots.
MATT: I'll keep this on deck just in case. Ancient
brass dragon. Just chilling on the side. You're on
deck, Grog.
TRAVIS: I'm texting you my turn.
MARISHA: Who's on deck? You are?
SAM: I need some healing. So. Shit. I've got to
get away from Keyleth. I've got to get healed.
MARISHA: No, stay. Hang out.
SAM: I will Dimension Door to the opposite
circular tower.
MATT: The opposite circular tower?
SAM: Yes, behind it.
MATT: All righty. Hand me the piece? All righty.
That's your action.
SAM: That's my action. That's it.
MATT: Grog. At the top of your turn, actually,
nothing happens because none of you-- all of you
are not able to see anything happen. Grog, it's
your turn.
TRAVIS: I would like to open the chest.
MATT: You pull it open. Potion of Superior
Healing.
TRAVIS: Hey, look at that.
MATT: I also want you to make a constitution
saving throw.
TRAVIS: 19.
MATT: 19? Wasn't a great roll. You take 20 points
of poison damage. Halved, because of your belt.
TRAVIS: Oh, I do have resistance because of the
belt! Yes, thank you. So ten.
MATT: And you are currently poisoned.
TRAVIS: Damn, son! From what, homie?
MATT: As you open the chest, this dark
black-purple smoke billows out as you grab and
pull the potion out of it. Almost like a trigger
or something. It fills your nose, your lungs.
You're coughing and it seizes the inside of your
chest. And so you are currently poisoned.
TRAVIS: Cool. Can I use my movement to run out and
toward this hallway? See how far I get.
MATT: You can get right inside, if you want.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'll stay just outside of it.
MATT: Okay, you're hanging right there, just on
the outskirts.
SAM: Do I see him?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I see you! Hey, Scanlan.
SAM: Does he see me?
MATT: No, because you were hiding behind the side
and he rushed right to the hallway.
TRAVIS: He's right behind me.
MATT: I'll say because you weren't hiding and as
part of the battlefield here, glancing about, he
does see you because you do not have a hide
action.
SAM: Okay.
TRAVIS: To be clear, I see you, and then I turn my
back on you.
SAM: Like a matador?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'm not focused on you right now.
TALIESIN: He's not mad at a door.
TRAVIS: I mean I can look at you if you want me
to.
MATT: Ends Grog's turn.
LIAM: It's already sent.
TALIESIN: That's awful.
MARISHA: That's pretty bad, man. That's real bad.
TALIESIN: I don't feel like a good person
anymore.
LIAM: Does that make sense?
SAM: Pawn to rook four.
TALIESIN: What? Yahtzee?
SAM: Woodchuck to gray squirrel, woodchuck to gray
squirrel.
MATT: All right, I see what you're doing. That's
your turn. Keyleth.
MARISHA: Do I feel anything around me?
MATT: Currently? What's the tremor sense?
MARISHA: 60 feet.
MATT: 60 feet? No movement. At all.
TALIESIN: Even the tower? 60 feet?
MATT: Yeah.
TALIESIN: All right.
MARISHA: Okay.
SAM: Five master D&amp;D players!
MARISHA: And no one's been in here, right? You
tried to go in there and then failed?
SAM: I tried the doorknob. I didn't really give it
all the effort.
MARISHA: I'm going to go (roars) and then use my
siege abilities to just beat down the wall.
MARISHA: First one is 20 total. No, I'm sorry, 22
total.
MATT: Yeah, that hits. Roll damage and then double
it. Percy, you're on deck.
MARISHA: Five plus seven is 12, 24 plus five.
MATT: Yeah, you just punch the door in and your
fist goes through it and you have to pull it off
the hinges and shake it off of your giant
battering ram-like fist. The door opens, reveals a
singular chest against the other wall.
MARISHA: Okay, I'll go ahead and open that.
MATT: Well, it's an action to open it, but you can
move up. What's your movement as an earth
elemental?
MARISHA: 30 feet walking.
MATT: 30 feet? Yeah, you'd be able to just get up
to the chest but you don't have another action to
open it.
MARISHA: Okay. This is like a building, right?
MATT: Yeah, you're having to duck down to get in
there. It's about ten feet tall and you're like
eleven-foot tall as an earth elemental, probably
littler than 12, so you're crouched down a little
bit.
MARISHA: Okay, I'm in there then.
MATT: That ends your turn, Percival, you're up.
TALIESIN: Okay, I'm going to take this opportunity
to head out of the room and I want to climb up on
top of this building. Then right up to this corner
right here. Actually, this corner right there.
MATT: Yeah, that's the end of your movement,
you'll be able to get there.
TALIESIN: Can I see Grog?
MATT: Currently no, you can not.
TALIESIN: I can't see anybody.
MATT: Nope. You have no sight on anybody. You get
to the top, aim, and the battlefield's quiet and
empty and you're like, "Ah, fuck."
SAM: You can't see Keyleth popping out of the--
TALIESIN: No, she's inside. I'm going to go to the
center of it and if I could use my action to lay
down and hide if that's possible?
MATT: Well, your movement's there so you can't
move any further.
TALIESIN: Okay, I'm going to lay down and, since
I'm on the roof, pull down to the roof and see if
I can get cover.
MATT: Okay. Are you trying to hide, or are you
just trying to give yourself cover?
TALIESIN: Cover.
MATT: So you're going prone.
TALIESIN: I'm going prone and I want to keep an
eye on that front door.
LIAM: It's movement to go up, is it movement to go
down?
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: Got any left? Got any movement left? To go
prone?
MATT: Well, no, to drop prone is fine. To get up
out of prone is just dropping to the ground.
MARISHA: Is he close enough to where I feel a body
go (thud)?
TALIESIN: I'm also completely silenced. Ten feet
all around me are completely silenced.
MATT: I know. Silence is different than vibration.
Unfortunately. I mean, it is vibration in the air,
but that's not going to stop vibration in the
ground. It just dampens the sound. Nope. He's just
outside of it, so you feel nothing.
MARISHA: Damn it!
TALIESIN: I'm going to keep an eye on that tower,
and if I see any movement I'm going to unload an
action on anything I see.
MATT: Got it. Make a general perception check for
me, if you don't mind.
TALIESIN: I'm going to use one of my resolve.
That's a save.
MATT: Saving throw, yeah, sorry.
TALIESIN: Okay, perception. That's a 14.
MATT: Ending Percy's turn, Scanlan, you're up.
SAM: I'm going to cast Healing Word on myself, at
level one.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: That is the coward's way.
SAM: It's three plus six, right?
MATT: Yes.
SAM: Great, awesome, nine more points, guys! I can
see Grog. I could take a pot shot at him, but that
would just kick the hornet's nest a bit.
MATT: You think?
SAM: I could score eight points of damage on him
and then die.
MATT: Yeah. You'd die.
SAM: I need to just heal. In that case, I will
dominate Grog.
MATT: Make an intelligence check.
SAM: Oh wait, shit, no, I can't do that. Is he
worked up, is he raging, can I tell?
MATT: Oh, yeah, he's going (huffing).
SAM: Okay, forget that then.
MATT: Yeah, you've worked with him enough to know
that while he's raging charm effects--
SAM: Forget it.
MATT: Sorry. I'm giving you guys benefit of the
doubt that you've all worked together enough to
the point where you do notice elements of
techniques and tells. Because it's helped you in
the past.
SAM: I could put on my hat of disguise.
(laughter)
MARISHA: What did Matt just say! We all know you
have that!
SAM: No, just so that you guys would think I'm a
kindly old man who just walked onto the
battlefield.
TALIESIN: Yeah, let's see how well that goes.
LIAM: Grog, put down your weapon!
MATT: Let me tell you. If there's anything to turn
Vox Machina away, it's elderly people.
LIAM: I was going to kill my friends, but now
there's this woman here.
SAM: If I use my bonus action Healing Word, to
heal myself, can I also use my action to cast a
higher level healing word on myself? Or is that--
MATT: No, it's a bonus action, it's used. Sorry.
SAM: Okay. Then I will cast Minor Image. Minor
Illusion or whatever it's called. That only has
60-feet range, 30-feet range, 60-feet range?
MARISHA: I smell so bad. I'm sweating so much.
TALIESIN: You're fine! There's nothing.
MARISHA: I need deodorant.
SAM: Shit. You know what, I'll do Major Image
then. Fine. Fuck it. I'm going to do Major Image
and it's going to sure look like Scanlan is just
walking right out to the edge of the water right
there. Not from there.
TALIESIN: Use the cake.
SAM: He's just going to appear right there, he's
going to come out from around that corner and look
out like he's looking for a target.
MATT: Percival, glancing over you can see Scanlan
emerges from around the corner, keeping an eye,
looking around the battlefield, and doesn't seem
to notice you're there.
SAM: You have to shoot.
MATT: Well, he wasn't holding an action.
SAM: I thought you said you were holding your
action.
TALIESIN: I'm holding an action for the tower.
SAM: Got it. Wait, for the tower? I thought you
said "I'm holding an action until I see anyone."
TALIESIN: I'm keeping an eye on the tower because
that's where I'm heading next.
SAM: Okay. That's my action then. I'm done.
TALIESIN: Don't worry, I will shoot at you.
MATT: Grog. Top of your round. You watch as the
braziers at the base of the tower flare up and
flames consume this outer area just on the
outskirts. Not the top, but just the surrounding
area of the tower and then die down, the walls of
flame burning to an ember and then vanishing. It's
your turn.
TRAVIS: Can I come inside here. Can you step on
that?
MATT: It's a small, a sigil raised platform.
TALIESIN: Do it. I dare you.
TRAVIS: I mean, I'm just curious. I mean it's hard
to--
TALIESIN: Say yes. When in doubt, say yes. What's
the worst thing that can happen? Other than your
spells get disenchanted.
MARISHA: Yes and, Travis.
TRAVIS: I'll go through the portal.
MATT: Okay. Out the other side you emerge.
TRAVIS: Can I head this way? Can I dash and
continue my action and head towards--
TALIESIN: Yeah!
TRAVIS: Head down this way.
MATT: You get right up-- oh god. You get right
about there.
TRAVIS: Can I use my bonus action to use my boots
of feral leaping to jump into the doorway?
MATT: Sure.
TRAVIS: No?
MATT: Make an athletics check to see if it
succeeds.
TALIESIN: I admire your commitment.
TRAVIS: 27.
MATT: Okay. Now I need you to make an acrobatics
check for me because it is a very small doorframe
you're trying to leap into.
TRAVIS: Oh, it's just the one. 13.
MATT: You do jump, but your head and shoulders
slam into the doorframe. So you get the additional
leap. You're now in the doorframe, you're
blocking it off. You have a little bit of extra
movement, but that's as far as you can get. You
have a ringing in your ears and you're like, "That
"smarts a little bit."
TRAVIS: That's my whole action.
MATT: You, as you're there by the chest, you hear
(grunting). You turn around and see Grog in the
doorway like (grunting), looking at you right in
the face.
MARISHA: In Terran I say: Hey Grog!
TRAVIS: Hey!
MATT: That finishes Grog's turn. Vax?
LIAM: Quick question! Already sent.
MATT: First question: no.
LIAM: Okay.
SAM: Second question: six inches soft.
(laughter)
LIAM: Is that true?! Tell me after. Okay.
TALIESIN: Wow, man!
MATT: Text your actions!
TALIESIN: Mid-game! You're asking to get fucked
with!
SAM: Third question.
LIAM: Yeah, no.
SAM: Shaved.
MATT: Jesus! Okay. Good to know. That brings us to
Keyleth.
MARISHA: Okay!
MATT: You're now between a chest and blocked door
frame with Grog in it.
SAM: Wait. How the fuck did Grog get all the way
over there?!
TRAVIS: Through the portal over here.
SAM: That's amazing!
TRAVIS: I was coming!
TALIESIN: Don't call it a comeback, he's been
there for years.
SAM: That's true.
LIAM: Vax is somewhere going: You got this.
MATT: Oh, I keep forgetting to ask you. Make a
concentration check when you took damage as a fire
elemental with advantage.
SAM: If it's anything like Hide &amp; Seek, you'd
probably be like: I really have to pee right now.
LIAM: I would just do it.
MARISHA: Yeah, I'm good.
MATT: With the fire elemental's constitution.
MARISHA: Yeah, that's even better. What do I have
to make? I keep my spell attack, right?
MATT: Yeah, I wanted to see if you lost
concentration on the Sunbeam.
MARISHA: No, I'm good.
MATT: All right, cool. It was 26 or 27 damage, so
you would have to make a 13 or 14.
MARISHA: Yeah, then I just made it. No, I'm
totally good.
MATT: What are you doing, Keyleth? You guys are
playing it really safe now!
TRAVIS: I'm in the doorway with a giant earth
elemental. I punched my ticket; I'm ready to ring
the bell.
MATT: That's true.
SAM: I stuck my face out and I got 140 points of
damage.
MATT: No, you-- okay.
TRAVIS: Keyleth's smug. Scanlan's like: Ugh!
MATT: I take it back. One of you is playing it
real safe.
TALIESIN: We're aware!
SAM: He may not even be playing with us.
TALIESIN: He is on Twitter right now.
LIAM: (singing) I stealthed myself out of the
narrative!
(laughter)
MATT: What're you doing, Keyleth?
MARISHA: Can I take Grog and use my slam attacks,
my multiattack, to take him and body slam into
this chest?
MATT: Sure, you can certainly try!
MARISHA: Yeah, sure!
TRAVIS: If I can jump and smash my head on the door
like an idiot approaching you, might as well tit
for tat.
MATT: You first attack would have to be a grapple
attempt.
MARISHA: My strength versus his, yeah?
MATT: Your athletics versus his.
MARISHA: I'm just an elemental; it doesn't tell me
that.
MATT: If the elemental doesn't have any athletic
skill, then it's just your strength modifier. Go
ahead and roll.
MARISHA: I rolled a natural 18. So that puts me at
23.
TRAVIS: 19.
MATT: No shit?! I was not expecting that! Not with
advantage! You reach out and grab, and you have
Grog. Make your other slam attack.
MARISHA: Which is a slam attack to hit?
MATT: Correct.
MARISHA: 17.
MATT: 17, this is against the chest, technically.
What's your armor class?
TRAVIS: 17.
MATT: Yeah. Okay. You reach and grab Grog. You
slam him and it destroys the chest. It splinters
underneath. Roll your slam attack damage.
MARISHA: Which isn't great. Six plus three, nine,
plus five, so 14 damage.
MATT: 14 points of bludgeoning damage to you,
Grog.
TRAVIS: Seven.
MATT: You're not prone, but you are moved to the
opposite side of her. The chest is shattered
beneath you.
LIAM and SAM: Shit!
MARISHA: Did it release a poison trap in any way?
MATT: I need you to make a constitution saving
throw. Grog, you make another one as all of a
sudden, poison gas fills the entirety of the
chamber around you as soon as you destroy this
chest.
MARISHA: I'm immune to poison.
MATT: You are unaffected by any of it.
TRAVIS: That's cool. 29. 17 plus 12.
MATT: So you succeed.
SAM: Are you double poisoned?
TRAVIS: I guess so. Start stroking out here in a
second.
MATT: 18 points of poison damage reduced to nine.
MARISHA: Does he take poison at the top of each
turn?
MATT: No, but he's poisoned, so he has
disadvantage on attacks and ability checks until
he gets rid of the poison.
TRAVIS: Can I make a retaliation? Is that
considered melee?
MATT: Against her? Yeah, I'll allow it.
TRAVIS: But I'm prone.
MATT: You're not prone. She just moved you over
and slammed you into it. You managed to maneuver
and get back on your feet, but your impact against the
chest destroyed it and released the trap inside.
TRAVIS: I haven't been able to say this in a long
time: Can I make this Reckless, Great Weapon
Master?
MATT: You can, but you have disadvantage on the
attack because of the poison, so it's just a
single strike.
TRAVIS: 26.
MARISHA: That hits for sure.
TALIESIN: It's going to make life complicated.
SAM: Yeah, I know!
TALIESIN: I've got shit I can do, but it's going
to be tricky.
SAM: You have to see the people you're doing it
to.
TRAVIS: 32.
MATT: 32 points of slashing damage.
MARISHA: Ooh! It's pretty good!
TALIESIN: That was foolish of you. Well, I don't
know. You always have a plan. I ain't going to
push it.
SAM: I don't have a plan tonight.
TALIESIN: I don't believe you.
MARISHA: Did I break any potions that were under
him when I slammed him into the chest?
MATT: Right now, the whole place is filled with
poison smoke. You have no idea.
MARISHA: I'm going to take my movement to get the
fuck out of here.
MATT: You have full movement, he already used his
reaction so he doesn't get an attack of
opportunity on you.
MARISHA: Can I go 20, use my bonus action to turn
into a water elemental and then dive under this
water?
TRAVIS: How many elementals can you turn into?
MARISHA: All of them.
TRAVIS: An unlimited number of times?
MARISHA: Yeah. Archdruid shit.
MATT: You are submerged in this water.
TALIESIN: It's why Scanlan's not dead yet. I just
wanted to make him desperate.
TRAVIS: Oh.
MATT: That ends Keyleth's turn.
MARISHA: That ends my turn!
MATT: Percival, you're up. You turn around and you
watch around the corner you have Scanlan peeking
around one side and you have Keyleth coming out as
an earth elemental, turning into a water elemental
then disappearing beneath the surface of the
water.
TALIESIN: I can't see anything else?
MATT: Nope. But you did hear the impact.
TALIESIN: No, I didn't.
MARISHA: Can't hear shit.
MATT: Oh, right. Silence, yeah.
TRAVIS: There's a giant tidal wave moving yonder.
TALIESIN: There's a bard over there. I'm going to
take a jump onto that island.
MARISHA: I'm stealthing, if that was not clear.
Hiding under there.
TALIESIN: Acrobatics check. That's 24.
MATT: 24.
TALIESIN: I'm going to spend the rest of my movement
running straight up that tower.
MATT: Okay! As you enter the tower--
TALIESIN: I'm not entering the tower. I'm running
up the tower. Sorry. My fault.
MATT: Ten, 15, 20, 25, 30.
TALIESIN: And then double run.
MATT: You're up on the tower now. As you get to
the top of the tower, you glance over and the
column of green energy that was left behind when
Colville vanished sits there, creating this beam.
This central, circular area right there is infused
with soft, sparkling, greenish energy.
TALIESIN: Huh. I've been having bad luck with that
lately.
TRAVIS: The whole top of the tower, or just the
middle of it?
MATT: Just the center circle.
TRAVIS: Is there a latch?
MATT: There is a trap door over that.
TALIESIN: I'm going to take cover from Scanlan
right there with what's left of my movement
against one of the walls.
MATT: You back up against the wall.
TALIESIN: I'm backing up against the wall and
that's my turn.
MATT: You currently have three-quarters cover in
that space.
TALIESIN: Okay. That'll do.
MATT: Ending Percival's turn, Scanlan, you're up.
SAM: Bonus action: Healing Word.
MATT: Yes. So you're holding your Major Image of
Scanlan out there right now. Grog, you saw enter
the chamber and vanish into the doorway.
SAM: Do I know where that goes? No. I don't know
how those things work. I heard a bunch of smashing
kitty-corner to me and I haven't seen anything
else.
MATT: Nope!
SAM: Cool.
TRAVIS: You could stand on that thing, though, the
platform.
SAM: What?
TRAVIS: It looks super-magical, this thing. It's
awesome. There's even little feet right here.
SAM: That sounds great.
TRAVIS: I don't know what those are. Are they
boots?
MARISHA: Stand here. Yeah, you beat me to it!
SAM: I'm going to have Major Image Scanlan ice
skate across the water in a jaunty way.
TRAVIS: Ice skating?
SAM: He's walking on water, as I've always wanted
to do.
MARISHA and TRAVIS: You can do that?!
SAM: He's not a real thing.
TRAVIS: Oh, right.
SAM: He can do anything. He's going to walk across
the water going, "Hey! Over here! Hey!" While he's
creating that distraction, I'm going to peek
around and see if I see anything around the
tower.
MATT: Around this way?
SAM: Yeah.
MATT: You peek around the tower there.
SAM: Anything?
MATT: Make a perception check, please. I would
like you to make a perception check as well.
SAM: 15.
MATT: You glance around. You can see, just on the
top of the tower, shoulder against the area, the
outer edge of Percival's form holding his gun up
and taking cover right up on the side there.
SAM: Okay, I duck back.
LIAM: Where's my Colville die?
MATT: End of your turn, Scanlan?
SAM: That's it, yeah.
MATT: The flames burst from the braziers around
the tower. The entire area incinerates around the
outside.
TALIESIN: It did that last round.
MATT: You're right, I marked that incorrectly.
TALIESIN: I've been keeping track.
MATT: I forgot to mark that. You watch as the two
separate towers give off a burst of lightning
energy and do not affect anybody. Keyleth, you
notice this. As you're inside the water, which is
just regular water.
MARISHA: Good!
MATT: As you're swimming through it, regular
water. Not terribly deep, it's about three or four
feet deep. You're flattening form as a water
elemental to hide beneath the surface. You get the
sense the water around you is starting to vibrate
a little bit. There's a strange effervescence to
it that wasn't there a moment ago. That's all.
Grog, you're up.
LIAM: I sent a question and the answer to your
roll, too. Sorry.
TALIESIN: Wonderful bottle of Pellegrino for the
table.
SAM: Naturally sparkling.
MATT: You rolled 27? You heard (footsteps).
TALIESIN: No, you wouldn't have heard. Ten feet.
MATT: That's right.
TALIESIN: Sorry, didn't hear it.
MATT: Nothing.
TRAVIS: Silent motherfucker. You're a goddamn Navy
SEAL.
TALIESIN: This is why in a normal game this would be
completely crippling me because anything could be
happening and you could not tell me. But on a solo
mission, it's pretty nice.
TRAVIS: In the room that I'm in, can I see
anything on the floor since I've been poisoned
fucking twice now?!
MATT: The cloud dissipates. You said you
want to sift through the rubble?
TRAVIS: To see if there's a potion.
MATT: Make an investigation check.
TRAVIS: Hey! Minus how much? Two. 13!
MATT: You spend your action rummaging through the
shattered remains of this. You find bits of the
trap mechanism within there and you find a
shattered glass vial with trace elements of a
healing potion that has since been destroyed.
TRAVIS: Can I get down and (licking)?
MATT: You do! You get down there. You get a
familiar weird medicinal, herbal flavor that is
mingled with shards of glass that are gathering on
the outskirts of your tongue.
TRAVIS: Not worth it. Okay. Yeah, let's see what
happens. Can I run out of the room? I'm going to
head towards the back portal. Actually, can I get
to here? She's in the water, right? She's not
sticking out some?
MATT: Make a perception check.
TRAVIS: Natural 20!
MATT: You glance over and you can see in the water
the slight, very different movement of the water.
You can basically see a slight form in there. Only
because you rolled really high.
MARISHA: Man, you beat me last time with a really
high roll.
TRAVIS: I'm an idiot, but you have to be really dumb
to go chopping at the water with an axe. It's just
water.
SAM: You would be just dumb enough to do that.
TALIESIN: Only a truly dumb person.
TRAVIS: She's just going to change again.
MATT: You used 25 of your movement, you still have
25 left. You've used your action.
TRAVIS: I'll keep running to the entranceway and
I'll stay outside. Do I have any more movement?
MATT: You have five feet more.
TRAVIS: I can't get around the corner, right?
MATT: Nah, you'd have to move next to it.
TRAVIS: I'm good.
MATT: You're on deck, Keyleth.
SAM: (sings with background music)
TRAVIS: Should have a countdown clock.
LIAM: There.
MATT: All righty.
SAM: Man, Liam's RP is so good tonight!
MATT: That ends Vax's turn, Keyleth, you're up.
LIAM: Hey man, I took my heart out and did this
for 115 episodes, all right?! Staying alive!
SAM: The last move, though, was so goth!
MARISHA: I'm going to come out of the water like
the Swamp Thing. I'm going to beam Grog with
another Sunbeam.
MATT: Grog, as you're waiting on the side, you
hear the ripple of water as you glance over. You
watch this giant wave as Keyleth's elemental
form emerges from the water. Out of the middle of
it, this beam of energy. I need you to make a
constitution saving throw.
TRAVIS: Wait. Mage Slayer. Advantage on saving
throws against spells? I have to be in melee of
them.
MATT: You might have to be in melee?
TRAVIS: I think that might be right.
MATT: I'll double check, just to be safe.
TRAVIS: I'm poisoned, so I have disadvantage on
saves, right?
MATT: "Against spells cast within five feet of
you."
TRAVIS: Because I'm poisoned, I have to roll this
again for disadvantage?
MATT: Poisoned just gives you disadvantage on
ability checks and attacks.
TRAVIS: Not saving throws?
MATT: Correct.
TRAVIS: 25.
MATT: Yeah, you take half damage and you're not
blinded.
TRAVIS: Oh, cool.
MARISHA: Your half damage is a ten, (counting) 21.
Not a great roll this go around.
MATT: You take ten points of radiant damage.
Blasted, it burns past your skin. It tickles a
little. It's like a bad sunburn.
MARISHA: I'm going to go into my earth elemental
form and--
TALIESIN: This is disturbing. I don't know what to
do about this.
LIAM: Die!
TRAVIS: Probably not kill the other caster, you
know.
TALIESIN: I didn't!
MARISHA: Is this an actual window here?
MATT: They're small slits that you can see
through, but that's it.
MARISHA: Okay! Yeah. Sure.
MATT: That ends your turn. Percival.
TALIESIN: God. I didn't see her do that, did I?
MATT: No. From where you're standing, you heard
the blast.
MARISHA: He can't hear shit.
MATT: No, that's right! Silence spell, man. It's
creepily quiet.
TRAVIS: You take the good, you take the bad, you
take them both and then you have Percy silence.
LIAM: Take your die of inspiration.
TALIESIN: I'm so fucked. Yep. This is dumb, but
I'm going to do it because I don't know you're
there. I'm going to walk over to that weird little
door.
MATT: You walk into the greenish energy. As you
step into this field, your body feels warm. No
sound.
TALIESIN: I just feel warm.
MATT: You just feel warm.
MARISHA: It's a patio heater.
TALIESIN: I'm going to open the door and see
what's in there.
MATT: As you go to pull for the door, it (clicks).
I mean, you don't hear a sound, but it resists.
LIAM: Oh, blew your action.
MARISHA: Man, we get so catty when we can! It's so
much fun!
LIAM: This is all I've got.
MARISHA: We're never mean to each other, you
guys.
TALIESIN: All right, just because this green glow
is freaking me out, I'm going to back up against
the wall and then my next action later is going to
be--
MATT: Have you taken any damage?
TALIESIN: Have I taken any? Yeah, I've taken 16
points of damage.
MATT: Okay, you sense as you're stepping in there,
not immediately but the sensation is that similar
to one of your allies were to cast a Cure Wounds
on you, it has a sort of regenerative property to
it, the longer you stand in it. It hasn't taken
effect yet.
TALIESIN: Okay, then I'm not going to back up out
of it, I'm going to get to the back side of the
hinge and I can't hold an action, obviously,
because I blew my action, but I'm going to prepare
to open and worry about what comes out.
MATT: Okay, so you go up into the very edge of
that radius and just hold your weapon.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: Okay, that ends your turn. Scanlan, you're
up.
SAM: Hi guys, Scanlan Shorthalt here.
TALIESIN: With a very important message about
Marvel Puzzle Quest.
MARISHA: I like your crown.
SAM: Thanks.
TALIESIN: It's nice, it would look good on me.
SAM: It's lofty. Knowing where Percy is, I'm going
to peek around the corner.
MATT: Peek around the corner, at this view, you do
not have eyeline on Percival.
SAM: Sure, but I kind of know he's up there.
MATT: You know he's up on the tower.
SAM: And I heard booms distantly over here.
MATT: You did, you heard thuds of impacts and a
burst of energy, you saw like a bright light glow
up over the distant sky for a moment.
SAM: Feeling a red-hot anger towards Percy for
shooting me--
TALIESIN: Oh, yeah. Bring it.
SAM: And also gaming out that there's people over
here, right centered on this spot I'm going to cast
Anti-Gravity.
MATT: Reverse Gravity?
SAM: Reverse Gravity.
MATT: Okay, on that spot.
MARISHA: Okay, that's fun.
MATT: All right, your illusion fades, it's
concentration.
MARISHA: That's one spell I wish we got to use
more in-campaign, it's a fun one.
MATT: Bringing it back.
SAM: 50-foot radius.
MATT: 50-foot radius which would also affect
Keyleth.
SAM: Keyleth for sure.
TALIESIN: And anybody in the tower.
MATT: Yep. All right so I need Keyleth and
Percival to both make a dexterity saving throw.
TALIESIN: What about my Boots of Spider Climbing
that are currently activated?
MATT: I need Keyleth to make a dexterity saving
throw.
MARISHA: This is going to be bad.
SAM: Are they always attached? Nice!
TALIESIN: They're activated, I ain't moving. I
can't be knocked prone, you can't do shit.
MARISHA: 12.
MATT: 12? No.
MARISHA: All right, let's go for a ride.
SAM: 100 feet up.
MARISHA: Whee!
MATT: (counting) That's 50.
TRAVIS: Oh, shit.
MATT: This is going to be interesting.
SAM: Because you said the top is like 90 feet up,
so I want her to go all the way up to the
ceiling.
TALIESIN: And then see what happens.
TRAVIS: A little unintentional Keyteor.
MARISHA: Yeah, a hundred percent.
MATT: Keyleth, you suddenly go firing up into the
sky. Percival, you watch as Keyleth spins up,
slams into the top of the field, I need you to
make a constitution saving throw.
MARISHA: Just a straight con save? Not good,
seven.
MATT: You take 29 points of force damage as you
slam into the field, and then it thrusts you 15
feet away from it, and then you head back towards
it.
TRAVIS: Do the basketball.
TALIESIN: Oh no, oh no.
MATT: So it won't affect you this round, but
you're currently being just bludgeoned repeatedly.
Percival, your hair is standing up on end above
you.
MARISHA: This is like some Freddie Krueger shit.
MATT: You take a moment to try and right yourself
and are now finding yourself having to fly upside
down.
LIAM: But that's the same shit, right?
MATT: Yeah, you're fine. It doesn't do anything to
you, but it took you a moment to readjust.
SAM: I'll duck back behind the thing.
LIAM: And nobody knows where I am.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we know, okay, we know. AT&amp;T thanks
you for your texts.
SAM: And I will say: drat, it didn't work on
Percy. I'll use my bonus action to say: Percy, I
wasn't aiming at you!
MATT: He doesn't hear it.
SAM: Shit! He doesn't hear anything!
MATT: That ends Scanlan's turn.
TALIESIN: I have been waiting to use this Silence
spell like an asshole this entire game.
LIAM: I rolled a 21 for that roll. That didn't do
it, did it? I sent you my roll. They rolled, so
did I. I texted you a 21.
MATT: It didn't affect anything because you were
flying.
LIAM: Oh, okay.
MATT: You had to right yourself, but as soon as
you started flying upward, you went, "Oh crap!"
and you caught yourself. That brings us to Grog's
turn at the top of the round. Keyleth and Scanlan,
definitely not Percival. Grog, you notice this,
too. Behind the entire chamber on each side, it
suddenly fills and flashes with that purplish-blue
energy. The energy travels through the center and
all the water and surrounding also flashes
once with that same purple-blue flash and then
dissipates and returns to what it was before. You
now notice that those rooms are connected to the
water and whatever's in the water when that goes
off--
MARISHA: That was the blue spheres?
MATT: No, that was the purple.
TALIESIN: Purple horseshoes.
LIAM: TGIF Flair.
MATT: Grog, you're up.
TRAVIS: I'm going to go into the room. Can I stand
on the crystal circle? Because I don't see anybody
else to hit.
MATT: You step onto the crystal circle.
TRAVIS: I concentrate real hard.
MATT: Make an intelligence check.
TRAVIS: Nine.
MATT: It's hard to concentrate. It's really warm
under your feet.
TRAVIS: That's it? Do I notice any writing or
bones around the circle?
MATT: No. It's pretty clear. But you're a few
inches taller than you were a second ago because
you're on the platform. That's cool.
TRAVIS: I don't see anybody. Does it go out to the
water?
MATT: Yes, it opens up out to the water.
TRAVIS: Did I happen to see Keyleth in her earth
elemental form, since I was outside, go whoosh and
fly up?
MATT: Yes. You're watching her being--
TRAVIS: That seems wrong. Okay. I'm going to use
my bonus action to take one of my superior healing
potions and that's my turn.
MATT: 8d4 plus eight.
LIAM: Sent you a monologue.
TALIESIN: O for a muse of fire!
LIAM: To be or not to be!
MATT: Keyleth, you're up!
TALIESIN: And down. And up and down.
MARISHA: I'm going to use my bonus action to turn
into an air elemental and fly.
TALIESIN: Goddamn it. Not cool!
MARISHA: I'm so hot. So sexy.
MATT: What's your fly speed?
MARISHA: My fly speed: 90 feet.
MATT: Yeah, you can get to Percival. You could get
to a lot of places from here.
MARISHA: How many rounds has it been? Do we know,
roughly?
MATT: It's been nine rounds.
MARISHA: Nine rounds. Then I'll use my last round
to--
MATT: You have one more round--
MARISHA: --of Sunbeam. This is my last round,
right? I'm going to fly directly above Percy.
Looking down over top of him a good 60 feet almost
exactly and right below me going to do my Sunbeam
down on top of his head.
MATT: You also enter the healing column. I need
you to roll a constitution saving throw,
Percival.
LIAM: Like the satellite in Akira!
TALIESIN: That's a constitutitution saving? Where's
my constitution? There we go.
SAM: Pretty good!
TALIESIN: 24.
MARISHA: Fuck! Fucking no one did! Fucking
everyone!
TRAVIS: Not me, I'm loving it. I've hit one
person.
LIAM: I've hit zero persons.
TRAVIS: I know.
MARISHA: 25 damage.
MATT: Halve that to 12. You take 12 points of
radiant damage, Percival, and you shield your eyes
just in time as the blast hits you from above
to have it not affect your vision.
TALIESIN: That ain't bad.
MATT: You still have about 60 feet of movement if
you want, Keyleth.
MARISHA: I'll fly that way to that corner.
MATT: Staying that far up. You can't fly quite
that high up with this range because the ceiling
is there.
MARISHA: Don't look at me like that!
TRAVIS: You don't have to make concentration
checks when you take damage, right? You just stay
elemental. You're that.
MARISHA: As the elemental, yes. It's my Sunbeam
that I've been rolling concentration checks
against.
TRAVIS: Gotcha.
TALIESIN: She's got Cyclops laser until we hit her
hard enough. Hey, look who you can see now!
MARISHA: I'm War Caster with pretty high wisdom,
so I'm trying to make it easier to not fail a
concentration check.
SAM: Oh Jesus!
TALIESIN: Look who you see now!
MARISHA: Oh, do I see Scanlan?
MATT: You do now! As you float over, you see the
tiny little gnome, right there on the ground.
TALIESIN: Good-bye.
MARISHA: (helicopter imitation) LAPD! (helicopter
imitation)
TALIESIN: Wow, that's a local joke right there!
TRAVIS: It'll only be there for four and a half hours from
12:30 to 3:30.
TALIESIN: They're already on their way in the
helicopter.
MATT: End of your turn, Keyleth?
MARISHA: Yeah, end of my turn.
MATT: That ends Keyleth's turn and we're going to
go to a break because we're at a break point here.
We'll come back here shortly to ensure that we
continue this roundabout battle of care and
delicacy.
LIAM: Battle of cowards!
TALIESIN: I am proud of what I've done so far!
LIAM: Same.
MARISHA: I would like to say, I feel like I've been
playing pretty aggressively.
MATT: You have been. You've been doing good. You
and Scanlan both have been doing pretty well.
Grog's been going door-to-door salesman.
LIAM: I have not lost a single hit point, Matt!
MATT: You have not!
TRAVIS: I've been looking for Vax!
TALIESIN: I've been sniping the way I've always
wanted to. I feel like such a badass right now. I
know it's going to end.
MATT: We'll be back here in a few minutes after a
quick break, guys. At the break, we have our
Wyrmwood giveaway. The keyword for this one is
"showdown." Put "showdown" in the chat room, one
word, when you are prompted to be entered and
we'll come back with the winner after the break.
See you guys here in a few minutes.
[break]
MATT: Welcome back, everybody. First off, we have
the winner in the chat for the black poisonwood
Wyrmwood box, which I didn't have around to show
you at the time, but it's really pretty. The
winner is CleverNameAlreadyTaken. Congratulations,
CleverNameAlreadyTaken. Danoba will get in contact
with you and get your shipping information. We'll
get that out to you ASAP. Signed by the cast.
Thank you again. So let's dive back into this
blood drizzle. You know.
MARISHA: Waiting for that first blood. Waiting for
it.
MATT: There's been a lot of first bloods, just no
consistent blood.
LIAM: Guys, the Raven Queen took me out of here 20
minutes ago.
MATT: You just find his equipment in the middle of
the battlefield.
MARISHA: Oh, poor timing.
LIAM: She gave me 20 minutes, she said.
MATT: Top of the round, Percival. First off, you
heal 20 hit points as your turn begins inside the
column of green light atop the tower. And it's
your turn.
TALIESIN: I'm going to shoot the lock. I'm going
to get within ten feet of that lock so that
there's no sound and I'm going to shoot the lock
open.
MATT: Make an attack roll.
TALIESIN: I'm going to use Retort for this just
because I don't want to waste anything worthwhile.
30 to hit.
MATT: Yeah, go ahead and roll damage.
TALIESIN: All right. Where's my fancy--? There we
are. That's ten points of damage.
MATT: Okay. The lock splinters and the trapdoor
falls open.
TALIESIN: All right. I'm going to run inside and
perch on the ceiling. I'm going to use my Spider
Climb boots. And what do I see around?
MATT: Okay, as soon as you rush to the stairs you
can see there's a bit of fog on the inside of the
chamber. It fills the room and obscures a lot of
the interior. So you move up onto the ceiling and
you're now underneath, inside the chamber.
TALIESIN: I don't see anything?
MATT: You are, for the purposes of this,
upside-down there.
TALIESIN: Sure. I'm going to hide-- and those
stairs keep going down?
MATT: They do. You have 15 more movement if you
want.
TALIESIN: I'm going to go down to the next level.
MATT: You don't have quite enough movement to get
there. You get just to the top of the stairway
onto the ceiling. We'll put you there for the sake
of keeping track of it.
TALIESIN: Can I see down there at all?
MATT: Yeah, the fog kind of dissipates below.
TALIESIN: Oh, in that case I'm not going to get
that close if I can't get all the way there
anyway. So I'm going to get right in that little
corner there and keep an eye out.
MATT: Well, to look down the stairs you'd have to
get--
TALIESIN: Oh yeah, I was going to say, I have to
get to the other side of the fog? I don't have
enough movement to get back from the fog, then?
MATT: Well, you're in the fog still but I mean, it
dissipates down the stairs. The whole chamber's
still filled with fog.
TALIESIN: Okay, I'm going to stay in the fog and
keep an eye on what's down there.
MATT: Okay. Boop. All righty. That ends Percival's
turn. Scanlan, you're up.
SAM: Bonus action: Healing Word.
TALIESIN: Wow, you are not rolling those well.
MATT: You have an air elemental swirling 80 feet
above you.
SAM: Yep. I just sang a little song to myself.
TALIESIN: I've softened him up for you.
SAM: Okay, so for all who care, I'm up to 63. And
I'm going to look at Keyleth, say into my earring,
Friends, let's go fucking kill Vax. At least find
him! This is not a fair fight without him! And
then I will Dimension Door to the opposite corner
again.
MARISHA: Oh, good call!
MATT: Keyleth, you hear his cry into the earring
and watch as, in a flash of vibrant pink-purple
energy, he steps through a small, magic-made
doorway and vanishes from your sight.
MARISHA: Yeah. Okay.
TRAVIS: Anti-gravity still going?
SAM: Oh yeah. Whose turn?
MATT: That ends Scanlan's turn. That brings us to
Grog. Sorry. Top of the round, now the exterior of
the tower bursts into flames. Fire climbs up and
incinerates the island around the central tower,
to no effect currently. Grog, your turn.
TRAVIS: Can I turn around, since my magic pedestal
has not done anything for me, and go through the
portal, please?
TALIESIN: Also, by the way, you see Scanlan as
well.
SAM: Hello! Bye-bye!
MATT: Ten, 15. You're now inside.
TRAVIS: Can I keep going straight across?
MATT: 50. You're about knee-deep in the water.
TRAVIS: Can I use my Boots of Feral Leaping to
leap horizontally 20 feet?
MATT: Go for it. Well, make the athletics check.
TRAVIS: 17.
MATT: 17, yeah. You just crest onto the edge. Your
ankle's kind of at the edge of the water. That's it.
TRAVIS: Yeah, fuck it. Can I use my dash to go
inside the tower from the bottom door?
MATT: You may.
TALIESIN: Yeah!
SAM: Has he hit the anti-gravity field yet?
MATT: Just as you get to the edge of that, I need
you to go ahead and make a dexterity saving
throw.
TRAVIS: Well, that's my game. Yeah, no. Seven.
SAM: I didn't know you were even there!
TRAVIS: I wasn't there. I thought it was put over
on that side of the tower.
MATT: So Grog, as you go--
SAM: Unintended consequences. Don't worry, I'll
get rid of it on the next round-- oh wait. You'll
plummet to your death.
TALIESIN: Oh no, he'll survive.
TRAVIS: I can't do much but hit things, so you
know.
MATT: For the purposes of this here, that puts it
about fair. Grog, you go flying up into the sky,
past the edge of the tower, slamming into the
ceiling over the battlefield. I need you to make a
constitution saving throw.
TRAVIS: Yes. 31.
MATT: 31, you succeed. So you take what would've
been 21 points of force damage, reduced to ten.
And you do not bounce off to return-- you manage
to stop yourself, but you're still about to be
forced back into it. You don't get pushed off, but
the gravity's still pushing you into it. So each
round you're up there, you're going to keep taking
this damage. All righty. That finishes Grog's
turn. All right. Mr. Stealthy Pants?
MARISHA: Stealthy Pants McGee.
SAM: Can you only send him moves in gif form?
LIAM: How did you know that's what I was doing?
This is that kid in the GoCart chair that spins
and spins and spins.
SAM: Sure, sure. I'm going to do a Mr. Bean
followed by a--
MARISHA: Followed by a Homer Simpson into the
bushes.
Followed by that kid that's like "Oh
shit!" as he runs by.
MATT: Here's the thing, and I'm being fair in this
circumstance. Keyleth and Grog, out of the corner
of your eye, you see a dash of black, winged
movement as, darting from the edge of this tower,
you see something out the side of this tower, like
climbing on the outside, dart and then vanish in
that direction.
TALIESIN: Wow.
LIAM: You don't know that.
TALIESIN: I don't know shit.
MARISHA: How did you get up the tower?
TRAVIS: He didn't go in the tower. He just climbed
up the side.
LIAM: Her miniature is facing that way. His
miniature is facing that way. I'm being a shit.
MATT: You want to fight me on this?
LIAM: Not at all. I started this game knowing that
Marisha was going to kill me. Ooh.
MATT: Early bird gets an early grave. All righty.
That brings us to--
MARISHA: I'm trying so hard.
MATT: Keyleth.
MARISHA: Okay, so Grog is suspended, being
repeatedly beaten into the ceiling?
TALIESIN: Vibrated to death.
MATT: Yeah, right now-- You didn't bounce off but
now you're slammed into it and being slowly pushed
into it, like (static crackling).
TRAVIS: Good times.
MARISHA: And I saw a black streak go this
direction?
MATT: From this wall to behind where the edge of
this building, and then vanish.
MARISHA: And I know Percy's somewhere in the
tower, but I don't know where?
MATT: Correct.
MARISHA: Okay. Yeah. Let me just try and find
people. I'm going to fly over top of where that is
and see if I can see anything. I'm going to look
for a stealthy Vax. How much movement was that?
MATT: That would've been-- oh god. Knocked you
over. Actually, as far as you can get is there.
MARISHA: Okay. Do I see anything from my awesome
aerial perspective?
MATT: You do not. There's the open door to the
building and there's the circular thing over there
but that's all you can see.
SAM: He could be somewhere over there.
LIAM and TALIESIN: (singing) Somewhere out there.
LIAM: I'll fucking shank your ass!
MATT: Keyleth?
MARISHA: Can I use the rest of my action to move
down? To just move?
MATT: Where do you want to move?
MARISHA: Let me drop down 60 feet. Or half my
movement speed or something like that, right?
MATT: Yeah, so you'd be about, let's say--
SAM: Matt, could I see her, by the way, when she
flew over and down like that?
MATT: Yeah, you saw her coast over and downward.
So there you go. That's your turn.
MARISHA: That's my turn.
MATT: All right, Percival, you're up.
TALIESIN: I'm going to go the next level down, see
what I see.
MATT: Okay. The fog has now begun to dissipate
from the entire chamber.
LIAM: It's like ten minutes. I'm going to check. I
could be wrong because I don't know shit.
MATT: You might be right. I was just guessing.
MARISHA: Did you make fog?
LIAM: No! Yes.
TRAVIS: Do you want to tell us anything you did?
LIAM: I didn't play this game.
TALIESIN: I'm just heading down, scanning, heading
down, scanning, and looking for anything.
LIAM: One hour.
MATT: Oh yeah, then never mind. It dissipates
because you step out of it.
LIAM: I'm a druid, yo.
TALIESIN: Fuck, I forgot that.
MARISHA: Did you do Fog Cloud?
LIAM: Yeah, baby!
MATT: Heading down, there's no furniture, just the
stairway. It looks like the interior of this has
been either unfurnished or cleared out. It's just
a series of empty stairs that lead up and down the
tower.
TALIESIN: I'm going to get all the way to the
bottom, then, and back myself against that bottom
door and I'm going to push all the way to the
bottom of the tower with my movement.
MATT: Okay. That's your whole turn?
TALIESIN: I was hoping there'd be a person in
there. I mean, that's all my movement, isn't it?
And that's all my action to move that as well,
right? Yep, I ran down that tower going, I want to
fight everybody!
LIAM: Good boy. Not metagaming.
MARISHA: Ooh, the m-word.
MATT: Finishing Percy's turn, Scanlan.
SAM: My turn? Jesus Christ, I don't know what to
do. I only see Keyleth. I've only seen Keyleth
this whole game! Do I see Grog up there, flying?
MATT: Yeah, you see Grog up there bouncing.
MARISHA: And Percy shot you!
TALIESIN: I'm of the opinion that, against the
wall, I don't think he sees him right now.
MATT: Right now, no, but if you were to look
around.
TALIESIN: If you were to back off a bit,
you would see him, maybe.
SAM: Okay, I will peek around the corner.
MATT: Okay, so you move five feet, glance over,
and you see Grog currently being jammed up into
the ceiling.
SAM: I kind of know where Keyleth is. I kind of
know where Grog is. No one has responded to my
text message of "Let's go find Vax."
TALIESIN: Sorry, new earring, who's this? Thank
you for being the only person who really laughed
at my good joke. That was a very good joke. Chat
probably liked it.
SAM: Bonus action Healing Word. Oh wait, wrong
one.
MARISHA: He's going to use all of his spells to
just Healing Word. 1d4 at a time.
MATT: Just slowly build it back up.
TALIESIN: And I will take it all away again next
time I see him.
SAM: Jesus, I don't know what to do. I'm not going
to go after Keyleth without backup.
MARISHA: No, but here. I'm going after Vax too! Ba
ra ra!
SAM: You don't speak English!
MATT: Well, technically she can.
MARISHA: Oh wait, we decided I can because it's
telepathic. I'm trying to find my boyfriend! He
fucking ditched me at this bar! Fucking asshole!
SAM: All right. So I'm going to announce to
everyone, I am going to search for Vax! Hold your
fire! And I'll walk, I guess, around this thing.
Can I get around it without--?
MATT: You can get 25 feet.
SAM: Actually, no, I don't know where he is at
all.
MATT: You see her floating. After Keyleth tells
you that, she's over here, moving down this way.
That's all you know.
LIAM: Baby, are you saving a Wish for me?
SAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: Oh, your other boyfriend? Okay.
LIAM: That's another universe.
MATT: One's in-game, one's out-of-game.
MARISHA: Oh sure. Sorry.
LIAM: One's real, Marisha. One's real.
SAM: All right. I'm going to start going this
way.
MATT: You get that far, less than that, even.
SAM: I'll use dash to keep going.
MATT: You can get about there. Tiny gnomish legs.
MARISHA: This is a big-ass map.
TALIESIN: This is such a big map! I love it! It
makes me very dangerous.
MATT: Beginning of Grog's turn, you watch the
lightning towers spark and then fire off radius.
Nobody's there. Grog, you're up.
SAM: Really, no one's near the lightning towers?
TRAVIS: Getting bug zapped.
MATT: Make another constitution saving throw,
please.
TRAVIS: Big southern mosquito. 30! 18 plus 12.
MATT: You succeed. So you take 12 points of force
damage.
TRAVIS: Dear god. That's already halved, right?
MATT: Yes.
TRAVIS: Okay, cool.
SAM: I guess I could have dropped Anti-Gravity. I
forgot.
TRAVIS: You did? Cool. With my bonus action, can I
use my Second Wind to heal 1d10 plus my stupid-ass
fighter level?
MATT: Go for it.
SAM: You want me to get rid of it?
TRAVIS: I'm fucking up here until you don't!
SAM: I forgot, I'm sorry! Can I do it now, Matt?
No.
TRAVIS: It's cool, I'm up there.
SAM: It's fine.
TRAVIS: I'm going to get the immovable rod out in
my hand, waiting to fall.
MATT: You've got the immovable rod out and you're
clutching it. So you're holding your action on it?
TRAVIS: I'll hold my action if someone comes
within striking range. Can I say that?
MATT: Are you holding your attack or--
TRAVIS: An action, not an attack. My action so I
can click the rod.
LIAM: I sent a question, and here comes a second
question. Here it comes.
MATT: You're on deck, Keyleth.
TALIESIN: Sorry, my fault. Hi.
LIAM: Got it. Okay. I'm good. So you know what I
want to do. I did it already.
MATT: Keyleth, you're up.
LIAM: Hey man, I worked really hard for 115
episodes. Allow me to be a fuckoff.
MARISHA: I'm going to look around. No sign of Vax,
I'm assuming.
MATT: From where you currently stand, no.
MARISHA: Scanlan, he's too fucking stealthy! I'm
going to go punk Grog. And then I'm going to fly
up within 60 feet of him.
SAM: You just gave up?
MARISHA: I can't find him! I looked!
SAM: For legitimately six seconds.
TRAVIS: I'm literally the helium balloon in the
grocery store that broke away from the cashier and
is fucking sitting up there.
TALIESIN: You're going on an adventure!
MARISHA: He's not going to let me do another
perception check! I tried!
LIAM: It's the best! Until I die.
MARISHA: I'm going to go up and be like: Sorry,
Grog! And hit him with a Blight spell. Let's say
level--
LIAM: That's going to shoot off your pinky toe,
man!
TRAVIS: I've got another one of those.
MARISHA: Let's say a level five Blight.
MATT: Grog, make a constitution saving throw,
please.
LIAM: Man, next campaign you're not going to be a
meat sponge like this.
TRAVIS: I won't be. 18.
MATT: 18, that's a failure. So full damage of
Blight on Grog.
TRAVIS: Whatever it is, I'll use my Stone's
Endurance.
LIAM: God, when you play your aasimar ranger, it's
going to be so weird.
TRAVIS: Yeah. I don't know what that first word
you said is. Aasimar?
LIAM: Your kenku druid.
TRAVIS: My tabaxi tortle.
LIAM: Tabaxi tortle half-breed bard. Yeah.
MATT: I multi-raced a little since I leveled up.
LIAM: Tabaxi with a shell.
MATT: Someone please draw that.
MARISHA: 49 points of necrotic damage.
TRAVIS: Let me roll my Stone's Endurance. Ten plus
my constitution. Minus 16. So 41 minus 16 would be
25.
MARISHA: Where'd that minus 16 go?
TRAVIS: My Stone's Endurance.
MATT: Wait, how much damage was it?
MARISHA: 49.
MATT: Oh, 49. Sorry, minus 16. So it'd be 33.
MARISHA: 42 plus seven is 49, right?
MATT: Keyleth, he screams out in pain as he's
being pushed into the ceiling. His veins bulge
with black energy as the Blight takes hold.
TRAVIS: Not cool!
MARISHA: Sorry!
TRAVIS: No, you're not.
MATT: You're about 50 feet of movement left.
MARISHA: Next is the blue, so let me go to that
back corner a bit more. That's good.
MATT: There you are. Ending Keyleth's turn, Percy,
you're up.
TALIESIN: I'm going to exit out the door and I'm
going to take a run back over here. This way.
(counting)
MATT: 30, if you wanted to get there.
SAM: Are you jumping across the river?
TALIESIN: I don't even know if I'm actually
jumping?
SAM: Does he have to leave the ground to jump
across?
TALIESIN: I was actually going to walk, to be
fair.
MARISHA and TALIESIN: I see what you're doing.
TALIESIN: Am I in the range of it at that point?
MATT: I don't know, are you?
TALIESIN: Where's the--?
MATT: You don't know. You didn't see.
TALIESIN: I was planning on walking, but I'm fine
either way. If you make a roll for it, I'll make a
dex roll.
MATT: Make a dex roll.
TALIESIN: It's a dex save? All right. 19?
MATT: No.
TALIESIN: Was it not? Just for fun, let's burn--
MATT: Indomitable?
TALIESIN: Let's burn a resolve.
MATT: Indomitable you mean, right?
TALIESIN: It's reroll a save?
MATT: Yeah.
TALIESIN: I wrote it down weirdly because I was
trying to conserve space. Yeah, no.
TRAVIS: I have a playmate!
MATT: Percival, you go firing up into the ceiling
as you attempt to make your way across the river.
Technically, you're one higher than that, but
that's fine. Make a constitution saving throw as
you get thrust up.
TALIESIN: Constitution saving throw. (counting)
24.
MATT: That's a success. You suffer 21 halved to
ten points of force damage. You and Grog are now
within visual range of each other, being pushed
into the force field ceiling.
TALIESIN: I still have my action. There's no way I
can use spider climb on the force wall, is there?
MATT: You can certainly try.
TALIESIN: Oh, I have to roll concentration.
MATT: You do.
SAM: For what?
TALIESIN: The silence spell. What is that?
MATT: That's a constitution saving throw.
TALIESIN: Okay, same thing. 16?
MATT: 16 succeeds. It's a DC ten.
TALIESIN: This is interesting.
MATT: It is. What are you going to do?
SAM: We're all flying now.
TALIESIN: I'm going to try and right myself and see
if I can put my boots on and walk on the ceiling.
MATT: As your feet touch the surface, they find
some purchase. It's like walking on a water bed.
They seem to be holding somewhat, but that's the
full of your movement.
TRAVIS: That's fascinating. Those boots are
ridiculous.
SAM: Water bed.
TALIESIN: That'll do.
MARISHA: Remember when there were water beds? Good
times.
TALIESIN: Those were such a pain in the ass.
MARISHA: Terrible for your back.
MATT: Scanlan, it's your turn.
SAM: I'm still walking across this room as fast as
my little feets can carry me. And I'm kind of out
of low-level spells at this point.
MATT: You can cast it at a higher level, it
just--
SAM: But it won't be a bonus action anymore, will
it?
MARISHA: 9th-level Healing Word. Do it.
SAM: Can I do a bonus action at a higher level if
I don't do a spell for my action?
MATT: You could sacrifice a higher-level spell
slot to cast a level two Healing Word as a bonus
action.
SAM: Ugh. Wow.
MATT: But you'd lose a higher-level spell slot
with only getting the bonuses of a level two
spell. That I'll allow.
SAM: That is insane. I will not do that yet. No,
I'll do that. I'm so down. Okay. Oh yeah.
MATT: What level do you use?
SAM: Level three. So that heals me another 12
points. Yeah man.
MATT: So that's your turn?
SAM: That's my bonus action. Then I'll use my
action to sneak out and look-- Oh wait! I can get
out and around back here, right? I'll do that. And
when I get out the door I'm looking around. What
do I see? I see everybody floating in the air?
This is crazy.
MATT: You see Keyleth over here. Both Grog and
Percival being held against the forcefield.
Percival seems to have righted himself and his
feet are actually affixed to the field and now is
walking, trying to move across it.
SAM: Do I let them go? I need help finding Vax,
but I don't even know if they're on my side right
now! They haven't responded to my text!
TRAVIS: We're on your side! Let me down!
SAM: Okay, then I'm going to release the gravity.
MATT: Okay. And with that, the gravity subsides.
TALIESIN: Do I fall?
MATT: No, you are held aloft. Grog, however,
plummets to the ground for 80 feet.
TRAVIS: Do I get to use the action to hit the
button on the rod somewhere?
MATT: As a reaction, you do. Where do you hit the
rod? At what height?
TRAVIS: I'll hit it at 20 feet above the ground.
MATT: 20 feet above the ground.
TRAVIS: Making that Halo dive.
MATT: Grog, make a strength check. I'm working on
it. Don't worry.
TRAVIS: 27.
MATT: 27, yeah. You manage to hold tight. Your
muscles strain from the falling impact of catching
yourself there.
LIAM: Does he immediately start doing one-arm
pushups?
MATT: Essentially, yeah. You suffer one point of
damage. Rolled a one on that one. From just muscle
strain.
TRAVIS: But the muscle's going to get that much
bigger.
MATT: No, it is. The muscle kind of pops out of
the socket and you wrench it back in with the
sheer force of your shoulder and back muscles.
LIAM: Micro-tears!
MATT: All right, Scanlan. That's your turn? All
right. That brings us to Grog. First and foremost,
you watch as the rooms flash with purple energy.
The water lights up for a second, suffused with
some sort of magical flash and then comes back to
rest. Grog, it's your turn.
TRAVIS: Oh, I'm sorry. I'm singing. I would like
to un-click the rod, actually. Yeah.
MATT: Okay. You fall to the ground, taking eight
points of bludgeoning damage, reduced to four.
SAM: That's first blood.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: All right. Can I run around over here? Do
I see fucking anything?
MATT: You see Keyleth up there. That's it.
Percival, you know, is up there.
TRAVIS: Both totally within range. Is there a door
over there that I can't see? Is there a door over
on this side?
MATT: On this side, the tower? Yeah, there's an
opening on each side, or each corner, yeah.
TRAVIS: Can I get to the door from where I am?
MATT: You can.
TRAVIS: Can I go inside?
MATT: You go inside? All right.
MARISHA: I'm so stealthy, I've lost myself.
MATT: So that's your action? So you get inside
there. You are now at the center of the tower.
I'll put you down there just because you're big
for the tower size.
MARISHA: Going assassin this time. Or thief? You
were assassin last time.
MATT: All right, ending Grog's turn. Vax.
LIAM: Troll text, coming your way!
MARISHA: Goddamn it. You are the literal worst.
LIAM: I know. Damn it, went to fix a typo I sent
to him and it just did it again. It said "basted"
instead of "hasted."
MATT: Technically you can't do that.
LIAM: Oh, okay. So then--
MATT: Not as that type of action.
SAM: He's sending you a gif right now of Dramatic
Chipmunk.
TALIESIN: That was well done, Grog. I'll tell you
later, but I had plans and you foiled a chunk of
them.
TRAVIS: Oh, okay. There's not a lot I can do. I'm
just chasing a bunch of people I can't see.
LIAM: I can do that. Sure!
MATT: So you're not doing the first thing?
LIAM: No, you said I couldn't do the first thing.
MATT: Not as a hasted action.
LIAM: Fuck, man.
TRAVIS: Oh, for the love of god.
LIAM: Okay, can I reverse that? I can reverse
that, right? If you go back to the first thing?
MATT: You can't hold a hasted action.
LIAM: Sure, but I have a regular action, right? So
I'll do it on the regular action.
MATT: Okay. The first thing you said?
LIAM: Yes, the first thing I said.
MATT: Okay. Scanlan, Keyleth. You watch as this
chamber over here, billowing fog emerges from this
chamber over here. The entire outside of this room
is now completely surrounded in fog.
SAM: We've got a rogue.
LIAM: Right, sorry. Yep. Good, but, yep. I'm
good.
TRAVIS: What the fuck did you just say?!
LIAM: On a hasted action, I can only attack. I
can't cast spells, which is what I suggested. But
if I just flip what I do where, I should be
relatively okay.
MATT: Yeah, but you can't hold a hasted action.
LIAM: Then I'll do the second thing.
MATT: That fog cloud's out.
LIAM: I understand, because that's not part of the
second thing.
MARISHA: So wait, is the fog cloud there or no?
MATT: The fog cloud's there.
LIAM: What am I supposed to do? Announce every
move to you guys while I'm hidden? It defeats the
purpose!
TALIESIN: If I tell you what I'm playing next game
will you just stop this?
LIAM: Dick, dick, dick!
MATT: Keyleth, it's your turn. You just watched
this fog billow out from the open doorway and
surround--
LIAM: I thought you said it was out?
MARISHA: No, he means it is literally out.
LIAM: Oh, out the door?
SAM: There's no door!
MATT: The door is open.
TALIESIN: The door got exploded.
MATT: Yeah, the door is shattered by Grog, so you
went in the chamber and fog cloud fills and
encompasses the surrounding area.
TRAVIS: I should go check that out.
MARISHA: I'm going to hover over--
LIAM: It's fine, it's fine.
MARISHA: First smoke. Where there's smoke, there
must be a Vax, so I'm going to hover over a little bit.
MATT: Okay, how far over?
MARISHA: Move me up 30 feet or so. Or 60 feet.
That's good.
MATT: That's 50 feet there.
MARISHA: And then I'm going to be like, Hey boo, I
recognize that spell. That's some druid shit! And
then I'm going to light up the entire area with a
Fire Storm.
MATT: Okay. All around it.
MARISHA: Radiating outward. Ten of them.
MATT: So you hear this and time slows for a
second. Over the earring. As you hear this small
whine, this (high-pitched whine) (explosion) And
it's nothing but bright light and flames around
you. It completely engulfs the chamber you're in
and around it. You guys watch and, I'll say this,
I'm going to say it burns off the fog cloud.
LIAM: So she did it inside the building?
MATT: Inside the building, all around it. So I
need you to go ahead and make a dexterity saving
throw.
LIAM: I'm not worried. Hold on, say that again?
MATT: Dexterity saving throw.
LIAM: Yeah, that's right. I'm going to use my
second Luck of the day. Oh, that's good. That's
real good. That's a 29.
MATT: All right. You've managed to dive behind
where the chest was open from Grog earlier, jump
into the chest, and slam it closed, just as the
flames engulf the interior, burning the outside
of the-- He's a little man. As it burns the
exterior of the chest, you manage to avoid all
damage from the spell.
SAM: Is it a refrigerator?
MARISHA: All damage?
MATT: He has evasion as a rogue. If he succeeds a
dexterity saving throw, he takes no damage.
TRAVIS: I love how cocky he is when he's like, I'm
going to die!
LIAM: I am going to die! It's just, later. You
three don't know shit.
TALIESIN: Actually, I saw that.
MATT: Yep. As the firestorm dissipates, that chest
is destroyed. You kick off the smoking bits of it.
MARISHA: At least I've taken out all y'all's
health potions. That was part of the goal.
MATT: Keyleth, you're going to stay where you
are?
MARISHA: I'll back up a little bit. Trying to stay
away from Scanlan. Wait, what's your range?
TALIESIN: My range is there is no getting away
from me. I have a minimum range of 400 feet. There
is nowhere to hide.
MARISHA: If I drop down behind the tower, could I
not be seen by Percy? Fly across this way?
TALIESIN: My shitty gun has a 400-foot range.
SAM: But it can't go through stone.
TALIESIN: No, it can't. Yet. I will make ghost
bullets one day.
TRAVIS: I would try to run up and grapple you or
throw something at you, but you're made of fucking
wind.
MARISHA: That's your only evasion that you have,
right?
LIAM: No, man, that's unlimited.
MATT: Keyleth, with the rest of your movement and
descending, actually you'd probably get about
there.
MARISHA: Until you get hit? You can keep doing
that until-- Wait, but I thought you have one that
gives you half damage and one that's all damage?
LIAM: I'm not telling you anything about my rules. You
can figure it out.
MATT: As you've seen Vax through the entirety of
your gameplay, you'd know that if he has to make a
dexterity saving throw, if he fails, he takes half
damage. If he succeeds, he takes none. Or he can
use his reaction to take half damage from a
melee.
MARISHA: A reaction?
LIAM: Since your husband told you, reaction is if
you try to hit me with a sword, and I can only do
that once per round.
MATT: Or any attack.
LIAM: Right, melee attack.
MATT: Oh, yeah, from any melee.
LIAM: Evasion is just dexterity saves. So use that
information. You can use that information,
Marisha.
TALIESIN: You know what doesn't take a dexterity
save? Sending to another dimension.
LIAM: Dimensions, Finger of Death. I mean it's
inevitable. You're going to kill me eventually.
It's true!
MATT: Level 20 rogue. Playing this for five years.
Still don't know how Uncanny Dodge works. "When an
"attacker you can see hits you with an attack." As
long as you can see them, you can reduce it by
half.
LIAM: I never claimed to memorize this book,
people. Next campaign, I'm going to fuck it up
just as much. If that bothers you--
MATT: That was the other ability. Evasion is the
one that he used. Yeah, evasion's every time.
You're good. All right, so that finishes Keyleth's
turn. You managed to dodge out of Percival's view.
Percy, you're up. Top of the round I need you to
make a constitution saving throw, because even
though you're standing on the ceiling, you're
still against the force.
TALIESIN: That's fine. Constitution saving throw,
let's do this. I've got a plan. I'm going to use
my second resolve, or my second thing,
Indomitable. Let's hope that's better. That's way
better, 19.
MATT: 19 will succeed, yeah, because it's an 18.
All right, so.
TALIESIN: And now I'm going to try and do
something stupid.
MATT: All right, so you suffer the 11 points of
force damage, reduced to five. Five points of
force damage and you are not jettisoned off the
force field. So it's considered rough terrain for
you to move across.
TALIESIN: Here's what I'm going to do. I'm going
to use 25 points of my movement to run.
MATT: Okay, it's rough terrain, so--
TALIESIN: Oh. I'm going to use my movement to run
15 feet.
MATT: 15, you're just--
TALIESIN: I'm going to try and take a running jump
to the top of the tower.
MATT: Okay, so you're going to leap and release
the boots? Make an acrobatics check, please. As
you go and try and leap for it--
TALIESIN: All right, acrobatics check. Come on,
baby. That's 23.
MATT: 23? All right, so you reduce the damage you
take from the leap.
TALIESIN: That's a much better fall than I was
going to get.
MATT: It would've been 18 points of bludgeoning
damage, reduced to nine. Nine points of
bludgeoning damage.
TALIESIN: And then I have to do another
constitution saving throw for the silence spell?
MATT: Correct. Well, first from the-- You have to
make it twice.
TALIESIN: Oh. 23.
MATT: And another one for the impact. One was for
the force field and one was for the fall.
TALIESIN: Natural 20.
MATT: Yeah, you're fine.
TALIESIN: And then, so I'm 23 points in. Is it
worth blowing any of this? Yeah. Am I feeling the
healing?
MATT: No, your movement dropped you outside of the
circle.
TALIESIN: All right. I'm going to use what little
I have left--
MATT: You have no more movement.
TALIESIN: I have no more movement, even from a
double-up? Using my action?
MATT: Oh, if you use your action for a dash? Then
you can get there, yeah.
TALIESIN: I'm going to use my action for a dash to
stand on the trap. Like, stand right to the trap,
yeah.
MATT: Well the trapdoor you blew open, so it's
currently open. So you stand right at the edge of
it.
TALIESIN: I stand there and I'm waiting to see
what the hell is going on at this point.
MATT: Okay, ending Percival's turn. Scanlan,
you're up.
SAM: Scanlan's up. Scanlan's going to peek around
the corner.
MATT: You see Keyleth floating there. You see the
flames burst around this interior, the fog cloud
dissipates.
SAM: I'm going to throw in a Firebolt right in the
front door. Wand of Fireballs.
MATT: Okay. How many?
SAM: Two charges. That's 9d6.
LIAM: Where you at, girl?
MARISHA: To quote the rogue: You don't know.
MATT: You kick off the broken chest. Right as you
right yourself, a beam of red light goes into the
room, explodes a second time. Make a dexterity
save with a DC of--
SAM: 15.
LIAM: 20.
MATT: Yeah, so no damage. You're like, "Oh god!"
You leap out of the way and as you pull your cloak
up and the cloak burns and singes on the outside,
but you manage to avoid the damage as you flatten
up against the wall.
SAM: I got him, guys! He's real rough!
TRAVIS: Two fireballs in a bunker and no damage.
MATT: Unfortunately, that's exactly the kind of
thing that rogues are really good at avoiding.
They're an up-close or lock-down type scenario or
they're going to be jumping around all your booms.
Scanlan, that's your action.
SAM: Bonus action, I'm going to put on Gloves of
Swim/Climb. I think I got them in Pathfinder. I
don't know what they are.
MATT: They'll give you advantage on climbing
checks.
MARISHA: They're climbing flippers?
SAM: Great. That's it.
MATT: That's your turn. Grog.
TRAVIS: Yeah. What's up?
MATT: Top of your turn. The braziers on the sides
of the tower burst into flame, incinerating all the
space around, which affects Keyleth, who is hiding
behind the side of the tower. I need you to make a
dexterity saving throw.
MARISHA: I thought the circles were going?
TRAVIS: Nope. It's the fire.
MARISHA: The fires? Did I get behind?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MARISHA: Goddamn it. That's fine.
MATT: Because the water glowed last time.
MARISHA: Dex saving throw? 15.
MATT: Nope. That is 30 points of fire damage to
you. As the flames subside, your wind form is
burned a bit. Grog, you're up.
TRAVIS: Would it be stupid to try to grapple a
wind elemental? There's not really anything to
grab, right?
MATT: I don't know. You hear the wind whipping
around outside, but you don't see anything.
TRAVIS: Could I step out the door? Like five
feet.
MATT: You look up immediately and see Keyleth
floating there in elemental form after the flames
subside.
TRAVIS: All right, let's just try it because fuck
it. Can I use my boots of feral leaping to make a
15-foot vertical leap with a DC of 16?
MATT: You can. She's 20 feet up in the air,
though. You glance up and she's 20 feet up.
TRAVIS: Just too much. Could I try and climb up
the side of the tower?
MATT: Sure. Make an athletics check.
TRAVIS: 18.
MATT: Yeah, you're able to get up to about her
height. You're technically base-to-base with her
against the side of the tower.
TRAVIS: Cool. I'm going to leap off the tower and
try to grab onto Keyleth.
MATT: Make a grapple check.
MARISHA: I am immune to grapple.
MATT: I know, but I want him to roll it.
TRAVIS: Okay. What can I do in this game? Zero
because you're immune to grapple.
MATT: Grog, you fall through and land on the
ground prone and partially in the water. You
suffer eight points of bludgeoning damage, reduced
to four.
SAM: First blood.
TRAVIS: Cool.
MATT: You also notice the field that surrounds the
chambers shifts in a bit. Scanlan, make a
constitution saving throw. You watch as it all
closes in by five feet.
SAM: 28!
MARISHA: He put a time limit on this whole thing.
TALIESIN: Good man.
MATT: You take 11 points of force damage and you
are not forced out of the way. However, you are up
against it being pushed against the wall, you have
to squeeze out of it. You can see it slowly
condensing itself. As it does, you glance up at
the sky and see this grinning, mysterious visage
made of cloud swirling energy. A grinning beard.
That's the end of Grog's turn. Vax, you're up.
LIAM: Okay. I've got movement, bonus action,
hasted action, and my regular action. I'm going to use
movement and bonus action to blast out of that
door. Everybody sees me arc up into the sky and
fly over this tower and disappear here. I'll tell
you what happens next via text.
SAM: We got a little Liam there! Liam talked!
MARISHA: It's a bottle rocket! Oh wait, nope.
MATT: You saw him disappear somewhere down below
there. As far as you know, as a marker, somewhere
in that area you saw Vax vanish.
TRAVIS: Fucking flying motherfucker.
MATT: Keyleth, your turn.
MARISHA: Okay. My turn. I've got a prone Grog in
front of me.
SAM: Yeah, man.
MARISHA: I'm going to do something great, right?
TRAVIS: Yep, fire it up.
MARISHA: Shit. But what to do? (grumbles) Oh god.
MATT: I'm confused by that image.
LIAM: Okay. I'm going to elaborate.
MATT: Keyleth, what're you doing?
MARISHA: Sorry, Grog. I'm going to try this one
more time.
TRAVIS: Do it, please. End my suffering.
MARISHA: I'm going to land.
TRAVIS: Give me some kind of contact with another
being.
MATT: You slowly descend, swirling wind arms.
MARISHA: I'm going to drop my form.
MATT: The wind form shifts out and Keyleth
descends, landing right down with you.
TRAVIS: Hey, Ki.
MARISHA: I'm going to say: Don't save against
this! And I'm going to try Plane Shift! Because it
fucking failed last time!
MATT: What's the saving throw on that?
MARISHA: Mine, 21.
MATT: No, but what's the saving throw?
MARISHA: I think it's wisdom.
MATT: Grog, I need you to make a wisdom saving
throw.
TRAVIS: No problem. Modifier is zero. Five.
MATT: Where are you shifting him to?
MARISHA: Do you have any preference on your
demise?
SAM: Demise!
TRAVIS: I don't know. Send me to the Ethereal--
no. Send me to Feywild.
MARISHA: No. That's too nice.
TRAVIS: Fuck you!
(laughter)
MARISHA: My original plan was to teleport you to
the middle of the water dimension, just have you
slowly drown.
SAM and TALIESIN: Sounds pretty awesome.
LIAM: That's merciful.
MARISHA: Or my other idea was to send you to the
Maze of the Abyss.
LIAM: Nah, water is a minute or less, right?
MARISHA: Yeah, we'll go to the water.
MATT: Grog, as Keyleth embraces you, there's a
shifting of energy. There's a flash as you see the
Divine Gate coast past you. Suddenly, you're in
the dark depths of a familiar ocean.
TRAVIS: Figures.
MATT: You're holding your breath. You know with
your constitution, you can hold your breath for a
decent amount of time. As you glance down into the
darkness of the shadow below you, you see movement
as a series of long, familiar tentacles begin to
emerge from the shadows below. You think, "Let's
"make this a final, glorious way to go."
TRAVIS: Do I?
MATT: I don't know, do you?
TRAVIS: Probably not.
MATT: You slowly clam up as you sink down as the
kraken takes you into its maw and swallows you.
MARISHA: I feel so bad!
TRAVIS: Fight on!
MARISHA: Man, that doesn't feel good.
MATT: First one down.
MARISHA: It doesn't feel good to be a bully,
everyone, let this be a lesson.
TRAVIS: Doesn't feel good to be a level 20
barbarian with these strong motherfuckers. Chasing
your damn tail.
MARISHA: I still have movement, yeah.
MATT: You have, in this form, 15 feet.
TRAVIS: I also don't have a Deck, for anybody
that's wondering. There's no Deck of Many Things.
MARISHA: Scanlan dropped his Reverse Gravity,
yeah?
MATT: Correct.
MARISHA: Scanlan's there.
LIAM: I sent a clarification.
MARISHA: Do I have enough movement to move over
there? Actually, you know what? No one's in the
tower, right? You went over there. Oh, shit.
Goddamn it.
LIAM: Such a question, isn't it?
MARISHA: Do I have my bonus action still? I do,
right?
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: I'm going to use my bonus action to turn
into an earth elemental.
MATT: Is it a bonus action to drop form?
MARISHA: Oh fuck, yeah. It is.
MATT: I'll double-check.
MARISHA: Let me go over there. I can't reach.
MATT: Yep, it's a bonus action to revert, so you
have to be in Keyleth form. You have 15 feet of
movement.
MARISHA: I'm going to use my awesome mantle which
allows me to jump.
MATT: What's your strength?
MARISHA: What?
MATT: What's your strength score?
MARISHA: Just my modifier?
MATT: Your strength score.
MARISHA: My strength score is 14, so I have plus
two to my strength.
MATT: That's the distance you can jump in feet is
your strength score. So triple that, you can jump
pretty far.
MARISHA: Let me jump behind there. Do I have
enough, with the rest of my movement, can I get
inside this building?
MATT: No, that would be part of your movement.
MARISHA: Then I'll stay there.
MATT: Okay. Finishing Keyleth's turn, Percival,
you're up. You heal 20 hit points.
SAM: That's nice!
TALIESIN: I'm going to head this way on the tower.
(counting) Do I see Keyleth?
MATT: Make a perception check.
TALIESIN: I'm down for that. That's a terrible
roll. That's 16.
MATT: She's not hiding, so you do see the very
edge of her. He has an eyeline to the very edge of
you. That's as far as you can get with your
movement. She has three-quarters cover.
TALIESIN: That doesn't matter to me. How far away
is she?
MATT: You're eyeballing maybe about 45, 50 feet.
TALIESIN: I'm going to do something really weird.
I'm going to pull out the Iron Bands of Bilarro.
I'm going to make a toss, try and nail her in the
head. It's got a range of 60 feet.
MATT: It does. Make a ranged attack roll.
LIAM: Take me out to the ball game!
MARISHA: Take me out to the-- what's after that?
TRAVIS: The crowd.
MARISHA: The crowd!
TALIESIN: 30.
SAM: It's a good throw.
MATT: All right. Keyleth, as you're ducking
around, you hear this faint shout in the distance of--
TALIESIN: Manners! Oh, you don't! Does it work?
MATT: No!
MARISHA: I have Freedom of Movement, too, cast on
me.
LIAM: Too late!
MATT: As the band expands and wraps around
Keyleth's body, you watch as she quickly slips out
of the bindings and the chains fall to the ground
before reverting back to a sphere.
TALIESIN: Damn!
LIAM: That's amazing!
TALIESIN: Fucking oh my god! That was clutch!
MARISHA: That was so good!
LIAM: Only because you remembered, holy shit!
MATT: That would have been bad.
TALIESIN: I just saw that happen, didn't I?
MATT: Yeah, you did.
TALIESIN: All right!
MARISHA: Thank god for that fucking 4th-level
spell.
TALIESIN: That was really scary. That was my
attack. I'm going to back off and then go back to
the center of that tower and sit and try to get
three-quarters cover over there. I want to stay in
the green light.
MATT: You're staying there and crouching low.
Ending Percival's turn, Scanlan, you're up. You
can see Keyleth from around.
SAM: I can?
MATT: You pull out of that side there.
SAM: I'm going to dash right towards Keyleth.
MATT: Dash?
SAM: No, just run.
MATT: That's your movement there.
SAM: How far away am I?
MATT: She's about 35, 40 feet.
SAM: So more than 30?
MATT: More than 30, correct.
SAM: Fuck you!
(laughter)
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: Goddamn it.
MATT: 35 feet, yeah.
SAM: Goddamn it! All right, I mean I'll just--
MATT: Sorry, Grog.
TRAVIS: A barbarian's world.
SAM: Sorry, changing my mind, seeing if this
works. What is the save?
MARISHA: Only when we reach level 20, boys, only
when we reach level 20.
SAM: Wisdom? She's so wise!
TALIESIN: Oh, a wise guy?
MARISHA: Early game druids kind of suck, later
games, kind of boss.
SAM: She's not immune to charm, though. I've
already charmed her once. Yeah, fuck it. One more
thing to check, sorry.
LIAM: Sam, 20 levels and you haven't got your
spells in order?
SAM: This is a brand new spell, I've never used
it! What's the range? It's 30 feet, great. I will
Dominate Person.
MATT: Dominate Person for Keyleth.
SAM: Yeah, it's not going to work because she's
super wise, but I'll try.
MATT: Okay, you need to make a wisdom saving
throw. You have advantage because you are
a half-elf, so you have advantage against charm
effects.
LIAM: Oh shit, with her wisdom? Good luck, buddy.
MARISHA: What do I have to save? 22?
SAM: 22.
MARISHA: Let me do the math really quick. Yeah, I'm
all right. I rolled a natural 16.
MATT: Sorry, Scanlan, she resists the spell.
SAM: It's fine. As my bonus action I will say to
her: That spell was an inspiration and we're still
on the same team, right?
MARISHA: I feel so bad I had to teleport Grog
away, but I'm still looking for Vax.
SAM: Okay, me too.
MATT: That finishes your turn. The field shimmies
and crunches even closer. You watch as this
distant building begins to collapse inward.
LIAM: Oh wow, Matt. Oh wow!
MARISHA: Did you turn it in?
MATT: That door's destroyed.
LIAM and MARISHA: Stay turnt.
TRAVIS: The portal's gone.
TALIESIN: So, two squares in all around.
MATT: Two squares in all around.
TALIESIN: I'm in. When we get four we actually
start to remove rock blocks.
SAM: What's up? Who's next?
MATT: Vax.
LIAM: I'm going to use my 120 feet of regular
movement to fly out of my hiding place into the
air. This is probably half my movement, right
about there. I can't see, about there. Don't
worry, this is temporary. I wouldn't do that. I
see Percival, Scanlan, Keyleth. I've used half my
movement about, I would guess. And I'm going to
use my bonus action to use Vow of Enmity on
Keyleth.
MATT: You watch as you suddenly turn and look up
into the sky as you see, giant wings unfolded, Vax
points down at you and with a giant
earth-shattering caw in the sky of a raven cry,
you feel this mark penetrate your chest, as he
marks you with his Vow of Enmity.
LIAM: I want to fly within 60 feet of her using
still my base movement.
MATT: You are about 60 feet here.
LIAM: I will use my regular paladin attack, which
is an attack-attack, to attack her. Which is at
advantage because of the Vow of Enmity.
MATT: Correct.
LIAM: Not great. I'm going to use a Luck. I'm
going to use a Luck. That's better. Not much
better. That is a 20.
MARISHA: Yeah.
LIAM: Right, so here we go, just a little bit,
though. A tickle for you, really. (counting) 28
and that's the first attack and then the second
attack--
MATT: Total of 28 on that one?
LIAM: 28, yeah, total.
MARISHA: 28 what damage?
LIAM: 28 damage. That was a combo, there was some
psychic, there was eight of psychic. Okay, then
the second attack is 25 to hit, which also hits,
but it's much dinkier. So that is eight.
MARISHA: Eight. That's 36 total.
LIAM: So that was movement plus paladin action,
and I will use my hasted action and bonus action.
I'll use my haste so I can go another 60 feet and
I'm going to fly about there. Then I'm going
to use my regular action to-- you guys don't
fucking know. I will tell you where I'm using my
bonus action to hide.
MATT: I'm sorry. What? You moved over, used your
paladin action to attack twice--
LIAM: Attack, attack for paladin action, and I
still have a hasted action and a bonus action. One
can be used for more movement--
MATT: Are you moving somewhere with one of your
actions? Is what I'm asking.
LIAM: 60 feet. Another 60 feet-ish for the base
movement to there. Everybody thinks I don't know
what I'm talking about!
MATT: No, I know. I need clarification because
they need to know where you ran off to. They still
see you. You're still out in the open.
LIAM: So my base movement gets me to probably
about here, and I use my paladin attack to attack
twice, right? So I've got bonus action and a
hasted action left. That is 120 feet left on one,
and then I can use the bonus action to hide.
MATT: I'm so excited for the new campaign.
LIAM: I know! (laughter) Me too!
MATT: This is my own fault.
LIAM: I have a great character planned! I can't
wait, but I know that I can use another 120 feet
from here to get to there, there, there, or there
and a bonus action to hide. It's all in the
fucking book dudes!
MATT: Your movement is 120 feet, which got you to
there, right.
LIAM: Paladin action which is attack-attack, and I
still have hasted action which can be used for
movement--
MATT: Do it. Text me where you are.
LIAM: It's right!
MATT: It's correct! You're completely correct! You
are completely correct. No, don't get shit for it.
You're doing your job. It's just a process to work
out for the scenario of this type of event.
LIAM: Hey man, send a message to Mike Mearls about
the 5th edition handbook. Thanks, Mike Mearls, I
love the handbook.
MARISHA: It's okay, everyone hates me tonight, so
were all in the same boat.
MATT: All righty, ending Vax's turn, Keyleth,
you're up.
MARISHA: Huh?
MATT: You got shanked twice with two daggers after
the Vow of Enmity and watched your Vax vanish off
somewhere in-- which direction?
LIAM: The last anyone saw me is here. Keyleth saw
me here going in this direction.
MATT: You watched him vanish that way right behind
the tower. What are you doing, Keyleth? Percy,
you're on deck.
TRAVIS: Isn't Plane Shift concentration?
MATT: Plane Shift? I don't believe it is. It just
happens.
MARISHA: l will look, though.
MATT: Banishment is concentration, that's probably
what you were thinking of.
MARISHA: I didn't have any concentration spells up
either.
TRAVIS: I just meant if you get hit--
MARISHA: In case you come back. Let me actually
check.
MATT: Keyleth, you're fine. What you got?
MARISHA: Fuck, I hope this doesn't fuck up. Peek
around the corner. Do I see Scanlan?
MATT: Yeah. This whole time you see Scanlan
running up to you and telling you all this.
MARISHA: (laughs) Sure. I'm going to peek around,
see Scanlan and be like: Hey, buddy!
SAM: Hey!
MARISHA: You see Vax?
SAM: He was a blur. Came over, shot at you, and
left.
MARISHA: Cool, good to know. Feeblemind!
SAM: Oh shit! Counterspell level six!
MARISHA: Fail. Well, you still have to roll for
it. Feeblemind level eight.
MATT: Feeblemind is an 8th-level spell. Go ahead
and roll-- (laugh) Okay, hold on.
SAM: Ah wait, the range is 30 feet.
TALIESIN: She moved five feet.
MATT: She did move up to peek, she said.
MARISHA: Range for Feeblemind is 150 feet.
SAM: Oh, okay. Sorry.
MATT: Wait, 60-foot range for Counterspell,
right?
SAM: Probably, yeah.
MATT: I'm pretty sure it is.
SAM: Yeah, It says range 60, it's used as a
reaction.
MATT: Yeah I know, doesn't matter either way. All
right, for you it's a Counterspell.
MARISHA: I should've backed up.
MATT: Yeah, you should've moved. It's all good. I
need you to make an ability check using your
spellcasting ability, so a charisma check.
MARISHA: And what does he have to do?
SAM: Wait, what? No. Counterspell is ten plus the
level, wait, what?
MATT: The DC equals ten plus level of the spell.
You have to roll a check and add your charisma
bonus.
SAM: Got it. So that's 13 plus six is 19.
MATT: 19. You need to beat 18 DC because it's an
8th-level spell you said?
MARISHA: Yes.
MATT: He needs to beat an 18. Counterspelled
Feeblemind.
MARISHA: You rolled a 19?
SAM: Yeah.
MATT: So as she goes to cast Feeblemind you
recognize the incantation from when she used it on
Raishan and you go--
SAM: I go: Verily you are-- bad person!
MATT: As the Feeblemind fades--
MARISHA: Fuck! I should've fucking been out of
range!
SAM: We're both making mistakes!
MARISHA: We're both really good!
SAM: I know.
MARISHA: I respect you so much!
SAM: I do too. We're making stupid mistakes
because we're so anxious.
MARISHA: But we're so good.
SAM: We really are.
MARISHA: We're great. And then I'm going to go to
my earth elemental form. I've still got shit to
do. I'm going to use my movement. Can I jump back
over and run behind the tower this way?
MATT: What's the movement of your elemental
again?
MARISHA: 30 feet. This way.
MATT: (counting) That's as far as you can get
right there.
MARISHA: Instead of curving around, can I just go
straight away from the blue thing? Just in case
the blue thing hurts.
MATT: What's that? You want to go around and
look?
MARISHA: Instead of curving, can I just go further
from the blue thing?
TALIESIN: Remember it's two points in at this
point.
SAM, TALIESIN, and LIAM: (singing) What's that
blue thing doing there?
TALIESIN: Oh man, we did grow up in that era,
didn't we? Oh, that brought it back.
MATT: Last turn when the fields shattered, it did
cause the lighting to go off. I forgot to mention that.
SAM: What lighting?
MARISHA: The blue?
MATT: Yes.
TALIESIN: The one Scanlan was next to?
MATT: Last round both of you were out of range so
I didn't mention it. I forgot about it in the
process, I was focusing on the field.
MARISHA: The blue thing went.
MATT: Yes.
MARISHA: So the circle is up next.
MATT: Possibly. So are you staying in the water?
MARISHA: No, if that's the case, let me step back.
Right there.
MATT: I'll put you there. At the end of Scanlan's
turn--
SAM: That was Keyleth's turn.
MATT: Sorry, Keyleth. You watch as the water and
the two chambers flash and the chamber crushes
even further. This is partially destroyed. And now
you're seeing-- we're using this as a marker--
it's starting to accelerate the destruction in the
interior. Pushing this in here.
LIAM: It's about to get real on the field back.
SAM: Why would Colville do this to us? He's a kind
and gentle lord.
MATT: Using that as a mark. That falls back to
this partially destroyed there.
SAM: Wow. All this work destroyed.
MATT: I know. All righty. Vax, sorry, Percival.
TALIESIN: I'm going to get up right over here.
MATT: I'm confused. The field should happen later
this round, but we'll get to it.
TALIESIN: I'm getting up over here on this point
of the tower and I'm holding my action until I see
even the slightest fucking little black feather
appear anywhere on this field and I'm going to lay
goddamn waste.
MATT: Okay. Ending Percival's turn, Scanlan, your
turn.
SAM: I run after Keyleth and I say: Wait I forgot!
Feeblemind. I will use Wish to cast Feeblemind on her.
MARISHA: All right.
MATT: Keyleth, I need you to make an intelligence
saving throw.
MARISHA: Just straight intelligence? Do I get
anything?
MATT: Whatever your intelligence saving throw is.
MARISHA: As the earth elemental? I keep my mental
stats, though.
MATT: That's right, because it's Wild Shape you
keep your mental stats.
MARISHA: Not that that means anything. Okay.
TALIESIN: Wow. I mean he had to get clutch, didn't
he?
TRAVIS: Drop that motherfucker.
MARISHA: I'm trying to make sure that I don't have
any type of weird resistance--
SAM: To impossible to defeat spells?
(groaning)
MARISHA: Terrible!
MATT: So roll 4d6 psychic damage.
TRAVIS: He's the king for a reason you guys.
MARISHA: He tried to do what he did to me!
SAM: 11.
MATT: So you take 11 points of psychic damage,
Keyleth. Your intelligence and charisma scores
become one. You cannot cast spells, activate magic
items, understand language or communicate in any
intelligible way.
MARISHA: Okay, I take how many? 11 psychic
damage?
LIAM: Wow.
MARISHA: So I'm at 115.
TALIESIN: That's changed things, hasn't it?
MATT: That's a swing cast right there.
TALIESIN: You're still a player.
MARISHA: I'm still going.
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: Don't count me out.
TALIESIN: She's now just a barbarian.
MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Can you shift into things?
TALIESIN: No.
MARISHA: Well, I'm currently shifted.
TALIESIN: She can't unshift.
MARISHA: Casting a spell isn't considered a part
of Wild Shape.
MATT: Wild Shape is not casting a spell, it's an
ability. She can still Wild Shape.
SAM: She can still fucking Wild Shape every turn.
MARISHA: It's an inherent druid nature ability,
it's not a spell.
LIAM: Would you know to do that in a frenzy?
MATT: It's not a frenzy.
MARISHA: Who, me?
MATT: Scanlan.
SAM: Yes. I'll duck somewhere so she can't see
me.
MATT: We'll say you got that far. Do you move in
there?
SAM: You said Feeblemind has a super long range,
right? I didn't move at all. I'm going to move
back over this way.
MATT: We'll put you there. It's my fault for
moving you. That finishes Scanlan's turn. Now the
field crushes in where it should've before. That was my
fault for doing it out of turn. Also, the flames
burst around the chamber. Percival, where are you
right now?
TALIESIN: I was just inside, over here.
MATT: You duck out of the way as the flames--
TALIESIN: I'm keeping an eye out.
MATT: That brings us to Vax's turn.
LIAM: Okay, I need to ask a question. Here it
comes.
MATT: My phone's starting to get low on battery.
LIAM: I'm plugged in by a computer.
MATT: Okay. Yes.
LIAM: I'm going to use paladin attack-attack.
That's good. Even better. That's 33 to hit.
MATT: Percival, what's your armor class?
TALIESIN: 18. That's fine.
MATT: Steps and is throwing daggers from the trap
door. He's inside the tower and rushed up.
TALIESIN: This means I get to take my attacks.
MATT: You do. After his first attack.
TALIESIN: That's fine.
LIAM: 38 on the first. Does he attack between my
two daggers?
MATT: It's his reaction. He hits as soon as your
first attack hits.
LIAM: 38 on the first.
TALIESIN: How much?
LIAM: 38.
MATT: 38 points of piercing damage to you.
TALIESIN: That's fine.
LIAM: Some of it's psychic, but who's counting?
MATT: Technically, no. You'd finish your action, which
is your attack action, and then he does all of his.
LIAM: Good. 25. That hit?
TALIESIN: 25 hits.
LIAM: That's eight.
MATT: Eight points of piercing damage.
LIAM: I will dump venom into it. You have to
succeed a DC 15.
MATT: Constitution saving throw.
TALIESIN: Yeah. Like 23.
MATT: Yeah, you're fine. As you throw both
daggers, you watch as Percival spins around with--
which weapon?
TALIESIN: I was going to use Animus.
MATT: With Animus and goes for his four attacks.
LIAM: Bring it.
TALIESIN: I can do real attacks because this is my
real--
MATT: Yeah, you were holding your action. You can
spend any grit you've got.
TALIESIN: This is sharpshooter. No, he's hard to hit
the first time.
MATT: He doesn't have that. Remember, Kerr took
away his cloak a long time ago.
TALIESIN: Cool. Sharpshooter.
LIAM: I was going to say I peeked up, but he's
sharpshooter.
TALIESIN: Sharpshooter plus I'm going to do
deadeye because I really want to hit this.
LIAM: You've only got four chances.
TALIESIN: That crits.
LIAM: What'd you roll?
TALIESIN: 19.
LIAM: And?
TALIESIN: Three.
LIAM: I'll use my last Luck. You have to reroll
the 19.
TALIESIN: Can you do that?
LIAM: Yes, I can. On attacks, yes I can.
SAM: He's checking if you do it before the roll or
not.
MATT: No.
LIAM: And it's my last Luck, so your next three
are clear. Absolutely can you use Luck on other
people's stuff.
SAM: I am calling it now: Keyleth still wins.
LIAM: And I can't remember if it's my third Luck
or fourth, so we're just going to call it my
fourth Luck.
MATT: You roll a d20 and choose whether.
LIAM: That's a two!
MATT: So the first attack misses.
TALIESIN: The first attack just misses? He can
just negate it.
MATT: He gets to choose whether you take his roll
or yours. He rolled a two.
LIAM: You've got three more shots. Of course
you're going to shoot me.
TALIESIN: I don't get my grit back, then? I
already marked it, it's fine. Let's do that again.
Let's twist again like we did last summer.
LIAM: Good old 11 Lucks Vax.
TALIESIN: That's a 26 to hit.
LIAM: Sure, that hits. I'll use Uncanny Dodge on
this one since I can see him.
TALIESIN: 1d10 plus 1d6 psychic, which is three,
four, five.
LIAM: First blood.
TALIESIN: Where's my brain? That's 23 points.
MATT: So you take 11.
TALIESIN: My third hit. Here we go.
MATT: You spending another grit?
TALIESIN: I'm spending another grit. Yeah, it'll
be no fun. No, I'm not going to spend another
grit. Still sharpshooter. That's 23 to hit.
LIAM: Just hits!
TALIESIN: I'm rolling so poorly. 20 points of
damage, plus five psychic, so 25.
LIAM: That's first blood.
TALIESIN: I can't spend an action surge in this
round, can I? On a held action.
MATT: On your turn is how it happens. Double check
for you, but I'm pretty sure. On your turn.
LIAM: You've got one more shot. Come on. Draw
blood.
TALIESIN: I'm going to use Thunderwave instead of
shooting.
MATT: Thunderwave is an action, it's not an
attack.
TALIESIN: That's fair. I would have done that at
the beginning if I would have thought about it.
Same thing. 15, so that hits. 26 to hit.
LIAM: Definitely.
TALIESIN: That's 24 points of damage.
LIAM: Gotcha.
MATT: That ends your reaction. That ends your
attacks. You can take the rest of your turn.
LIAM: Question. Is the green beam still there?
Does it do anything? Are you going to tell me
later? Just throwing it out there.
MATT: You can feel the warmth around you, but it's
not doing anything immediately. You have to start
your turn there.
LIAM: Those were my two actions, right? I don't
need to disengage because I'm not within melee.
Right back down. That was-- okay.
TALIESIN: Oh, I have to roll to see if I keep my
spell. Con save.
MATT: Go for it.
TALIESIN: 25.
MATT: 25 succeeds on the first one. Roll again for
the second one.
TALIESIN: 25.
MATT: You still maintain it. That finishes Vax's
turn. Keyleth, you're up.
MARISHA: Do I see Vax at all? Probably not.
MATT: No, you do not see Vax at all.
MARISHA: I'm going to use my bonus action to turn
into a water elemental and swan dive into the
water. Then I'm going to swim over to the edge of
the pond where Scanlan is. 90 feet.
MATT: You're right over.
MARISHA: Yep. I'm going to come out of the water
and I'm--
SAM: How does she know where I am?!
MARISHA: You fucking Feebleminded! I can still
see, motherfucker! I still have eyes! I'm going to
come out of the water and I'm going to attempt to
whelm him.
SAM: What's that even mean? Not overwhelmed, just
whelmed.
MARISHA: Whelm. Make a strength saving throw.
SAM: A strength saving throw. Okay. These aren't
good. 14.
MARISHA: Failure!
SAM: Can I Cutting Words? No, right?
MATT: No, it's your own check.
MARISHA: It's an attack. You take 2d8 bludgeoning
damage.
MATT: You can Cutting Words to reduce the damage
if you'd like to.
MARISHA: 11 plus four, so 15 damage. You are
grappled and unable to breathe.
SAM: Jesus!
MARISHA: Do I still have movement?
MATT: You do. You have about 30 feet of movement
left. Probably about 20, since you did use some of
your movement to get into the water.
MARISHA: That's okay. I just want to take my
grapple with him and my whelm and take him back
under into this creek.
SAM: You can do that?
MARISHA: Yes.
SAM: You can hit, grab, and pull all on one
action?
MARISHA: Whelm. It's my ability. I'm basically a
big elemental and you're stuck inside of me.
SAM: But like, Bigby's Hand can either hit or
grab, not hit and grab and pull.
TALIESIN: Bigby's Hand is not a beast.
MATT: It's a different effect, unfortunately. Let
me see here.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I forgot to bleed you. Damn. It's
okay.
MATT: Yeah, you are restrained and unable to
breathe.
SAM: And she's pulling me away?
MARISHA: I mean, you're stuck inside of me until
further notice.
MATT: Yeah, because you're whelmed and he's a tiny
gnome, yeah. So you pull him into the water. So
you're in her space currently, inside Keyleth's
elemental form, unable to get out and pulled under
the water. Keyleth, does that end your turn?
MARISHA: Yes.
MATT: Percival.
MARISHA: And I'm now under the water, hiding with
Scanlan inside of my belly.
LIAM: You should check hoo-ha.
MATT: I'm checking.
TALIESIN: I assume, because he's got five billion
feet of range, that he is long gone?
MATT: You get the sense that he is not just beyond
that door.
TALIESIN: Cool. I'm going to shift to the other
side of the tower, stay in the healing range, and
hold my goddamn-- I'm going to run over here, stay
in the little green light, hold my fucking action
until I see feather. I'm up and ready.
MATT: All right, that ends your turn, Percival?
TALIESIN: And do I heal, since I'm in the green?
MATT: No, because you started your turn out of it.
The green has to be inside the center circle.
TALIESIN: In that case, I'll use my bonus action
to down a healing potion.
MATT: Go for it. Scanlan, you're up.
LIAM: Did the green beam do anything for me or did
it not work?
MATT: You have to start your turn in the beam in
order to get the effect.
SAM: So her intelligence and charisma went to one,
but her wisdom still exists? Okay. Good to know.
All right. Can I use verbally-based spells?
MATT: We said previously that you can still cast
underwater.
SAM: Okay. Then I will cast underwater and cast
Dimension Door.
MARISHA: Aw, I knew he was going to do that!
TALIESIN: Does he have to be able to talk in order
to do that?
SAM: We just asked that.
MATT: We previously established in the kraken
battle that you guys were able to cast spells
underwater. That continues here.
SAM: And I will, since I don't know where I am, I
will bamf to a place that I do know, which is--
where would I go? Let's go to the room across the
water over there.
MATT: Which room?
SAM: Right there, near the PacMan teleporter.
Yeah.
MATT: Okay. Inside the room?
SAM: Yeah, closer to the water's edge, but yes.
MATT: Okay, there we go. All right. At the end of
your turn, the field crushes in further. It's now
moving faster and faster, moving ten feet at a
time.
LIAM: This is the end.
TALIESIN: (singing) My only friend, the end.
MATT: Well no, the lightning towers would go off,
but they do not because they have been slowly
crushed and destroyed, eaten by the field.
MARISHA: The blue? Does that mean it skips?
LIAM: Yeah. I will use a bonus action to dump all
my Lay on Hands back into myself. So that's the
first thing. And I will--
MATT, TRAVIS, and TALIESIN: Bless you.
LIAM: You know, I will fucking stay put. Then I'll
tell you.
MATT: Okay. Keyleth, your turn.
MARISHA: It's my turn already? Okay.
MATT: The numbers are getting down and half the
party's just staying in place, doing nothing, so
your turn.
TRAVIS: Especially one of them.
MARISHA: Okay, I pop my head out of the water. Do
I see anybody?
MATT: Currently, no. You are alone on the
battlefield.
MARISHA: Okay. I'm going to switch to an earth
elemental. I'm going to come out of the water. I'm
going to walk over to the edge of the tower. I'm
going to be like, fuck whoever's in this shit! And
go boom, and start bringing this tower down with
my Siege Monster.
MATT: Go ahead and roll an attack against the
tower.
MARISHA: Do I have to roll to hit still?
MATT: Yes, you do.
MARISHA: First attack, 14.
MATT: 14 hits. It's an easy-to-hit tower. Go ahead
and roll damage.
MARISHA: Okay, that's 2d8 plus five.
MATT: You get two slam attacks?
MARISHA: I do. That's 15, wait. Yes. 15 damage,
doubled, right? So 30? And then second attack.
Much better than that. It was a natural 12, so
plus eight. So 20.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: Yeah!
MATT: So Percival, you feel this impact on the
tower. What's going on? (impact) As the back half
of it begins to crumble and collapse backwards.
TALIESIN: All right. I can't use any of my held
action to run, because that was not my intention.
MATT: No. This all begins to fall and crumble. Oh
man, this is going to be interesting. We'll say
for the purposes of this, I'll turn it this way.
Yeah, it's all falling apart at this point, which
works fine.
MARISHA: Fuck all y'all! I'm stupid and angry!
TALIESIN: Regardless, my reaction will be to run
away from where it's falling.
MATT: Yeah, this is all just falling down. There
is a little bit of this that's still hanging on
there. Large portion of the tower is collapsed and
is unusable. Percival, you crumble and slide off
and fall into the ground.
TALIESIN: Shoes.
MATT: I know. You're attaching to it as it falls
so go ahead-- Are you just staying onto it?
TALIESIN: Yeah, I'm holding on for dear life.
MATT: All right. So you do not make an acrobatics
check and it crumbles beneath you. The rocks begin
to grind and tear into you as you fall in with
it.
TALIESIN: Okay, so I wouldn't try and dodge? I
don't get a dodge for any of that?
MATT: Not if you're adhering to it and it
collapses inward.
TALIESIN: Oh, I mean, I didn't know the situation.
I was just trying to be safe.
MATT: Okay. It's falling back and then crumbling
inwards.
TALIESIN: Oh yeah, no, no, no.
MATT: Make an acrobatics check.
TALIESIN: Okay, sorry, yeah. I thought it was like
surfing.
MATT: You were for a moment, and then it all
collapsed.
TALIESIN: Acrobatics check? Come on. Oh yeah! 28!
MATT: 28? Okay, yeah. So you manage to only
suffer four points of bludgeoning damage and you
land, not prone, as you ride it down and are
standing there on the side, with an angry earth
elemental now slamming into the sides of it.
TALIESIN: 25 constitution saving throw.
MATT: Okay. Keyleth, you do suffer 22 points of
bludgeoning damage from the tower pieces
collapsing down upon and around you. Reduced by
half, because you're an earth elemental.
TALIESIN: Do I see Vax at any point?
MATT: Nope.
TALIESIN: Do I see Scanlan at any point?
TALIESIN: Okay.
MATT: Actually, yeah, you would see Scanlan.
TALIESIN: Can I take my shots?
MATT: Yeah.
TALIESIN: All right.
SAM: How many?
TALIESIN: Three. Four! Ha.
SAM: He sees me?! Through all that fucking
rubble?
MATT: Well, he rode it down to the ground and made
an acrobatics check to stop, and you're not
hidden.
SAM: I'm dead.
TALIESIN: First one is sharpshooter to hit. Nope.
I take damage.
MATT: A misfire?
TALIESIN: That's a misfire.
MATT: The first shot's a misfire. Scanlan, don't
give up yet.
TALIESIN: So that's four points of psychic damage
to me, because I have half saved. Add that.
That's 92 now, is what I'm at. And then, fuck
Animus. I'm going to the Retort gun for the
moment.
MATT: Okay, so you swap out to Retort. Second
attack.
MARISHA: Oh, boo!
TALIESIN: Retort's down.
MATT: He goes to fire, (fizzling). Pulls the
second gun, (misfire).
SAM: I hold up my gun and say, Need one,
motherfucker?
TALIESIN: I can't hear you. And I pull out my last
shot. This is my last shot because I've burned
everything.
MATT: This is Bad News?
TALIESIN: Yeah. And that's, come on, don't do this
to me. Oh, at least it's a hit. 19.
MATT: 19. Scanlan, what's your AC?
SAM: I'm going to Cutting Words that with my
little taunt and reduce it by--
TALIESIN: I can't hear him, but okay.
SAM: Oh, that's true. Never mind. Well, then I'll
Cutting Words the damage. You can do that, right?
MATT: I think the target of the attack has to be
the target of the Cutting Words. Because yeah, it
reduces the damage because you fuck with them.
SAM: Okay. Well, then you hit.
TALIESIN: It's not going to be a bad hit.
SAM: They're all bad hits. Massive hit.
MARISHA: That was so good!
TALIESIN: 29 points of damage.
MATT: You know what? "Use your wit to confuse-- a
creature that you can see within 60 feet of you
"makes an attack roll."
TALIESIN: Technically, I guess he could do a
visual thing.
MATT: I'll let you do it. So before you put the
damage down, go ahead and roll.
SAM: It's going to have to be a really good roll.
MATT: We'll see.
SAM: Nope.
MATT: It's a d12.
SAM: Oh, it's a d12! I've been doing d8s this
whole time!
MATT: d12, man.
TALIESIN: Oh, it's even worse!
SAM: One.
MATT: Yeah, so take the damage. The shot blasts
into your shoulder. You see the blood erupt from
you. You've been hit by this before.
SAM: Ow! Ow!
MARISHA: Did you not realize?
LIAM: I'm using a Sharpie, yeah.
TALIESIN: Too late now, anyway! Yeah, I know, it's
like, we might as well burn it. We're burning it.
MATT: Percival, that ends your turn? Scanlan.
TALIESIN: Yeah. Oh, I mean, no, that's not my
turn. That was my reaction.
MATT: Right, because Keyleth brought it down.
TALIESIN: Yeah, so it's Keyleth's turn. Sorry.
MATT: Right, because you were waiting--
TALIESIN: I was holding my attack until I saw
people.
MATT: Right. Okay. So that brings us to the top of
the round. Percy, it's your turn.
SAM: What?! He can hold three attacks?
MATT: Well, he held his action to attack as soon
as he saw somebody, and he saw you and Keyleth. He
attacked you.
SAM: And one attack is three?
MATT: Four attacks. A 20th-level fighter, it's
their thing.
MARISHA: It's what fighters do.
TALIESIN: Just barely fixed my gun. Barely.
MATT: All right, so that's your action.
TALIESIN: And now I'm going to do an action
surge.
MATT: Okay. So you fixed which one? Animus?
SAM: He's going to shoot me eight times!
TALIESIN: Shot number one with grit, because I'm a
little nervous about this. 26. I didn't call
sharpshooter, so I'm just going to call that 31 to
hit.
MATT: Okay. That hits.
TALIESIN: That hits. 1d10 plus 1d6. That was
terrible. 11 points of damage.
SAM: Sure, yeah.
MATT: Next attack? Second?
TALIESIN: So I'm all out of grit now. That's nice.
Attack number two is 28.
MATT: Hits. Roll damage.
TALIESIN: Oh, that's better. 17 points of damage.
SAM: I will Cutting Words. Top of the round, I get
my reaction back.
MATT: It hasn't come back to your turn.
SAM: Then I'm dead.
MATT: Scanlan goes unconscious with that second
hit.
TALIESIN: Cool. I still have two attacks? I'm
going to take my movement to run over to him.
TRAVIS: Shove a healing potion in his mouth.
TALIESIN: That's as far as I can go?
MATT: It's water and you're walking through water
right now.
TALIESIN: That water freaks me out. I don't want
to quite step in that water.
MATT: So you could stay up, over here.
TALIESIN: Yeah, just over there. Keep me up on the
little bit because I don't want Keyleth to see me,
because she's scary.
MATT: I mean, she can see you. You're not hiding
from her. She's this giant behemoth.
TALIESIN: Okay, I would like to curl a little bit
then out of her range of vision.
MATT: You're out of movement right there. That's
as far as you will get.
MARISHA: I know exactly where you are.
TALIESIN: I know.
MATT: And she can sense it. She feels the
footfalls.
TALIESIN: I have two more shots? All right, I'm
taking a shot-- actually, unconscious, I don't get
grit back? It's death I get grit back. All right,
so, taking another-- but when he dies I get a
grit.
MATT: Okay. He's prone, technically, so you have
disadvantage on the attack.
TALIESIN: Oh, well then, hm. Fuck it, then. I'll
hold my attacks and use my bonus action to do a
heal.
SAM: On me?
TALIESIN: No, on me.
SAM: Aw.
TALIESIN: Yeah, so I'm done. I'm just getting my
1d10.
MATT: Scanlan, I need you to make a death saving
throw, please.
SAM: 17.
MATT: All right, so that's one success. Keep that
in mind. All right.
TALIESIN: 22 back.
MATT: The fields (crushing). Another ten feet. I'm
using this to mark how deep in it's getting now.
So we'll say there.
TALIESIN: So that's 194. I'm back up to 194.
MATT: Also, the water, which is now filled with
bits of broken stone, however still sets off.
TALIESIN: That's why I didn't step in it.
MARISHA: That's a good call.
MATT: That brings us to your turn.
LIAM: So from my hidden position, I would like to
use ten or 15 feet of movement, whatever I would
need to peek out and throw Whisper at Percival's
face.
TALIESIN: How would he even know where I am?
LIAM: Well, I would peek out. I'm looking around
and I know that I would see you. I was in here and
I'm hidden.
MATT: Well, you were hidden until you attacked,
which revealed you there.
LIAM: Isn't it a sneak attack from a hidden
position?
MATT: It is, but once you hit him, he sees you.
This is just for placement. I want to put you on
the field once or twice this battle!
LIAM: I know! So I'm using Whisper. That's good,
that's a 25 to hit.
TALIESIN: That hits.
LIAM: I'll bamf to him as I do it. It's sneak
attack damage. That is nine plus that is 11. Plus
all these guys.
TALIESIN: None of this is magic, is it?
LIAM: Some of it's psychic.
MATT: Unfortunately, all the big spellcasters are
either down or can't cast spells.
LIAM: That's 40 points of damage. And this is my
paladin attack, so that was one. I'm going to use
the other attack with Whisper, I've still got it,
to throw it at Keyleth's face. Which I will do.
That definitely hits. That is a 31. Right. So not
a lot of damage, though. (counting) That's 15 of
damage. That was maybe 15 feet of movement,
paladin attack-attack and I say: Oh!
MATT: Did you bamf to her as well?
LIAM: Yeah. It really pains me. It really does. I
use bonus action to disengage. I have most of my
original movement and hasted action left.
Disengage. You guys don't know where I went.
MARISHA: You disengaged?
LIAM: Yeah.
SAM: You know what I would have done on the third
attack? First blood. You did a lot of nothing
damage to both of them and then hid.
MARISHA: Kind of.
MATT: That ends your turn. Keyleth, you're up.
MARISHA: Do I see Percy? Oh wait, I can feel him.
MATT: You can feel him, yes.
SAM: You'll never win, Vax! Scanlan from the
grave!
TALIESIN: I'm going to point out, by the way, I
don't think I've actually attacked you.
MARISHA: Me?
TALIESIN: Yeah. Just saying.
MARISHA: Are you thinking that's going to save
you?
TALIESIN: No.
MARISHA: Okay.
TALIESIN: I'm making plans.
MARISHA: What do I want to do with you?
TALIESIN: That is a question.
MARISHA: That is such a question. What's next?
Next is the fire, right? Oh. Hang on.
MATT: Keyleth, top of your turn. You feel two
footfalls very gently in the rubble on the other
side of the tower.
MARISHA: Can I make my way to them?
MATT: If you'd like to.
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: What's your movement here?
MARISHA: Here's the question. Since I know kind of
where he is, can I use my bonus action to turn
into a fire elemental and go to him?
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: I'm going to do that. My fire elemental
movement is 50 feet.
TALIESIN: She looks like she's about to fire a
mortar into a compound.
MATT: You, moving 50 feet, through the rubble,
since you can move through small spaces, right?
MARISHA: Uh-huh. Actually, shit, I didn't mean
fire. I meant water. If that's doable. It's fine.
I already called it.
MATT: If you want to do water elemental, you can.
MARISHA: No, I already called it.
MATT: Okay. Fire elemental. You (counting). Vax.
You were hiding up in the rubble.
LIAM: That's not where I am. I just sent it to
you. You asked me and I told you.
MATT: You sent me two pictures.
LIAM: You asked for clarification. I give it to
you. So no one would see me as you put me where I
am. Why would she be able to go in there?
MATT: She knows exactly where you are and as a
fire elemental, she can dodge between cracks.
LIAM: Did she run out of movement, though?
MARISHA: I have 50 feet, yo.
LIAM: Kill me.
MARISHA: So pouty!
LIAM: I knew it was going to happen!
MATT: As you're sitting there hiding, there's a
bright light and there's a slight crevasse between
the rocks as a flaming burst of fire elemental
Keyleth emerges to assault you. What're you
doing?
MARISHA: First, I'm going to enter your space
immediately and you take 1d10 fire damage and you
catch on fire. Seven damage. Two touch attacks.
I'm doing both attacks at once here. First attack
is 22.
LIAM: Nope.
MARISHA: Second attack doesn't hit either, then.
MATT: She swipes with one fire claw, you barely
dodge out of the way. A second one hits the stone
behind you as you duck low.
TALIESIN: But he's on fire.
MARISHA: But you're on fire.
LIAM: Tonight in this game.
MARISHA: Do I have any more movement?
MATT: It took you most of your movement to get there.
You have five feet of movement.
MARISHA: Can I move through this crack on the
other side here?
MATT: I'll allow it.
MARISHA: Sorry, boom mics.
MATT: With the rubble and everything in here... Ending
Keyleth's turn, Percival, you're up.
TALIESIN: I'm making a mad dash for Scanlan.
MATT: Okay. (counting)
TALIESIN: I can't make a jump to see if I can
get a little further across there?
MATT: What's your strength?
TALIESIN: My strength sucks. My strength is 12.
MATT: You jump and land. You're up to your chest
in water.
TALIESIN: I'm going to use the rest of my action
to continue to run towards Scanlan.
MATT: You're going to use an action to dash?
TALIESIN: Use an action to dash. Can I get a
little further, or is that as far as I can get?
MATT: Maybe five more feet.
TALIESIN: I want to be on the other side of him,
if that's okay.
MATT: You can get to there.
TALIESIN: That'll do.
MATT: That's your turn?
TALIESIN: That's my turn.
MATT: Scanlan. Death saving throw.
SAM: 11.
MATT: You're fine. That's two successes. The field
crushes in further. Slowly pushing in. At this
point, by the way, so you're aware, Percival.
TALIESIN: I thought I had a little bit of room.
MATT: You have a little bit, this whole chamber.
Let me use this to mark it here. That's where it's
closing in. Closer and closer. Vax, your turn.
MARISHA: Wait, when is it the top of the round?
MATT: It just went. That was Percival.
MARISHA: Did the torches go, or no?
MATT: No, they go after Scanlan's turn, now, the
field. You're right. Thank you for the reminder.
TALIESIN: Hey, look at that!
MARISHA: Sorry, I'm totally helping the DM.
TALIESIN: No, you're killing Vax! Well done!
MATT: Valid point. The area around the tower
ignites in flame. You're immune to fire, Keyleth.
I need you to make a dexterity saving throw.
LIAM: Right. I get advantage. 29.
MATT: That's a success. You take no damage because
of evasion.
MARISHA: Ballsacks.
LIAM: Is it my turn?
MATT: Your turn.
LIAM: I'm separated with a wall from her a
little bit.
MATT: Slight gap in the wall.
LIAM: I'm going to skitter five or ten feet. I
know she can hear me, but he can't. Then I'm going
to use a little more movement. This looks like a
hole, so I'll floof out to about here. I'll
paladin attack-attack Percival from the air over
the water. Yeah. Oh, that's not very good. That's
18.
TALIESIN: That's my armor class.
LIAM: Hits. The second attack is not, so it
doesn't hit, but the first one does and it's sneak
attack. That's 18 plus these guys. Here we go.
(counting) 40.
MATT: 40 points of piercing damage to you.
LIAM: One attack hit, one missed. I used bonus
action to hide, a little bit of movement to get
here, attack-attack. So I have hasted action and a
lot more movement left. I'll use the rest of my
base movement to go. I will tell you where I'm
going.
SAM: You're going to heal me.
LIAM: Mm-hmm.
MATT: Ending Vax's turn. Keyleth, you're up.
MARISHA: Okay. Blue, that's gone. I know he's
around here somewhere, yeah? Over around this side.
MATT: Yes. You felt a little (clicking).
MARISHA: Can I jump into the water and swim around
as a water elemental and see if I can get to this
other side?
MATT: You turn into a water elemental.
MARISHA: This might not be the best call. If I get
around here, can I poke my head up and see if I
find him?
MATT: I have to wait to find out.
MARISHA: I just projected where I was going to be,
though, he could just change his fucking mind!
LIAM: He projected my position four times tonight.
It's just the nature of the game, man.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MARISHA: Don't sext him while you're at it!
Jesus!
SAM: The new campaign will be all texts.
MATT: Never mind. You felt no (clicking). Instead,
he just disappeared from sight. You saw him go
this direction, but you have no idea where he is.
Do you want to remain fire elemental?
MARISHA: Well, I was jumping into water elemental
to go around, but if I don't feel him land, then
I'll go earth elemental. Let me start stomping up
and over and seeing what I see.
MATT: Sure. I'll let you step up over rough
terrain.
MARISHA: (grumbling)
MATT: Dashing through.
MARISHA: Okay. Do I see anything? Do I see any flying
asshole rogues?
MATT: You don't see anything.
LIAM: It's my only mechanic.
MATT: Percival.
MARISHA: It's a good mechanic!
TALIESIN: This is probably the best use of this.
I'm going to use my action surge. I'm going to
hold my action, but I'm going to use my action
surge. I can use an action surge instead of
holding my action. Just to stab this fucker three
times.
MARISHA: Brutal!
MATT: The first attack. Roll an attack with
advantage because he's on the ground.
SAM: I'm prone. I get half!
MATT: Only against ranged attacks.
TALIESIN: 29.
MATT: That hits. It's an auto-crit. You fail two
death saving throws.
TALIESIN: Here goes the second one. 29.
MATT: And with that, you shank Scanlan.
TALIESIN: Oh look, I get a grit back.
MATT: Scanlan bleeds out.
SAM: Who will tell my story?
TALIESIN and TRAVIS: Not me.
TALIESIN: I'm not proud of this. I'm never telling
anyone. I'm like: I don't know, he ran off. I am
going to move out into this direction over here
because I know the walls are caving in. I have 30
movement. I'm going to move right over here to
start getting out of the way.
MATT: Over where?
TALIESIN: Around the corner.
MATT: The wall's up against there.
TALIESIN: In that case, I'll head that direction.
(counting) I'm holding my action for the second I
see anyone start to fuck with me.
MATT: You already used your action.
TALIESIN: That was my action surge.
MATT: Oh. Action surge first. You hold your action
in case you see anything.
MARISHA: That's a good idea.
TALIESIN: I can do a lot of damage now.
MATT: End of Percival's turn.
TALIESIN: Just have to bet that I can plow
damage.
MATT: The water bursts with magical energy. No, it
was fire last time, so now it's lightning. Blue
things are gone, nothing happens. Also, it crushes
in once more. Bringing us to there. Currently, the
walls have crushed in.
TALIESIN: I always knew it would be the three of
us.
SAM: You did?
TALIESIN: No. I just always wanted to say that.
LIAM: You always said it would be Grog and
Keyleth.
MARISHA: Yeah, I thought it was going to be
me and Grog again.
TRAVIS: With all the magic that I have?
TALIESIN: If you had gotten your hands on
anybody--
MARISHA: Yeah, if you had closed the gap, that's
it. That's down for any of us.
TRAVIS: Disengage. Shift. Element. You just (poof)
right out of it.
TALIESIN: And also, can I mention, isn't he still
on fire? Make it harder to--
LIAM: Matt. One.
MATT: One. Okay. So, couple things. One, roll 1d10
fire damage, Marisha, by the way.
TALIESIN: Thank you. Lead him out.
MARISHA: Nine.
MATT: Technically twice, since you didn't do it
last turn, right?
LIAM: I was about to say, I didn't stop drop and
roll or anything. Literally about to say.
MATT: It's an action to put it out.
LIAM: Yeah, so I didn't do it.
MATT: So, nine fire damage, and then roll again.
MARISHA: So nine now, and then another four. So,
13.
LIAM: 13. Got it.
MATT: And then you fail your constitution saving
throw as the wall slams into you, pushing you
back. Oof. You take 28 points of force damage, and
you are thrown, prone onto the ground right
there.
LIAM: Great.
MATT: That ends that turn. Vax, your turn.
LIAM: Okay. I will use movement to get up.
MATT: Half your movement.
LIAM: Half my, 60 feet of movement to stand up,
got it. And I will fly low along the ground--
MATT: Also Vax--
LIAM: Are the boots off?
MATT: The boots are off.
LIAM: Okay. So it's not 60, the wings are up, so
30 feet to get up.
MATT: Correct.
TALIESIN: Oh, thank god.
LIAM: 30 feet to get about-- I don't know, can I
perch there? Flying low? I should be within 60
feet of Kiki, and I have Vow of Enmity still, so I
will attack-attack-attack.
MATT: Yeah, you can barely see her. You just
barely have her in range. Percy. You watch as he
glides in the air--
TALIESIN: Oh, hey, I got a shot!
LIAM: This is here, this is here. There's a gap
there?
TALIESIN: Yeah, but you wouldn't have flown up to
your perch.
LIAM: Okay.
TALIESIN: I will take my shot.
MARISAH: Out of the shadows, boy!
LIAM: Everybody hates me.
MATT: Everybody hates each other!
TALIESIN: First shot.
MARISHA: As the internet said earlier, we're really bad at
shit-talking each other. Just embrace it.
TALIESIN: First shot, I'm burning my grit for a
Sharpshooter.
MATT: She's been Feebleminded! Don't play Woe is
Me!
TALIESIN: Going to burn my grit for a Sharpshooter
in hopes of really doing some damage.
MATT: He got Plane Shifted, he got shanked by
Percival! You're doing all right!
TRAVIS: First time we've seen you in three hours and 45
minutes.
TALIESIN: 25 to hit.
LIAM: That probably hits a lot.
SAM: First blood!
TALIESIN: Here, I'm using good dice for this. Oh
yeah. 28 plus six psychic, so 34 points of
damage.
LIAM: I can use Uncanny Dodge on that, since I can
see him if he can see me.
MATT: Correct.
LIAM: So, half that.
TALIESIN: Half of 34.
MATT: That would be 17. Next attack?
TALIESIN: Next attack.
MARISHA: Kill him!
TALIESIN: Oh, goddamn it. Animus is down. That was
a 20. Bad News comes out. That's a third attack.
Come on, Gil.
MARISHA: Is that a crit?
TALIESIN: No, it's not a crit.
MARISHA: Damn it, so close.
TALIESIN: That's a 27 to hit.
LIAM: Yeah, you're good.
TALIESIN: Where are my dice for that?
MARISHA: Not that I'm cheering on for your death
or anything.
LIAM: Yes, you are.
MARISHA: I'm just excited. I'm excitable.
TALIESIN: That's 26 points of damage.
MATT: 26 points of piercing damage.
TALIESIN: I can't use a bonus to reload, can I?
MATT: Nope. Not your turn.
TALIESIN: So I just reloaded. All right.
MATT: So your last attack is to reload.
SAM: I cast Slowly Decompose.
TRAVIS: I cast Waterlogged.
MATT: Okay, so now you land there, and can make
your attacks on him.
LIAM: It's still my turn. Oh, wow, that's
amazing.
MATT: Yep. That was his reaction.
LIAM: Dagger dagger dagger. Yeah, that's a 30 to
hit. Oh, it doesn't matter, because I've got Vow
of Enmity up. I was going to say am I still
hidden, but I've got Vow of Enmity. That is sneak
attack on that. That's 30.
MARISHA: Oh, Scanlan! We could have been pit
fiends together! But I got Feebleminded! Oh no!
And you died! We waited too long!
MATT: I had these minions at the ready, just in
case!
SAM: Aww!
MARISHA: We were going to be awesome!
TRAVIS: That would've been fun.
MATT: I know. Pit fiend on a full melee round
against a single target can do an average of 115
hit points of damage and lock down healing.
LIAM: 44 on the first.
MARISHA: Damage?
LIAM: 44 damage on the first? Does 18 hit?
MARISHA: Yes. Pretty much everything hits these
motherfuckers.
LIAM: You get ten on that. 28 on the third, also
hits. That is 12 on the third.
MATT: You've used all your movement.
LIAM: Yeah, I'm done because I'm not hasted any
more. I used half to stand up and the other half
to get there. I used-- it's complicated, folks.
Paladin attack-attack and bonus to do a third
attack. So I'm done.
MATT: Keyleth, your turn.
MARISHA: All right! Let's dance! I jump. As I
jump, I'm going to turn into a water elemental.
Ker-splash. Then use my movement speed to
come up. I'm going to try to whelm Vax.
MATT: A leap there would be 20 feet of movement.
MARISHA: With my dope mantle.
LIAM: She's not so dumb that she thinks she's an
earth elemental forever?
MARISHA: I'm an archdruid!
LIAM: You have an intelligence of one.
MATT: Marisha, technically your mantle isn't on
you right now because you're in elemental form.
MARISHA: Beast Shape says that anything that's on
me absorbs into me.
MATT: Absorbs into your form.
MARISHA: And elemental is my form.
MATT: But you're not getting your ring of
protection bonus, you're not getting your other
elements that you have in physical form. They stay
within you so when you transform back, the effects
return, but you don't get the Jump ability. What's
the strength of this guy?
MARISHA: 20 strength.
MATT: Oh yeah.
LIAM: Suddenly, five rules lawyers around the
table.
MATT: Water elemental there. I'll say half your
movement to get into the water, the jump. Turn
into a water elemental.
MARISHA: How much speed do I have left?
MATT: Half of your swim speed.
MARISHA: So 45. Can I get to Vax?
MATT: (counting)
LIAM: Oh, difficult terrain!
MARISHA: I can swim! I'm a fucking water
elemental!
MATT: You're just in melee range with him.
MARISHA: Blub blub blub! Whelm again.
MATT: Do you have to move into his space for
whelm?
MARISHA: Each creature in the elemental's space.
So yes.
MATT: He's unfortunately just out.
MARISHA: Then I'll do my two slam attacks. Bam
bam.
TALIESIN: He's low, man.
MATT: You're just out of range for being whelmed,
so that's good.
SAM: Weirdly, taking away all of Keyleth's
intelligence has made her a more effective
fighter.
MARISHA: 20. Misses. I've got to roll high in
order to actually get you. That's even better!
25!
MATT: Roll damage.
MARISHA: Roll, baby! 17 points of damage.
LIAM: Uncanny dodge.
TRAVIS: So casual.
MATT: You take eight points of bludgeoning damage
from the water.
MARISHA: Okay. That's it.
MATT: That brings us to Percival.
TALIESIN: I'm going to try and fix my gun with my
roll.
MATT: This is your action.
TALIESIN: And boy that does it.
SAM: It's so fixed.
TALIESIN: Sometimes it'll really break. I'm going
to make my way up on top of that tower.
MATT: Right there?
TALIESIN: Yeah. A little closer.
MATT: Just so you know, the force field is right
there.
TALIESIN: Oh, never mind. I thought it was a
little further back. I'm going to try to cross the
water and get back to the other side of the water
again.
MATT: (counting) Right there.
TALIESIN: That'll do it. Just let the two of them
settle their differences.
MARISHA: Not a bad call.
MATT: Now, the energy fields burst with purple
energy.
MARISHA: Was so hoping I was going to have Vax in
that water.
MATT: Actually, they don't! They've been destroyed
by the fields, so they do not have an effect any more.
MARISHA: It's just us kids.
MATT: Which saves you because that would have
knocked out your form. However, the fields move in
further, completely destroying this here.
TALIESIN: I am so excited by this.
LIAM: I'm going to be dead. I'm a dead man.
MATT: This all goes away. Just the edge of the
water now. We're in on this area now. Vax, it's
your turn.
LIAM: I would like to paladin attack Keyleth with
Vow of Enmity twice. The first one is a natural
20. Let's just calculate that, shall we? That's
one. Get all the dice first. (counting) Not that
great, actually. That is 58 for the first attack.
MATT: 58 damage to your water elemental.
MARISHA: Wait, is that magical? No, it's straight
damage, right?
LIAM: Eight psychic and double on all the dice.
MATT: Magical dagger attacks, so you do not
resist.
MARISHA: What was the first one, 56?
LIAM: 58.
MARISHA: That's not right, either! No, that is
right.
MATT: You can't see Percival.
MARISHA: What was the other one?
LIAM: 14.
SAM: Can't be done! Don't you get it? The math's
not there! You have to deliver more than 200
points of damage in a single round to kill her!
You can't do it without us! The math is not
there!
LIAM: So that was paladin attack-attack. I'll use
disengage.
TRAVIS: Fly into the wall. Do it. Burn yourself
up, every inch.
LIAM: I don't want to do the phone thing. I'm going
to fly 60 feet, but Percy doesn't see me. She
does. I fly to about here. 60 feet. I'm on the
other side of this tower.
MATT: You disengaged from her.
LIAM: Disengage and then my movement of 60 feet.
MATT: All right. That ends Vax's turn. Keyleth,
you're up.
LIAM: Here she comes.
MARISHA: Yep! I'm going for that motherfucker
right there!
LIAM: Percy would have shot me out of it. I stay
low.
MATT: Technically, on that side, there is no water
there. This is all gone. This has all been eaten
away. You'd have to get up onto the land there.
MARISHA: Then let me go earth elemental and walk
on over to him.
MATT: You can move partially.
MARISHA: There we go.
MATT: That's as far as you can right there.
MARISHA: Total? I can't get any further?
MATT: Nope. With a 30 feet speed for an earth
elemental, right?
MARISHA: Yes.
MATT: That's as close as you can get.
MARISHA: Okay. Yeah.
MATT: That's your turn? You still have an action.
MARISHA: There's nothing I can do as an earth
elemental with Feeblemind.
MATT: You can use your action to dash towards him
if you wanted to.
MARISHA: Sure. I'll get right up in his face. I
can't grapple him? I can't do anything?
MATT: The field's up against there, so
technically he had to fly around and land.
LIAM: Is it just this island left now, Matt?
MATT: Yep!
MARISHA: Okay, wait. Is it all the way up into
here?
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: Sorry. I don't mean to retroact things.
If that's the case, can I do an air elemental and
fly over?
MATT: Sure, you can do that.
TALIESIN: This system's a little confusing.
MATT: I know, my apologies.
TALIESIN: You're doing great.
LIAM: We're vamping.
MARISHA: In that case, let me do a fire elemental,
if that's okay, and then I'll go 50 feet. I've got
50 feet of movement and I can move through
one-inch spaces.
MATT: You can just get up to where he is.
MARISHA: Can I get in his space and catch him on
fire immediately?
TALIESIN: He's already on fire still.
LIAM: It's your third try at a form, dude.
MARISHA: Are you still on fire?
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: Should I have rolled again?
MATT: You should have taken damage last turn.
LIAM: I'm probably down, then.
MARISHA: Six points of damage.
LIAM: I'm unconscious.
MATT: As you land--
TALIESIN: You can burn him out.
MATT: He's smoldering on the ground. You go over
to where Vax is, and he's just burning. His
unconscious body is burning.
MARISHA: I go: Hey, Scanlan, I found him! I found
Vax! Scanlan?
MATT: You look over and see on the field that's
pushing forward, there's a Scanlan corpse being
rolled as it shoves him closer onto the
battlefield.
SAM: First! Blood!
LIAM: Is there water? The water's gone.
MATT: The water's over here. We'll put you there.
MARISHA: He's on fire.
MATT: Percy, your turn.
MARISHA: I can still attack him.
MATT: The corpse? Yeah, you can. Go for it.
LIAM: I thought you used all your shit to get
there.
MARISHA: No, I just walked there.
LIAM: Okay, cool.
SAM: And Grog just suffocated.
MATT: Nah, he's got constitution for days. He's
got five more minutes on this shit.
MARISHA: What do I have to roll to hit him, by the
way? He's down and unconscious, so do I have to roll?
LIAM: It's two death saves per.
MATT: Melee, you have advantage to attack him.
LIAM: I'm not going to dodge sleeping.
TALIESIN: You're literally sitting on him. You're
going to burn him.
MARISHA: Yeah, both of my attacks hit.
MATT: His body incinerates.
MARISHA: I just sit on him, I'm like: Sorry!
MATT: Yeah, each time.
SAM: Oh, each time and she hit him twice?
MATT: Hit him twice. So Vax's body burns away.
LIAM: I'm two out of three. She's got to hit me
one more time.
MATT: Oh, that was just the first hit? I thought
you hit him with both.
MARISHA: I hit him twice.
LIAM: Oh, so the first one's two. Peace!
MATT: Both attacks. You're incinerated.
TALIESIN: I'm a little fucked, but we'll see how
this goes.
SAM: A little?! You. Can't. Win!
MARISHA: Sorry, boo.
TALIESIN: It's okay. Do you have the sensory?
Anytime you turn to rock, you can tell where I am,
so it doesn't really matter. I'm going to drop
Silence. I'm going to use my bonus action to cast.
Can I see her?
MATT: Yeah.
TALIESIN: I'm casting Hex. I'm taking three shots
from where I'm standing with Animus.
MATT: Not four?
TALIESIN: Four, god, I'm just getting used to it.
Four sharpshooter. Number one is 19 to hit.
MARISHA: Hit. I'm really easy to hit.
TALIESIN: Oh shit, that's pretty good. That's 27
normal points of damage. Five psychic and five
necrotic.
MARISHA: So 37 total?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MARISHA: What's the first one, is it piercing?
TALIESIN: Piercing.
MARISHA: Which I take half of because it's not
magical.
MATT: It is magical because you're shooting with
Animus.
TALIESIN: Oh, so I don't have to break this up.
This is magical damage.
MARISHA: So 37 total? Okay.
TALIESIN: Shot number two. Come on, man, this is
all I need. Fucking fuck fuck. I take two psychic
damage as it jams. I'm jamming a lot.
SAM: I'm jamming!
TALIESIN: Shot number three is Bad News, which is
not magic.
SAM: We jamming!
TALIESIN: 25 to hit.
MATT: That hits.
TALIESIN: It's not awesome because you take half
damage because it's piercing.
LIAM: First blood.
TALIESIN: It's 26 points of piercing damage.
MATT: Plus d6 necrotic. So 13.
TALIESIN: Plus one necrotic.
MATT: 14 points of damage.
TALIESIN: I'm going to run up the tower. No,
straight up the tower. Spider boots.
MATT: I know, there's fire there. You get there.
TALIESIN: I want to get out of the way of the fire
when it finally rolls. Trying to get inside of it.
SAM: Can you get to the middle and stay there
until the whole island kills her?
MARISHA: I mean, I can do that too.
MATT: End of Percy's turn. The field crushes in
even further, which unfortunately does hit you,
Keyleth. You get pushed in. Make a constitution
saving throw.
MARISHA: Just a straight con save? Don't fuck me,
Gil. That's good. 20 total.
MATT: 20, okay. You do succeed. So you take, wow
that's a good roll. Six, six, six, six, five, two,
four. No, against you. 29 divided, so that's 14
points of force damage. You're now being crushed
into the rubble and pushed up the top of it.
MARISHA: Okay.
SAM: Would you say she's jamming? Into the wall?
MATT: She's jamming pretty hard into that wall.
MARISHA: Whose turn is it?
MATT: That is the field's turn over. It's
Keyleth's turn. You're up.
MARISHA: So wait, what did the field just do?
MATT: It's crushing you guys inward.
MARISHA: Did it do the torch or did the torch
already happen?
MATT: The torch unfortunately could not because
the territory that it would be on-- I mean, the
torch goes off, I would say, but you're immune to
fire and Percival's out of the way, and only part
of it is currently available. It's crushing it
very tight.
MARISHA: Cool. Cool cool cool.
TALIESIN: And you took damage from the force
field.
MATT: So it's your turn, Keyleth.
MARISHA: I'm going to go earth elemental.
TALIESIN: Goddamn it.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: Oh yeah! I'm going to jump all over,
Kool-Aid man style, do a big old fatty jump leap.
Or, if I can get to Percy?
MATT: You won't get to him with your movement,
unfortunately, because there's a lot of rubble in
the way.
MARISHA: Okay. I can't jump over it?
MATT: You do, but your movement-- You can't jump
more than you can move when you don't have the
cloak on.
MARISHA: Am I within ten feet of him?
MATT: He's about 15 feet from you.
MARISHA: Fuck! Okay. That's it, then.
MATT: All right. Percival, you're up.
TALIESIN: I'm going to try and fix my gun because
it's the only chance I have. Oh, just barely makes
it. Yep. And then, since I don't have an attack,
man, there's nothing I can do. I'm going to run on
the outskirts on the outside of the tower, behind,
and get some cover.
MATT: Here?
TALIESIN: Yeah, on the wall. I'm literally on the
wall. It won't crush next round, will it? I mean,
at current rate, I'm not doing anything dumb? I
mean, I would know, though, if it's been going at--
MATT: You get the sense that, on this side, it
will, but not on this side--
TALIESIN: So yeah.
MATT: End of Percival's turn, it crushes in again.
Now keeping tabs on where it lies. There is the
edge. There, and then on this side, it's right up
against you, Percival.
SAM: It's cramming!
MATT: Keyleth, your turn.
MARISHA: Can I move five feet to reach him?
MATT: Yeah. You can get up on top there and bash
downward, essentially.
SAM: Do it!
MARISHA: He still has a decent amount of hit
points, though.
SAM: Yeah, but you can draw first blood.
MARISHA: This is a force wall. If I throw him into
it, it's going to suck?
TALIESIN: It's not that bad. I've hit it three
times already.
MATT: Yeah, him and Grog have been thrown into it
a few times earlier.
SAM: Crush him!
MARISHA: Okay, can I grapple him and pummel the
shit out of him?
MATT: Yeah, if you want to grapple with the first
attack.
MARISHA: I'm going to grapple with the first
MATT: All right, I need you both to make athletics
checks, please.
SAM: That's you.
TALIESIN: Yep.
MARISHA: Don't fuck me, Gil! That's not bad.
TALIESIN: I'm seven.
MARISHA: 19.
MATT: So the first attack, she reaches down and
grabs you. Now, the giant elemental form has
wrapped its fingers around your shoulders and
torso. You're unable to move from the spot.
MARISHA: Do one more attack on him. Do I get
advantage on the grappling?
MATT: Your movement is zero. Hm? Your next attack,
you attack him. You don't get advantage.
MARISHA: I just attack him? Not good. Sorry, 12.
TALIESIN: That won't hit me.
MATT: Nope, so you're held there in space.
Percival.
TALIESIN: Thunderwave, 5th-level.
SAM: You can do 5th-level spells?
TALIESIN: Yep.
SAM: Damn!
MATT: Thunderwave from which one?
TALIESIN: From my Stone King Cincture.
MATT: That's true. All righty. So go ahead and
make, what's the saving throw on that?
TALIESIN: DC 16.
MATT: DC 16 constitution. Go ahead and make a
constitution saving throw, Keyleth.
MARISHA: Saved with a natural 18.
SAM: It's 6d8 halved thunder damage.
MATT: And she gets pushed, or does she not get
pushed?
SAM: No. Because she saved, she doesn't get
pushed.
MATT: Okay, so still grappled.
TALIESIN: 6d8? All right. Halved. (counting) 29
halved.
MATT: Right, so 14. End of your turn, Percival?
TALIESIN: That counts as a whole attack, doesn't
it? Then I'm going to run-- I can't. She's got me.
I can't even attempt to break free.
MATT: Actually, you could have, but you spent it to
cast Thunderwave. It would've if she had failed
the save.
TALIESIN: I don't get to add a d6 to that of hex
damage, do I?
MATT: Technically you do, yeah.
TALIESIN: Hey, six points of necrotic.
LIAM: Oh no, she's down to 106.
SAM: Until the next turn.
TALIESIN: I'm still higher.
MARISHA: You are still higher.
TALIESIN: Actually, no, I'm not. Never mind. I'm
at 107. So yeah! One point higher.
MATT: Percival, top of your turn. This side stops
closing in. This side does. Percy, you are now
being smashed between the wall of the tower and
the field as she's holding you in space. I need
you both to make constitution saving throws as
you're having to hold him there to keep him in
space. But you have advantage because you're
pulling away, I'll say.
TALIESIN: Yeah, 18. So it's 26.
MARISHA: 17.
MATT: All right, So you fail. You do get pushed
back 15 feet and you take, oh man. All right.
That's a good roll.
TALIESIN: Technically, since I'm grappled, do I go
with her?
MATT: No, because it breaks the grapple because it
pushes you back. So that's 30 points of force
damage to you, Keyleth. 15 to you. However, you
are currently restrained as you are being held
against the wall and the force field. You're
pushed back.
MARISHA: Oh, and he's stuck?
MATT: He's being sandwiched between the stone wall
and the force field, like (crackling). We're
talking like Tetsuo-crush. All right.
TALIESIN: It's my turn now, right? Or no?
MATT: No, now it's Keyleth's turn.
SAM: And that's when the Irresistible Dance kicks
in. Delayed response.
MARISHA: Can I take and through this wall, push it
and start crushing Percy? Two slam attacks with
the wall, crush crush?
TALIESIN: Yeah, no, I'm into that.
MATT: All right, so go ahead and make an attack.
MARISHA: Against the wall or against Percy?
MATT: Against the wall.
MARISHA: First one is a 20 total. No, 21 total.
The second one is a 19 total.
MATT: Okay. I won't have you roll damage because
it's siege, but what you do is each one of these
shoves forces him into the wall. So I need you to
make two constitution saving throws.
TALIESIN: Two constitution saving throws. Here we
go. That's a 19 and a 21.
MATT: Both succeed. So that's 27 points of force
damage, reduced to 13.
TALIESIN: Okay, so that's 92 minus 13.
MATT: That's a shitty roll. Ten points of force
damage, reduced to five.
TALIESIN: 74.
MARISHA: Does he take any from being sandwiched?
MATT: I mean, he's taking the damage because he's
being sandwiched.
MARISHA: Okay. Can I use my bonus action to go
earth elemental again?
MATT: You have to change to a different form.
MARISHA: Then I will stay.
MATT: Okay. Percival, your turn.
TALIESIN: I'm going to try and squeeze around out
of this.
MATT: Top of your turn, make a constitution saving
throw.
TALIESIN: Oh, fine. Natural 20. I really would've
liked that on a shot, but that's okay. It would
have made life way easier.
MATT: That is 19 points of force damage, reduced
to nine. Right, so you're trying to escape from
the restraint? All right, make an athletics check.
Athletics or acrobatics, I believe. Let me double
check real fast.
TALIESIN: If I can just use my boots to squeeze
off the side--
MATT: Well no, it's not breaking from a grapple
necessarily. It's from being pinned. This isn't
weaseling out of it. This is pure force, so this
would be athletics.
TALIESIN: I can't try and sneak through the
window?
MATT: No, the window, it's a slit. It's like that
wide and your back is pressed against it.
TALIESIN: This is not how I wanted to go out.
Athletics, then? Oh boy. Nope.
MATT: All right, so you're still restrained.
TALIESIN: I can't see her at all, can I?
MATT: Currently, no. She's behind the wall,
pushing you into it.
TALIESIN: Yep. Huh. Hmm. Yeah, no, I got nothing.
MATT: All right. At the end of that, the field
pushes in once more.
TALIESIN: Breaks the wall, probably.
MATT: Well no, it's pushing against that. It's not
pushing further, sorry, because they're both
stopped. They're now holding that space. So you
don't take damage again. It doesn't force you. But
you're still pinned. Keyleth, your turn.
MARISHA: What is best right now?
TALIESIN: I want to have a moment.
MATT: What is best in life?
MARISHA: Yeah, can I do two slam attacks on him
again? Bam, bam, multi-attack?
MATT: Pushing him into the wall again? Okay.
MARISHA: Not good. Same thing for that first one.
Twelve. Oh wait, it's hitting the wall, though?
MATT: You're essentially just pushing against the
wall. It'll shove, yeah. It's essentially a ten or
lower.
MARISHA: Okay, so 15 damage for that first one.
MATT: No damage on this. You're just pushing the
wall, so the force against him. So make a
constitution saving throw, Percival.
TALIESIN: I make one or two?
MATT: We'll find out. Roll a second attack.
MARISHA: Natural 19.
TALIESIN: It's the one thing I'm good at. Oh, not
this time. Ten and 12.
MATT: Ten and 12. All right. You take, first, 24
points of force damage.
TALIESIN: 24.
MATT: 24 points of force damage. Keyleth, I need
you to make a strength check, please. Or a
strength saving throw.
MARISHA: Strength saving throw?
MATT: Correct.
MARISHA: Natural 17, so 23.
MATT: So as it pushes back, you manage to keep it
back and then shove him back into it. And then, oh
my god. That is 25 points of force damage to you,
Percival. And Keyleth, make another strength
saving throw as the section of wall that you've
pushed in, that's loose and you're shoving him
with, is being shoved backward.
MARISHA: Natural 19.
MATT: You've managed to hold it in place. Still
restrained, you're slowly sandwiching him. Making
a Percival sandwich. Percy, your turn.
TALIESIN: Hail Mary. Trying to squeeze out of
this. Nope. That's eight.
SAM: The ghost of Scanlan floats in front of you.
MATT: Make another constitution saving throw.
MARISHA and LIAM: (chanting) First blood! First
blood!
TALIESIN: I can't count, guys! 25.
MATT: 25, okay. So you take 13 points of force
damage. Keyleth, your turn.
MARISHA: Keyleth, my turn? Argh! Squishy squishy!
Squishy Percy! Ooh, no, ten total.
MATT: Ten total? Just barely.
MARISHA: And second one, 12 total. Those were bad
rolls.
MATT: Roll two constitution saving throws,
Percival.
TALIESIN: This might be the end. I'm at nothing.
18 and 11.
MATT: First one succeeds. You take 11 points of
force damage.
TALIESIN: I'm out.
MATT: Second push, you feel Percival begin to pop
and squish against the outer field. And for the
purposes of this, one more round of shoving and,
with a (squish), Percival-jelly begins to ooze out
from behind the wall in which you shove him
against the force.
TALIESIN: You hear everything I own crack.
MATT: While you were technically healing 20 points
every round underneath the green beam--
MARISHA: Oh shit. Wow, yeah.
MATT: The field dissipates. The rubble begins to
separate and float in space. The ruined corpses of
all your allies then float aloft around you and
are slowly re-stitched back to life. Grog appears,
pulled back from the water dimension, from the
depths of the drowning. And you see the bearded
patron descend from above. As he pats you on the
head and goes--
MARISHA: I was never religious in-game, but now I
am!
MATT: "Good job!"
(laughter)
MATT: And with that--
(yelling)
LIAM: All hail the queen!
TALIESIN: Without a spell to her name.
MATT: Level 20 druids, man.
SAM: In 30 days, she'll know what happened.
MATT: Yep.
MARISHA: Yeah, in 20 days I'll be like, what?
TALIESIN: I had the weirdest dream a month ago!
MARISHA: I dreamt I killed you, and you, and you.
MATT: It's funny, I was like, okay, once they
start getting into the high-level spells this is
really going to turn-- And then Feeblemind. All
right, this is going to be a drag-out brawl to the
very end.
TALIESIN: I was really hoping I could burn some
grit back and then do a whole bunch of damage all
at once.
MARISHA: But man, you dodged my Feeblemind. That
was hot. That was amazing.
LIAM: I did what I came here to do.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I went to the Water Plane with a few
hundred HP left. I was super healthy in the
water.
SAM: Like a sensory deprivation tank.
MATT: That deprives you of all the senses,
eventually.
MARISHA: I had to get vengeance from fucking it up
last time.
TRAVIS: So it's cool.
MATT: Well done, guys. Congratulations, Keyleth.
MARISHA: I finally won one!
SAM: Thanks to Marvel Puzzle Quest!
TALIESIN: Thank you, Marvel Puzzle Quest for
sponsoring our ultimate fighting championship.
TRAVIS: That is the most messed-up map I've ever
seen.
TALIESIN: That was mean. I started this game being
the most clutch, powerful motherfucker on the
planet and ended it like-- Confined spaces fuck
gunslingers.
MARISHA: I'm the queen. Everyone bow down to me.
MATT: That's the Feeblemind face. My wife, ladies
and gentlemen. Thank you guys so much for playing.
Thank you guys so much for sticking with us, if
you're still here. We'll be back next week to
discuss-- Some of you will be here for Talks
Machina, I believe, and next Thursday to do the
Q&amp;A. After that, have a wonderful holidays and New
Year. And is it Thursday yet? Good night, guys.
[music]