GILMORE: Hello Tal'Doreians!
We have an exciting
new product we want to share with you
today on Gilmore's Glorious QVC.
What you see here is a beautiful
major arcana tarot deck
featuring some of the most prominent figures
of "who's who" in picturesque Tal'Dorei,
painted by the brilliant Lady Ioana Muresan.
Printed on the finest card stock parchment
with glittering gold foil imported from
the mines of Kraghammer,
this is truly a showstopper for any
high society soiree.
You're not just telling their fortunes,
you're bedazzling their future.
Now today we're offering this beautiful purple
and gold deluxe edition as well as...
...that-that's it, actually.
I wouldn't offer anything other than
the finest edition in my store.
The going market retail price of these cards
is four platinum, or forty gold pieces,
or four hundred silver pieces,
or four thousand copper pieces,
but today, we are giving you the special
Gilmore's Glorious QVC value of--
Sherri, no, we're still filming those.
Please! You're getting them all smudgy.
The special Gilmore's Glorious QVC value
of 24 gold pieces and 99 copper.
That's right. Just two and a half platinum pieces!
But that offer only lasts until the disclosed
amount of seconds
runs out on the timer in the corner.
Scry now! Or come down and visit me,
Gilmore, at Glimore's Glorious Goods.
In the Outdoor Promenade District of Emon.
♫