Hello everybody! Are we on the internet?
No!
We're not on the internet, we're live at WonderCon!
We're here at a Critter meetup.
We're gonna ask a bunch of Critters
what they know about the show they love.
Test their true knowledge.
Let's talk to them and find out what's up.
Hi Kayla.
Hi.
Where'd you come from for WonderCon?
I came from Oregon.
All the way here from Oregon?
Just to come to this fountain?
Mm-hm!
Who is the only member of Vox Machina
to not have died?
Keyleth.
Ooh, that's so good.
How many cloaks does Vax have?
Um, like 10 billion?
Three.
Okay.
Name all four members of the Chroma Conclave.
Can you?
Yeah.
Umbrasyl, Raishan, Thordak, and...
Vorugal.
For a bonus, name the fifth member.
Starts with a B.
Yeah it does.
[laughs]
Who is the only member of Vox Machina to not have died yet?
Keyle-e-e-e-th!
What kind of feathers did Vex give to her
half-sister when the party went to Syngorn?
It was owlbear.
Oh my god, how do you know this?
Do you want a "Free Denise" pin?
Sure!
Okay, there you go.
Free her!
Eh, someday.
What kind of feathers did Vex give to her half-sister
when the party went to Syngorn?
Those were owlbear feathers.
They sure as f**k were!
What later villain did Vox Machina almost encounter
in their first visit to the Fire Plane?
The Cinder King.
Correct!
Can you name all four members of the Chroma Conclave?
Raishan, Thordak, uh...
Uh...
I'm blacking out again.
He's blacking out.
He's been drinking since 9 a.m.
Yeah, that's what Finnish guys do.
I get it.
It's what Irish guys do too.
Where is Denise?
BRIAN: She's not here.
She couldn't make it because of the Witness Protection Program.
Okay.
Well, you're dressed as Scanlan.
Why is he your least favorite character
from Critical Role?
Ah, piece of sh*t.
Who possessed Craven Edge before Grog?
Lord Briarwood.
Yes, that's correct.
Good god!
Percy knows a lot about the show that he's on.
What is Scanlan's mother's name?
I'm a terrible person and I don't know.
That doesn't make you a terrible person!
It just makes me like the rest of Vox Machina.
Absolutely!
Pike's mace is particularly effective
against which type of creature?
Undead.
Slam dunk.
Would you like a "Free Denise" pin?
Oh my god.
She has one on.
Part of being a great host is observing things
that happen on your show.
I have a question for you, though.
Hit me.
Do you want a "Free Denise" pin?
I do not.
Okay. [laughs]
A lot of things in this life are free.
Denise is not one of them.
♪ Talks Machina theme ♪