Wielding an oversized axe not quite your style?
You find the panache and pageantry of wizard life
a tad too ostentatious?
You may just want to pull that hood up
and go rogue.
Roll for stealth you pickpocketing bastards,
this is your rogue quick build for D&D 5e.
♫ Don't know how to play ♫
♫ we'll show you the way ♫
♫ Handbook, handbook, handbook ♫
♫ Handbook-er Helper ♫
Handbooker Helper
♫ Ding ♫
Rogues are clever hands-on adventuring types who are quick on their feet
and nimble with their hands.
So your number one priority is dexterity
and since rogues can adapt to so many different walks of life,
your second highest stat depends on the sort of rake you mean to be.
If you plan on being a mastermind or
dabbling as an arcane trickster, hit up intelligence.
Or if you see yourself fast talking your way through all your problems,
well, then lean into charisma instead.
[Ding]
There are so many ways to go with rogue, but
let's focus on the core three for now
which you'll branch into at level three.
First up is Thief,
your best bet for a jack-of-all-trades, dungeon delving scrapper.
You'll have faster hands, quicker steps, and at higher levels
you'll just get more sh*t done.
Next up is the Assassin, for those looking to be more lethal.
This is the path you'll want to take if you hope to set up elaborate assassinations,
taking a target out all in one go.
Friendly piece of advice though,
you might want to make sure you have a party willing to take the time
for such elaborately planned hit jobs.
Finally, for the rogue with a little spice thrown in,
you can choose the Arcane Trickster,
who uses magic to aid them in their morally Grey pursuits.
Put to good use, rogues can scout ahead,
find potentially deadly traps,
and get in at least one good shot before many fights get started.
Sometimes, finishing them before they've even begun.
On top of all that, rogues come with a HUGE boon.
The combination of Expertise and Reliable Talent.
Early on you can choose a handful of skills
that you get to double your proficiency bonus for.
Reliable Talent makes those same skills virtually failure proof,
making rogues the best in the realm at what we do.
Now get your hands dirty, and remember:
you might not see me, but I'll be watching.
♫ Handbook, handbook, handbook ♫
♫ Handbook-er Helper ♫
Handbooker Helper
♫ Ding ♫
[Music]