If you only know one thing about Dungeons & Dragons
other then the fact that it involves both dungeons and dragons
it's probably that it utilizes a twenty-sided die
or d20.
This is the die the entire system revolves around
and the die you will be rolling the most.
This polyhedral punk determines
all of your successes and failures in the game
with twenty being the best
and one being the absolute worst!
♫ Don't know how to play ♫
♫ we'll show you the way ♫
♫ Handbook, handbook, handbook, ♫
♫ Handbook-er Helper♫
Handbooker Helper
♫ Ting ♫
I hear a lot of beginners ask
"How do I know when to roll?"
Well, here's the beauty of it:
most of the time, you don't have to!
That's for the Dungeon Master, or DM, to decide
all you have to worry about is what your character wants to do
and how you wanna do it.
If it seems like a challenge in needs of Fate's opinion
the DM will ask you to roll a d20
the outcome depends on how tough it would be
for your character to achieve the goal at hand
and, of course, whatever the cursed dice have to say.
You wanna to attack something? Roll that d20
and your resident DM will let you know how hard you hit it
or how bad you biffed it.
However you're not left alone with the Dungeon Master's wrath and the smite of the dice
you're a badass hero, and you have a lot of things that you're good at
and...possibly a few things that you're bad at
and those things are all based around six abilities scores:
Strength, Dexterity, Constitution
Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma.
(Ting)
These scores will give you modifiers, either bonuses or penalties,
that you add to your rolls to help determine
if your rogue sticks the landing on that stealthy back-flip into the shadows
or falls flat on their face (awkward giggle)
We'll get more into these six scores in another video.
Now, how about these six other dice?
Well, the number after the 'd' represents the sides of the die
You have a d4, a d6, d8, d10, and a d12
These dice are primarily used for damage or healing
and will generally correspond with what weapon you're using
or how powerful a spell might be.
If you see a number *before* that letter 'd'
this is how many dice of that type that you roll.
That great-sword does 2d6 damage?
Roll two six-sided dice.
Healing a friend for 3d8 hit points?
Roll three eight-sided die
add up the numbers to see just how powerful that ability was.
If you're currently looking at a set of gaming dice thinking:
"What the hell is this one?" It's a percentile die.
Certain classes have abilities that utilize percentage rolls
and you bust out Old Dusty here, along with a d10
and get a percentage out of one hundred.
It's pretty cool, right?
Honestly, percentage rolls don't come up too often
but when they do? Man, are they interesting!
That's you're gaming dice basics
and all we have for you on today's episode of Handbooker Helper.
Now, get out there and roll some dice!
Stay natural, my friends.
♫ Handbook, handbook, handbook, ♫
♫ Handbook-er Helper♫
Handbooker Helper
♫ Ting ♫
♫ Music ♫