(laughing)
MATT: And welcome back to tonight's episode.
So, picking up where we left off, Vox Machina,
having to find and collect the artifacts known as
the Vestiges of Divergence to prepare themselves
for battle against the Chroma Conclave, a group of
extremely dangerous chromatic dragons who are
wreaking havoc on the Tal'Dorei countryside,
and get vengeance for the loss of Vex and Vax's
father in the past. Er, sorry, mother. The
father's still around, and kind of a dick.
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: It's been a long week. However, you guys
have been making your way into the Feywild in
search of a specific item known as Fenthras,
a bow of which Vex has been sort of keeping an
eye on this whole time.
LAURA: Ahh, totally.
MATT: Just like that. (laughs) We're all having
Gen Con plague residual, here. They've made their
way through a number of strange, dangerous,
and awkward encounters in the Feywild, including
an encounter with their father, I meant to say
earlier, in Syngorn, which is currently hiding out
in the Feywild until they've prepared for battle
against Thordak the Cinder King. You went to the
Moonbrush and parleyed between pixies and
werewolves, you pushed past the Gilded Run,
a series of enchanted, dangerous rivers that keep
the Shademirk Bog in check from spreading across
the land with its corruption, and you stepped into
the Shademirk Bog, its strange, sludgey, black,
corrupt interior, stumbling upon what appears to
be a small hovel built out of a tree trunk.
The gnomes, making their way towards via Vex's
broom, caught a partial glimpse of the creature
that lived within, a door was suddenly opened,
and upon floating back, the broom was robbed of
its magical enchantment temporarily. The party
regathered and are now deciding what to do here in
the depths of the Shademirk Bog. So, as the gnomes
have returned, your broom has seemingly been
proven to still function--
LAURA: Don't say 'seemingly'.
MATT: Why? It's fun.
MATT: It's fun.
MARISHA: We confirmed.
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: What would you guys like to do?
SAM: All right, so that place over there,
the hut.
LAURA: Yeah.
SAM: I think it was not a good idea to go over
there. I think it's one of the things that
what's-his-fuck warned us about.
LAURA: Garmelie?
SAM: Yes.
LAURA: The hag, right?
SAM: I don't know. I wasn't really paying
attention.
LAURA: Yeah, no, he warned us about...
TALIESIN: I'm feeling the hag. Is anybody else
feeling the hag?
SAM: Something about a hut.
LAURA: I am not feeling the hag.
LIAM: I'm not feeling the hag.
MARISHA: How do you mean? Yeah, how do you mean,
feeling?
LIAM: I've had enough hag.
TALIESIN: We're not feeling the hag, but I think
we should avoid her.
LAURA: The Hut of Wodenna.
MARISHA: The Hut of Wodenna, right.
SAM: Yeah, that's probably Wodenna.
LAURA: It could be.
SAM: So why don't we go around the hut? Is that
possible? Is Garmelie gone?
LAURA: Garmelie's gone.
MATT: Garmelie left, you guys.
SAM: Oh yeah.
TRAVIS: Peaced out.
MATT: He wouldn't even enter the forest with you.
LAURA: However, she is aware of our presence, now,
isn't she?
SAM: So? We're big and scary. She's a little old
lady.
LIAM: What's the terrain like around this hut?
MATT: The forests of the Shademirk Bog is a very
very thickly wooded swamp with thick-trunked trees
and almost weeping willow-type sagging canopies,
but the entirety of each piece of brush here is
coated and seemingly seeping this kind of black
sticky tar-like ichor that just kind of pools and
seeps into the ground, so even traversing this
territory's been a slow, arduous process.
There is a small clearing around where this tree
trunk hovel is currently located, and the tree
itself does not appear to match the surrounding
trees
that kind of embody most of this forest
terrain.
LIAM: Does it look possible to skirt around it
from where we are?
MATT: You could skirt around it, most definitely,
yeah. It's just something you saw in the distance
and went and inspected, you could avoid it
entirely.
LIAM: Okay.
TALIESIN: And we do have a direction to move.
LAURA: Yeah, we know, we know that is not where
the bow is.
MARISHA: Yes, it was on Garmelie's list of things
to avoid.
SAM: But maybe she could help us in a way.
LAURA: I know, it's so terrible! I want to like
explore everything here because--
MARISHA: I wonder if she knows the other hags that
we've encountered.
LAURA: Forsythia...
SAM: It's like that urge when you're standing at
the edge of a cliff, like part of your body wants
to jump a little bit?
LAURA: Yeah.
SAM: I kinda wanna go in there.
LAURA: Kind of like when I dove into the river.
SAM: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
MATT: Yeah, exactly.
MARISHA: Well, see, you guys did kind of jump,
and it didn't feel good, right?
LAURA: Right, true.
TRAVIS: Devil's advocate.
MARISHA: So...
TRAVIS: What if she's lonely, and two, what if
she's not the hag and she knows where the hag is?
MARISHA: One, I'm certain she is lonely, and two,
she's probably the hag.
TALIESIN: I'm pretty sure she's the hag.
MARISHA: She's definitely probably the hag.
LIAM: We've kind of already had this conversation
before we went and poked a badger with those
floating instruments, we really don't need to do
every single thing.
LAURA: No, we don't, we really don't.
TRAVIS: I'm just saying you're profiling, is all.
LIAM: And I have a bad history with hags,
and I would like--
LAURA: Yes, you do.
LIAM: --to skip this fucking place.
TALIESIN: I'm okay with that. I, honestly I could
use a bit of sleep at some point and I think
moving in the correct direction, getting a bit of
sleep somewhere safe...
LAURA: And we've been do-si-doing the whole time
we've been having this conversation, definitely.
TALIESIN: I'm working on that as well.
MARISHA: I feel like we're trying to talk
ourselves out of this, aren't we?
LAURA: I think we need to not go towards the hut.
MARISHA: Okay, we'll not go towards the hut.
LAURA: To the tree, to scariness.
TALIESIN: If there was a time to not be us,
this is the moment.
MARISHA: It's probably now.
LAURA: This is that time.
TALIESIN: Right now.
TRAVIS: I take out the javelin of lightning.
ALL: No!
SAM: You have a javelin of lightning?
LAURA: He does.
TRAVIS: I do.
TALIESIN: He does, in fact, have a javelin of
lightning.
SAM: Why have you never used a javelin of
lightning?
LAURA: He has, he has one time. Don't.
TRAVIS: And I, I just make sure that it's clean
and put it back.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Let's just sneakily go off and just not pay
any more attention to this charming little tree.
MARISHA: Okay.
TALIESIN: I feel like we've done enough damage for
one day.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we've gotta at least come back this
way, so, you know.
LAURA: This is true. Ugh.
MATT: All righty. You guys--
TRAVIS: We go around. Stealthily.
LAURA: Stealthily walk away from the hut.
TRAVIS: Do we still have Pass Without a Trace?
LAURA: Do we still have Pass Without a Trace
going, or do I need--no, it dropped, it dropped.
MATT: You traveled quite a while, yeah.
LAURA: Because we fought something, so I would
need to cast it again. Which I do! Cast again.
Pass Without a Trace.
SAM: Thank you!
LAURA: Um, maybe Dust of Tracelessness behind us
so the hag
doesn't feel tempted to maybe follow in
our footsteps.
TRAVIS: Don't tell me what to do, devil-woman.
TRAVIS: I take out the Dust of Tracelessness.
It looks good, I put it back.
LAURA: Grog, please, flower-girl, please.
TRAVIS: Javelin or Dust of Tracelessness,
they go together. If I do one, I do the other.
LAURA: You're terrible. That's terrible.
TRAVIS: I need a little danger in my life.
TALIESIN: I promise you, we're going to kill
something very soon.
LAURA: Soon!
TRAVIS: There's a giant werewolf following us...
LAURA: We just killed the crocodile plant.
We just killed a crocodile plant.
MARISHA: That's true.
LAURA: Seriously, we just fought something.
MARISHA: You were inside his gut. You have to
remember that.
LAURA: Just did that.
TRAVIS: I didn't really hit it that much,
it was very unsatisfying.
(All laugh.)
LAURA: Let's walk away.
LAURA: I wanna stealth.
MATT: All right. Everyone make a stealth check.
MARISHA: All right. New d20.
LAURA: Oh, high hopes!
TRAVIS: Did you say Pass Without a Trace?
LAURA: Pass Without a Trace, I cast Pass Without a
Trace.
TALIESIN: Huh. That's weird.
MARISHA: That's a dick move. That is a--
TALIESIN: That's weird.
LAURA: Did you get a 20, did you get a 20 on it?
TALIESIN: I got a 19.
LAURA: Aw.
MARISHA: He got a 19 and I got a three.
LAURA: Oh, come on.
(All laugh.)
LAURA: That's just not cool.
MATT: That's actually pretty funny.
SAM: That's one better than before!
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: Are these new opal dice?
MARISHA: It's a step in the right direction.
LAURA: They are.
TRAVIS: They switched, yeah.
SAM: New dice.
LAURA: There's no excuse now.
MATT: All right, so.
LAURA: I think it's just a curse on you, Marisha.
MATT: Stealth.
TRAVIS: 25.
MATT: 25. Vax?
LIAM: Did we use the Dust of Tracelessness?
LAURA: No, we used Pass Without a Trace, though,
so add ten.
LIAM: No? Well, I will settle for a 27.
MATT: Okay, with a plus ten?
LIAM: No, I, didn't we use--
LAURA and TRAVIS: Pass Without a Trace.
MATT: Pass Without a Trace was used.
LIAM: I just, oh, all right.
LAURA and MATT: You said Dust of Tracelessness.
LIAM: Oh, 37.
MATT: Lotta traces going on, it's fine. Plus ten
added, so 37.
LAURA: 36.
MATT: 36.
MARISHA: 20.
TALIESIN: 35.
SAM: 30.
MATT: All right, and Pike...
LAURA: Pike!
MATT: All right.
(All laugh.)
MATT: Ehhh, natural three. It's okay. You guys
make your way around the outskirts of this kind of
open glade area, scooting by. As you begin to
separate, finally getting to a point where the
direction you're trying to head, where you noticed
seemingly all the liquid that's seeping from,
the actual movement, momentum of the horrible
black material was like pushing slowly outward
from apparently some center place? You follow that
slow flow best you can. As you begin to pull away,
you hear a slight creak sound in the distance.
(creaking)
LAURA: No. Can we see if the door shut?
TRAVIS: Hide! I hide.
LAURA: Did the door shut?
MATT: Perception check.
LIAM: Yeah, perception.
LAURA: Um. 25.
MATT: You look back over your shoulder and notice
the door just (creaking, bang) and closes.
LAURA: Okay.
TRAVIS: Fuck.
LAURA: No, that's...
MATT: As it closes--
TRAVIS: She's out here now.
MATT: --there's a sudden flash of wind, and
there's a flicker in Pike's form as all of a
sudden she (flickering sound)
LAURA: No!
PIKE: Guys?
MATT: And her divine form vanishes in place,
apparently sent back to the source of where she
projected her essence.
LAURA: She didn't get, like, stolen or something?
LIAM: That is never not unsettling.
LAURA: Away?
MATT: Uh, not to your knowledge. It's similar to
the previous times that she's been unable to keep
her form there for you. Especially between planes,
you can imagine it's been rather difficult for
her to be here for the time she has.
LAURA: Maybe the hag cast a Dispell she did on the
broom?
MARISHA: Yeah, Dispell Magic.
TALIESIN: Or maybe things just got strange.
MARISHA: Poor reception.
SAM: Something I said.
LAURA: Love you, Pike.
TRAVIS: Something you said. (laughs)
LAURA: Definitely something you said.
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: All right.
MARISHA: Can we see the hag moving
inside the hut through the window?
MATT: You make a perception check as you're
glancing that way.
TRAVIS: Can I look for Ukurat?
MATT: Perception check.
MARISHA: Oh my god.
LAURA: Seriously?
MARISHA: 14.
MATT: 14? You see movement on the inside,
but no actual physical bead on an entity.
You just see the light being broken in the
window.
LAURA: Okay, so she's...
MARISHA: Yeah, she's inside.
LAURA: That's good.
TRAVIS: A gigantic 11.
SAM: You've yet to break single digits with them.
TALIESIN: New die.
MATT: You barely notice anything beyond the trees,
you have to remind yourself, oh, there's a house
there. But.
(Laura laughs.)
TRAVIS: That sounds accurate.
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Who are these people, like, (gasps).
LAURA: Keyleth, what direction was the big scary
blight on the land?
MARISHA: Northeast?
SAM: Northwest.
MATT: Northwest.
MARISHA: Northwest. Northwest.
LAURA: So we head that direction.
MARISHA: This direction.
MATT: All right. (laughs)
MATT: Following Keyleth's lead, you guys begin to
slowly make your way through this bog and--
LAURA: Keep an eye out for anything moving.
MATT: Everything's slowly moving in its own right,
this kind of (sludgey sound)
LAURA: Shit.
TRAVIS: Easy there, tiger.
MATT: Sliding of awful liquid.
LAURA: Anything seemingly aggressive.
MATT: Understood.
TRAVIS: Don't shoot any trees.
MATT: As you kind of push further, further
northward, you guys are having...
do you have to sneeze?
LAURA: It went away.
MATT: Okay, good. You get the sensation,
it's not even a sensation, the rest of the party
-- aside from you-- you guys are getting knee-deep
in this liquid now, and it's to the point where
you're having to take one step, lurch it out of
the liquid onto another, and you're having to go
out of your way to kind of hug the edges of trees
where the roots themselves are protruding to give
yourself some kind of foothold as opposed to
getting stuck in this bog. You, Scanlan,
are having a particularly rough time trying to
walk on your own, because with each... though with
your light form, it's a lot of strength to even
pull your
little feet out of this tar-like substance. So.
TRAVIS: Yeah, Pimps-a-lot, you wanna?
SAM: Absolutely.
TRAVIS: Okay.
TRAVIS: Can I pick him up? And it's black stuff,
right?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Can I smell the black stuff on him?
MATT: Yeah, I mean, it permeates the area but it's
particularly strong at his feet and lower
extremities, almost went up to his upper thighs.
It is a, it smells like a combination of wet
blacktop, sulfur, and compost decay.
TRAVIS: Yeah, in the summer?
MATT: Yeah, like a hot, hot, Florida compost,
yeah.
TRAVIS: I know that exact, accurate smell.
MATT: Yeah. It's delightful.
SAM: Drakkar.
TRAVIS: You smell terrible.
SAM: Sorry.
LAURA: That's a lot, coming from Grog.
SAM: That is true.
TRAVIS: How about you, I'll put you on my
shoulder, but how about you sit on my shoulder
like strapped back there and just hang out the
back?
SAM: Sit on your shoulder straps.
TRAVIS: No, don't put your feet near my face,
like hang out on the back of me.
SAM: All right, all right. Thank you for the
lift.
TRAVIS: No worries.
LAURA: It's good, you can keep an eye out for the
hag following behind us.
SAM: That's good.
SAM: Wait, am I like being Yoda-carried right
now?
(All laugh.)
LAURA: Yes.
TRAVIS: I'm flipping and climbing vines and shit.
MARISHA: Oh man, that makes me want a Scanlan
backpack. Oh man.
MATT: Okay. As you guys push on forward,
Keyleth guiding the direction, you're the only
one who moves without an issue. Are you tracking
ahead of the party, or are you staying with them?
LAURA: I am tracking a little bit ahead of them.
MATT: All right. You travel for about another hour
or so forward, and you, just being naturally alert
as you are, notice some shift of movement that is
more sudden than the slow sway of some of the
various branches and boughs of nearby trees.
A little bit in the direction you're traveling
and to the left.
LAURA: What did it look like? Just movement?
MATT: It moves again, and you see what appears to
be some almost large rock-like figure that's
shifting, and the more you take a moment to focus,
it looks like a humanoid-type creature hunched
over, facing away from you.
LAURA: (mouthing) We should go, we should go that
way.
LAURA: Can I point everybody to go around,
keeping a wide berth?
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: Lead the way.
LAURA: Percy, look over there with your eyesight,
look through
your little scope and see what you see.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna try and scope it.
MATT: Okay. Make a perception check with
advantage.
TALIESIN: Ugh. Could be worse. 16.
LAURA: Oh.
MATT: Okay. You, um. You take a moment and kind of
train on this movement. You now see there are two
figures that are facing each other, and they
themselves are covered in this horrible liquid,
and you recognize the form a little bit.
These, they're humanoid, but they have long,
exaggerated jaws, very long forearm limbs, tall,
straggly black hair, long, pointed hooked nose,
and they're both eating something that's
partially stuck in this bog. These are trolls,
these are two large trolls that are currently in
the process of eating some sort of creature.
TALIESIN: A pair of trolls.
LAURA: (whispering) We need to be very quiet.
MATT: You've had a piece of troll in your bag for
a while.
LAURA: Oh!
TRAVIS: Oh yeah. Troll dick.
LAURA: So we've killed them before, that's good to
know.
TRAVIS: Yeah. They're huge.
MATT: Trolls are pretty big.
LAURA: They were--
TRAIVS: About how big are they?
MATT: Like... I'd say, even with the hunch,
nine feet tall.
LAURA: Yeah. Just... you know, maybe go around?
SAM: Yes, we should go around.
LAURA: What do you think?
SAM: We could kill them quite easily.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: Well, there's two of them that we see.
TALIESIN: That we see.
TRAVIS: Hey, Percy.
LIAM: They're stupid, aren't they?
LAURA: Didn't, wait--
MARISHA: I don't know.
LAURA: Didn't Tiberius turn into a lady-troll?
TALIESIN: That was a thing, yes.
MARISHA: That happened.
LAURA: Oh.
MARISHA: To be fair, also, everything in the
Feywild--
SAM: What?
MARISHA: -- has been more sensitive, defensive,
and more intelligent.
LAURA: They could be smarter.
TALIESIN: They could be smart trolls.
LAURA: They could be, like, hag trolls, which is
just terrifying.
TALIESIN: They're eating something that's stuck.
LAURA: Which could be us very soon.
TALIESIN: Which could be us very soon.
LAURA: We need to keep moving.
TALIESIN: Let's keep moving.
LAURA: The longer we stand still, the more stuck
we get.
MATT: You hear this (grunt) in the distance,
and you now, looking through your scope,
you see that one of them has looked up from its
eating, its mouth covered in all sorts of shiny,
fresh liquid, and it kind of glances past.
Its eyes, the pupils are white against yellow
eyes, so it has this very kind of flash across a
cat's face type gleam across the eyeballs.
They kind of... (grunts)
LIAM: Can we all see this?
MATT: Yeah, you guys can see, since you've all
made note of these creatures in the distance.
LIAM: Why don't we back it up slow for once?
LAURA: Well, how about we don't move at all right
now?
MARISHA: Everybody freeze.
MATT: Turns around, (trollish grunt), says
something to the other one. They both grab a big
chunk of whatever they're eating, jam it in their
mouth, and then dive down into the muck.
SAM: Oh, shit.
LAURA: Can we get up in the trees?
MATT: If you'd like to try and climb them.
LAURA: Can we try and climb the trees?
TALIESIN: We're going to try and climb a tree.
SAM: To what end? Then we're just gonna sit here
forever?
TALIESIN: For a minute.
LAURA: Well no, we can go from tree branch to tree
branch. Are they tightly enough connected that we
can travel on the top of the trees?
MATT: Possibly. Might require some jumping.
SAM: I am a backpack right now.
LAURA: I'm gonna get on the broom and fly up.
MATT: You fly up.
LIAM: I'll climb after her.
MATT: Okay. Go ahead and make an athletics check,
if you don't mind, Vax.
TRAVIS: I'm not scared of trolls.
LIAM: 18.
SAM: Could you be, please?
MATT: It takes you a minute, but you manage to get
up to the tree. You come up into the trees.
Do you break the canopy, or do you stop up at the
branches?
LAURA: I wanted to... yeah, sure, I'll break the
canopy.
MATT: Okay. As you're climbing up, your sister
actually goes past where the branches, leaves,
and the top of the trees end. Before you can
really kind of speak out to question, she
disappears. You, Vex, come shooting up off the top
out, and you can see now before you the Shademirk
in its entirety, kind of wrapping around the base
of this one mountain, that kind of comes up into
two sharp peaks, like horns on some sort of a
large debased devil, but it's just a formless rock
mold that comes up into those two peaks.
Looking around you, you can see the trees are
very, very dense and heavily packed together,
and what immediately catches your eye is about
two, three miles ahead, right towards where the
base of the mountain seems to sink into the
Shademirk, there is one very, very large tree that
stands above the rest of them.
LAURA: Oh, shit. Why didn't I go above the canopy
before?
MARISHA: Is it to the northwest?
MATT: It is what would be considered to the
northwest of you. It, whereas the rest of the
Shademirk continues to this relative 20-,
30-foot-tall canopy, this tree probably goes
up about a hundred-plus feet and the branches
string outward and have long strands and vines
dangling from them, it's, this is a massive
example of local flora and fauna.
LAURA: Wow. Okay. I say, I see the tree! And I
come back down into the canopy.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Can I come down and grab... Keyleth? And
lift her up into the tree too?
MATT: Sure.
MARISHA: Ooh.
TRAVIS: How high are the lowest branches?
MATT: The lowest branches are about seven feet
up.
TRAVIS: You wanna lift?
SAM: I'm just a passenger. I'm on you. If you're
not going up, I'm staying on you.
TRAVIS: I'm not going up.
LAURA: You're not gonna go up in the tree?
SAM: We're gonna--
TRAVIS: You think my giant ass is gonna jump
frockily-fucky-fucky from branch to branch in the
treetops like some kind of acrobat?
LAURA: I don't know.
TRAVIS: No! No.
SAM: We're standing our muck.
MARISHA: Well, okay, is what we're trying to do
figure out a way to not have to walk in the muck?
LAURA: Yeah, I think so.
MARISHA: You're--
LAURA: I feel like the trolls are gonna pop up,
like, somewhere near us.
TRAVIS: Can I put my back against a tree?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: A large tree.
MATT: Yeah. The nearest tree, the one that Vax
actually climbed up, is the one that's closest to
you guys, and it's close enough for you to just
take a five-foot step back up into it.
SAM: I'm back here! I'm back here, I'm back here,
I'm back here!
LAURA: You're against the tree.
TRAVIS: I turn around. The trees talk.
SAM: It's me. Don't back up into a tree--
TRAVIS: I spin around again and put my back to
this tree.
SAM: I'm still back here! I'm still back here!
TRAVIS: Oh.
LAURA: While that's going on, can I fly down and
get Percy out of the muck
and bring him up into the tree?
MATT: Sure.
LIAM: I'm gonna chime in over the earring and say,
Somebody could turn Grog into a marmoset or
something, that would work for the circumstances.
LAURA: Oh, shit.
MARISHA: That's what I was gonna say, I can always
polymorph you for a moment, Grog.
TRAVIS: I might be down with being some kind of
monkey.
MARISHA: You want to be a monkey? Yeah. What kind
of monkey?
TRAVIS: Gorilla.
MARISHA: Okay.
LAURA: Oh, shit.
MARISHA: And I turn Grog into a gorilla.
MATT: And with that, Grog's already pretty large
form just grows smaller and hairier.
TRAVIS: Nimble as shit.
LAURA: What the fuck! I should get Scanlan...
MATT: You look down at yourself and kind of
marveling at your hands, which haven't changed too
much other than the place some of the fingers and
thumbs, you already have pretty big, strong,
hands, but you also pull up one of your feet from
the muck and you can see the additional appendage
that you now have in the prehensile toes.
LAURA: Grog, get in the tree, get in the tree.
TALIESIN: I don't see a change, I'm not sure.
TRAVIS: No.
LAURA: Tree.
LAURA: Please.
TRAVIS: Grog.
LAURA: Aw.
SAM: Also has the mind of an ape.
MATT: Yep.
LAURA: Seriously?
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: Which might be more intelligent than what
he was before...
MATT: Actually, let's...
TRAVIS: Ah, shit.
MATT: Let's have a look what the--
TRAVIS: Gorillas can't--
MATT: Let's see, let's pull up the Monster Manual
here and see exactly what we're working with.
LAURA: Gorillas are pretty fucking smart.
TALIESIN: Yeah, you have one, don't you?
MARISHA: I think I do.
LAURA: I think they'd be smarter than Grog.
MARISHA: I do, but I don't have it in my little
book.
LAURA: They can learn sign language, they have,
like, an entire, yeah.
LIAM: Strongjaw's kitten?
LAURA: Oh!
MATT: All right, we'll go with the stats for an
ape, 'cause that's what's here and available.
They do have intelligence of six, so you are as
intelligent as you were before.
(All laugh.)
TRAVIS: But I do this with my foot.
MARISHA: Looks good on you, Grog.
TRAVIS: I'm gonna-- can I?
MATT: No, you can't talk.
TRAVIS: (gorilla noises)
LAURA: Shit. Scanlan, do you want to ride on
Grog's back still,
or do you want to come up in the tree?
SAM: No, I don't--
TRAVIS: (gorilla noises)
MARISHA: Ooh, you'd be like a little silverback
baby.
LAURA: Can I go down and grab Scanlan and put him
on the broom with me?
MATT: Sure.
LAURA: Okay.
SAM: Thank you.
LIAM: Honestly, I can't even tell the difference.
TRAVIS: That still translates, right?
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: Okay, I know the twins are good on
flying, for the most part.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'll stay down here as bait.
LAURA: Yeah, yeah.
LIAM: I don't know, how long ago did you bust out
my wings for me, DM? Under 24 hours?
MATT: Yeah, it's been under 24 hours. So
unfortunately your wings are not available.
LAURA: No wings for you.
MARISHA: Well, but you can walk unhindered,
right? You can walk fine?
LAURA: Yeah, yeah.
MARISHA: Can someone borrow your broom?
LAURA: Again? Yes.
MARISHA: Again. (laughs)
LAURA: Yeah, that worked really well last time.
Totally. Somebody can.
MARISHA: Give it to your brother. He's
trustworthy, right? Right? Right, Vax?
LAURA: He had the carpet before, so. Maybe not so
much, but the whole point was for the trolls to
not have us on the ground, the trolls, but.
MARISHA: Oh, right, that's true.
LAURA: Can we just try to travel amongst the
trees?
TALIESIN: Let's see what happens.
SAM: Stick to the plan.
MARISHA: I'm gonna go ahead, I'm gonna use a
Beastshape and I'm gonna go into an eagle form.
MATT: Okay. Giant eagle. All right. Beastshape is
taken, he's gorillafied,
you have Scanlan up on your broom.
LAURA: Yes.
MATT: And then Vax and... Percy, are you just
traveling through the canopy?
LAURA: Shit.
MATT: Or are you carrying somebody, Keyleth?
LAURA: Do you wanna carry Scanlan?
MARISHA: I can carry Scanlan.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: How thick are the trees here?
LAURA: I feel like we could--
MATT: They range anywhere from between five feet
and--
LIAM: I had such a hard time when I flew up the
other day, such a hard time...
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: And everyone's just floating up, easy as
pie.
MARISHA: To be fair, I've been flying a lot longer
than you have, Vax.
LAURA: That's true, and your wings are much larger
than hers were.
MARISHA: It's true.
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: Yeah. And I've got a skinny little broom,
so I'm not flapping any wings.
LIAM: I'm skinnier than your broom.
LAURA: Yes, well.
(Marisha laughs.)
LIAM: Let's do it.
TALIESIN: All right.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: Then I guess I can take one of you on the
broom with me.
TALIESIN: Take him. I'll be fine. I'm gonna,
I have a potion of climbing.
LAURA: Do you wanna hop on this, since you have no
flight?
MARISHA: Ooh, potion of climbing, nice.
LAURA: Brother?
MARISHA: All right, I fly over to Scanlan.
LIAM: No, but I will anyway.
SAM: I'm with you now?
MARISHA: (eagle sound)
LAURA: All right, he's on the broom with me.
MATT: All right, so the twins are on the broom,
they go up. Grog, you just have a field day
leaping through those branches, and just coasting
through, keeping an eye best you can on the
guiding broom above the actual tree canopy.
You go ahead and
grab Scanlan as well and follow suit.
MATT: As soon as you break up as well, you can see
the large tree in the distance. Percy, doing the
best you can to keep an eye on Grog or at least
listen to that regard, you drink your potion of
climbing and begin leaping off and kind of
ninja-scattering your way through the higher
branches of the trees as well.
TRAVIS: Anime shit.
TALIESIN: Oh yeah.
MATT: So if I can go ahead and get Grog and Percy
to go ahead and make three successive athletics
checks, if you could.
TALIESIN: With advantage?
MATT: This would be, for you it would be
advantage, yeah.
TRAVIS: What's the modifier for king of the apes?
MATT: You know what, I'll give you advantage on
this just 'cause you're an ape.
TALIESIN: Athletics or acrobatics?
MATT: Um. For the purposes of climbing and
grabbing,
I would say this is more of an athletics check.
TALIESIN: Okay.
MATT: Since this is more upper-body strength
and--
LAURA: Not parkouring, not parkouring through the
treetops.
TALIESIN: That'll do.
TRAVIS: That's a 20, 12 plus eight.
TALIESIN: 16.
MATT: All righty.
TRAVIS: 21.
TALIESIN: 24.
MATT: All righty. Last one.
TRAVIS: Not so great. 23.
TALIESIN: Natural 20.
MATT: All righty. To your surprise, as the potion
energy surges through your body, even with the
relatively slick surface that a lot of these
branches and trees have, you have an innate
ability to point out which ones are the strongest,
easiest to grab a hold and just keep the momentum
going in the semblance of a parkour-like
leap-and-grab-type circumstance, you have managed
to move through almost with the grace of the
gorilla ahead of you. You lose sight a few times,
but you guys do take the better part of the next
forty minutes or so to eventually make your way
closer and closer to the tree where the shadow,
the shade of it against the permanently dusk sun
now begins to creep over the place you are in the
forest. You have now entered a shaded nightfall by
the actual tree's location and placement.
The lower forest below you is pitch-black at this
point, other than a little bit of light that
filters in from nearby lit areas of the forest.
(Audible feedback.)
LAURA: Oh.
MATT: Oh?
SAM: There's a punk band warming up.
(All laugh.)
MATT: Never ends. There we go. You guys make your
way towards, are you going straight for the tree
or are you...?
LAURA: Okay. Do we wanna go straight for the tree
now,
or do we wanna like rest up before we do
that?
TALIESIN: I think we want to observe it and rest
up.
LIAM: Observe, yes.
MARISHA: Like scout?
LAURA: Watch it and see what's going on with it?
LIAM: Yes.
LAURA: Before we just go straight to it?
TRAVIS: We don't have the mansion, right?
SAM: We have the mansion.
TALIESIN: We do. We have the mansion.
TRAVIS: (gorilla noise)
SAM: How many hours since we've slept last?
MATT: I'd say it's probably been, surmising,
six to seven.
TALIESIN: Really? It's been since the river.
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: Yeah.
SAM: So we can at least do some, we can get closer
and do some recon.
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: Let's do recon, let's observe it for the
next six to ten hours
and then rest up in the shag.
LAURA: That's a long time. All right.
MARISHA: I go ahead and I take off with Scanlan
and do kind of
a high aerial loop around the tree.
SAM: (worried noise)
MATT: All righty.
LAURA: Oh jeez, around the tree? Around it?
MARISHA: Just at the top, really high. Really
high, getting nice--
LAURA: I wanna kind of perch on top of a tree
nearby and just kind of see it from there.
MARISHA: Watch.
TALIESIN: I want to see if I can find the source
of the bog muck.
MATT: Okay. You both make a perception check from
being up in the tree.
SAM: Wait, tre-- oh.
MARISHA: Do I have advantage because I'm an
eagle?
MATT: Well, it would be--
SAM: Above the tree, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
MARISHA: Don't eagles have advantage?
SAM: Eight.
(All laugh.)
MARISHA: I do have advantage.
SAM: Just 'cause.
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: Eagle eyes.
MARISHA: Eagle eyes. 27.
MATT: 27. As you coast around the outside of this
gargantuan tree, you can see there are a number of
places where the branches meet and where elements
of the bark are slightly split, and there is just
a slow, perpetual flow of this black tar-like
substance. You've seen it on smaller scales
seeping from the trees in this actual forest,
it's like the entirety of the landscape is kind
of creating this, but the bulk of it, whether it
be the source of the general corruption or at
least is the largest central location of its
source? There are a number of places throughout
this tree where it's just seeping out like sap.
MARISHA: Like sap.
LAURA: Like bleeding out oil.
MATT: Out of the actual tree.
MARISHA: Like even the top of the tree and stuff.
LIAM: Like evil maple syrup.
MARISHA: Evil maple syrup, yeah.
LAURA: Mm, sounds tasty. Can--
TRAVIS: Like ghostbusters.
LAURA: -- we see any kind of movement, any kind of
things moving around the tree?
MATT: You don't see anything moving around the
tree at the moment, other than just the gentle
swaying as a little bit of wind hits the sides of
it, portions of its long hundreds and hundreds of
hanging vines just kind of slowly get moved and
tangled by the windfall. If you want to make a
perception check as well.
LAURA: Okay. That would be 30.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: I got a natural 20. Using Luck.
MATT: Great. So the two twins up there on the
broom, as you kind of glance around the other
side, you both can see the branches themselves
occasionally will shift and curl up, almost like
an arm recoiling, and then relax slowly back out
again,
like a stretching arm held still for too long.
LAURA: Oh, shit. I think the tree is alive and not
in a normal plant sort of way.
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: You also notice some of the vines that are
wrapped around and kind of curled around these
branches as well occasionally recoil and pull in
and shift and move up, it's like there's a whole
ecosystem based around numerous forms of plant
life that cause this thing
to almost act like a giant organism.
LAURA: Fuck, I do not wanna get close to that
thing.
MARISHA: I know, that's intimidating.
LIAM: I'm gonna rest my chin on my sister's
shoulder and just stare for a minute and say,
you know, that bow is going to be reeeally cool.
LAURA: God, I hope so.
LIAM: Yeah. Worth it.
MARISHA: Still on my back, Scanlan, you wanna get
closer?
SAM: I'm using my eight perception, I report to
the others, it's just a normal tree, guys.
(All laugh.)
SAM: Nothing out of the ordinary, no movement,
nothing. It's safe.
LAURA: Thanks, Scanlan. Your eyes, your eyes...
TRAVIS: Can I check myself for parasites?
MATT: You find a number of them, actually.
They're delicious.
(All laugh.)
MATT: For the two of you that are below the
treeline, you don't get a grand view above,
it's too hard to see, but you guys make your way
close to the actual base of the tree?
LAURA: Ugh! No! What? The base of the fucking
tree?
LIAM: No, no.
LAURA: No fucking way, don't do that.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna get close enough to at least
make out some detail.
MARISHA: And I'll do kind of a tighter loop around
it.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: See if I can get any more details.
MATT: All right. Percy, you have to get pretty
close to even get a view because of the density of
the trees the closer you get to this. So you guys
are probably going to have to get within 20,
30 feet to get a view of the exterior of the
large tree.
LIAM: That's a bad idea.
LAURA: Yeah. Can we see him walking towards it?
MATT: No, you have no view of them this high in
the canopy.
LAURA: Fuck.
MATT: They're below the treeline. Percy,
as you get closer you begin to notice that the
actual roots of the tree almost come 10 feet up
before they merge with
the outside of the tree itself, a number of--
TALIESIN: Is it a solid trunk, or is it like a
combined trunk?
MATT: It's a solid trunk in most of its places,
but there are swaths of vines that wrap around it
and curl and create these giant, tight nets,
almost like a Rat King of tails across certain
portions of its exterior near the base, and where
some of
the roots join with the central tree trunk.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna back up and try and find a
place to scan the ground,
find a place to put a door for our mansion.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: Safe.
MATT: Okay, I mean, there are a number of areas
that are somewhat clear on the ground, but there
is no-- All the landscape is coated with this
molasses-type material, even the bits that aren't
submerged and are relatively shallow, there is
still that substance all across them.
MARISHA: I was doing a tighter loop.
MATT: Right.
MARISHA: Of the tree, see if I can get any more
details that we haven't already seen.
MATT: Okay. Keeping your eyes out as best you can
as you loop around a second time, you get closer,
no real change in what you're able to observe.
You have a higher detailed look at it, but once
again, you see a number of these vine-clusters
around the base of some of these branches,
you see elements where the bark has split and
sealed over and split again
and just spills out more of this black filth.
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: You aren't able to make out any sort of
other details about its surface.
MARISHA: I fly back to the others.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Percy?
TALIESIN: Yes?
LAURA: Are you on the ground?
TALIESIN: No, but I'm close to it.
LAURA: Do you see any sort of animal life around
the tree?
TALIESIN: Nothing, no.
LAURA: The only thing I've seen is actual branches
moving like arms. I think the tree's alive.
TALIESIN: If I were animal life, I would live
beneath the surface.
LAURA: Like the trolls.
TALIESIN: Like the trolls. I think there's quite
possibly things that live in the muck.
Probably not on top of it.
LAURA: Do you guys think maybe we should, um.
We should get in the mansion and have a nice
little chat and figure out what the fuck we're
gonna do?
SAM: Sure. Sounds good to me.
TRAVIS: How do I not become a gorilla anymore?
LAURA: Yeah?
LIAM: Yeah. We want to be at full strength.
MATT: You don't.
MARISHA: It's up to me.
LIAM: Don't run in willy-nilly.
TRAVIS: I look at Keyleth and I go--
MATT: She doesn't see you, 'cause she's way above
the trees and you're just kind of down in the
forest as a gorilla going--
TRAVIS: I'm on the ground?
MATT: You're not on the ground, you're up in the
actual tree top.
SAM: While we still have a, I'll phone down to Vex
and Vax and Percy and say, while we still have a
giant eagle, is there any point to us, to me and
Kiki scanning back to where those trolls were and
just making sure they're not following us or
anything?
TALIESIN: No, although if you find a log
approximately two feet thick,
I could certainly use that.
SAM: A log?
TALIESIN: A log, about two feet thick.
LAURA: About how long, though?
TALIESIN: Doesn't matter.
LAURA: You wanna fly down? We fly down, I take the
broom and try to find a log.
LIAM: Yeah, you're in control.
LAURA: All right.
MATT: All right, so the two of you kind of-- make
a perception check.
LAURA: (laughs) Yeah.
LIAM: Seventeen.
LAURA: That's interesting. I got fifteen.
MATT: Okay, uh.
LIAM: What a lackluster okay.
LAURA: Yeah, okay.
MATT: It takes you guys the better part of an hour
to finally find a piece of abandoned dead tree
husk from which you'll be able to carve a piece
that
matches the description of what
Percy's requesting.
LAURA: All right.
MATT: Requires some cleaning, it is very thick
with the actual tar, but you do manage to bring it
back to him. A little larger than what you wanted,
but it can be carved down.
TALIESIN: It's fine, I've got a thought,
so I'm gonna try something.
MARISHA: I drop Grog's polymorph and my eagle
form.
SAM: (screams as though falling)
MARISHA: ...after I've landed.
SAM: Oh, okay.
MATT: Okay. You are back to your regular Grog
self.
TRAVIS: My pants are down, as my hand was behind
my bottom, just contemplating flinging some poo.
MATT: All right, and in that brief moment all of a
sudden you are, well, some of your sense have come
to you. Not much else has changed other than your
physicality, but...
TRAVIS: Hi guys.
LAURA: Hi Grog.
LIAM: I think a little bit actually got out,
buddy.
LAURA: Gross! Come on.
TRAVIS: It didn't, don't worry.
LAURA: So foul.
MATT: All right, so. You've all managed to
reconvene a little ways off from the base of this
large tree. What do you wish to do?
SAM: Should we--
LAURA: (singing) Mansion it up!
SAM: Yeah?
TALIESIN: I could use some sleep, and I've got a
little thing to work on for the moment.
SAM: Okay.
LIAM: What are you doing with this log, Percival?
What is this for?
MARISHA: Is this what we were talking about that
time?
TALIESIN: Swamp shoes.
MARISHA: Swamp shoes.
LAURA: Swamp shoes?
TALIESIN: I think some swamp shoes might not be a
terrible idea.
MARISHA: I can help you with those.
TALIESIN: Thank you. Swamp shoes.
LAURA: So you can walk like me?
TALIESIN: Yes. I mean, not quickly, it won't help
you walk quickly, it's not necessarily the most
stealthy thing on earth, but you won't drop two
feet into the muck every time you take a step.
LAURA: That's good.
TRAVIS: I've got a question. Can one of us that
can turn into things go in the muck?
LAURA: Oh.
TALIESIN: Maybe.
LAURA: I feel like, is it bad? Do we get any kind
of bad vibe, bad energy off the muck?
SAM: Other than it being black magic?
MATT: Roll an insight check.
TALIESIN: The muck is unhappy to be there.
MARISHA: That mud looked at me the wrong way.
LAURA: No, but I mean, what if it makes us sad to
be around it?
TALIESIN: It does make us sad to be around it.
LAURA: Nineteen. Nineteen.
MATT: Those are some nice boots you're wearing,
you're probably gonna have to get a new pair when
all this is over. It stinks, it's sticky,
the muck itself is probably not a very nice
conversationalist. It doesn't also from what you
can tell appear to be sentient or give you any
kind of bad vibe that you can pick up.
LAURA: Okay.
TALIESIN: It's just muck.
MATT: From looking at it. It is muck.
TRAVIS: I mean, I'll go in and--
MARISHA: I can go.
TRAVIS: Yeah?
LAURA: Stanky-stank.
MATT: Stanky-stank.
MARISHA: Sounds fun.
TRAVIS: What are you gonna turn into?
MARISHA: Something that burrows. I guess I
technically could've taken a short rest, correct?
MATT: Not yet, no.
TALIESIN: We haven't yet.
SAM: So we're doing this now?
MARISHA: In the time we're just chilling? Okay,
well, I'll take a short rest.
TALIESIN: Let's take a long rest, I mean.
SAM: Well, no, I--
MARISHA: I just want to take a short rest, just--
MATT: A short rest is about half an hour or so.
Half an hour to an hour.
MARISHA: Yeah, just enough time, and then I'm
gonna
turn into an earth elemental and I'm gonna
swan dive--
SAM: Wait, wait!
LAURA: Swan dive?
MATT: We'll get to that. Because as you take your
short rest and
begin sitting amongst the ground or
the bough of the trees--
MARISHA: I thought we were in the mansion.
MATT: No, the mansion hasn't been cast yet.
MARISHA: Oh.
MATT: So as you're resting, here amongst the tree
tops--
LAURA: We're in the tree tops.
MATT: Yeah. The branches begin to sag ever so
slowly.
LAURA: Shit.
MATT: And particularly Keyleth and Percy,
actually Grog as well, you begin to feel the
branches slowly almost trying to push you off
them, like you sort of slide forward.
MARISHA: Did I say something? I don't know.
TALIESIN: No, you didn't say anything.
LAURA: Trees, you're so lovely, even though you're
covered in this black stuff, I can tell that you
have really good personalities.
MARISHA: You've clearly been moisturizing.
TRAVIS: You really don't think that's--
MATT: All the branches begin to slowly sag down.
LAURA: Shit! I push off, we're flying, we're
hovering.
MATT: And you guys all begin to slide down--
TALIESIN: I'm going to make a jump to another
tree.
MARISHA: Yeah, I do the same.
MATT: Okay, make an athletics check, both of you.
SAM: I will too.
LAURA: What about you, Grog?
MARISHA: Oh my god. This is horrifying.
TALIESIN: Oh my god.
TRAVIS: All right, I'll try.
MARISHA: Ten.
TALIESIN: My potion has worn off, hasn't it?
MATT: At this point in time? How long does it
last?
TALIESIN: One hour.
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: I frenzy raged last time.
MATT: Yeah, so you have disadvantage.
SAM: You're dead, sir.
LAURA: Oh no.
TRAVIS: Don't worry about it.
LAURA: Oh my god, you rolled 19 twice in a row.
TRAVIS: Yeah, 19 and 16.
LAURA: Oh, okay.
TRAVIS: 24.
MATT: Okay, so you leap onto another tree branch.
SAM: I got a 23.
MATT: You also leap after and actually land next
to Grog.
SAM: Hey, buddy!
GROG: Hey, pal!
MATT: What did you get, Percy?
TALIESIN: Seven.
LAURA: Oh no.
MARISHA: 10.
LAURA: Oh no!
MATT: You both reach, leap for the branch,
but you're a good foot and a half, two feet
short, and as your fingers catch the edge--
MARISHA: Percy, catch me!
MATT: It's slick, and both of you go plummeting
about 15 feet to the ground. You both suffer four
points of falling damage as you catch yourself on
the ground, kind of jamming your ankles a little
bit. There's a (splash) of liquid as you impact
and the lower patch goes partway up your calf,
almost to your knee, as you hit and you have to
wiggle to try and--
TALIESIN: I want the mansion, now.
SAM: Okay.
LAURA: Can we drop the endless rope down, say,
hey, grab on.
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: And try to yank 'em back up into the tree.
MATT: Okay. You guys take the rope and begin to
pull yourself up.
You feel your branch begin to slowly--
LAURA: Oh, I was on the broom.
MATT: You're still on the broom this whole time?
LAURA: I've been on the broom, yeah, I don't wanna
stand on anything.
MATT: All right. Then you manage to get the rope
down, you guys grab onto the rope and you pull
them ever so slowly out of the muck. It's a lot of
weight. I need you to make a strength check.
LAURA: Can I tie the rope off on a branch?
TALIESIN: It won't hold.
LIAM: Can I help?
MATT: Sure. Sure, we can do that. You don't need a
strength check to tie the rope off, we'll just
take it. You guys manage to pull yourselves at
least out of the muck, however, you've gotta climb
up the rope to try and get back in the branches?
TALIESIN: I'm just gonna hold on.
LAURA: We just need to get in the fucking
mansion.
TALIESIN: We just need to get in the mansion.
MARISHA: Yeah, can we have the mansion?
SAM: Okay, I'll do the mansion.
MARISHA: I mean, we can still come in and out of
the mansion.
SAM: Yeah, that's true, that's true.
MATT: All right.
SAM: I will cast the mansion. I will sing the song
to conjure it.
(Sings) Home, home on the range,
where the trees are acting real strange,
where chickens are pecked,
Vex shoots me in the neck,
and the hot tub is filled with grenades.
(All laugh and applaud.)
MATT: Well done.
TRAVIS: I'm sick, don't make me laugh that hard.
MATT: All right. With that, Scanlan, after leaping
onto the next branch, you create the doorway into
the mansion up in the trees. You guys all slowly
eventually climb back up and get to where the
entrance is, and each member of Vox Machina
currently present leap into the mansion,
to safety, where it's seemingly much more clean,
though
you are dragging clumps of this liquid on
the main carpet.
TRAVIS: That's good.
TALIESIN: It's fine.
SAM: I command my servants to wipe our feet.
TRAVIS: Whoa whoa whoa, I'm sure you want to test
the gunk, right, Percy?
LAURA: Yeah, we should--
SAM: Oh, go out and test it?
TRAVIS: Is it flammable, is it poisonous,
is it acidic?
MARISHA: I take my fire hands and I see if I can
light the gunk on fire.
MATT: Okay. As you bring it near, the gunk does
not burn. You see one little pssh as a bubble
bursts and there is a little burst of sulfurous
flame, but it burns away in an instant, the actual
liquid itself does not catch.
MARISHA: Okay. I start taking my short rest.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: Should one of us lick it?
TALIESIN: Sure.
SAM: Grog?
TRAVIS: I take a pinky-smear--
LIAM: Give it to Mikey, he'll try anything.
TRAVIS: Like a droplet, right, I stick my tongue
out, and I touch it to my tongue.
MATT: It resembles, and it's only familiar to you
because you've tried this before, it's like
tasting the filthiest copper coin you've ever held
in a pocket before. It has that kind of metallic
residue to it, but also this kind of earthy
griminess where it's probably been devoured and
digested by a number of creatures before it found
its way--
LAURA: Ew!
TRAVIS: I detect a note of digestive tract.
MATT: It is not pleasant by any means.
LAURA: Do you feel evil? More than usual?
TRAVIS: I raise my hand-- no.
LAURA: Okay.
TALIESIN: Give me a little bit and I'll do
something to it. I don't really know what I can
tell you, but I'll take a look.
LAURA: Hold out your hand, then.
TALIESIN: Thank you. I need that tree as well,
let's take that down to-- want to help me with
this before your nap or after?
MARISHA: I dunno. After.
TALIESIN: All right, I'll start on it, then you
can help when you finish.
MATT: All right, so you guys begin...
TALIESIN: I'm gonna go work for a little bit.
MATT: Okay. What are the rest of you doing?
LIAM: I'm gonna hobble past Vex and say, you know,
I think that broom is not as well-suited for, um,
men. I think you might have done Gern a favor.
I've just taken a very long spin class.
I sort of tenderly walk past.
LAURA: Well, I have a seat, sorry I didn't think
about.
LIAM: Oh dear.
MATT: So Vax goes to rest his bruised arch.
(All laugh.)
MARISHA: Is that enough time?
MATT: You're making those--
TALIESIN: I'm gonna make swamp shoes.
MATT: Okay, that's gonna take you--
TALIESIN: They're very simple, but yes, I have to
make a lot of them.
MATT: You have to make a pair for most everybody
here.
TALIESIN: And I'm going to be enlisting her help,
it's literally just thin slices, I'm not making
them super nice, I'm just--
MARISHA: I druidcraft the shit out of those.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I'm gonna have her--
LAURA: I'm gonna come out of the door with you.
TALIESIN: That's pretty much what I'm doing other
than sleeping.
MATT: Okay, go ahead and make four tinkering
checks.
SAM: I'm gonna inspire him once with an
inspirational quote.
You have to look through the
rain to see the rainbow.
(All laugh.)
TRAVIS: I gotta leave, I can't--
TALIESIN: I have to take a negative 10 for that,
like that really removes 10?
MARISHA: Did you get that from a fortune cookie,
where'd you get that?
TRAVIS: I can't be here when this happens.
SAM: Hey, pal. Life is what happens when you're
making other plans.
If plan A doesn't work,
there's still 25 letters left in the alphabet.
LAURA: Oh, wow.
TRAVIS: Oh my god.
LAURA: That's three inspirations you've just given
him.
TALIESIN: Let's burn that page.
MATT: That's borderline Lisa Frank quotes here,
this is...
LIAM: Kill him!
TALIESIN: Can I remove that extra two from your
charisma? I'm gonna wipe it out.
MATT: Yeah, all that reading finally goes to
shit.
SAM: It was my footprints you saw.
TALIESIN: It's proficiency bonus, plus dex.
MATT: Yes, go for it.
SAM: I was carrying you all along.
TALIESIN: I hate you. I hate everything that you
stand for. Oh, this is nice. This is, um.
MATT: Remember, you don't have to use the
inspiration dice if you don't want to.
TALIESIN: It's two 26s.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: I'm keeping the inspiration dice.
And, let's see, and two 19s.
MATT: All righty. Yeah, you guys take the better
part of the next hour to make some loosely
functional swamp shoes. They'll get you a short
distance, they're not gonna last you a long time.
TALIESIN: They're not pretty. They're made of
rope.
MATT: Yeah. All right. So you finish your short
rest.
MARISHA: I really wanna swan dive into the muck.
LAURA: I feel like, Keyleth, a swan dive is maybe
not the best idea because I feel like it'll make a
lot of noise. Maybe nice and quiet.
MARISHA: If I tighten my abs and keep my feet
together, it shouldn't make much noise at all.
TALIESIN: You've been watching a lot of Olympics.
MARISHA: I have been watching a lot of Olympics.
LIAM: I come back in with a big bag of ice.
MATT: And two spirits trying to hold it for you.
TRAVIS: Did we take a long rest or just a short
rest?
LAURA: Short rest right now so Keyleth can go into
the muck.
TALIESIN: I'm going for a full long rest after my
crap.
LAURA: I'm gonna go outside with her and just
hover on the broom to keep an eye.
SAM: I'm going out as well and I'm just sort of
shuffling in place and moving.
LAURA: Do you wanna hang out on the broom with
me?
SAM: Oh yes, that would be better.
MATT: All right, so the two of you on the broom.
Grog, what are you doing?
TRAVIS: I'm going into the kitchen with the
Titanstone Knuckles,
and I'm gonna start hitting things.
LAURA: Wow, Grog's getting aggressive.
TRAVIS: Well, I wanna see if I can upgrade the
knuckles, so I'm gonna start using them.
LAURA: Oh, smart. Smart.
SAM: I have a training basement, but okay, sure.
TALIESIN: And there's food.
MATT: You guys make your way to the front door,
in the distance you can hear a series of dull
thuds, bangs, cracks, and various sounds as Grog
begins to just punch his way through the entirety
of your mansion's kitchen.
LAURA: Do you wanna check on that?
SAM: Seems like it's normal.
LAURA: All right.
MATT: You doubt you'd ever see a fully dominated
spiritual servant look nervous, yet at this moment
you have about 17 of them all just going
(high-pitched whine).
You just tear through the vicinity.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: You're trying desperately to finish up your
short rest, as you get up, you hear this noise as
well as you guys make your way to the front door.
You're left to try and finish up this project,
probably for the next 20 minutes or so,
while they go ahead and attempt this process.
Vax, you're resting up your loins with ice.
LIAM: No, I mean, I'm gonna take my bag of ice and
I'm gonna sit on the doorjamb and watch them go.
And just see if they need help, but I'll
stay here if I can.
MATT: All right. You.
LAURA: Scanlan, do you wanna actually sit on my
lap so you don't have to suffer through the
indignity that Vax just did?
SAM: Yes, that would be lovely, thank you.
MATT: All right, so as you guys step out,
Keyleth.
SAM: Will you tell me a story?
LAURA: Whatever you want, darling.
MATT: Keyleth, as you step off of the tree branch,
are you gonna climb down
or just leap down into the muck?
MARISHA: I swan-dive. I take a minute to compose
myself. And then--
LAURA: You're earth elemental?
MARISHA: --as gracefully as possible, pull like a
Pocahontas,
and then turn into the earth elemental
as I dive in.
TALIESIN: Sail!
MARISHA: Sail!
MATT: All right, as you do, your form suddenly
ripples and extends out into the form of your
elemental body. You slam into the surface and sink
down below. You guys see a slight (burble sound)
in the liquid, and it leaves this sort of crater
of splash that slowly closes up over with no sign
of Keyleth now visible on the surface.
LAURA: I'm gonna hand Vax the endless rope and
say, you might just wanna drop that down to the
muck so she can get out if she needs it. Maybe.
Like fish for her.
LIAM: Yeah, I go and I tie one end of it to the
heaviest piece
of furniture I can find in the
foyer.
MATT: All right. No heavy furniture per se,
but there are a series of large marble pillars
that are load-bearing within the interior,
and that's probably your best bet, so you go
ahead and wrap the rope around that.
LIAM: Yes, I use the swirly-whirly knot.
MATT: Great. The one that Pike taught you from her
sailing days.
MARISHA: I start to earthglide, breaststroking
through the mud under the swamp to the tree.
LAURA: To the tree, you're going to the tree?
MARISHA: I'm heading towards it.
SAM: Wait, hold up.
MATT: Swimming through the tar itself is a slowing
process even as an earth elemental. Earthgliding
would mean going subterranean to where the actual
physical earth and soil is what you can traverse
through. The tar is not natural in comparison to
your elemental form,
so you'd have to go beneath the actual bog.
MARISHA: How much further down is it?
MATT: I'd say it's probably anywhere from three to
five feet, depending on certain things, that's to
get past how much of it has seeped into the
ground.
MARISHA: Okay, then I go down.
MATT: Okay. You go down, and you have to get lower
the closer you get to it, as the actual seep,
the actual depth in which this substance seems to
have penetrated the dirt gets lower and lower.
You begin to move through as you glide in the
darkness.
SAM: You know what, we should've definitely tied
that rope to her before--
LAURA: Yeah, before she went in, yeah yeah yeah.
MARISHA: I wanna use my tremor-sense too to just
be aware.
MATT: Yeah, every now and then you feel a twitch,
a large twitch in the ground, and you kind of
shoulder-charger into what seems to be a large
root that is dug into the ground. And you start
finding little pockets here and there beneath
these roots of that awful tar-like substance that
have just been pushed into the ground like these
little tar geodes, if you will. You start feeling
around and finding these large roots that are just
a heavy network of chaos beneath the tree.
You're now under the tree, probably a good 25,
30 feet below it.
MARISHA: Okay. If I reach and out touch one of the
roots,
like just run my hand along it, what happens?
SAM: God, what is she doing?
TALIESIN: You're my hero.
MATT: You run your hand along the root. It's
stiff, the surface of the bark itself is a little
rough at the touch. Yeah.
TALIESIN: Sorry. I just love that word.
SAM: Dick joke.
MARISHA: I move back a little bit, kind of getting
away from the tree.
MATT: Okay, glide backward, away from that large
root that you had run into.
MARISHA: Do I sense any type of creatures living
under here?
MATT: Not within your vicinity, no.
MARISHA: Any movement, nothing crazy?
MATT: Just the occasional shift, like a very faint
movement that's
rather sudden in certain areas nearby.
MARISHA: Okay, I'm gonna start making my way back
to the mansion.
TALIESIN: It was good, it was good.
MATT: You earthglide back up, you guys, after
waiting a few minutes, suddenly emerging from the
bottom of the bog, you see Keyleth's now covered
in black tar-like material,
her elemental form emerges.
MARISHA: Ooh, like the swamp thing? Do I look like
the swamp thing?
MATT: Kinda.
MARISHA: That's cool.
LAURA: Are you okay?
MARISHA: (rock noises)
LAURA: Oh, right. Cool.
MATT: She talks. It sounds like a slow-moving
rockslide. (rock sounds)
LAURA: Awesome.
TALIESIN: Do you speak rock?
MARISHA: That's very poetic. And then I kind of
make my way up and drop earth elemental form.
MATT: Okay, as you drop the form, much of the muck
just kind of drops off of where the form once was.
A little bit's still clinging to the bottom of
your robes, but mostly clean.
MARISHA: Yeah, I think it's good, I didn't really
see much or learn much more than we already knew.
LAURA: Did you see any creatures around?
MARISHA: No creatures.
SAM: Did the muck try to eat you?
MARISHA: The muck did not try to eat me.
It's not as deep as I would've thought, actually.
It's only three feet or so deep. I do believe
that the tree is living, though. I think its roots
were kind of twitching and moving around.
SAM: But you felt the roots, it's not an illusion,
it's a real tree.
MARISHA: It is a real tree.
SAM: Okay.
MARISHA: The roots were very turgid.
SAM: Hmm. What a good word.
MARISHA: Someone taught that to me earlier.
TALIESIN: I feel like a terrible person, I think.
It's just a great word, that's all.
MATT: All right. So with her return, what are you
guys gonna do?
TRAVIS: (punching sounds)
LAURA: Do you wanna go, maybe?
SAM: Yeah, I guess we should go in and see what
going on, what's cooking in the kitchen.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: As you guys rush into the kitchen,
and looking around, you can see now every
cabinet's pulled off of its hinges and shattered
in half, what was a central stone island is now
just a pile of smashed granite.
SAM: Damn it.
MATT: Every single possible breakable utensil,
platter--
TRAVIS: Don't forget the holes in the wall.
MATT: Oh, it is just ruin. You see every servant
is now on the ground trying to scoop things up,
and as soon as they get a handful to go ahead and
set it somewhere,
just slapped out of their hand by a fist.
SAM: Grog, what are you doing? This is our kitchen
and we need to eat dinner here!
TRAVIS: I'm trying to activate these, and they
require pain. (yells)
MATT: With that, what was once a large black
cauldron that was used in soup and other sort of
base-like liquids, is now, pwang, a large heavy
ding is now on the inside in the shape of a fist,
and it's half as useful.
LAURA: Grog!
TRAVIS: Do I notice any difference in the
gauntlets?
MATT: Make a perception check.
TRAVIS: At disadvantage?
LAURA: Because you're super tired.
MATT: Yes, because you haven't rested yet.
TRAVIS: One less. Ten.
MATT: No difference whatsoever.
TRAVIS: Maybe I need to hit people.
LIAM: I start backing away slow.
(All laugh.)
TALIESIN: I walk in at this point and I'm just
looking for some chicken.
MARISHA: I also walk in. Scanlan!
LAURA: Oh, you're not an earth elemental anymore.
MARISHA: Are you remodeling?
LAURA: That's too bad.
SAM: I didn't intend to, but Grog has forgotten
that I have a whole training ground downstairs
that he could've used. Grog, if you need to hit
something, someone,
I can give you a few of the servants.
TRAVIS: Would you?
SAM: Sure, I've got like a hundred of them.
TRAVIS: How many?
SAM: You guys don't mind, do you?
LAURA: Wait, do they feel pain?
MATT: They all turn to you and kinda go.
TRAVIS: How many can I have?
SAM: Have a dozen. Baker's dozen.
TRAVIS: I go into the next room.
TALIESIN: A dozen bakers.
TRAVIS: With the dozen servants.
LAURA: Go downstairs, Grog!
TRAVIS: What if a change happens, don't you wanna
be there?
LAURA: All right, yeah.
LIAM: Scanlan, does your house unbreak itself if
Grog breaks it, you know, if it goes away,
it poofs and it comes back, is all his damage
there or does it--
TRAVIS: Please. Grog always leaves his mark.
SAM: The damage, I believe, I've never seen damage
this bad in our place before, but. I believe it
will reset. It goes back to normal at the end.
MATT: We'll find out.
LAURA: We haven't looked at the spa since we
destroyed it.
SAM: I haven't been down to the spa in a while.
TRAVIS: I pick up one of the servants by the head
and I try and crush his head.
LAURA: Oh, no!
MATT: Your fingers pass through its spectral form.
There's no actual--
TRAVIS: Make yourself grabbable.
SAM: You have to try harder, Grog.
MATT: Passes through again.
TRAVIS: Fix this. You fix this now. I will break
more stuff.
SAM: I thought that would work, honestly.
TALIESIN: Is Keyleth still covered in goop?
TRAVIS: I punched the cow before.
LAURA: You did punch a cow.
MARISHA: I kinda fwooshed it off.
TALIESIN: Do you have any left on you?
LIAM: Grog, he doesn't want you to know this,
he told me this the last time you were here,
you actually have to do that 33 times before it
takes hold, so just keep going.
TRAVIS: I grab again. I grab again. I grab again.
I grab again.
MATT: As you keep going, you're not even sure
quite what a 33 is, but you just keep going.
The servant stands there, its kind of loosely
formless face, other than you can see eyes,
a nose, and a mouth, but the features are very
plain and translucent,
just stay wide and staring straight at you.
TRAVIS: Fine, fine. Bring me a cow.
LAURA: Ohh.
SAM: We usually have one cow.
MATT: The servants vanish and come back,
you hear a familiar (dinging).
LAURA: No, I hated it when you punched the cow!
TRAVIS: No, no, no.
TALIESIN: I'm going back to my room.
TRAVIS: It's time to ring this bell.
LAURA: No.
TRAVIS: I beat the shit out of the cow.
(All groan.)
LAURA: That is awful. I leave, I can't watch,
I go and look for chicken.
SAM: Before you beat this poor senseless cow--
TRAVIS: It's a purple, like, ethereal cow.
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: It's still a cow, it's still a cow, don't.
TRAVIS: I'm gonna rocky ribs the shit out of this
cow.
LIAM: Street Fighter it?
MATT: Bonus round. You take the next half an hour,
beating the non-living crap out of this spectral
cow, which, every impact has a sound hit.
Does not seem to react in pain as much as
(distressed mooing). There's no physical damage
seen upon its form, it just gets knocked around.
LAURA: That's good.
SAM: I've got an idea. I can fix this, Grog,
I want you to be a satisfied customer. Let's go
downstairs.
TRAVIS: Okay.
SAM: Okay. I take him downstairs.
MATT: All right.
SAM: I say, you're gonna punch me and keep
punching me as long as you can. All right?
TRAVIS: Are you sure?
SAM: And I transform into a triceratops.
LAURA: Awesome.
MARISHA: I go downstairs to watch.
TRAVIS: Is this my day-birth or something?
SAM: Birthday. I mean, (growls)
MATT: Yes, as you hear the growling creature
you've never seen before in your life, horns
protruding from the front of its bony, armored
headpiece, its scaled armored body standing before
you, massive, snorting, you just start punching
the crap out of it.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Rage-punching.
(All singing Jurassic Park theme.)
SAM: I'm gonna fight back a little.
MATT: A little bit? All right. You guys do begin
to scrap back and forth for the next ten minutes.
'Cause it takes ten minutes of solid punching and
missing for Grog to eventually whittle your
triceratops hitpoints down to zero. However,
in the process, you do manage to get a bit gored,
suffering a total of nine points of piercing
damage throughout the entirety of this, just
little scrapes and scratches, the occasional
puncture wound, but eventually you get one solid
crack with the gauntlets across his face,
and the triceratops form shifts back down to a
tiny little Scanlan Shorthalt.
LAURA: Don't hit him, don't hit him!
SAM: Wait, wait, did it work? Are your gauntlets
better or whatever you're trying to do?
TRAVIS: Do I feel anything?
MATT: Perception check.
LAURA: You need to rest so you can perceive things
better. Oh.
TALIESIN: Can you roll lower?
TRAVIS: I could. There's one number lower.
(All laugh.)
MATT: No seeming change whatsoever. Although no
scarring. The good thing about the gauntlets is
that they're powerful enough where all those
impacts
don't appear to have scratched or dented
the surface.
TRAVIS: No.
SAM: Am I okay?
MATT: You're a little sore. That last hit did
carry over a little bit, the form didn't absorb
the entirety of the blow. You did come back with,
uh. Four points of bludgeoning damage to your
chin, so you're, you know, a little bit of blood
on the corner of your lip that you can taste,
and your jaw is a little sore on the right side.
TALIESIN: Just for fun while everything's going
on, I'm running two passive experiments in my lab
while I'm working on the shoes.
MATT: Sure.
MARISHA: Oh, and I help him finish the shoes by
helping druidcraft them.
TALIESIN: I'm leaving some of the muck on some
chicken that I took from the kitchen to see if it
has any effect on flesh after a long exposure.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: And then I'm distilling some to see if I
can even
identify anything in there or anything weird.
MATT: All right. So what are you guys doing now?
TRAVIS: Being disappointed.
TALIESIN: Do you have to roll for that?
MATT: Disadvantage.
LAURA: Natural 20.
(All laugh.)
LAURA: I was saying it, but it really happened!
TALIESIN: Metaphor! Metaphor!
SAM: You know what, Grog, you could, it might make
you feel better if you repaid the favor.
I've been meaning to try to upgrade Mythcarver.
TRAVIS: Yeah, come get it. Come get it.
SAM: All right, I'm gonna do a stab. I'm gonna
sing a note and see if this does anything to
Mythcarver. I'll just go (sings a note) and I'll
try and jam it through his arm.
MATT: Okay, you hit up a scale of notes,
and one note resonates with the blade, and the
harmonic resonance kind of causes it to shake ever
so slightly as it kind of amplifies the sound.
Go ahead and roll an attack.
LAURA: Oh my god.
SAM: 18 plus nine.
MATT: That definitely hits. Go ahead and roll
damage.
SAM: Uh, not much. 1d8. Three, six, plus one...
ooh, nine!
MATT: Nine points of damage to you, Grog,
as the blade kinda sinks about four inches
through one of your pectoral muscles.
TRAVIS: (grunts)
SAM: And I will sing as I withdraw it as well.
(sings a note)
MATT: You pull it out and the blade almost
vibrates as it does, it scatters the blood off of
its surface as you withdraw it from the wound.
SAM: Do I notice any change in the weapon?
MATT: It is bloodless.
SAM: Damn it.
MATT: No noticeable change.
TRAVIS: Nothing?
MATT: Nothing.
TRAVIS: You're only gonna do it once?
SAM: But it hurts you!
TRAVIS: Nah. Do one more, but like, angry-sing.
SAM: All right. All right, one more time.
I'll do some like Black Sabbathy sort of
(heavy metal screaming).
MATT: (laughs) Go for it.
SAM: All right.
MATT: Take advantage on this one because of your
intense singing.
SAM: 18 plus nine.
MATT: All right, go ahead and roll damage.
LAURA: Oh my god.
SAM: Ooh, yeah, that's better.
SAM and TALIESIN: Ooh!
SAM: 15.
MATT: Shnk! Other pectoral muscle now.
TRAVIS: (yelps)
MATT: A matching wound, this one kind of, (yelps),
tickles you a little as it goes a little deeper
and kinda tickles the outside of a lung.
SAM: All right. I withdraw. And any change?
MATT: As you withdraw, it kind of rings with the
pullback, blood scattered, blade is clean,
no noticeable change.
SAM: Ah, damn it. All right, forget it.
TRAVIS: These things don't work.
SAM: I know, these suck.
TRAVIS: What are we doing wrong?
SAM: I don't know. Wish there was a manual.
TRAVIS: Have we looked for instructions? Is there
writing on the Titanstone Knuckles?
MATT: There are various carvings on it.
TRAVIS: Carvings.
SAM: Anything on mine?
MATT: There are runes around the base of it.
What languages do you know?
SAM: Nothing. I know Common and Gnome.
MATT: Yeah, you don't recognize it.
LAURA: I'm gonna go up to Grog and cast Cure
Wounds at third level.
MATT: Okay, go for it, you can roll that up.
LAURA: Ten whole points of healing.
TRAVIS: Thanks, man.
MARISHA: I also go ahead and cure myself up.
MATT: Okay. All right.
SAM: We're about to take a rest.
MARISHA: Eh.
MATT: What else do you guys want to do?
TRAVIS: I'm gonna long rest now.
TALIESIN: Long rest, eat some chicken.
MARISHA: Wait, do we have any vague plan, wait,
we plan at dawn?
LAURA: We'll plan tomorrow morning.
MARISHA: We'll plan at dawn.
TRAVIS: We'll plan at dawn.
LAURA: I wanna go upstairs and just open the door
and keep an eye out of it for just a little bit
and see what I see out the doorway.
MATT: Okay. Make a perception check.
LAURA: Oh, come on! Oh, um. That would be a 15.
MATT: 15. All right. How much time do you spend
out there?
LAURA: Well, at the door?
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: How much time can I spend and still get a
good rest?
MATT: Well, I mean, you need an eight-hour rest
for a full night's rest, so it depends how much
time you want to push off until you begin taking
your rest.
LAURA: Oh, right. Well, how about a couple hours?
MATT: Okay. First hour, seemingly no real change.
Second hour,
go ahead and make another perception check.
LAURA: 17.
MATT: 17. You do notice a little ways off,
some of the tree brush shifts a little bit,
and then you see what looks to be a few trees
kind of (fwoosh).
LAURA: Disappear?
MATT: Seemingly there's now a hole in the canopy
where once was straight canopy.
TRAVIS: What do you think that is?
LAURA: I dunno.
TRAVIS: Like a giant werewolf maybe?
LAURA: A giant werewolf eating an entire tree?
TRAVIS: Tree's not missing.
LAURA: The tree, like, disappeared?
MATT: There is now a hole in the canopy where
there was not previously, seemingly the treetops
that filled that space have kind of moved out of
the way.
MARISHA: They go straight down?
LAURA: Oh, I bet something was sitting in the tree
maybe and was keeping still. That could be it.
Can I look down underneath us and see if the
trees are kind of staying put where we are?
MATT: Yeah, and glancing about, nothing is really
moving in your vicinity, and the area, the part of
the canopy that is now missing, is a pretty large
area.
LAURA: It seems bigger than a creature would be.
MATT: It would probably have been the sudden
removal or shift of multiple trees to leave that
opening in the canopy.
TALIESIN: All right.
LAURA: Holy moly.
MARISHA: Maybe something has trees on its back and
moves.
LAURA: Wow, maybe the hag can just move her hut
magically whenever she wants.
Do you think that's possible?
MARISHA: I don't know, maybe.
LAURA: But the big scary tree, that's staying
still.
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: Was it coming from that direction?
MATT: Yeah, it's still in its place.
LAURA: What direction was it coming from?
MATT: Actually, it would be kind of southwest from
where you are now.
MARISHA: So the direction we came from.
MATT: No, you came southeast, not the direction
where you came from, it's still maybe a
quarter-mile to a half-mile from where you
currently are, so it's not on your path per se.
TRAVIS: Can I roll some hit dice to heal up?
LAURA: All right. Shit.
MATT: Well, for a full night's rest you're fully
healed.
LAURA: I guess I shut the door. That's creepy.
MATT: All right. You close the door.
LAURA: I don't know who I would talk to about
that. Can I go find Keyleth, are you asleep yet?
MARISHA: No. I don't think so. I've been helping
Percy with his shoes.
TALIESIN: Yeah, we're in my room. Making shoes.
MATT: Okay. Shoes are finished now.
LAURA: Oh. Okay. So you guys are together?
MARISHA: Just finished making shoes.
LAURA: Oh, look at those beautiful shoes.
They're lovely.
MARISHA: Yeah, they might work.
TALIESIN: They're not, but thank you.
MATT: They're pretty rough. They're pretty rough.
LAURA: No, no, those look great.
MARISHA: Thank you.
TALIESIN: Rustic. Very rustic.
MARISHA: Thank you. I'm proud of them, Percy.
TALIESIN: I'm proud too.
TRAVIS: Your shoes suck.
TALIESIN: You're not here.
MATT: He did pop in briefly to just tell you
that.
LAURA: (Grog voice) Those shoes suck.
MATT: And closes the door.
SAM: He did that to everybody's room, just in
case.
MATT: To cover all his bases.
SAM: Hey!
MATT: Perfect.
LAURA: Can I sit down?
MARISHA: You were supposed to be a bootmaker.
You're super-judgey.
LAURA: Oh, this is true.
TALIESIN: You were a bootmaker, that's very true.
MATT: You did start making your own boots, yeah.
LAURA: That was your very first--
TRAVIS: You didn't ask me to make the boots.
LAURA: Can I sit down and start playing with the
shoes? And, um, ask, Keyleth? Do you know of
anything that would cause entire trees to vanish?
MARISHA: How do you mean, vanish?
LAURA: Well, I was staring at the door, and all of
a sudden, around a space,
about three trees just disappeared.
MARISHA: Like something really large passed in
front of it?
LAURA: No, like they dropped, and there's a hole
in the canopy.
TALIESIN: Huh.
MARISHA: That's different.
TALIESIN: That's interesting.
LAURA: Do you know of anything that would cause
that?
TRAVIS: In the Feywild?
MARISHA: Do I know of anything that would cause
that? Can I roll a nature check or something?
MATT: Roll a nature check.
MARISHA: Don't fucking fail me.
LAURA: Would we have learned anything about that
in our studies?
MARISHA: (yells wordlessly)
SAM: Wow, those dice.
LAURA: Maybe just don't use them anymore.
TRAVIS: Don't know who you pissed off...
MARISHA: 14.
MATT: 14.
LAURA: They're so nice and-- maybe just put them
on display!
Maybe put them in a really pretty
glass case.
MATT: No. Make 'em work for you. Make 'em work for
you. You paid for that shit.
LAURA: Turn 'em into jewelry?
MATT: I mean, there are a number of things that
could've done it, whether it be lumbering,
people chopping down trees takes them down.
Creatures that are large can push over trees.
Trees that are dying and rotting and eventually
fall over on their own.
LAURA: Did it look like they dropped down,
though? Or did it look like they dropped over?
MATT: It's hard to know from this perspective.
You just saw them kind of fall out of the canopy,
so you're not sure if it was at an angle or
straight down or what.
MARISHA: That could be so many things.
LAURA: Yeah.
MARISHA: It's hard to say.
TALIESIN: At this point, can I tell anything about
the muck from just boiling it to separate
components? Trying to just see what's in there.
I'm assuming it's probably just death-paste,
it's just rot.
MATT: It looks to be just congealed decayed
matter. It does not have any properties that you
can tell on a chemical level at least that stand
out.
TALIESIN: But it is decayed matter.
MATT: It is various types of decayed matter,
organic matter.
TALIESIN: The tree is producing it.
LAURA: So it is like oil.
TALIESIN: Well, here's my question.
MARISHA: It's producing a lot of it, too.
Way more than it should.
TALIESIN: What do trees need to live?
TRAVIS: Grass.
SAM: Sunlight and water.
LAURA: Sunlight and water.
MARISHA: And a little bit of minerals and dirt.
TALIESIN: Where is the sunlight?
LAURA: Not here.
TALIESIN: And the tree's alive.
MARISHA: Well, we're also in the Feywild.
LAURA: Might not need the same thing.
MARISHA: Might not need the same thing.
TALIESIN: Well, it's got to eat something.
This is what it's producing,
and it's got to eat something.
LAURA: Maybe it eats living creatures?
TALIESIN: Maybe it eats trees.
LIAM: So Percival, would you imagine that the
science of the Feywild, I don't know what that
phrase means, would it be the same as our own
world? Maybe it follows different rules.
TALIESIN: It probably does, but at the same time,
you don't get something from nothing. And...
life needs things to live.
SAM: That's so poetic.
TALIESIN: You don't get life from nothing.
A little iffy.
LAURA: And we did see those branches moving like
actual limbs on a being
as opposed to branches on a tree.
MARISHA: Well, I mean, nothing here has really
been natural.
LAURA: It could be like a venus flytrap.
TALIESIN: It's just a hypothesis, but what if the
tree's carnivorous. Or omnivorous.
LAURA: I think that's a very viable option.
MARISHA: So you think maybe it's the tree that ate
that other group of trees?
LAURA: Possibly.
TALIESIN: It's very big.
MARISHA: It's a cannibal tree?
TALIESIN: It might be a cannibal tree.
MARISHA: It's eating its own kind?
TRAVIS: I mean, the sphinx did say that the bow is
the heart of a cancerous tree, I think if we're
expecting to not find the tree, we're stupid.
MARISHA: Does Fenthras mean anything? Fenthras
doesn't mean anything, right?
TRAVIS: I am the wrong one to ask.
LAURA: Fenthras, is that elven?
MATT: Fenthras is elven.
MARISHA: Is that a name?
MATT: There is no direct translation to it,
per se, but its name has hints or at least bases
of the ancient elven words for protector and
growth.
TALIESIN: Interesting.
MARISHA: Protector and growth.
TRAVIS: Why don't we poison the tree?
LAURA: I think it's already poisoned.
TALIESIN: How do you poison a poisoned tree?
LAURA: Give it sunlight.
TALIESIN: Sunlight is definitely something you
should put in your arsenal.
Whatever it's not used to being exposed to.
LAURA: Sunlight and water. Fresh water.
TALIESIN: I don't think rot is going to be how we
kill this thing.
I think it's not going to be like
the crocodile.
TRAVIS: Abba music.
LAURA: (laughs) Abba music.
MARISHA: No, it seems--
TALIESIN: It needs purification.
SAM: Don't worry, Pike can... oh.
TRAVIS: I also have poison.
SAM: Oh, okay.
TALIESIN: I think it might just laugh poison off.
TRAVIS: Oh.
TALIESIN: I don't know.
TRAVIS: What about honey?
TALIESIN: Nothing laughs honey off.
LAURA: You have honey? Can you make honey in
your--
TALIESIN: Can you make honey in that jar?
LIAM: Pull out the magic jug, yeah.
LAURA: You can make fresh water in that jug,
though, can't you?
TRAVIS: I got honey for you.
TALIESIN: You've got very little brain, don't
you?
MARISHA: Make some maple syrup?
SAM: How about holy water?
TRAVIS: No.
LAURA: Maybe? I don't know.
TRAVIS: I mean, I can make some water if you wanna
bless it.
SAM: No.
TALIESIN: That's not what we're hoping for.
MARISHA: I mean, when I was in my earth elemental
form, I got up underneath the tree, I mean,
I feel like if we needed to, I can get inside of
it.
TRAVIS: (laughs) By yourself?
LAURA: I think that could be a very scary
prospect.
TRAVIS: Let me tell you a tale of two people that
went inside a dragon.
LIAM: Worked out.
MARISHA: Yeah, they're still sitting here today.
It's fine.
TALIESIN: I was about to say, I don't think it's
much of a cautionary tale, really.
MARISHA: No. If anything, it's a terrible,
terrible influence.
TALIESIN: Yes. I think that's definitely,
I think light, I think electricity.
MARISHA: Well, it's not short on water, that's for
sure.
TALIESIN: There is water in the, was there
groundwater of some kind?
MARISHA: I mean, it was sludgy enough. Was there
groundwater?
MATT: I mean, there were pockets or some bit of
groundwater in there, but a lot of the dense
pockets you found were just deeply seated pockets
of that sludge-like material that seems to be
produced or put out by the nearby roots.
MARISHA: Right.
LAURA: When you talked to the trees around you,
did it seem like they were actually alive,
or was it all dead forest that we've been
traveling through?
MARISHA: When I communed with nature?
LAURA: Yeah.
MARISHA: Everything was alive everywhere.
That's what, the rules here haven't really--
SAM: Have you been talking to any of the trees
around here? Right around here?
MARISHA: Yeah, I can. I can.
LAURA: Maybe before we sleep. Can you talk to the
nature?
MARISHA: I can.
TALIESIN: I'll watch this.
MARISHA: Do we have any questions that I might
want to figure out before I--
SAM: Is the big tree eating you all?
LAURA: Are you friends with the big tree? How can
we help?
TALIESIN: Can we cure you?
MARISHA: Cure the tree, is the tree eating other
things, can we cure the tree...
SAM: Is that a tree?
MARISHA: Is that even a tree?
LAURA: Oh, what if it's a big scary creature,
not actually a tree?
TRAVIS: Can we hurt the tree?
LIAM: Does the tree have a weakness?
LAURA: Yeah.
MARISHA: I'll maybe try and figure out...
okay, all right. I'm gonna go step outside.
LAURA: Do you want to hang out on the broom so you
don't actually step--
TRAVIS: You're just giving the broom away now.
LAURA: Well, I just don't want anybody to actually
stand on a tree for very long.
TRAVIS: Just saying.
MARISHA: I have to be connected with the ground,
I think.
TALIESIN: Tie a rope around her this time.
LAURA: Right.
MARISHA: Okay, yeah, tie a rope around me.
And I jump back in the mud.
MATT: You land (splash), close to knee-deep in the
actual muck below you.
MARISHA: I'm gonna kind of lay back into it.
LAURA: Oh, jeez!
SAM: Ooh, like American Beauty?
MARISHA: Sensory deprivation tank-style.
LAURA: I just send things down onto her.
SAM: Chicken?
MATT: As you lay there, you slowly sink into it,
until you guys just see the outside of Keyleth's
face emerge, some of her horned crown sticking out
of the muck. A little bit of her chest and her
knees and some of the hands emerging, the rest of
her is submerged entirely in this muck.
TRAVIS: Sweet.
MATT: You close your eyes and begin reciting the
incantation of the spell. You begin to worry as
she begins to sink further in, but as she finishes
the incantation she stops sinking and it brings
her to the surface halfway and keeps her at this
balance point there.
LAURA: We're just staring out the door down at
her.
TALIESIN: Holding a rope.
MATT: Suddenly your consciousness kind of extends
into all the nearby, and it's rush because there's
just life all around you, life itself is dark,
it's twisted, but it is living. What do you wish
to ask of the nearby essence?
MARISHA: Um, okay. Can I figure out what is
feeding the tree, what the tree, if the tree is
consuming things around it, what is fueling the
tree?
MATT: The response?
MARISHA: I sense a lot coming out from the tree,
that's clear,
can I sense an energy going in
towards the tree?
MATT: Well, your question is, what is feeding the
tree? You have to ask a question.
MARISHA: What is fueling the tree, yes.
MATT: Sondur.
SAM: Sondur?
LAURA: We aren't listening to this.
MARISHA: Sondur.
TRAVIS: I love having a character who can't read.
No pressure.
MATT: Sondur is the only response you get.
MARISHA: What is the tree's weakness?
SAM: Poovah.
(All laugh.)
SAM: Shamalaka.
TALIESIN: Terry.
LAURA: (laughs) Terry.
MATT: You get no response, it seems like the
question doesn't take hold in the connection,
there is no answer to that question. It doesn't
consume
the question asked as part of the incantation.
LAURA: Remember, we asked if it was an actual
tree, if it's an actual tree.
SAM: Has it been eating you?
LAURA: (whispers) Who is Sondur?
MARISHA: Who is Sondur? That's actually,
I should've thought about that,
that's a good one.
MATT: It has to relate to the area, terrain,
bodies of water, actual information about
individuals? The living essence of the forest
would not probably know that.
MARISHA: Okay. Then can I ask the living fauna
around me if this tree is sucking life force from
them? Is the tree in the middle hurting the plants
all around, like for example--
MATT: The answer is yes.
MARISHA: Is that all I got?
MATT: That's your two questions. You asked one
that wasn't effectual,
and thus the incantation
did not consider it utilized.
SAM: Is it a tree?
MATT: One more question.
MARISHA: Is the cancerous tree more than just a
tree?
SAM: Good question.
MATT: Yes.
SAM: Yes.
MARISHA: Sure, that probably... sure.
TALIESIN: We got a name.
MATT: And with that, suddenly, you feel the
incantation break its hold with the nearby life
sources, you begin to sink once again.
LAURA: (gasps) Pull her out, pull her out.
MATT: As you guys pull up as you reach up and grab
it, pulling her free from the swampy morass,
and carry her back up to the entrance of the
mansion.
SAM: What did he say?
MARISHA: Sondur.
SAM: Sondur.
LAURA: What do you mean, Sondur?
MARISHA: Sondur, that's...
LAURA: Is that a band, what is it?
SAM: Flight of the Sondurs?
MARISHA: (laughs) Flight of the Sondurs.
TRAVIS: Is that like an elven word?
LAURA: Is it an elven word?
MARISHA: Is it an elven word?
LAURA: That we've heard?
SAM: Do any of us recognize the word?
MATT: None of you recognize the word, but it does
sound like a name with elvish background or
heritage, or at least some sort of ancient elvish
roots to the name structure. It doesn't have
specific meaning, but there are names you've heard
of people of
elven lineage that are plays on a similar sound.
LAURA: Does it sound... I mean, what would those
names mean?
MATT: Well, I mean, the one that's closest to you
is your father's, which is Syldor.
LAURA: Right, and he's a dick, so the tree
probably is too.
SAM: Sondur, Syldor, they're brothers.
MATT: Totally.
SAM: Isn't that how it works?
LAURA: That is how it works. Vex and Vax.
MARISHA: Percy.
TALIESIN: Yes?
MARISHA: You've done a lot of reading of the elven
culture. Do you know anything about a Sondur?
MATT: You have no idea.
TALIESIN: I have no idea. I'm racking my brain and
wishing I had access to a library.
LAURA: Do you have a library here?
SAM: Do I?
MATT: Well, you can have one apparate within the
mansion, if you wish.
SAM: With books?
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: Of course I have a library! It's in my
personal chambers where I do all of my studying.
TRAVIS: Keyleth.
LAURA: Oh. We have to go to your actual bedroom?
TALIESIN: It's all pornography. Just the entire
library is like--
SAM: Only in the back.
TALIESIN: It's like Beauty and the Beast,
it's just pornography.
MARISHA: Yes, Grog?
TRAVIS: Did you ask if the tree was just one
thing?
MARISHA: It didn't appear to be one thing.
Because it was harming the plant life
around it. So it's not necessarily all connected,
it seems. But it is also definitely not just a
tree.
TRAVIS: What if we, like, salt the earth? That's
an expression.
TALIESIN: It's more than an expression, it's
legitimately something you do. Unfortunately,
you need salt for that.
LAURA: Do we have salt? Do we have lots of salt
here in the mansion, Scanlan?
SAM: It's all over the floor of the kitchen.
LAURA: Oh, but we can't bring it out, we can't
bring it out.
TRAVIS: I have 12 gallons of salt water.
MARISHA: Didn't you get a bunch of salt when you
jumped into the--
LAURA: I don't know if 12 gallons is enough to
kill a tree.
MARISHA: --when you did the cannonball contest?
TALIESIN: That wasn't salt.
TRAVIS: I've heard them say it before, they're
like, oh, you are the salt of the earth.
TALIESIN: That wasn't salt, that was something
else, and I used it all for the cannonball.
SAM: So what's our plan? Do we attack this thing
with brute force? How do we corrupt the ground?
You can turn the ground to stone, will that help
anything? Right?
TRAVIS: What's on the other side of this tree?
It's huge, it's a hundred feet.
TALIESIN: Inside the tree is the bow. I think if
we remove the bow, I think if we find the bow
inside the tree, I think that's how--
SAM: That's a lot of tree to search, it could be
way up, it could be in a branch.
LIAM: What is the legend, at the heart of this
tree?
TALIESIN: The heart of this tree. I think we go
in.
TRAVIS: It used to be a titan that had its heart
broken or something.
LIAM: Probably inside.
LAURA: Yeah, what if the--
SAM: It says it now acts as the heart to a
cancerous tree corrupting the verdant land.
TALIESIN: If I were the heart of a tree,
I'd be in the center.
MARISHA: It was a bow that felled the titans.
LAURA: I feel like we probably should've done some
research on Fenthras before we came out here.
SAM: We can go to my library.
LAURA: Look in your library, I am following you to
your library.
TALIESIN: I'm curious to see the library,
I just want to see
what a giant disaster this is.
MATT: You did receive a little information about
it from Allura, from her research as well.
LAURA: Yes, that's right, that's right!
MATT: Did you write that down?
SAM: Maybe?
LAURA: Yeah, but I listened to her real hard when
she was talking.
SAM: Marisha writes down everything.
MARISHA: I do, it's just... where.
SAM: The bigger question is how does she find it.
MARISHA: How do I find it, exactly. When did we
talk to her?
MATT: Last time you were in Whitestone, right
before you left for the actual Feywild.
LAURA: Aw man, I don't think I wrote it down,
I think I was just listening.
MARISHA: All right, Feywild, hang on.
SAM: I know that Simon's mom is Elwen.
MATT: There you go. See? Perfect. That was
pre-stream.
SAM: I know that...
LAURA: Fenthras! No, that's all I wrote.
MATT: (laughs) You were so excited for a second.
So excited.
LAURA: I was so excited 'cause I saw it written
down, but no, I didn't write.
MATT: No.
LAURA: I'm sorry.
TRAVIS: You're gonna make me check my notes?
LAURA: I didn't write it down. Dammit. Balls.
But I have a real good--
SAM: I know that there's a hatmaker named Deirdre
somewhere in the world.
MATT: Guys. You guys.
LIAM: Would a really successful history check help
Vex remember what the fuck she was told?
MATT: (laughs) Go ahead and make a history check.
LAURA: Okay, okay, okay.
TRAVIS: I've got vegemite written down.
TALIESIN: I think that's a shopping list.
MARISHA: God, I was clearly writing incredibly
fast.
LAURA: Shit history.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
SAM: Did you roll it?
LAURA: 17 is what I rolled.
SAM: Well, that's something.
MATT: 17 is not too bad.
MARISHA: I have 'archfey, black heart'.
MATT: Yes.
LAURA: Okay, that jogged my memory a little bit,
I sort of remember.
MATT: There you go.
MARISHA: He was an arch-- yes, go ahead.
MATT: There was an archfey that existed here that
was apparently the holder of Fenthras that was
betrayed and his heart became corrupted and thus
became the center of this corruption.
SAM: There you go.
MARISHA: So we can assume that the archfey is
probably Sondur.
LAURA: Sondur.
MARISHA: And he's probably still inside the tree,
and he probably is not gonna let go of his bow.
LAURA: What exactly is an archfey?
MATT: An archfey, from your knowledge and
experience, they're very powerful fey creatures,
some largely belonged to some of the leading
courts in the Feywild,
the Seelie and the Unseelie.
LIAM: Oberon.
LAURA: Oh.
MATT: Some unaffiliated. Like for instance,
in Midsummer Night's Dream,
Titania and Oberon would totally be archfey.
LAURA: Archfey. Okay.
MATT: Very, very powerful and influential fey
creatures that both have understanding and powers
to bend the surrounding Feywild to their will.
MARISHA: And then he must have fought in what was
known as the Calamity?
TRAVIS: Yes.
MATT: Well, the Calamity wasn't against the
titans, the Calamity, those were the final battles
of the gods physically on Exandria before the
Divergence in which they
separated from all their creations for good.
MARISHA: Where does 'black heart' come from?
MARISHA: Why did I write that down?
MATT: His heart was corrupted? I don't know why
you wrote it down.
MARISHA: I wrote down 'black heart'.
TALIESIN: Seemed like a thing.
MARISHA: Seemed important.
MATT: Sure.
LAURA: Okay.
MARISHA: 'Cause he was corrupted. Okay.
SAM: So we're fighting an archfey inside a tree.
LAURA: So we know how to fight the tree. Okay.
SAM: We gotta get the archfey out of the tree.
TALIESIN: We gotta get the archfey out of the
tree.
MARISHA: So someone's going into the tree.
LAURA: Maybe we can talk to it.
SAM: What's its name again? Sorry.
MATT: Sondur.
SAM: Sondur.
MATT: Was the name you were given.
LAURA: Maybe if we call out to him, he'll talk to
us.
MARISHA: Maybe.
LIAM: Maybe if we put Shorthalt forward...
LAURA: You're so charming.
TALIESIN: You are so charming.
SAM: Yeah, sure.
TALIESIN: And you have so much good advice.
TRAVIS: Do fey creatures live a long time?
SAM: Hey, Sondur, Sondur, give us your bow.
TRAVIS: What if he was betrayed by something in
the Feywild, and we found that thing,
whether it was a comrade or a--
LIAM: Well, that seems likely, but we'd have to
turn over every stone in la-la land to find it.
LAURA: Or we have to talk to him and find out,
and maybe...
TRAVIS: Yeah, and you can talk to trees.
MARISHA: I can. I can attempt to talk to the
tree.
TALIESIN: After a rest, I'm going to sleep.
LIAM: Scanlan and Keyleth combo?
MARISHA: Huh?
LIAM: Scanlan and Keyleth duo to talk to the
tree?
SAM: What are we asking the tree?
LAURA: In the morning.
SAM: Yeah, but what are we--
TRAVIS: Who betrayed it.
LAURA: We're gonna talk to Sondur and see,
you know, why are you acting this way?
LIAM: Yes, how can we help you, how can we fix
what's going on?
LAURA: Oh no, look at his face, he looks like that
is a very bad idea.
MARISHA: (laughs) Why are you acting this way?
MATT: No, I'm just, I'm just enjoying you guys
planning and plotting.
SAM: We're just gonna say hey, Sondur, how can we
help you?
LAURA: Yeah yeah yeah, like how can we help you?
Why are you hurting?
MARISHA: Please give us your bow, yeah.
LAURA: No, no, don't even bring up the bow right
now, let's just try to help him out.
MARISHA: So wait, are we here on a mission to
cleanse the land? Is that what we're posing as?
We're like missionaries?
LAURA: I mean, if we did cleanse the land,
that would be a wonderful thing.
TALIESIN: That would be great.
MARISHA: It would be a wonderful thing.
TALIESIN: But we're also getting the bow.
LAURA: The bow is a wonderful thing. I have a
pretty fucking cool bow now, I don't even know if
this new one's gonna be as cool. You don't even
know what Mythcarver does, Titanstone Knuckles
aren't advancing at all, who knows? Maybe this bow
is shit and
the whole point of this is so we can help people.
TALIESIN: I think it'll give you wings so you can
fly.
TRAVIS: Can't we just say that we're obsessed with
the hundred-foot fucking
moving tree in the middle of the Feywild?
LAURA: Maybe we just think it's really cool.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we've come to talk to it, no
bullshit.
SAM: We're fanboys.
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: No.
LAURA: Yeah, like we've heard tale and it's
wonderful.
TRAVIS: We wanna know what's up.
SAM: Great. That sounds like it's gonna end well.
TRAVIS: Well, if he pulls any shit then we kill
it.
SAM: Okay.
TALIESIN: I am going to sleep, there's nothing
that can be solved right now that cannot be solved
over coffee and bacon.
LAURA: We don't have bacon.
MARISHA: Just chicken and waffles.
TALIESIN: I will make bacon from chicken.
SAM: Chicken-skin bacon.
LAURA: Ooh. That actually sounds really good.
TALIESIN: That actually sounds really good.
LIAM: Tofurkey.
MATT: All right. You guys all taking your long
rest?
(Various sounds of agreement.)
MATT: All right, you all--
LIAM: No, I'm going to knock on my sister's door
before she falls asleep.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: Oh shit, I'm pretty tired, what's up?
LIAM: Hey, well, you know, we don't get a lot of
time to talk alone because everything is so fucked
up, but you seemed really on-edge. More than
normal, when we lived there before.
You know what I'm talking about.
LAURA: Oh, yeah.
LIAM: Are you all right?
LAURA: Um. Yes? I don't know. It's the weirdest
thing, I never realized how much it affected me
until we actually were faced with it again.
It was good, standing in front of him with
everyone else, wasn't it?
LIAM: I've... he's not a concern for me anymore.
I don't think fondly back on it, we have bigger
things on our plates, but I do care how he affects
you, and there is no question how much it affected
you when Percival made his offer in that room,
and I was a little surprised. And I'm not trying
to start an argument or anything like that,
I know why he did it, of course. And every fairy
within a thousand miles of that room could see how
deeply it affected you, and it surprised me,
because... Look, if that makes you happy,
it is to be embraced, and I'm certainly in
support of anything that gives our father
heartburn, but...
I'm sorry, his offer, in your brother's
eyes, is a bit like gilding a lily or framing a
sunset. You have always been the coolest person I
have known, ever, in my life. And you still are.
You're already perfect, at least in your
brother's eyes. And I guess I just hope you
believe in you as much as I do, because it's quite
a bit.
LAURA: Thank you. I mean, I can't give back the
title, that would be kind of shit.
LIAM: Well, you're a countessa know, I understand,
that's what you are.
LAURA: Baroness, no, baroness, actually.
LIAM: All right.
LAURA: Just a little bit cooler than before.
Just a little?
LIAM: Whatever floats your boat, Stubby, but,
you know. Just don't wuss out on me now.
LAURA: I won't.
LIAM: All right? You've always been stronger than
me, I need you to keep doing that.
LAURA: It's all an act, dear.
LIAM: Bullshit. That's it.
LAURA: I love you. Thank you.
LIAM: I love you too.
LAURA: Go get some sleep. Your feathers are all
ruffled.
LIAM: All right.
MATT: All right, so as you separate and go find
your own ways to rest, you guys find your way to
your dreams for the evening, getting a full
night's rest, HP resolved to full, spells
returned, and we're gonna go ahead and take a
break here, restroom break for a few minutes,
we'll see you guys back here in just a minute.
Once again, thank you, Lootcrate, you guys are
awesome.
ALL: Lootcrate!
MATT: All right, we'll see you guys here in a few
minutes.
[break]
SAM: Lootcrate, lootcrate, lootcrate.
MATT: Welcome back, everyone. So, we had a quick
break, you guys, coming to consciousness the next
morning, freshly rested, the smell of some cooked
chicken in the downstairs area
and a little bit of
chicken-skin bacon...
LAURA: Can I go knock on Percy's door before we
head downstairs, just really fast?
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: Um. Percival?
TALIESIN: Yes, yes, good morning.
LAURA: Sorry. Good morning. I forgot you're grumpy
when you wake up.
TALIESIN: It's all right.
LAURA: Look, Vax came and talked to me last night,
and he actually reminded me of something that I
forgot to say to you, which is: thank you.
Seriously.
We haven't really had a moment to say
anything, and...
TALIESIN: No.
LAURA: Really, what you did back in Syngorn was
more than I ever expected, and honestly it's,
I don't know of any other time that somebody has
stuck up for me quite as much, outside of Vax.
So thank you.
TALIESIN: You're welcome. And... it's the lovely
thing about a title, and I had one to give,
is that it's, when used appropriately and
properly, it's mostly there to remind you you
don't really need it.
LAURA: Right. Question, though?
TALIESIN: Yes?
LAURA: Because I sort of realized, being a
baroness of Whitestone, that I literally owe my
fealty and allegiance to... you.
TALIESIN: Yes.
LAURA: All right.
TALIESIN: Well, technically my sister, but yes.
LAURA: Okay.
TALIESIN: If that makes you feel a little better.
LAURA: Thank you, Grand Sire de Rolo, and if
there's anything you ever need in return,
all you have to do is ask.
TALIESIN: Never do that again, that was very
weird. It was really, it was... it was worth it to
see the look on his face.
LAURA: It was quite wonderful.
TALIESIN: It was quite wonderful. No, and it
worked out well, because technically speaking
there's only really about 15 foot square that's
actually standing
that you technically have a baronry over.
LAURA: Oh.
TALIESIN: And at the moment it is currently a
shrine to the Raven Queen,
so that works out well.
LAURA: Oh, that's what... so technically we gave
it to Zahra, didn't we?
TALIESIN: No, she's just fixing it up for us.
LAURA: Okay, all right.
TALIESIN: We did not give it to her. It wasn't
mine to give. Just the title. You're welcome,
and... it doesn't change anything.
LAURA: Good, that would be very strange,
wouldn't it?
TALIESIN: Yeah. Although I imagine you're
eventually going to
become very insufferable, but yes.
LAURA: Only sometimes, dear.
TALIESIN: Oh, you have to be... there's a thing.
But we'll get to that later. There is a thing,
I forgot, there is a thing.
LAURA: Does it have to do with the Hunt?
TALIESIN: Yes, a thing, we'll get to that,
it's really not important right now. That's if we
survive, that would be very important, but right
now it's not.
LAURA: Not... not a given.
TALIESIN: No.
LAURA: We might die today.
TALIESIN: We might.
LAURA: I'm gonna get some coffee.
TALIESIN: I think that's an excellent idea.
Let me join you.
MATT: You all eventually find your way down,
breakfast served in a central dining table with
no platters, no silverware.
LAURA: Thanks, Grog.
TRAVIS: It's a mansion! We could eat somewhere
else.
MATT: The meals are just placed literally on the
table.
TRAVIS: Bare-bones. I like it.
SAM: All right, eat up, let's go.
MATT: You finish your meal, and you guys prepared
yourselves, what are you doing?
SAM: We go out into the world, right?
TRAVIS: Bum-rush the tree.
LAURA: Uh-uh.
TALIESIN: I have shoes for everybody.
SAM: Oh!
MARISHA: Yes.
SAM: Those are terrible shoes.
TALIESIN: They're awful, I'm aware.
TRAVIS: We put the shoes on?
LIAM: What do they look like?
TALIESIN: We're going to wear the shoes.
SAM: Yeah, describe them.
TALIESIN: They're swamp shoes. They're circular,
they're like large circles, and there's like a
base connected to them, and whole thing's
connected together with ropes.
MARISHA: Kind of like snowshoes but with more
surface area.
TRAVIS: I'm only wearing that if it helps.
TALIESIN: It does. It will keep you from sinking
into the muck. It will allow you to, you'll have
to walk very slowly, you can't walk very quickly,
and if things get hairy you can cut them off,
they're just wood and rope, they're not that
complicated.
MARISHA: Basically, wood paddles on our feet.
TALIESIN: Yes. Move like a giant frog.
MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: I put the giant frog-shoes on.
MATT: All right, you put them on. You guys exit
the mansion?
LIAM: I set the Deathwalker's Ward for necrotic
damage.
MATT: Okay, necrotic damage is set. Okay.
As you guys emerge--
LAURA: Oh. Wait.
TALIESIN: You don't need them, though. You're the
one person who doesn't need them.
LAURA: How long does Protection Against Poison
last? Oh, it's only an hour, okay, so no,
I don't want to cast it yet.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: But you have that.
LAURA: I do.
MARISHA: I won't take that.
SAM: Maybe now would be, we're going straight to
the tree, right?
MARISHA: Are we still doing our--
LAURA: Aren't you going to try to talk to it?
TALIESIN: Talk to it, see what happens, and if
everything goes terribly, we just retreat back to
the mansion, it's not going anywhere anytime
soon.
SAM: Should any of us hide?
TALIESIN: I'm going to keep back in the treeline.
LAURA: I can only cast it on one person, though,
Keyleth. I don't have, I'm not as good with
spells as you, so if you can do it to multiple
people, it might be good.
MATT: All right.
LIAM: Do we have any fancy, um, fancy--
LAURA: (posh voice) Fancy?
LIAM: Crystal bowls for Keyleth to crush up and
feed us from?
LAURA: What?
SAM: Crystal what?
LAURA: Oh, like a Fancy--
LIAM: Heroes' Feast, yeah.
LAURA: Heroes' Feast? I don't know if we have--
LIAM: Never mind.
MATT: I don't think you have one purchased and
ready.
TALIESIN: I don't think we have one.
LIAM: I don't claim to understand anything.
MARISHA: We'd have to make that decision now,
while I'm learning
my spells at the top of the day.
TALIESIN: No, no.
SAM: Don't do it.
LAURA: We should've done it last night if we were
gonna do it.
MATT: Yeah.
TALIESIN: It'll be fine.
LAURA: It's gonna be fine, we're all gonna die.
SAM: All right.
LAURA: How are you guys gonna go talk to him,
are you just like walking to him?
TALIESIN: A tree is just a door that hasn't been
made yet, remember.
MARISHA: That is true. That is an old Druidish
proverb.
TALIESIN: It's an old Druidish one?
MARISHA: Yep.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
MATT: All right. So. You guys emerge from the
mansion?
SAM: Yeah, anyone want to go stealth or anything?
LAURA: Yeah yeah yeah.
SAM: It's just gonna be all of us presenting
ourself?
LAURA: Maybe we'll go stealth... well, can a tree
see us? I dunno. Let's go stealth.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: Why not? And you guys can go talk to it.
SAM: All right.
MATT: Roll stealth checks as you emerge from the
mansion,
up into the boughs of the tree where you
left the exit.
TRAVIS: You don't think we're, like, perfectly on
this tree's radar?
That going stealth is
insulting?
MARISHA: I'm kinda wondering if the tree has a
tremor-sense.
LAURA: Oh, that's true. All right, all right,
you're right.
SAM: Don't do stealth, I'll present us all as a
group.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: All right. You emerge. Still the dusklight,
that kind of warm purplish-orange perpetual
sunset glow in the sky. The tree there remains.
You glance out. That little pocket where the
trees were is filled once more. The trees now
stand, the pocket is now done.
LAURA: That's where, that's where the hole was!
But it's not a hole anymore!
MATT: Make a perception check as you're looking.
LAURA: That's good, that's good. 29.
MATT: 29. About three-quarters of a mile further
west from your current location, there is now a
different opening in the canopy, similar size,
but even further out that way.
LAURA: What the fuck? It's further away.
Trees fucking moved. At least it's further away
from us and not closer to us.
MARISHA: Wait, is it the same... maybe it is
something big blocking it, with like an invisible
field? I don't know. I don't know.
MATT: So. What's the plan?
SAM: We have no plan. So let's just walk right up.
I take, me and Keyleth take tip of the spear,
and we just walk right up to the base of the
tree.
LAURA: I float on my broom.
MATT: Okay, so. What's the marching order?
SAM: Scanlan and Keyleth first.
MATT: Scanlan and Keyleth at the front.
LAURA: Oh no, oh no.
MATT: Who's after them?
TRAVIS: I'm in the middle.
MATT: All right, so Grog's up next.
LAURA: Trinket's behind Grog.
MATT: Trinket's behind Grog, all righty.
Percy? Vax? Are you guys holding up the rear?
TALIESIN: Yes.
MATT: And you're on the broom above.
LAURA: I'm on the broom, yes.
MATT: All right, got it.
LIAM: I actually think I want to tail Grog.
MATT: All right.
LIAM: Thank you.
TALIESIN: I'll take the rear, then.
MATT: All right, so Percy's at the rear,
Vax and Trinket are both right behind Grog as you
guys push forward. You touch down in the swamp,
the actual thickness of the morass, moving
forward very slowly with the swamp shoes.
Grog,
you get two steps before they break under
your weight.
TRAVIS: Good.
MARISHA: We tried.
TRAVIS: I take them off.
MATT: Okay. But the rest of you, it does help,
you are not sinking. Your progress is very slow,
slower than it was previously when you were
already at half-speed, but you aren't breaking the
surface of the actual substance. It is sticky,
and you have to pull it forth, and it is tension
put on the ropes, but for the most part,
most of you are light of foot, and it's not a
huge issue. Except for you. Trinket's just up to
his elbows, just (sloshing) through the water.
LAURA: Does he look miserable?
MATT: He's not enjoying himself.
LAURA: Do you wanna go in the crystal? Okay.
MATT: And he just keeps pushing forward.
LIAM: All right, I'm scritching his ears while we
walk.
LAURA: Thank you.
MATT: You push onward. It's not too far of a
distance, it takes you ten or fifteen minutes to
reach the very base of the tree where you had
previously scoped out. The large roots climb up
ten, 12 feet before emerging from the base of this
large tree. Maybe, at this point you can look at
it now, taller than you thought at a distance.
It's roughly 80 to 100 feet in width and probably
over 150 to 200 feet tall. It is just a thick,
solid, giant tree.
LAURA: That is a huge-ass tree.
SAM: As we approach, I take a little muck and I'm
going to draw like a little tree on my forehead
and one on Keyleth's forehead as well.
MARISHA: What are you drawing?
SAM: Just like a little mud tree on your
forehead.
MARISHA: Oh, yeah.
LIAM: Not a penis at all.
LAURA: Oh, yeah.
MARISHA: How is my tree?
LAURA: Looks kind of like a dick.
MARISHA: Scanlan!
SAM: Don't worry. It's for a good cause.
MATT: You step up to the heavy roots there,
and the mass of vines that are all clustered and
matted together. What do you do?
TRAVIS: We fan out.
SAM: Just a little bit.
LAURA: Yeah, we kind of branch, we just spread out
a little bit.
MATT: All right, so you guys spread out a little
bit.
MARISHA: Are we trying to talk to it first?
LAURA: Yeah, yeah, talk to it. Be charming.
SAM: I call out to it. Sondur! Sondur, hear us! We
are your devotees! We have come to pay homage and
respect to you. We follow your ways and your
teachings.
MARISHA: And I make myself to look like the
tree-dick on my forehead.
SAM: We wear your mark on our heads to show
respect.
Please show us your power and grant us
your blessings.
MATT: Long absence of sound following your
statement. Couple of small vines as part of that
knotted mess kind of twist tighter and then relax.
Does not appear to be any sort of reaction beyond
that.
MARISHA: I cast Speak with Plants.
SAM: Okay.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: Just repeat--
MARISHA: Are you waiting for me?
MATT: You imbue plants within 30 feet of you with
limited sentience and animation, giving them the
ability to communicate with you and to follow your
simple commands.
MARISHA: Sondur. Can you hear me?
SAM: Question one.
MATT: There is no response.
MARISHA: I am Keyleth from the Air Ashari.
Druids of the prime realm.
Are you still present?
MATT: This low, cracking, creaking sound of heavy
wood on wood-fall begins to slowly emerge in your
head. It just says,
"I am here."
MARISHA: We would like to see your heart.
LAURA: What?
SAM: Wow. Straight to it.
LAURA: Just straight-up. Just right in.
SAM: Just straight to it. Just go straight for...
I wanna spend the night with you.
Just straight there.
MATT: There's a pause. You hear, (snapping
sounds), and you notice the vines, some are
pulling and snapping while others begin to slowly
pull apart.
That giant mass of vines that are clustered
between two of the large roots that merge with the
tree? Begin to untangle and fall free, revealing
what appears to be a slowly opening pathway into
the tree itself. You now see what looks to be
about four and a half feet tall and about three
feet wide, a tunnel, like a crack in the bark
itself,
that disappears into darkness deeper into
the tree.
LAURA: No.
MARISHA: Me and my fellow companions are coming
in.
LAURA: No, this is so stupid.
SAM: Coming in?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
SAM: All right.
TRAVIS: Wait, how big is it?
MARISHA: I go in first.
SAM: Wait, you're going in?
LAURA: What, you're just going in?
SAM: Going with Kiki.
TALIESIN: Going in.
TRAVIS: You said four and a half feet...
MATT: Four and a half feet tall, about three feet
wide.
LAURA: So we can all fit in.
MATT: Well, you're gonna have to practically crawl
to get in there, Grog.
TRAVIS: Not this guy.
LAURA: You can fit in there.
MATT: You can fit, but you're gonna have to
crawl.
MARISHA: Just army crawl.
LAURA: Can Trinket fit through?
LIAM: It's gonna be a squeaker.
MATT: Trinket's gonna have to get down and like--
SAM: Your Pokeball.
LAURA: I know, I can just put him in the crystal
and then--
MATT: You can do that too, yeah.
LAURA: I'll put him in the crystal.
MATT: Okay. Trinket into the Raven's Slumber.
SAM: Do you want to stay outside?
LAURA: Grog, you can do it.
TRAVIS: Not normally.
LAURA: Turn your shoulders.
TALIESIN: (chicken noises)
LIAM: Could you pour some Crisco out of that magic
jug of yours and lube up?
LAURA: Yeah, oil yourself up, real good.
MATT: Just Winnie the Pooh you through?
SAM: Mayonnaise. Mayonnaise is slippery. Butter.
LIAM: This is Sparta. Come on.
TRAVIS: I'm going in, I'm going in.
MATT: Oh, bother.
LAURA: Oh, bother.
MATT: I don't know why he's British suddenly.
All right, so, marching order.
Who's going in first?
MARISHA: Me.
MATT: Keyleth.
SAM: And me second.
MATT: And Scanlan, who's going in after them?
LIAM: I am.
LAURA: Then me, behind him.
MATT: Vax, Vex.
TALIESIN: Then me.
MATT: Percy. And then finally Grog.
LAURA: Grog!
MATT: All right.
MARISHA: Bringing up the rear this time, Grog.
MATT: So.
LIAM: Here comes the general.
MATT: As you begin to make your way into this
entrance to the tree--
LAURA: Oh no. We are so dumb.
MATT: This scent catches you as soon as you step
five, ten feet into the darkness.
LAURA: It smells like fart?
MATT: It's metallic, iron-like. Sharp, acrid,
uninviting. As you step inside and your hand
touches the inside of the entranceway, Keyleth,
as soon as your fingers make contact with the
slick wood, there's an image that flashes in your
head.
LAURA: Oh, god.
SAM: The whispers, the whispers.
LAURA: Oh no.
SAM: Oh my gosh.
LAURA: Don't hit that.
MARISHA: Watch the--
LAURA: That would be so bad.
SAM: Oh boy.
LAURA: I'm gonna smack his ass right now. Whack!
SAM: Ordinarily I would plug Lootcrate right here,
but this is too tense.
MARISHA: Wait wait wait.
TALIESIN: Way too tense to talk about all the
great things Lootcrate will send you every month.
SAM: Way too tense, yeah, I'm too nervous to
remember the three-dollar-a-month discount that
you would get by signing up--
TRAVIS: That's Lootcrate.com/crates.
LAURA: No, it's /criticalrole. And it'll take you
to crates.
TALIESIN: Crates will just show you everything
they have.
MARISHA: We're not alone.
SAM: What do you mean?
LAURA: What do you mean?
SAM: There's creatures?
MARISHA: He's watching us.
SAM: Who?
LAURA: Sondur.
MATT: As you're saying this, your hand's following
the side, and it opens up again. You only have
about five feet of walking before this tiny tunnel
opens up into an interior chamber.
TRAVIS: Well, I hope he's watching. We just
crawled in his tree anus.
MATT: His tranus?
(All laugh.)
SAM: Ah, Matt.
LIAM: Bad DM.
MARISHA: Sondur. Is this you leading us straight
to you?
MATT: Nothing.
TRAVIS: How about we hit the wall?
LAURA: No! We're trapped in the tree.
SAM: I will, I'll try one more time and just say,
Sondur, we are... Sondurites, here to pay homage
to you. Please, show yourself and make us feel
your presence.
MATT: Are you guys still entering, or have you
stopped?
LAURA: (sings) Oh, Sondur... (stops singing) We're
walking forward, we're walking forward.
MATT: Because some of you are still outside of the
tree.
TALIESIN: Still going in.
MATT: Okay. So you all eventually make your way
inside this space.
MARISHA: I look at Scanlan and wipe the tree-dick
off my forehead.
MATT: Okay, it's pitch-black in here, by the way.
SAM: (whispering) It's our sign!
MATT: Percy, you see nothing. The rest of you have
some semblance of dark-vision here, so you can
see, the interior here, it is wall-to-wall vines
and thick, heavy roots. You are definitely on the
inside of the tree, this portion of the giant
hollow chamber. You can see it kind of lifts up.
Entangled webs of these branches and
smaller, long-dead trees jutting out inside,
like actual smaller physical trees within the
large tree. As you all enter, the little bit of
light behind you, Grog? Begins to shrink,
and you look over your shoulder as the entrance
you came through slams closed and you are all left
in darkness.
LAURA: We're just stuck in a tree now.
TRAVIS: Well, he puckered up.
MATT: The smell gets stronger and stronger.
At that point, as Grog, you kind of pull your way
through, and you're all standing
shoulder-to-shoulder in this dark space,
this one singular tree root that's sticking up
from the center in two different places.
This thin, reedy voice begins to echo through,
sourceless around you, that says,
"I know you. The moment you touched my
sickness, I knew you."
At this moment, small patches of fungal clusters
begin to illuminate in the room. Areas of the
vines and ground just spring to life, and this
dull blue glow begins to fill the room with very,
very low light. You can just make out shapes.
You can see that the vines are just very slowly
shifting around you. The walls are not still.
That little bit of movement you'd occasionally
catch on the outside of the tree, it is perpetual
inside here. It is this constant churning mass of
living tree. You look up, and you can see all the
branches come and mat together into this conical
ceiling, where a number of vines drip down and
just hang, hundreds of them. You see the vines are
slowly coalescing in the center of this upward
kind of pinnacle. Slithering one into the next
like a thousand slithering snakes.
A voice comes out again.
"Why do you come here, children of the
lost?
What purpose brings you to Sondur's madness and pain?"
LAURA: We've come to help you.
MATT: A mass in the ceiling separates ever so
slightly, and you watch as two feet descend from
this strange apex. You now see the feet are a full
creature, held aloft by connected tendrils of
black plant matter, emanating from the back and
shoulders, as it slowly descends from the ceiling.
A thin, elf-like individual, their body comprised
of hundreds of small plants, leaves, and thorns.
The only semblance of flesh you see across the
face is the nose, the eyes, and the mouth.
The rest of it just slowly giving way to a
similar nest of plant-like vines that completely
fill the exterior of this room. It slowly touches
down, its feet hitting the ground, and as it does,
the tendrils all detach and withdraw back into
the ceiling, leaving it there, arms to its side,
its head down. Its face comes up, its eyes
immediately open with this bright yellow glow that
kind of bathes you. You can see the form,
the edges of all of your allies now, even being
framed by this light that's just pouring forth
from its face.
LAURA: I bow.
LIAM: Follow suit.
SAM: Sure, I'll bow as well.
MATT: You all bow before this creature. Do you
bow? All right.
MARISHA: I stand as well.
MATT: All right.
"You all come here, but one of
you is the reason."
It looks straight towards you. The light focuses
and narrows from his eyes.
"You. Sweet, broken Vex'ahlia. Unwanted daughter,
unproven ally. Selfish and cruel. You drive those
"whom you would call family into danger and death
for your own gain. I understand you."
There's a softness and sadness to the face as
he takes one step in your direction.
"You are lost without
form. Without knowing who you are, child.
"You stand shattered by expectation.
"Presenting an illusion of confidence.
Behind it, you never left that bloodied girl,
"dagger in hand, body at your feet. You are a
killer, run as you may. The tears you cry are not
"in vain, my sweet, my dear Vex'ahlia. You can rise
above your trembling destiny. I have lived a
"thousand years and a day. I have seen many things.
I can grant many gifts."
LAURA: Are we still pretending to like this fuck?
SAM: Nope.
LAURA: I don't want anything you offer.
MATT: "You mistake. My intent is not to hurt,
but to understand. I see lots of my youth in you.
"We are not as different as you may think.
You have things I do not. Companionship.
"I have been without for so very long. And the
ones I have let in have hurt me so very deeply."
His eyes actually cast away from you for a
second and he steps back into place. Almost seems
to, his confident form withdraws into this almost
hanging, sad position.
LAURA: You've been betrayed.
MATT: We all have in some degree, yes.
LAURA: Is that why you are what you are now?
MATT: I don't even remember. I just know that I'm
alone and she left me there.
LAURA: She? Who is she?
MATT: Memories have faded. I just want someone to
understand me, that's all. Can you understand me?
LAURA: Sondur. I understand.
MATT: "Is there trust in you?"
His form steps forward once more, his head tilted,
looking at you curiously.
LAURA: You want to be loved.
MATT: I wish a bond. A companion once more.
Would you embrace me? Embrace your rebirth?
I could give you so much.
LIAM: Vex'ahlia.
MATT: I could give you the means to protect them.
Your home.
LAURA: What would you ask in return?
MATT: Your heart.
LAURA: My heart is someone else's. And I pull my
bow.
MATT: He withdraws a moment. The tendrils whip out
again and connect into his back,
and he's pulled aloft, back, further in.
"All I ask is one who
knows my pain. What is your answer?"
LAURA: I release the arrow.
MATT: Roll an attack.
LAURA: I'm sorry, I feel so guilty about it!
SAM: He just wanted a kiss and you shot him!
MARISHA: He's a dick.
LAURA: 25.
MATT: All right. Go ahead and roll damage.
SAM: Just a lonely guy.
LAURA: 16.
TALIESIN: I have no respect for anyone who says
we're not so different.
MATT: 16 points of piercing damage.
LIAM: And shitting black diarrhea out of the
tree.
MATT: As the arrow hits his form as he's being
pulled up-- (gasps)-- you hear the air escape like
he had the wind knocked out of him. His glowing
yellow eyes blink, blink, and his jaw kind of
hangs open. There in the low-lit darkness.
And you watch as more of that black, thick tar
just begins to pour from his mouth onto the
ground, splattering and seeping into the floor.
His jaw slowly closes.
"Then I am to be alone."
He reaches his hand up, and you watch--
MARISHA: Oh shit!
MATT: -- as these vines reveal and give to him
this large curved bow that he grasps in his hand.
The other vines curl around his body, and you can
see his form begin to build, like his actual body
begins to grow as the vines become part of him.
His face of flesh disappears behind an exterior
of dark and gnarled wood. The voice grows deep as
he all of a sudden withdraws into the side of the
tree itself, and then bursts forth, landing on the
ground. Not an elf-like entity, but some sort of
gnarled root-like tree creature, holding Fenthras
in one hand.
LAURA: Was that bad? Should I have not attacked
him?
SAM: You did great.
LAURA: Okay.
TALIESIN: No, no, he was being terrible.
LAURA: We should probably--
MATT: Your choice is made.
LAURA: I call out Trinket--
MATT: Become another memory here and keep me
company in oblivion.
SAM: Oh, god.
MATT: The two dead trees quake and begin to lift
up--
MARISHA: Oh, fuck.
MATT: -- from the sides of the tree. Everyone roll
initiative.
TALIESIN: Oh.
TRAVIS: Yeah!
LAURA: I feel so guilty.
MARISHA: No, he was a fucking cock.
LAURA: He was terrible, was it mean?
MARISHA: No, dude.
LAURA: Okay, we're in the tree, we're in the
tree.
MARISHA: Like you said, I don't trust anyone who
says we're alike, you and I.
SAM: What, were you gonna give him a hug and get
possessed forever?
LAURA: I know, he's offering terrible things,
right?
TALIESIN: He was a dick.
MARISHA: I also don't like anyone who tries to act
like
we didn't make our own choice to come in here.
TALIESIN: And for that matter, anybody who says
we're not so different,
that's usually a sign of a terrible person.
MARISHA: That we're totally different.
TALIESIN: Terrible person.
SAM: Because we're terrible people.
TALIESIN: Well, that's very fair.
LIAM: He's creeping on my sister, fuck him.
MARISHA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: I was only not shooting him to be
polite.
TRAVIS: Oh, shit.
MATT: All right, so. 25 to 20, anybody?
TALIESIN: 21.
MATT: 21.
LIAM: 23.
MATT: Nice.
TRAVIS: Just so you know, your notepad is in the
upper-left.
LIAM: Secrets.
LAURA: (laughs) Scootch-scootch.
MATT: All right, and so. Vax, Percy, 21, er,
20 to 15?
TRAVIS: 18.
MARISHA: 15.
SAM: 15.
MATT: All righty.
LAURA: I got that one hit and that was all I got.
I'm sorry.
MATT: All right, and then...
LAURA: 14.
MATT: 14? Okay. All righty. So, top of the round,
Vax. You have first up.
You're currently over here.
LIAM: Yeah. I can see fuck-all through this
magical window--
MATT: I understand.
LIAM: So I see where I am in that circle,
what are the big clumps of poop in the middle?
MATT: This right here is part of the root that is
growing up in the center of this tree. There are
two trees on the side that are shifting,
and the actual large dark-rooted form that is now
Sondur is over here on the far side.
LIAM: All right, boots click, uh, I am hanging
back behind-- is Trinket out still?
LAURA: He's out. Oh. I haven't brought him out
yet, I haven't brought him out.
MATT: No.
LIAM: All right. Then I'm just leaning out from
behind Grog
and I am going to dagger-dagger-dagger him.
MATT: All righty, go for it.
LIAM: And I'm first to attack so I have
advantage.
MATT: You do.
LIAM: Okay, so the first hit is a 26.
MATT: 26 hits.
LIAM: Yeah, second is a 26.
MATT: Hits.
LIAM: And the third is a 21.
MATT: 21. All three hit.
LIAM: Okay, so the first one is sneak attack.
MATT: It is.
LIAM: This one is the flame-tongue, here it goes.
Six and seven,
here comes the sneak attack damage.
MATT: All the sneak attack damage!
LIAM: Say again?
MATT: Percy, you're up next, just so you're
aware.
LIAM: (mumbling) 30 for the first.
MATT: 30, nice.
LIAM: Seven for the second, and eight for the third.
MATT: Great, all right. You, tapping the boots,
rush out behind Grog, fling all three daggers,
all seem to stick into the wood-armored exterior
of Sondur's treant form. You see he kind of pulls
back a bit from the impact. Damage definitely has
been sustained unexpectedly.
LIAM: Where am I in relation to the party,
to my sister?
MATT: You're right there, your sister is right
there. So you're about 10 feet from her.
LIAM: I'm gonna just roll forward and crouch in
front of her low,
to give her a shot but be in
front of her.
MATT: All righty. There you go. All right,
that finishes your turn.
That brings us to Percy.
TALIESIN: I'm going to dart to the right and keep
about 10 to 15 feet distance away from the
exterior wall, because that looks creepy as fuck.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: About there. First thing I'm gonna do is
I'm gonna pull out Bad News and I'm gonna take a
shot, and I'm gonna try and disarm him.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: So. We'll see if that does anything.
Natural 20.
LAURA: Yes!
SAM: At least five a session.
LIAM: That loaded die was the best investment we
ever made.
TALIESIN: It was the best, it was such a
wonderful, wonderful--
SAM: Did a fan give that to you?
TALIESIN: A fan gave that to me, yes they did.
MATT: All right, natural 20.
TALIESIN: Natural 20, and that means I don't even
burn the grit for it, and that's arm-shot, so.
Strength saving throw against a DC 19.
MATT: That is 21, so yeah, it manages to maintain
it.
TALIESIN: Okay, so it maintains it. I forgot to
cast Hex, but god damn it. That's fine.
So, taking my shot...
MATT: Dice times two.
TALIESIN: That went well. That's 19 times two,
that's 38.
MATT: 38 points of damage.
TALIESIN: That's 44 points of damage.
MATT: 44 points of damage on the critical hit.
TALIESIN: Of piercing damage. I'm gonna reload.
MATT: All right.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna cast Hex.
MATT: The impact manages to hit part of the wood,
it splinters,
not doing as much damage as you'd
expect it would.
TALIESIN: That's fine.
MATT: It's still a nice hit, but the form seemed
to resist it--
TALIESIN: Seems to be taking it. That's fine.
I'm casting Hex.
MATT: All right.
TALIESIN: I'm giving him disadvantage on strength
saving throws.
MATT: All righty.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna take another shot--
MATT: Ability checks, not saving throws.
TALIESIN: Yeah, checks, excuse me. I'm gonna take
another shot at getting that damn bow out of his
hand. So we'll see if we can do that. Yeah,
that's a 19, so that's 32 to hit.
MATT: That hits.
TALIESIN: He can roll his saving throw.
MATT: 17, so no.
TALIESIN: So no, he drops the bow.
MATT: The bow gets dropped.
SAM: Oh, shit!
TALIESIN: Bow's on the ground.
MARISHA: Oh, bow's on the ground, bow's on the
ground.
TALIESIN: That's a terrible roll. That's okay.
So that's ten points of piercing damage and two
points of necrotic damage.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: How do you want to do this?
MATT: So you fire the second shot, does hit,
a little crack of impact, the wood on the
exterior splinters a bit, the necrotic hit does
still push through. All right, that finishes your
turn, as Fenthras gets blasted off, a finger's
actually missing from the impact.
A finger begins to grow back.
TALIESIN: Bow's on the ground!
MATT: All right, Grog. Actually, no, before you're
up, we're at count 20. All right.
SAM: Count 20.
LAURA: What's that mean?
MARISHA: What does that mean?
MATT: So. Suddenly the ground quakes for a second,
part of the roots expand--
TALIESIN: Oh, shit.
SAM: Lair actions.
MATT: -- and a cloud of gas begins to fill a small
area about that big.
LAURA: Oh, of course.
MATT: I need Scanlan, Keyleth, Vax, and Vex to
make a constitution saving throw.
MARISHA: Where's that dice?
LIAM: Oh, that's our specialty.
MARISHA: Yeah, right? Not bad.
LAURA: Oh, natural 20!
MATT: Nice.
LIAM: I'm gonna burn a Luck. 16.
MATT: All right.
MARISHA: 20 total, 20 total.
SAM: 20 total.
MATT: Okay.
(All laugh.)
MATT: All of you guys manage to just in time--
TRAVIS: He's pissed.
MATT: -- catch your breath and keep below the
poison cloud as it dissipates in the vicinity of
you, so you reduce the damage to each of you guys
to be
12 points of poison damage to all of you guys.
MARISHA: Damn. That's half.
MATT: So that's 12 points of poison damage to each
one of you guys. Now, Grog, it's your turn.
TRAVIS: I would like to advance-- I would like to
rage.
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: I would like to advance as far as I can
get towards the treant.
MATT: You can get right there, you're not quite
close enough to hit.
TRAVIS: Hey, that's cool, and I'm gonna use the
chain of returning with the blood axe, and I'm
gonna throw it at the tree.
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: At Sondur.
MATT: Go for it.
TRAVIS: That's not great. Oh! 20 total.
MATT: 20 total? All righty.
(background music becomes distorted)
LAURA: Oh no. We gotta get a new cable, a new
cable for you.
SAM: It's dying.
MATT: I know, I have a new iPad coming, actually.
LAURA: Oh, okay.
MATT: It's in the budget, having issues,
strangely. Which is a shame, because this works
really well for this battle. I dunno. Maybe.
SAM: Music help!
MATT: I'll try.
MARISHA: Oh, that got so awkwardly quiet.
LAURA: Oh no, it's all...
MATT: Yeah, I don't wanna tear it. Whatever,
it's fine, it's fine.
MARISHA: It just sounds weird inside the tree...
TALIESIN: Acoustics.
MARISHA: Acoustics.
SAM: If anyone works for Apple and wants to send
us all new iPads.
(All laugh.)
TALIESIN: iPhones. iPad Pros.
MARISHA: Preferably in rose gold.
(The music comes back in, less distorted.)
SAM: Better? Better!
LAURA: That sounds better.
MATT: It's working better.
MARISHA: Yes, much better. Much better.
LAURA: Yeah.
MARISHA: You're good.
MATT: Okay, cool. We're good.
SAM: Forget those iPads.
MATT: So, Grog, what was your attack roll?
TRAVIS: It was a 20 total.
MATT: That does just barely hit. Go ahead and roll
damage.
TRAVIS: 24.
MATT: 24 points--
TRAVIS: Ahh, plus... four points of necrotic
damage, for 28.
MATT: 28 points of damage. The axe, with all your
heaving might behind it, travels the ten feet to
slam into the chest of Sondur. Reaches up and
tries to grab it, smashing it between his hands to
hold it there. Go ahead and make your strength to
pull it back.
TRAVIS: 18.
MATT: 18, yeah, that works fine, okay.
MARISHA: It appeared he took damage from the
necrotic?
MATT: Yeah, he did.
TRAVIS: On Percy's and mine.
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: So he can take necrotic damage.
TALIESIN: Apparently he can.
LAURA: That's good, that's good.
MARISHA: Good to know.
MATT: But not as impacting on the necrotic damage
as much as you'd hoped.
LAURA: Oh, okay.
MARISHA: On the necrotic damage.
TRAVIS: But Liam did, I mean, Vax did something.
MATT: Yeah, you guys have all done damage to him,
it was just
generally lesser than you hoped it would be.
TRAVIS: Yeah, yours was surprisingly good.
LAURA: Piercing damage...
MATT: Well, his just, he just sneak attacked.
TALIESIN: We haven't found a winner.
LAURA: Okay.
LIAM: Sneak-attack damage.
TALIESIN: We haven't found a winner, we've just
been hitting him really god damned hard.
MATT: But anyway. So you pull the axe back,
grab it from the chain, it's back in your grip,
you're fine, you're good to go. Does that end
your turn?
TRAVIS: That does.
MATT: All right, at the end of your turn,
he's gonna go ahead and burn two legendary
actions to cast a spell.
LAURA: Oh no! He's like a dragon!
MATT: All right. I need-- (laughs)
LAURA: I should've just gone evil.
MATT: I need everyone, all of you, to make a
dexterity saving throw.
SAM: Is he casting a spell?
MATT: He is, yes.
SAM: I will attempt to Counterspell it.
MATT: Okay. All right, go ahead and make your d20
plus six.
SAM: I'm gonna go at level five.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: Level five. What do I, d20 plus six?
MATT: Correct.
SAM: 24.
MATT: 24?
SAM: Yeah.
MATT: All right.
MARISHA: Hell yeah.
MATT: He goes to create this spell, and suddenly
it fizzles in midair,
unable to actually take effect.
(Sam rings a bell.)
MARISHA: Hell yeah, Scanlan! Hell yeah.
(All laugh.)
MATT: All right, so that finishes that. Ending
Grog's turn, the legendary actions return now.
SAM: Return?
MATT: Yes.
SAM: But he's just used them!
MATT: Yeah, it comes back at the end of his next
round. At the beginning of his round, you watch as
his form begins to seal up the wounds he had
taken, beginning to heal ever-so-slightly.
LAURA: It's his turn now.
MATT: He reaches down and grabs the bow from the
ground, and you watch as he sinks down into the
ground, roots reaching up and grabbing him,
and he vanishes into the bottom of the tree.
MARISHA: Whoa. Yeah.
That makes sense. It's what I would do.
SAM: He's getting that invisible figurine that he
has.
MATT: And reemerges--
SAM: Oh, hi. Hi, friend.
MATT: -- way up in the top of the tree, out of the
branches up there, his upper torso extends outward
and he pulls back the bow--
LAURA: Oh no.
MATT: -- and begins just unleashing arrows that
are forming out of his hand, these thin
thorn-like arrows are built out of his viny-like
arm, and he pulls back and releases them as they
snap as arrows towards you guys. He's going to
make a bramble-shot attack at you, Grog.
SAM: Bramble-shot. Sounds tasty.
MATT: That is going to be 21.
TRAVIS: Hits.
MATT: That hits. All right. So you take 14 points
of piercing damage, reduced to half, so you take
seven points, plus four points of lightning
damage.
TRAVIS: Lightning damage?
(Computer alert sound.)
SAM: Hi, hi Liam.
LIAM: Not my computer.
MATT: Plus an additional 18 points of piercing
damage.
TRAVIS: Halved?
MATT: Halved to nine.
LAURA: Wow.
MATT: As the arrow hits you, and then bursts into
a series of jagged, thorny vines that wrap around
you. I need you to make a strength saving throw.
TRAVIS: That's pretty awesome.
TALIESIN: We're gonna set him on fire, we're gonna
hit him with light,
we're gonna hit him with things.
MARISHA: I was thinking fire too.
LAURA: Lightning. Lightning? Has anybody tried
electricity yet?
TRAVIS: 22.
MATT: 22. You feel the bramble vines wrap around
you and try to hold you in place, and you just
angrily burst out of them.
SAM: Yes!
LAURA: Yes!
MARISHA: Fuck yeah!
MATT: You are not restrained.
SAM: Yes, for once.
MARISHA: (laughing) Yeah, you're not grappled.
MATT: He's gonna go ahead and unleash two more
arrows--
LAURA: Shit, Jesus.
MATT: -- this time towards you, as he's kind of
focused now on the--
LAURA: Both of them at me?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Rejection's a bitch.
MARISHA: Yeah, rejection.
MATT: He's not too happy with being rejected,
it seems.
MARISHA: He's been alone for too long.
MATT: The first one is 24 to hit.
LAURA: That hits.
MATT: Second is a 25 to hit.
LAURA: Both hit.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: I'm gonna die.
MATT: So you take--
MARISHA: No, you're not.
SAM: Nah, you'll be fine. (whispering) She's dead.
She's dead. She's definitely dead.
MATT: 13 points of damage with one lightning, and,
that's a lucky roll, eight points of piercing
damage with one lightning.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: As two additional arrows just wh-whack!
right inside of you, and you look down and can see
these large, thin stiletto-like wooden forms that
are just
pierced into your armor and cut into your flesh.
LAURA: Is that plus one additional lightning
damage, you mean?
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: Okay, so 14 and nine?
MATT: Right. Yep. That's gonna end Sondur's turn.
The two dead trees that you saw quaking on the
sides suddenly burst out, the roots becoming legs,
and you watch as two treants emerge from the
sides of the tree.
TRAVIS: Oh, I was joking when I said it.
TALIESIN: You shouldn't have been.
SAM: Oh my god.
MATT: Large sort of freed and sentient trees begin
stomping forward towards you guys. This one is
going to go ahead and rush up to you folks,
while this one is gonna go right for Percy,
which is right in its side there.
SAM: God, this is a tough one.
MATT: Two slam attacks against you, Percy.
MARISHA: Ooh, fuck.
MATT: That is a 19 to hit.
TALIESIN: That hits.
MATT: And a natural 20.
TALIESIN: That doesn't hit.
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: Natural 20.
MATT: That sucked. For you. Right, so the first
hit, you take 17 points of bludgeoning damage.
The second hit, 28 points of bludgeoning damage,
as the giant tree just whack! And as soon as you
try and get out of the way, the giant fist comes
down and slams you right across the neck and
shoulders, causing you to take a knee, and you can
feel the muscle pop from some sort of
overextension. The giant tree now, you can see its
bark contorted in this angry face as it pours more
of that black oil-like liquid out of the corner of
its mouth. The other one that's rushed up against
the two of you is going to go ahead and take one
hit against you, Vex, and two hits against you,
Vax. Sorry, it only gets two slams. One on each.
My apologies.
One against you, Vex, is going to
be sixteen.
LAURA: Oh, it misses.
SAM: Hey!
MATT: You duck out of the way and it actually
slams the large root tree to the front of you.
The other one goes to Vax. That is going to be a
26 to hit.
LIAM: Oh yeah. Uncanny dodge.
MATT: Okay, so you take--
LIAM: Oh, at disadvantage, excuse me, because of
the cloak of displacement.
MATT: Rolled an 18 on the second one, so it still
hits you.
So that effect goes away, but you would take
18 points of bludgeoning damage, reduced to nine
because of your Uncanny Dodge. All right,
that ends their turn. Now it is Scanlan and
Keyleth's turn. What are you guys doing?
SAM: Preference?
MARISHA: I'm gonna go for the ents.
SAM: I'm gonna go for the big guy.
MARISHA: All right. So you go first, then.
SAM: All right. I'm gonna go a couple steps to the
right,
like split the difference between me and
Percy.
MATT: All righty.
SAM: I will cast, I will use the wand of...
well, jeez,
lightning or fire, lightning or fire.
MARISHA: Fire.
LAURA: Try fire.
SAM: Wand of fireballs, I'll use three charges.
MARISHA: Fuck yeah.
SAM: At the big guy upstairs.
MATT: Up there?
SAM: Yeah.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: Pew-pew.
LAURA: Big guy upstairs. Santa Claus?
MARISHA: The CEO of this tree.
MATT: DC of what on the spell?
SAM: 15.
MATT: That, yeah, he makes his save with a 19.
So half-damage,
go ahead and roll that, five charges?
SAM: I'm going to use three, I get three charges
and then two more is five...
yeah, five. Yes, five.
MATT: Yes, so--
SAM: So it's 10d6.
MATT: Correct.
SAM: Okay. Six, eight, 14, 16, 17. 23... 28, 32.
33.
MATT: 33.
SAM: Halved.
MATT: Half that for 15, or 16 actually, sorry.
16 points of fire damage as the Fireball bursts
up where you can see some of the roots are blown
off and a bit of the upper ceiling collapses and
hangs for a second.
LAURA: Did it look like it actually affected him,
the fire?
MATT: It looked like he took damage from it,
yeah.
TRAVIS: It didn't catch fire.
MATT: It didn't seem to catch fire, no. In fact,
the decaying liquid
it seems to be spewing out of it, it's almost--
TRAVIS: A natural retardant?
MATT: Yeah, it's preventing any flame from
catching on the creature in the vicinity as the
flames slowly go out. The vines begin to reform to
close up the ceiling, and you see Sondur is still
kind of gliding through the vines and using them
to move along the upper outside of the tree.
Is that going to be the end of your movement?
SAM: Yeah, I'll use a bonus action, gah,
do I heal or do I inspire? What's more helpful
here? I will heal Percy a little bit.
I can only cast Healing Word at level one
as a bonus action, right?
MATT: You can cast it at any level you want to as
a bonus action.
SAM: Oh, okay.
MATT: Since you didn't actually cast a spell,
you used the wand.
SAM: Oh, that's true. Okay, well then I'll do it
at, uh, level two.
TALIESIN: Okay.
SAM: I don't know what I'm gonna need today.
It's 2d4 plus five.
TALIESIN: Okay. Do you roll that or do I?
SAM: I do.
MATT: Plus six, technically, because your charisma
went up.
SAM: Ooh! Oh, nice. I will sing to him, let's see
if I can do this. "Come on, come on, get your
Scanlan on, it's Thursday night and it won't be
long, gonna play my flute, play my shawm,
it's Thursday night and it won't be long 'til I
get your health up, get your health up, I got all
you need, no I don't shoot bows, I don't swing
swords, but damn I can sing."
(All cheer.)
MATT: You take that god damn inspiration.
MARISHA: That was really good!
LIAM: Sang for his supper.
SAM: 4d4 plus six. Er. Four plus six, ten.
Ten, ugh!
LAURA: Ten is better than nothing!
MARISHA: That's pretty good.
MATT: Ten hit points as the song pushes your
healing at a rapid pace because it's so inspiring.
All right. Are you staying where you are,
Scanlan?
SAM: I already moved a little bit, I'm gonna stick
right there, yeah.
MATT: Yeah, you moved ten feet, so you're gonna
stay there? Okay. Keyleth.
MARISHA: Okay, so these trees that are moving
appear to be living trees more or less, correct?
MATT: Appear to be, yeah. From what you can tell.
MARISHA: I'm gonna cast Tree Stride on myself.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: And then I'm gonna go into fire elemental
form and flame on.
TALIESIN: Yeah!
LAURA: Oh shit, girl!
SAM: Have you done that before?
MARISHA: No, and I don't know if it's really gonna
work.
SAM: You're Johnny Storm?
LAURA: Flame on!
MARISHA: Oh, I've been a fire elemental before,
yeah.
MATT: So you're gonna move next to this tree,
then? Is that what you're gonna do?
MARISHA: Well, I'm casting Tree Stride.
MATT: Right, but Tree Stride, you have to,
you have the ability to enter a tree. You must
use five feet of movement to enter a tree.
MARISHA: Right. I'm casting Tree Stride because
it's a concentration that lasts a minute.
MATT: Right.
MARISHA: And then I'm going to use my bonus action
to flame on.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: This is pretty cool.
MARISHA: If this works.
MATT: Where once was Keyleth is now a fire
elemental.
LAURA: I fell over, I was so impressed.
MARISHA: All the rage of the fire ashari.
And then I'm going to enter inside that treant
right in front of me.
LAURA: She's going to enter inside of it.
MARISHA: I'm going to very nicely enter it with
its permission and consent.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: And then I'm going to multi-attack.
MATT: So you're using this to just stay within the
tree while punching it on fire.
MARISHA: Well, ideally, because as per the rules
of Tree Stride, I may use, I instantly know the
location of all other trees of the same kind and
as part of my movement I can pass into
any other trees of my choice of that same kind.
MATT: Yep.
MARISHA: So I'm gonna take this guy on for right
now.
MATT: Okay, go for it. So, make your attack rolls
against this treant.
TRAVIS: Interesting, Keyleth.
TALIESIN: You are doing some crazy shit.
LAURA: Crazy shit.
MARISHA: We'll see.
SAM: We brought a gun to a tree-fight.
(All laugh.)
MARISHA: Those are pretty good. The first hit,
sorry, I don't know my... I'm trying to find what
I add here. Okay. So the first one is going to be
25 to hit.
MATT: 25 hits, yep.
MARISHA: And the second one's going to be 16.
MATT: Just barely hits.
MARISHA: Fuck yeah.
LIAM: (Malone voice) They send one of yours to the
Feywild, you send one of theirs to the morgue.
(All laugh.)
MATT: Don't forget your additional, because even
if you're a fire elemental you still get your
additional fire damage.
MARISHA: Flame hands, which is an additional d6,
correct?
MATT: Correct.
MARISHA: So I am rolling 2d6 plus three twice,
so I'll do 4d... or, I'll roll 3d6 twice.
First one... not bad. Eight plus five is 13,
plus another three, so 16. 16 for the first one.
MATT: 16 points of fire damage, all right.
All right, the next one?
MARISHA: The next one is 14.
MATT: All right.
MARISHA: And until the creature takes an action to
douse the fire, the target takes-- oh, it also,
anything that if I move within, it immediately
takes 1d10 damage whenever I move into its space.
MATT: All right, so go ahead and roll another
d10.
MARISHA: Nine.
SAM: Also, if it's a tree it instantly dies.
LAURA: That's just the rule, that's just what it
says.
MATT: You notice as you tear into its body with
the Tree Stride to open it up, it looks down
confused as you pull into it and then just begin
pummeling and scraping the inside of its form.
As you do so, from the inside, what little bit of
fire retardant-like black liquid was somewhat
dried or coated on these, not as thick as it was
on Sondur, not only has it caught fire but the
wood here is very, very ready for kindling,
and it's vulnerable to fire, everything in that
was doubled, so you just tear into it--
(All yell.)
MATT: You just watch as this treant has a flaming
elemental in its stomach just bursting forth in
gouts of fire. You watch as it begins to crack up
the center and parts of it are just bursting into
flames and burning at the top.
LAURA: Holy crap.
MATT: It's having a bad day right now.
LAURA: Keyleth. Serious.
MATT: Is that the end of your turn?
MARISHA: That I am satisfied with, yes.
MATT: All right. Ending Keyleth's turn, that
brings us to Vex, you're up.
LAURA: Okay. I'm gonna step just a little bit away
from that flaming tree.
MARISHA: Yes. It is now a safety hazard.
LAURA: To the side, I'm just gonna step to the
side. Yeah.
MARISHA: Careful for falling limbs.
LAURA: I'm gonna Hunter's Mark Sondur, damn it.
MATT: Okay, as you pull back it does get an attack
of opportunity on you.
LAURA: Aw.
MATT: That is an 18 plus ten, 28.
LAURA: Oh, fuck.
MATT: So you take--
SAM: A billion.
MATT: -- 17 points of bludgeoning damage as you
rush back--
LAURA: Motherfucker.
MATT: -- and the flaming treant just reaches out
and strikes you across the back of the head,
almost sending you tumbling to the ground.
Giant dull thud in the back, you can feel the
headache growing in your skull, but you continue
forward.
LAURA: Ah! (strained) Fuck you. Okay. I Hunter's
Mark Sandor. Sandor?
MARISHA: Sondur.
TALIESIN: Sondur.
LAURA: Sondur, Sondur. Sandor is in Game of
Thrones.
MATT: Yes.
LAURA: And then I'm going to attack him with the
sky sentinel bow.
MATT: Go for it.
LAURA: (nervous noises) 17 on the first one.
MATT: Misses.
LAURA: Natural 20 on the second one.
MARISHA: What up!
LAURA: And 19 on the third.
MATT: Misses.
LAURA: Fucking balls mother bitch, okay, wow.
MATT: But the critical hit, so go ahead and roll
damage for the critical.
LAURA: So what, do I just double all my dice?
MATT: Yeah, double the dice and then add the bonus
at the end.
SAM: How's the Sky bar?
MARISHA: I think this is caramel? Nope, fudge.
TALIESIN: Oh, you got the fudge end.
MARISHA: I got the fudge end.
LAURA: 16 times two is 32, yeah? Plus seven,
plus two. 41.
MATT: 41 points of damage.
LAURA: On the first attack. And then I'll attack
him again. 'Cause that was just one.
MATT: Right, that was the sky sentinel. You didn't
double the bonus, right,
that was just the dice roll?
LAURA: Nope, I just doubled the dice.
MATT: Shit, yeah, with Hunter's Mark, yeah,
that's slick. All right, go for it.
LAURA: Okay, so the second one, I'm gonna attack
him through the blazing bowstring.
MATT: Go for it.
LAURA: And that is a 30.
MATT: 30 hits, yes.
TRAVIS: How high is Sondur?
MATT: He is roughly 30 feet up.
TALIESIN: At the very least, I might try and get
him to drop the bow, and then you're gonna be the
one who has to grab it if things get...
LAURA: Is 14 plus eight, is 22. 22 on the second.
MATT: 22 points of damage. Nice.
LAURA: And that was with eight points of fire
damage. I don't know if that matters.
LIAM: Is he pressed against the roof of this
chamber?
MATT: He's getting up towards the roof, yeah.
LIAM: Towards it.
MATT: As the two arrows shhhk to the side,
the one single arrow pierces into the side of his
chest and arm where Percy had shot before,
and the arrow disappears into the side,
and you see a burst of electrical energy causing
the one arm that was getting ready to pull one of
its thorny arrows kind of goes limp for a second,
and a second arrow just shoots right in the side
of the face and is now protruding from underneath
his cheekbone. (angry breathing)
LAURA: And for my movement, can I get on my broom
for my movement?
MATT: You'd have to--
LAURA: I'd have to pull it out.
MATT: Your broom is kind of slung over your
shoulder.
LAURA: Right. Okay. Then I'm just gonna...
I feel like anywhere I go it's danger-zone in
here. I'm gonna try to hide behind that tree in
the middle,
but I feel like that's a bad idea. Yeah.
MATT: You're right there.
LAURA: I don't want him to be able to hit me with
arrows if possible.
MATT: Right, no worries. At the end of your turn,
he's going to use two of his legendary actions to
try and cast a different spell, actually.
He begins to, from up there above, lifts his hand
up like this. I need everyone but Grog to make a
dexterity saving throw, including the treants.
MARISHA: Including me inside the treant?
SAM: I guess I will try to counterspell this one
as well.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: Also at level five, I don't know if that
helps.
MATT: All right. So go ahead and roll, plus six.
SAM: All right. Plus six? 16.
MATT: Nope. Sorry. Close, you were one off.
So dexterity saving throws for the treants.
Nope. And nope.
LAURA: 17.
LIAM: 29.
MATT: So Vax succeeds.
LAURA: 17.
MATT: Grog, you don't have to worry about it,
'cause you're out of the radius.
MARISHA: 16.
TALIESIN: 14.
SAM: Oh, am I rolling for--
MATT: Yes, you are.
SAM: What is the save?
MATT: This is a dexterity saving throw.
SAM: Dexterity saving throw. 14.
MATT: All right. Vax, only you succeed. Suddenly
you feel as if there is a sense of weightlessness,
or at least you're being drawn at a very intense
speed upward in the room. Vax, you manage to reach
down and grab one of the roots on the ground and
hold yourself there while the rest of you are
thrown, including the treants, at a similar
velocity as you would plummet off a cliff,
but upward. Up into the ceiling and roof,
slamming into the roots, crack! And then gravity
returns to normal and all of you fall, once again,
slamming back down onto the ground.
MARISHA: Am I immune to that as a fire elemental?
MATT: You still take bludgeoning damage as an
elemental.
MARISHA: Just resistant to it.
SAM: How high's the roof above the ground?
MATT: It's about 50 feet at the top.
LAURA: So 100... no, that's just two times in a
row.
SAM: Two 50 drops.
LAURA: Wow.
MATT: That's a total of 24 points of bludgeoning
damage to all of you except for Vax.
MARISHA: I take half damage.
MATT: You take half that, because--
MARISHA: How much did you say it was? 24?
SAM: 24.
MATT: Not you, Grog, you're unaffected by it.
Yeah. But the treants also take it.
SAM: Oh! Poor guys.
MATT: All righty.
SAM: No problem, no problem.
MATT: End of Vex's turn. Vax, you're up.
You watch as all of your friends and the treants
come crashing down from the ceiling, slamming,
you hear the groans of various people getting up
off of root knots on the ground.
Your feet come back to you, and it's your
go.
LIAM: So the treants are prone, right?
MATT: In fact, everybody here for the most part is
prone, yes.
LIAM: Everybody's prone, and that gives me
advantage on the attack as well, doesn't it?
MATT: Technically, yes.
MARISHA: I'm immune to prone.
LIAM: All right, so I'm just gonna whip down and
stab into the treant that's at my feet now.
MATT: All righty, go for it.
LIAM: Okay, first attack is a 29.
MATT: That definitely hits.
LIAM: Well, actually, yeah, 29. Second attack is a
29.
MATT: Hits.
LIAM: Third attack is a 17.
MATT: Hits. All three hit.
LIAM: Okay, so the first one...
MATT: Percy, you're up next.
LIAM: Which is with the dagger of venom,
I don't know if it'll do anything, but I'm gonna
use the poison in it. Two... eight... 28, and the
poison DC on that is 15.
MATT: No, it does not succeed, it rolled a one.
LIAM: 11 points of poison damage on top of that.
MATT: All righty.
LIAM: Second attack does seven. This is the
flametongue dagger,
I don't know if that's going
to do anything--
MATT: Sorry, how much on the first attack again?
LIAM: And the third attack does--
TRAVIS: Liam, how much was your first attack?
LIAM: I don't remember, now. Uh, I can figure it
out...
MATT: Make sure I got it right.
LIAM: It was roughly, it was 20-something. 25.
MATT: Yeah, we're good, we're good. All right,
third strike?
LIAM: Third strike got eight.
MATT: Eight, got it.
LIAM: Thanks.
MATT: As it's on the ground, sprawled out,
flames still burning off of it, you leap up onto
its thigh and come down to some of the open wound
that Keyleth's fire elemental's been tearing
through, you're just prying into it with your
daggers and pulling the bark back, revealing its
softer, burning underwood, if you will. You do a
sincerely awful amount of damage to it, and it
looks like the creature's already in dire
straits.
SAM: This is one of the treants?
MATT: One of the treants, yes.
SAM: Oh, okay.
MATT: Does that end your turn?
LIAM: I just quickly look into Keyleth's flaming
eyes and say, "Finish it off," and then I'm going
to run double speed along the curve of the wall
underneath flying fuck.
MATT: This way?
LIAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: Other way, I think.
MATT: Oh, this way. The one that's not flaming?
LIAM: Past Keyleth and the one that I just stabbed
the shit out of.
LAURA: Oh, the other way, you were going the right
way.
MATT: This way.
LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: Okay. You're about there with your
movement.
LIAM: I've got double speed.
MATT: All right. Oh yeah, double speed, you'd
actually get closer to there if you wanted.
All right, that ends your turn. Percy, you're up.
Actually, at the end of Percy's turn he's gonna
use his last legendary action to go ahead and make
an attack with Fenthras. As he sees you running
past, Vax, he goes ahead and takes one arrow shot
at you
as you're running super fast across the
floor.
LIAM: Disadvantage.
MATT: No, because, well, no--
LIAM: Turns on--
MATT: -- no, you did, at the beginning of your
turn it did, you're right. So. Good thing, too,
19 and a one. It goes to fire but you're too
quick, and as it releases its spikelike arrow,
you hear it go right past you, catching the edge
of the cloak and actually going through it,
leaving a small hole in the corner, but no impact
to you. All right, so now, Percy, it's your turn.
TALIESIN: We're both prone, does that mean that
we're in combat,
or can I walk away from it and it doesn't--
MATT: You're both prone, you can walk away without
it getting an attack of opportunity, you just
spend half your movement to get up.
TALIESIN: All right, I'm spending half my movement
to get up, and I'm backing up against the wall.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: Backing up against the wall. I'm not
using Bad News, I'm going to use Retort,
I'm going to try and, first thing I'm gonna do is
use a bonus action to heal a little bit. Yeah.
That's nine plus twelve, so that's 21. Figure
that out when it's not my turn. Next thing I'm
gonna do is I'm gonna start shooting to try and
get that bow out of his hands one more time.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: First shot...
MATT: This is with Retort, right?
TALIESIN: Retort, yeah. Same trick, but not nearly
as much damage. That's 16 to hit?
MATT: Hits the nearby wood, splinters off one of
the vines, sending a shower of broken wood chips.
TALIESIN: Firing again.
LIAM: C'mon, dangerous nerd, do it!
LAURA: (laughs) Dangerous nerd.
TALIESIN: That's another 16.
MATT: Can't quite catch a bead on it. Being a
human without dark vision, it's hard to see it in
the low glowing light.
MARISHA: I give off a soft glow.
MATT: But at a distance.
TALIESIN: 18 to hit?
MATT: That misses.
(All groan.)
TALIESIN: God damn it. Okay. That's my bloody
roll.
MARISHA: That's always a bummer, man. That sucks.
MATT: Ending Percy's turn, that brings us to our
next set of lair actions. All right.
TALIESIN: God damn it.
MATT: Suddenly all the vines on the nearby walls
on the inside of the tree whip out and begin
grabbing anyone nearby. Percy, Scanlan, Keyleth,
and Vax, you guys are all of a sudden, the vines
try and wrap around you. They pull you back.
MARISHA: Immune to grapple.
MATT: So yeah.
LIAM: Dexterity save?
MATT: The vines try and wrap around you, Keyleth,
and burn in the process. You are still pulled
right against the wall. I need Vax, Scanlan,
and Percy to make a strength saving throw.
SAM: Strength.
LIAM: Strength.
MATT: Yes.
SAM: Oh, god. Just straight strength?
TALIESIN: 23.
SAM: 15.
LIAM: Burn a Luck. Ah, 20.
MATT: 20, okay. Vax and Percy, you guys manage to
break free of the vines. Scanlan, you are
considered grappled, so your speed is zero.
The vines are actually holding you against the
side. They're not hurting you or anything,
but you cannot actually move from your space
'cause you're being held against the wall of the
tree.
That ends the legendary action. Grog,
you're up.
TRAVIS: Can I run immediately underneath Sondur?
MATT: Sondur, yes you can.
TRAVIS: Are there any vines that are hanging from
him? There are none?
MATT: There are vines hanging from the ceiling,
but he himself just kind of sunk into the tree
and then emerged above, he himself does not have
any wayward vines that are just hanging.
TRAVIS: Right. Are there any vines that look like
they might be thick enough for me to try and climb
up if I wanted to get to his height?
MATT: Probably a couple, yeah.
TRAVIS: Could I grab a few of those vines to try
and climb up to where he's at?
MATT: Make an athletics check. With disadvantage.
And then you have advantage because you're
raging, so just a straight roll on that.
TRAVIS: Athletics. 23.
MATT: 23, all right, let me check and see how far
you can actually climb at that speed.
SAM: Tense fight, guys. Wouldn't wanna be in it
with anyone else.
LIAM: Us against the environment.
SAM: I think that my plan should work.
MATT: I'd say your physical strength and your
ability to just kind of one hand over hand,
not even pull up, especially with your Titan
gauntlets and that type of a roll, you could
probably get right up to him, but that's gonna be
your action to get up there.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: So you'll only have your bonus action left
at that time, but essentially you climb up and get
right up to where he is at the top of the tree.
As he's up there pulling the bow back, getting
ready to, you see another pointed arrow kind of
shift out of his arm, you come right up to his
face and you're right there holding on with the
vines,
with the axe hanging over your shoulder
with the chain.
TRAVIS: With my bonus action, can I let out the
loudest howl I possibly can.
MATT: Yes, you can.
TRAVIS: (howls)
MATT: All righty.
MARISHA: Calling in the cavalry.
LAURA: Yeah, come on! Please, I hope he can get in
here.
MATT: That's your turn?
TRAVIS: That's my turn.
MATT: All right. It is now Sondur's turn.
SAM: Oh boy.
MATT: All righty.
LAURA: He's deaf from that howl, he's definitely
deaf.
MATT: No, not so much. Sondur takes Fenthras and
actually lets go of it to his side, and these
vines grab it and hold it in place just wherever
he lets it go. As he pulls back, his fingers curl
up into these giant, extremely hard petrified
root-like clusters, and he just starts starts
whaling on you as you're holding onto that vine.
Three strikes against you.
The first one is gonna
be a 25.
TRAVIS: Hits.
MATT: Second one is a 23.
TRAVIS: Also hits.
MATT: Third one is a 15.
TRAVIS: Misses.
MATT: It hits you, but just not enough to do any
damage. So, looking at this, that brings it to,
oh no, that's two. 14 points of bludgeoning
damage on the first one, halved.
And the second one--
LAURA: Oh, it's just the fucking coolest.
MATT: 22 points of bludgeoning damage, reduced to
11. I need you to go ahead and make a strength
saving throw to maintain your hold on that vine.
As he just bats you around.
TRAVIS: That's a 21.
MATT: 21. It punches you twice, and your grip
causes you to slide a foot, but you catch yourself
and you're still maintaining yourself. The vine is
now swinging from the impact, and you're in the
process of this weird momentum where you're
passing by a little out of control with your
movement up in the air of the inside of this
tree.
TRAVIS: Awesome.
MATT: So that's gonna end its action. You now
watch as Sondur reaches up and grabs the bow again
and shifts into the tree to get away from you.
You do get an attack of opportunity, though.
As you come around, watching him sink in with
your one hand on the axe.
TRAVIS: Oh, that was so close to being a crit.
That is a 33.
MATT: (laughs)
LAURA: 19 isn't a crit for him, right?
TRAVIS: No.
MATT: No. So go ahead, I will say the damage is
gonna be a 1d10 rather than a 1d12, just for the
sake of, you're swinging with one hand.
TRAVIS: That's... wait, no, that's 22 plus one
point of necrotic damage, so 23.
MATT: All right, so 23 points of slashing damage
as you come around, as the vine is arcing around,
whack! You cleave through, catch part of the side
of the shoulder and the jaw. Part of this hard
bony root exterior actually gets carved off and
you see more black ooze spill out from underneath
as it shrieks, pulling back into the tree.
You watch him vanish, you're still left there.
TRAVIS: Killed him.
LAURA: Good job, Grog.
LIAM: Smacked him into the wall.
TRAVIS: Not so tough, really.
LIAM: Go hide like a potato in the earth.
Oh jeez.
MATT: As high up as Sondur can get, right at the
edge, actually emerging out of the ceiling portion
of the top of it, ten feet higher than he was
before, he comes out with Fenthras.
LAURA: Ten feet higher than he was before?
MATT: Before, he was out of the wall, before the
ceiling even came up into a cone. He's now coming
out of the ceiling in another part.
LAURA: Jeez.
MATT: Now hanging out halfway and ready to go
ahead and let loose with a bow, that's gonna end
his turn, however.
LIAM: How high off the ground is that apex that
he's hanging out of?
MATT: Right now he's 40 feet up.
LIAM: 40 feet, all right.
MATT: Yep. That ends his turn, it is now the
treants' go. They both get up, using half their
movement. (laughs) Let's see. That one currently
is just being harried with the flames on the
inside, it takes, does it take any damage on its
turn?
MARISHA: It does. Unless he douses himself,
he takes another 1d10.
MATT: Go ahead and do 1d10 damage to him.
MARISHA: Six.
TALIESIN: Doubled.
LAURA: Doubled, yeah.
MATT: As it begins to take the damage, it begins
to pat out the flames, but as it does, the fire
just roars into this inferno, and you hear it give
out this creaking, painful (pained groan) as it
tumbles forward in a timber fashion, the flames
actually burning the life essence out of the
treant. It falls to the ground, dead, smoldering.
SAM: Hey, damn!
TRAVIS: Yes.
MATT: You pop out of his form as the living entity
is no longer living and you are but an elemental
now. I'm gonna leave him there just for reference,
because it is a big thing to get through.
But you are now pushed off to the side.
That treant is gone. The other one gets up and
steps over to Percy.
TALIESIN: I made a friend.
MATT: You did. As you just manage to avoid that,
the treant comes up
and goes into a double-slam against you.
LAURA: Fuck.
MATT: That is gonna be 19.
TALIESIN: That hits.
MATT: And 21.
TALIESIN: That also hits.
MATT: All righty. You take--
TALIESIN: I'm fine.
MATT: 13 points of bludgeoning damage. 20 points
of bludgeoning damage on the second hit.
LAURA: (gasps)
TALIESIN: That's mean.
MATT: It's now pushing you up against the side of
the tree. You can feel the roots hitting the back
of your head, and as you ricochet off the impact,
you come into another fist right to the face.
You feel the nose break under the impact and
possibly a tooth get loose as you spit blood out
the side. It was a rough hit on you.
TALIESIN: Yeah, that was rough.
MATT: All right. That ends the treants' turn.
Scanlan and Keyleth, you're up.
MARISHA: You're still--
MATT: You're grappled, and currently prone.
SAM: Okay.
MARISHA: Where is he? Where are you, Scanlan?
SAM: I'm against the close side of the wall.
MATT: You're over there.
But because your movement is zero and you're
grappled, you cannot get up. So right now you are
prone and stuck to a wall.
SAM: Can I pull out a wand, or not even?
MATT: You can pull out a wand, you're just at
disadvantage for all attacks right now.
SAM: All attacks. Even spell attacks?
MATT: You have disadvantage on attack rolls,
and any attack rolls against you have advantage,
yeah. If they're within five feet of you.
Otherwise they have disadvantage.
MARISHA: I might be able to try and do something,
if I can go first.
SAM: That's attack rolls, Fireballs just happen.
MATT: Correct.
MARISHA: Maybe I can burn you away.
SAM: I'll do Fireball on the treant. I'll aim it
far away enough so that it won't hit us.
Is that a thing? Is that possible?
MATT: It is, it's hard because you're on the
ground and he's right there.
SAM: Can I go up?
LAURA: Can you hit Sondur?
SAM: Well, yeah, but I don't know how--
MATT: It's your call. It's a tough circumstance
here, because to hit the treant from your
perspective, you'd have to hit behind it,
but you have no view behind it
because you're on the ground.
SAM: Got it. Got it. All right.
MATT: I mean, if you want to try that, I'll give
you a roll, and based on how good you roll it may
or may not hit an ally.
SAM: Then I will not risk it and I will just
Fireball good old Sondur, I guess.
MATT: All righty. How many more--
SAM: I'll use three more charges. I have seven
total.
MATT: Okay. Seven total left? Or total?
SAM: Total. So I've used three.
MATT: Well no, you used five last time.
SAM: I thought the first one is just three balls?
No? I don't know how this shit works.
MATT: What does it say on the actual item?
SAM: I don't have it anymore. I lost it months and
months ago.
(All laugh.)
MATT: It's a good thing it's in the Dungeon
Master's Guide. God damn it, Sam. Let me know
these things, I can get you the item printout.
LIAM: King of improv. Right here.
MATT: Okay. Wand of Fireballs, has seven charges.
You can use an action to expend one or more
charges to cast the Fireball spell. For one
charge, it's the level three, and for each
additional charge it's more than that. So.
SAM: So I used three charges.
MATT: So you used three charges, you have four
charges left, yes.
SAM: Okay, so I'm gonna use three on him.
MATT: Oh, three more? All right. Go for it.
That'll be another 10d6.
TALIESIN: I don't understand how magic works.
LAURA: I don't know, I don't understand that at
all.
MATT: We'll see if he makes his saving throw.
It does not make the saving throw, it's gonna use
its legendary resistance to automatically make
it.
LAURA: Aw.
MARISHA: Fucking dick.
LAURA: Does that half it again?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: I have a question.
MATT: What's your question, Grog?
TRAVIS: I forgot about Retaliation. That's a new
feat I have.
MATT: Yeah, where when it hits you you can use
your reaction, but you used your reaction to get
an attack of opportunity, so you still hit him.
TRAVIS: Oh, that's true.
MATT: But essentially, they don't have to do that
now. As long as they hit you, you can use your
reaction to just hit them back.
TRAVIS: Hit them back.
MATT: So yeah, as long as you stay within melee--
TRAVIS: As long as I'm within five feet.
That count on his two hits against me?
MATT: I mean, you can only do it once, because you
only get one reaction.
TRAVIS: One time. Okay.
MATT: And you technically already hit him with
that.
TRAVIS: That's true.
MATT: Same thing, so you used your attack of
opportunity,
so you can do that whenever anybody hits you.
LAURA: See, you're fine.
MATT: You're good, but good to remember.
SAM: Laura, are you like...
LAURA: About to die? Yeah.
TRAVIS: I haven't used it before.
SAM: All right, that was 29. So 14.
MATT: 29. Halve that, 14 points of fire damage.
LAURA: Like one more hit and I'm unconscious.
MATT: As another Fireball bursts into the air,
lighting up the room even brighter for an
instant. You can see now as the smoke clears,
the front of Sondur's form is black and beginning
to char with each blast of flame. A lot of the oil
has dried off and is now coming off in clumps.
LAURA: That's good.
MATT: Almost like dried mud. All right.
SAM: I will also heal Vex. She's close enough,
right? Yeah? Yeah? Ish?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
SAM: With an inspirational quote.
LAURA: (laughing) No.
SAM: Something Percival once said a long,
long time ago.
TALIESIN: Oh no. Oh no.
LAURA: I'm ready.
SAM: Life needs things to live. That's it.
That's the whole quote.
(All laugh.)
SAM: Earlier tonight. Percival von Fredrickstein
von Rollo de Frankenstein de Roll.
Credit where credit is due.
LIAM: Put it on a kitten poster.
SAM: Oh, and I'll do it at level three, so that's,
sorry, not inspiration, healing, healing, healing.
LAURA: Oh, okay.
MATT: That's right, this is a healing spell,
all right.
SAM: So that's 3d4 plus six.
MARISHA: Oh man.
SAM: 12.
LAURA: Okay, thank you!
TALIESIN: 12 helps.
MATT: All right, Keyleth.
MARISHA: Okay. I am going to march over to that,
oh man, to that guy.
TALIESIN: Number two?
MARISHA: Number two. Treant number two.
MATT: All right.
MARISHA: I want to see if I can Tree Stride
through him--
MATT: Did you take damage from the fall earlier?
MARISHA: I did.
MATT: Make a concentration check.
SAM: (sings a note)
MARISHA: Even though I have resistance on
bludgeoning damage and all that shit?
MATT: Yeah. So just add your constitution
modifier.
MARISHA: Oh, my constitution modifier? As a--
MATT: As a fire elemental.
MARISHA: Just my modifier?
MATT: Yes.
MARISHA: Eight.
MATT: Yeah, so Tree Stride has faded. Sorry.
MARISHA: Fuck!
MATT: Concentration spells when you take damage,
man.
MARISHA: Well, I still whelm him. That guy in
front of me. I still can move into his space.
MATT: Into his space. Go ahead and make your
attacks.
MARISHA: That's my fucking opal dice again.
Asshole. Oh look, and that was 18.
SAM: You gotta roll it angry.
LAURA: Oh, maybe that's the key.
TALIESIN: Maybe you have to roll it angry.
TRAVIS: You're being so fucking nice.
TALIESIN: Angry die.
LIAM: But she's always angry.
LAURA: Just like "arrgh" every time you roll it.
MATT: Keyleth must embrace her anger to actually
make the dice work for her. I like that.
MARISHA: Two slam attacks.
LAURA: See, that's Taliesin's secret, he's always
angry.
TALIESIN: Always angry.
MATT: Are you rolling with advantage?
MARISHA: Do I roll with advantage?
MATT: No.
MARISHA: No.
MATT: Sorry, I saw you roll two dice, so I...
those are both attacks at once? Got you.
MARISHA: No, I'm rolling my three dice.
SAM: Two slam attacks, right?
MATT: You have two slam attacks. Did you roll to
hit on those?
MARISHA: Oh, wait, no, I don't think I did.
MATT: That's what I'm asking.
MARISHA: I forgot that part.
MATT: Do that first.
MARISHA: Oh, man. Two 11s. Which, 17 to hit both
times.
SAM: Make a wish.
MATT: Both hit.
MARISHA: Okay, so the first one, um. 15 for the
first one.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: All the big ones, they just--
TRAVIS: Love it.
LAURA: They're pretty but--
MARISHA: And another 15 for the second one.
LAURA: Why would you do that?
MATT: And for the first one, it was...
TALIESIN: That don't suck. And then he's on fire
now, right?
MARISHA: He's on fire. Oh, and he takes another
d10 because I moved into his space.
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: Oh, good good good, that's good.
MATT: And he's on fire.
MARISHA: So another four points from me.
SAM: (softly sings along with the background
music)
MATT: All righty. The flames burn up into his
form, he starts shrieking as the flame starts
curling up its body, it does not like being on
fire. That end your turn?
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: All righty. At the end of your turn,
Sondur is gonna go ahead and--
SAM: I'm just gonna go ahead and borrow this.
Possibly permanently.
TALIESIN: God damn it.
MATT: Is gonna cast another spell.
TRAVIS: Over here, you piece of shit. Nope.
LAURA: Anything?
TRAVIS: I cough weakly.
MATT: The bow's held aloft, he looks down and sees
you on the ground, Vex.
LAURA: Ow.
MATT: And just extends his fingers and says,
"You had your choice."
Make a constitution saving throw.
LAURA: Oh, good. 20.
MATT: 20? Success.
(All cheer.)
MATT: So you take half damage.
SAM: Half damage? Wait, what? No damage!
MARISHA: That sounded like a lot of dice.
LAURA: That's a lot of dice.
LIAM: That's a fucking miracle is what that is.
TALIESIN: That sounds like a handful of hate.
That was like four dice.
TRAVIS: It's okay, they're all d1s.
MATT: 31 halved... you take 16 points of necrotic
damage.
TALIESIN: You're good.
MARISHA: You all right? Still up.
MATT: As the Blight spell takes over--
SAM: Whoa.
MATT: -- you feel the vines wrap around you and
the life force pulled from your form momentarily.
Suddenly they crack and break as you shove them
off, the air pulled from your lungs, and you gasp
for air, holding onto that last little sliver of
life you still have.
MARISHA: Two can play at that game, motherfucker.
TALIESIN: You need healing.
MATT: All righty. Now it's your turn, Vex.
LAURA: Now it's my turn.
MATT: Yes.
LAURA: Okay. I'm gonna take, can I--
MATT: You're still prone on the ground, by the
way.
LAURA: I stand up.
MATT: All right, so that's half your movement.
LAURA: Can I take a greater healing potion?
MATT: You can.
LAURA: As a bonus?
MATT: Yep.
LAURA: How much is that?
MATT: Greater healing would be 4d4 plus four.
LAURA: Okay. 11 plus four is 15. Okay.
SAM: Okay, okay.
TRAVIS: It's that hit back.
LAURA: Okay, that's good, that's good. 37, okay.
Okay. I guess I will,
his Hunter's Mark is still on him, right?
MATT: Actually, you should make a concentration
check because of the Blight damage, which I forgot
to take as far as the fall damage earlier as well,
so make two concentration checks.
LAURA: Cool.
MATT: Yeah, so add your constitution modifier.
TRAVIS: (laughs) Yeah.
LAURA: 19 for the first. And a natural one for the
second.
MATT: Yeah, no, that's faded, sorry.
LAURA: Okay, cool. Okay, so--
MATT: Actually, Percy, I need you to make a
concentration check as well.
I need to get better at that.
LAURA: I guess for my-- Jesus Christ.
MATT: Two, one for each slam.
TALIESIN: It's a constitution?
MATT: Yeah, add your constitution modifier.
TALIESIN: Ten.
MATT: Yeah, so the Hex has also faded, sorry.
TALIESIN: Damn it.
LAURA: Fuck. I guess I'm gonna Hail of Thorns
him.
MATT: Okay, go for it.
TRAVIS: Well, tit-for-tat, give him something
else.
LAURA: Right?
TALIESIN: Just hurt him, just hurt him.
SAM: Yeah, man.
LAURA: Okay, so that's a regular attack.
MATT: What level are you casting it at?
LAURA: Oh! Right, oh, I can cast it at higher.
MATT: Yes you can.
LAURA: I'm gonna cast it at a level four.
Fuck it.
MATT: Go for it! So go ahead and roll the attack.
LAURA: Okay, that is... I roll a d20 and then I
add what? My spell attack bonus?
MATT: No, it's just a regular attack, and if it
hits-- because you cast the spell as a bonus
action onto an arrow, release the arrow,
and if it hits--
LAURA: 27.
MATT: 27 hits. So you do damage for the arrow,
plus an additional 4d10 damage, yeah.
LAURA: 4d10.
LIAM: Girl!
LAURA: That's good, that's good, that's good.
Oh, that's good, okay. 17 for the actual hit.
MATT: Nice.
LAURA: And then an additional 4d10?
MATT: Yep.
LAURA: Wow. That's awesome. Hopefully these will
be good. 20 additional.
MATT: 20 points of damage to him. Nice. As you
release the arrow, it sticks into his chest.
(chuckles) "You will--" (explosion sound)
It just
bursts in his chest, these thorns go spraying into
him and the nearby area, just like a pipe bomb
went off in his chest, and he's just like
(gasping roar of pain). All right. And do you want
to move or stay where you are?
LAURA: I'm gonna stay where I am.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: But I'm gonna hold onto that tree.
MATT: Okay, you grapple onto that tree. End of
your turn, he's gonna use his last legendary
action to make one attack with Fenthras back at
you out of anger. That is a 25.
LAURA: That hits me.
MATT: All right.
SAM: I'm gonna actually, wait, can I Cutting Words
that?
MATT: Sure. What are you gonna do? What do you
say?
MARISHA: C'mon, c'mon.
SAM: I'm gonna insult him. I'm gonna call him a
(clears throat)
"Oi, you fobbing elf-skinned flapdragon!
"You paunchy ill-breeding lewdster! You
unmuscled reeling ripe mumblenews!"
Shakespeare insult generator.
MATT: That is fantastic.
TRAVIS: That's unbelievable.
MATT: That's really quite good.
LAURA: He's really old, so that really means a lot
to him.
MATT: Unfortunately, they fall on deaf ears,
he's beyond 60 feet from you,
and doesn't hear the insult.
SAM: What? I thought the roof was only like 45
feet up, 50 feet up!
MATT: But you're over there.
SAM: I yelled it really loud.
TALIESIN: Did you use the cone? No, you can't use
the-- oh, you could use the cone.
MATT: Just on the cusp. At an angle, let me see
here, 'cause he's about 55 feet from you and then
is 40 feet up, yeah, at the angle, he's just out
of range.
MARISHA: Aw, Pythagoras's theorem, man, c'mon,
that's right at 60, right?
MATT: Just misses him.
MARISHA: A-squared plus b-squared equals
c-squared? C'mon.
SAM: No problem.
MATT: Yeah, he's just out of the range. You shout
it, it echoes, it was a great insult, but he's too
focused--
LAURA: Fuck.
MATT: -- and looses the arrow. It manages to catch
you for...
TALIESIN: Oh, don't make that face.
MATT: 15 points of piercing damage and one point
of lightning damage.
LAURA: Okay. Okay.
MARISHA: Still up?
LAURA: I'm good.
TALIESIN: Ish.
LAURA: Ish.
TALIESIN: Esque.
MATT: All right. Up at the top of the round.
Vax, you're up.
LIAM: All right, I think from where I'm standing
I'm close enough to see that Keyleth is absolutely
mauling the tree, she's right on top of it,
right?
MATT: That appears to be the case, yes.
LIAM: With double speed I can get there, yeah?
MATT: Yes, you can.
LIAM: All right, so I'm gonna flit across the
floor, come up right behind Keyleth, shoot right
around the side of her and stab up and in,
one-two-three.
MATT: Go for it.
LIAM: First attack is a 28.
MATT: 28 hits.
LIAM: Second attack is a 29.
MATT: Hits.
LIAM: And the third attack is a 26.
MATT: Hits, all three hit.
LIAM: Sneak attack on the first. Two plus six is
eight... 30.
MATT: 30 points.
LIAM: For the first attack, second attack does
seven, and the third attack does ten.
MATT: Ten, all righty.
LIAM: Ten and seven.
MATT: You rush up from the side, seeing the
inferno engulfing the creature as it's shrieking
in pain, you rush up and just start stabbing it
repeatedly, throwing your dagger up into the
various exposed parts of its bark form. You can
see it's actually breaking apart from the inside.
It's still holding itself together, but it's
looking pretty rough.
LIAM: Am I burning at all, as I just came up next
to flamey here?
MATT: What's the radius, Keyleth?
LAURA: On fire damage.
MATT: What's the radius to take damage? When they
come within a certain area of you?
MARISHA: No, it's when I'm--
TALIESIN: Sharing space.
MARISHA: Five feet, maybe? Wait. I think it's when
I'm sharing space.
LIAM: Because that came up in the past, being
around her.
MATT: No, you're right, it doesn't affect,
you're fine, you're fine.
LIAM: Woo!
MATT: You're good. You can feel the heat,
it's emanating from it, definitely. All right.
That end your turn, Vax?
LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: Percy, you're up.
TALIESIN: I just watch this. I put my gun down,
pull out my sword,
and just start hacking at the tree.
MATT: Go for it.
SAM: What happened?
TALIESIN: That's 25.
MATT: 25 hits.
TALIESIN: 23.
MATT: Hits.
TALIESIN: And 27.
MATT: Hits. All three hit.
(A dice clings loudly against a glass.)
TALIESIN: That's a thing that happens now.
Okay, and so that's...
(Travis elbows the set, which makes a loud thump
noise)
TRAVIS: Jesus. Thunder strikes outside the tree.
LIAM: What was that?
LAURA: That was Travis hitting the side of the
room.
TRAVIS: I'm too big for this world.
TALIESIN: 35 points of slashing damage.
MATT: On the first hit? Rolled together?
TALIESIN: All three together.
MATT: I was like, holy shit.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I just went thump-thump-thump.
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: You're a greater barbarian than I am.
MATT: As it's on fire and shrieking, you pull the
sword out and, seeing the wounds that Vax already
left open, you leap up off of one knee, leap up,
spin it around, and jam it into the center where
you see the bark is actually splitting, and with
that, you look down at Keyleth, and together,
she forces outward as you dig down with the
blade. The treant actually splits up the middle
and then just falls to two sides and begins to
burn from the inside.
SAM: It's looking pretty rough.
(All laugh.)
MARISHA: Is he dead? He's dead.
LAURA: That's good, that's good.
MATT: He is dead and on the ground there,
just burning.
SAM: Loot the body. Might get some acorns.
LAURA: So much lumber.
MARISHA: Let's make s'mores after this!
MATT: Percy, do you want to move or do you stay
where you are?
TALIESIN: I'm going to move, I'm going to charge
north, just to split the group up a bit.
MATT: Over here?
TALIESIN: Yeah, actually if I can hug the edge a
little closer--
MATT: Like there, or around this way, you mean?
TALIESIN: Around that way, and then ten feet away
from the wall.
MATT: Ten feet away.
TALIESIN: And then, bonus action to put my mask on
in case anything more gassy happens.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: And then I've got a grit left,
so fuck it, I'm gonna-- oh no, because I can't
switch weapons fast enough. Never mind. I'm gonna
call it.
LIAM: I have a question, and I could be wrong--
MATT: Yes?
LIAM: I thought Percy gave me that mask.
TALIESIN: I took it back from you last game.
MATT: He did.
LIAM: Oh right, I forgot.
TALIESIN: 'Cause you weren't there.
MATT: You weren't there and he was walking through
the swamp, yeah.
LIAM: That is true.
TALIESIN: Yeah, you can have it back if you want,
I just took it for the swamp.
LIAM: Nah, it looks good on you.
MATT: It's now count 20.
LAURA: Any sign of umber-werewolfy--
TRAVIS: Ukurat.
LAURA: Ukurat?
MATT: So. First you watch as a low mist begins to
slowly filter into the room. Everyone in this
radius here, it's gonna be Keyleth, Vax, Percy,
and Vex,
I need you all to make a wisdom saving throw.
SAM: Oh.
MARISHA: Wisdom.
MATT: Yes, as the fog fills the--
LAURA: Natural 20!
TALIESIN: 19.
SAM: Wow.
LIAM: Best wisdom roll of my life.
SAM: What'd you get, Liam?
LIAM: 21, which was huge for me.
MATT: 21.
LAURA: Natural 20.
MARISHA: 18 plus 11, so 29.
TALIESIN: 23.
MATT: Jesus Christ.
TRAVIS: It's just on that smog thing.
MATT: You feel like the fog as it fills your
senses begins to cloud your mind and your vision
begins to blur, but then you shake it from your
mind and focus in and it has no effect on you.
LAURA: Yes!
MATT: Lot of fucking help that did. At which
point, the area that it closed before, where you
guys entered, you hear this loud creaking sound
and the breaking of wood and bark.
TALIESIN: Yeah!
MATT: Suddenly you watch as it's forced open as
these two feral claws (growls).
(All cheer.)
MATT: And Ukurat darts inside from the entrance.
Looks around, looks up. "Where's my quarry?"
LAURA: Up, up, up!
MATT: Looks up and sees Sondur. "So be it."
And begins jumping onto the wall and climbing
and running up the side of the actual--
TALIESIN: Parkour.
MATT: Parkour, indeed.
SAM: You could cut me out first! Okay, just go,
it's okay.
MATT: Gets up and runs, and he only manages to get
just up to
where we'll say where Sondur is there
in his turn.
LAURA: Look at how big they both are.
MATT: But he's now right up in the face of Sondur.
Sondur's like, (grunts).
SAM: Sic 'em.
MATT: All right, that ends his turn, 20, Grog,
you're up.
TRAVIS: I've been so taken out of this fight,
it's driving me crazy. I'm hanging from vines,
I see Wolfman come up, I'm not gonna be left out
of this.
Can I try and Tarzan my way over into the
fray?
All: Yes!
MATT: Yes. This will be the majority of your
movement and your action to do so.
TRAVIS: Just get me there, baby.
MATT: All right. So you, go ahead and make an
athletics check.
TRAVIS: Okay. With advantage.
MATT: With advantage. At disadvantage because of
your skill check, so just regular attack.
LAURA: No.
MATT: What'd you roll?
TRAVIS: A one.
TALIESIN: Watch out for that tree.
MATT: Getting your momentum, you pull back and
your feet catch the edge, and you push off,
and you swing out, and as you reach for the next
vine (snapping sound).
MARISHA: Oh my god.
LAURA: Ohh. Boo.
MATT: You plummet to the ground. That puts you,
you take
eight points of bludgeoning damage and fall prone.
TRAVIS: Okay. And prone. That's probably more
insulting.
LIAM: Are you halfway done yet, Groggy?
TRAVIS: Because it fails, does that still take up
all my action? All my whole thing?
MATT: I mean, you still have your bonus action.
TRAVIS: To get up?
MATT: No, half your movement, but yeah, you won't
be able to this turn, so.
TRAVIS: I'll cry a little.
LAURA: Do you have any other bonus, anything you
can do for a bonus action?
TRAVIS: Do I keep my rage, because I fell and took
damage?
MATT: Uh. Let me double-check the specifics for
the rage here, if it's, just to make sure.
TRAVIS: I think it has to be an attack.
MARISHA: I mean, he's gotta be pretty angry.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I'd be angry.
MARISHA: I'd be angry.
LAURA: Yeah, I'd think that would piss him the
fuck off.
MATT: No, you took damage, so it maintains.
(All cheer.)
MATT: You're really angry now, you're like "Fuck
this!"
TRAVIS: I'm good.
MATT: All right. So. That ends Grog's turn.
It is now Sondur's turn. Sondur, who is looking
at this sudden large werewolf entity that shows up
out of nowhere knows he has to get away from this,
and is gonna go ahead and attempt to begin by
vine-walking into the, well he heals a little bit
first, sorry. And then he's gonna go ahead and
vine-walk into the wall. Ukurat does get an attack
of opportunity on him. That does hit, a 27.
So he takes 15 points of slashing damage.
And vanishes back into the wall and emerges on
this side here.
MARISHA: Exactly where Grog was? That's cool.
MATT: Over here.
LAURA: So close to where Grog was. Damn it.
MATT: From there, he's gonna go ahead and make
three attacks with Fenthras.
First one's gonna be at you, Vex.
SAM: My God, better miss.
MATT: That is a 20.
LAURA: 20 is my armor class.
MATT: Aw. You suffer 15 points of piercing damage
and
four points of thunder damage, or, uh,
lightning damage.
LAURA: 19?
MATT: 19.
LAURA: Cool.
SAM: You're still alive!
LAURA: I'm still alive.
SAM: Wow. That's impressive.
MATT: Shhnk. The first arrow hits you and you take
the damage and lean against the tree, and you're
still standing. He goes, (angry roar), pulls back
and takes another shot.
TALIESIN: God damn it.
LAURA: Can I shout out, "I was wrong! Uh...
you're so dreamy!"
MATT: Same exact roll, 20, hits you again.
SAM: Damn it.
MATT: Natural nine on that one. This one is going
to be... that is eight plus three, eight points of
piercing damage plus three points of lightning,
so.
MARISHA: She's down.
MATT: With that, Vex falls unconscious onto the
ground. With his third and final shot of the
round, he's gonna look down at, I'm gonna say at
Percy, who's right below. Take a shot at Percy.
Natural 20.
MARISHA: What? What?
TRAVIS: Wow.
MATT: It works against you, sometimes.
TALIESIN: Bastard.
MARISHA: Fucker's having a good round.
MATT: 23 points of piercing damage and four points
of lightning.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna do a missile snare.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Yes!
TALIESIN: 23 points of piercing damage?
MATT: Correct.
TALIESIN: That's gonna be 13 points of piercing
damage.
MATT: Okay, plus four lightning, so 17.
TALIESIN: And can I use that four, I'm gonna take
that four lightning, can that hit the glove?
MATT: We can say you bring up the glove and it
does--
TALIESIN: I mean, like, hitting, so--
MATT: Yeah, it takes the damage, but you kind of
bring it up instinctually and it does seem to rev
some charge to it.
TALIESIN: All right, so that's rolling now,
that's in play.
MATT: There you go.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
MATT: All right. That ends his turn. The treants
are gone. Let's see. That's gonna bring us to
Scanlan and Keyleth.
SAM: You wanna do--
MARISHA: I don't know if I can be grappled.
We can Dimension Door, though, I can try and take
you--
SAM: Nah, I can't do that to you.
MARISHA: I can try coming to get you undone.
SAM: I can't Dimension Door you.
MARISHA: No, I mean, I mean burn you from the
vines.
SAM: Oh.
MARISHA: Like get you ungrappled. I don't know if,
so, question.
Could Bigby's Hand toss a fire
elemental's ass?
MATT: Yeah, I mean, you have some sort of
physicality to you,
it's just somewhat fluid in
its structure.
MARISHA: So it's like a magical hand meets magical
fire elemental could kinda work?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Like a Molotov cocktail.
MARISHA: All right. Here's what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna go over to Scanlan and I'm gonna burn
the vines around him that are holding him in.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: Is that your action, though?
MATT: That would be your action, yeah.
MARISHA: That's my action?
SAM: Don't do that, then. You need to, no,
you need to attack--
LAURA: Yeah, don't use your action to--
SAM: Fuck that. I'm fine.
MATT: So as you run up to Scanlan, he's telling
you this. What are you doing?
SAM: Leave me, I'm fine, this is cozy.
MARISHA: I go, "Okay." And I hold my action until
I wait for Scanlan. I wait for Scanlan.
MATT: Okay, so you move over there and you hold
your action waiting for Scanlan to...
MARISHA: To--
SAM: To throw you.
MARISHA: To throw me.
MATT: Okay. All right. Scanlan.
SAM: I will heal Vex with my bonus action first,
right, she's still within range, yes?
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: (singing) I'm... I don't know.
I'm giving you everything,
all that health will bring, this is true.
TRAVIS: Fucking Spice Girls.
LAURA: Is that Spice Girls?
SAM: (singing) And all I want from you is a
promise you will kiss me forever.
MARISHA: It was girl power that healed you.
LAURA: Girl power healed me. I feel it.
MARISHA: I'm feeling it, yeah. Spice magic.
SAM: (singing) I'm - I'm! - giving you
everything, all that health I bring, yeah--
All right, so that's at level one.
MATT: So 1d4 plus six.
SAM: Eight.
LAURA: Awesome.
MATT: So you heal eight. You come to consciousness
again on the ground, face-down, you can see the
sludge sort of filling in your nostrils--
LAURA: (gasps) Spice Girls?
MARISHA: This is my jam.
SAM: And then I will cast Bigby's Hand.
MATT: All righty. Next to Keyleth.
SAM: Next to Keyleth, and cup her gently.
MARISHA: I turn into a fireball myself.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: And just sort of cup and fling.
TRAVIS: Cup that ball.
MARISHA: Very gently.
TALIESIN: As you've cupped so many before.
SAM: Yes.
MATT: Okay. Roll a d20 plus eight.
SAM: What is that for?
MATT: That is the strength of Bigby's Hand
throwing the elemental.
TALIESIN: (singing) I believe in you, you can do
the thing.
SAM: 24.
MATT: 24. You lob the elemental in a wide arc.
It makes it most of the way, and then falls past
and lands on the ground there. You are by him.
Not quite a hit on that one, unfortunately.
MARISHA: God damn it!
MATT: But you do take five points of bludgeoning
damage from the fall.
LAURA: Ooh, nice.
MATT: A 25 or higher would have got to him.
He's a long ways away!
MARISHA: Five points halved, or was that--
MATT: That's halved.
SAM: Hey, you've still got your attack.
MARISHA: Did I?
TRAVIS: Yeah, you've been thrown.
MATT: You held your action, so you can still use
your action to do something if you can.
TRAVIS: Can you?
MARISHA: Can I--
SAM: Just throw a fireball?
MARISHA: I can't do that.
SAM: Aren't you Johnny Storm?
MARISHA: I gotta be there.
MATT: Yeah, it's a melee thing.
MARISHA: Do I still have any movement?
MATT: No, just your action. To get through,
I'd say... what's your speed as an elemental?
MARISHA: 50.
MATT: 50? It took you 25 to get there, you still
have 25 feet, I would say.
MARISHA: Can I start climbing 25 feet up the
wall?
MATT: Make an athletics check.
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: Using the strength of the fire elemental.
Add your strength modifier.
MARISHA: Not good.
MATT: What'd you roll?
MARISHA: Five.
MATT: Five? You start climbing up, you get maybe
five feet up the wall, but already the impact of
the fall and most of your round exhausted you for
this one pass.
MARISHA: Okay, well then I'm gonna take the rest
of my action, I'm just going to angrily slam into
the tree, and see if I can catch the tree up under
him on fire.
MATT: Okay, cool. Ending your turn, Keyleth.
Vex, you're up.
LAURA: I'm up?
MATT: Yeah, you're conscious, you're on the
ground.
SAM: Run away.
LAURA: Uh, oh right, you're on the ground.
Can I, ah, fuck. Okay.
MATT: Actually, hold on. Sorry, I'm gonna be a
dick here.
TALIESIN: Really?
MATT: He's getting his legendary actions back at
the end of Keyleth's turn, watching Scanlan heal
you, he's gonna use another one of his legendary
actions to take an attack on you as you come to
consciousness on the ground.
LAURA: You're an asshole, Sondur.
MATT: He does attack at disadvantage, though,
because you are prone. That puts him at a 16.
LAURA: Yay!
(Loud computer noise in the background.)
MATT: He fires an arrow, but it hits the ground
inches from your face. You see the spike impact
and then turn to dust.
LAURA: Youuu.
MATT: All right, so take your turn.
LAURA: Fuck. I'm gonna... it's useless, I can't do
anything.
SAM: Heal yourself.
LAURA: I know, but my heal is an action,
and then I can't attack.
SAM: Do you have any more potions?
LAURA: Um. I've got, oh, I've got a superior
healing potion,
that's better than a greater, right?
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: Okay. I'll use that.
SAM: Is that like a venti?
MATT: Yeah, that is 8d4 plus eight.
SAM: Whoa!
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: That is one of the pricy healing potions.
LAURA: Oh, well, okay.
TALIESIN: Burn it!
LAURA: Ten...
MARISHA: That would've been so cool had it
worked.
TALIESIN: I know. Had it worked.
LAURA: 20 plus eight... 28.
MATT: 28 you heal, yeah.
SAM: That's the last time I listen to you.
TALIESIN: It was a good plan.
LAURA: Okay, so I'm back at 36. Okay. I'm gonna
run and duck behind Grog.
MATT: Well, you get up, which is half your
movement, so you have five, 15 more feet,
so you can move three squares.
LAURA: Can I get to Grog?
MATT: No. You can get there, is the closest you
can get.
LAURA: All right, I'll go to there and then I
will, I'm gonna Hail of Thorns him again.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Oh wait, is that--
MATT: No, your Hail of Thorns is a bonus action,
and you already used your heal spell, so no.
LAURA: A bonus action, okay. Then I'm gonna,
so I've got two attacks on him.
MATT: Yeah, you do.
LAURA: I'm gonna hit him with two attacks.
MATT: Go for it, roll for the attacks.
LAURA: I get another flaming bowstring, I've got
one more flaming bowstring.
MATT: Vax, you're up next, by the way. Go for it.
SAM: Someday Travis will attack again.
MATT: The first one is the flaming bowstring.
TRAVIS: Will he?
SAM: It's been like eight weeks.
MATT: 17. The flaming shot unfortunately goes
wide,
slams into the wall next to him and the
flame curls up.
LAURA: Okay, so 23 on the second hit.
MATT: Second hit does hit, so roll damage.
LAURA: 15.
MATT: 15 points of damage? All righty.
LAURA: And then I'm gonna duck behind the tree as
much as I can.
MATT: Well, that was your full movement was to get
there, so.
LAURA: Can I not use my full movement to get--
MATT: To get behind the tree? Hmm, you wouldn't
really have much of a shot at him. I guess he--
LAURA: Could I have shot him before I moved?
MATT: You would've been there, suuuure. I normally
don't let that retroactively happen.
LAURA: Okay okay okay.
MATT: I'm gonna say you're halfway through.
You're sort of there.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: All right. So. That brings us to Vax.
You're up.
LIAM: Vex just healed herself, right?
MATT: She did, yes.
LIAM: All right. All right. And is he within 60
feet of me?
MATT: Actually, uh, he is, but at the end of Vex's
turn he's going to take a second shot.
LAURA: What? What? Why?
MATT: No, he's gonna use his other two legendary
actions to cast another spell.
LAURA: He just has so much.
TALIESIN: Asshole!
MATT: Angry that she gets up and runs off to the
side, he says,
"You stay DOWN."
I need you to make another constitution saving throw.
LAURA: Jeez Louise, come on, man! Saving throw?
MATT: Yes.
LAURA: 19.
MATT: 19? What's your constitution modifier?
LAURA: Zero, but I have a +2 on all saving throws
with my ring.
MATT: That's true. Nice. All righty. That is...
TALIESIN: God damn it.
TRAVIS: Yeah, when it's like, when he's playing
fucking Applejacks back there.
MARISHA: I know.
LAURA: Is this another Blight, did he cast Blight
again? Motherfuck.
MATT: 41 points of necrotic damage, halved to 20,
you take 20.
LAURA: Oh, god.
SAM: You out again?
MARISHA: You're down again, aren't you?
LAURA: No, it was halved to 20, so I'm 16.
SAM: Hey!
MATT: But a second Blight is used.
MARISHA: Blight's nasty.
TALIESIN: Blight's nasty.
MATT: All right. Vax, now it's your turn.
LIAM: He's within 60 feet of me?
MATT: He would be, yes.
LIAM: All right. And is there anyone around me? I
just can't see too well from here.
MATT: There's people around you, but there's
nobody next to him.
LIAM: Next to him, no, I know. Fuck it. I'm gonna
burn a bonus action and shoot out the wings and
I'm gonna fly into his face and stab into each
side of his neck.
TALIESIN: Fuck yeah!
MATT: All righty. All of a sudden, the giant raven
wings streak out from each side of you and the air
in the entirety of the room begins to swirl around
you, your hair gets tossed, as the giant wings
begin to push him into the air. The raven-like
dagger-wielding champion of the Raven Queen leaps
up and finds himself face-to-face with Sondur,
blades out. Go ahead and make your attacks.
MARISHA: The breeze from his wings kinda stokes my
fire elemental form a little bit
and I'm kind of into it.
MATT: There you go. Yeah you are! Vax, go for it.
LIAM: 28 on the first.
MATT: Hits.
LIAM: 29 on the second.
LIAM: As I stab into both sides of his neck,
I say,
If you want to get to my sister you gotta
get through me.
Stab-stab. First one is ten,
second one is eight.
MATT: All righty. As you jam both blades into the
side, the flames kind of curling up from the hit
of one, the poison dagger jammed into the other,
the head descends and the mouth opens and from
the inside you can see the semblance of the
human-like face you saw before come peek through,
leaning out, almost like the queen alien's
secondary mouth. It kind of leans into your face,
and the grin curls up in this evil smile.
"I'll take both of you at this rate. There's only
so many betrayals one can survive."
It clinks back into the head, the jaw closes.
That finishes your turn, Vax.
LIAM: Yep.
MATT: Percy, you're up. At the end of Vax's
turn...
no, he can't, he already used his spell,
you're right.
TALIESIN: All right. Okay.
MARISHA: This guy had a rough breakup or
something, man.
TALIESIN: No breakup is that rough. I'm going to,
I'm switching back to Bad News, and I'm going to
reload and I'm going to try and, got that last
grit,
I'm gonna just try and get him to drop the bow.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: Come on, Percy.
TALIESIN: Part one. That'll do. 24.
MATT: 24 hits.
TALIESIN: He has to make a strength saving throw.
MATT: Okay, that is a two, he's gonna use a
legendary resistance,
the second one, to make the save.
TALIESIN: Made the save using a legendary
resistance.
MATT: Yes.
TALIESIN: Okay, that's fine, don't care.
MARISHA: (laughing) Don't care.
TALIESIN: That'll do. That's 20 points of damage.
MATT: All right.
SAM: He has to make a strength check?
TALIESIN: He has to make a, it's strength saving
throw.
SAM: Saving.
TALIESIN: Yeah, he makes it.
SAM: Because I had a Cutting Words a while back.
MATT: Right, but it means he has disadvantage,
but even if he fails, which he would've in that
case, he still gets to make it automatically as
part of the legendary resistance.
SAM: So that's negated my Cutting Words as well.
MATT: For a legendary resistance, it does.
Which is why if you can burn through those early,
then they're a little more vulnerable.
TALIESIN: And just because nothing else seems to
be happening, I'm just gonna burn my Action Surge
and just keep plowing into him for two more
shots.
MATT: All right. How much damage did the first one
do?
TALIESIN: That did 20 points of damage.
MATT: Nice! (gunshot sound)
TALIESIN: Taking another shot, that's 29.
MATT: Hits.
TALIESIN: That's 28 points of damage.
MATT: Three hits. Go ahead and roll the other two
damage, now.
TALIESIN: Hm?
MATT: So you hit with all three, so.
TALIESIN: No, I've been doing damage.
MATT: Oh, those were the damage.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: Oh, I'm sorry.
TALIESIN: Sorry. That's 20 points of damage and 28
points of damage. 22... wait.
20 points of damage on the first attack.
MATT: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Attack I just did was 28 points of
damage.
MATT: 28, sorry, all right, and then the third
one.
TALIESIN: And then the third one.
MATT: Roll to hit.
TALIESIN: That hits, that's a 31.
MATT: All righty.
MARISHA: Do you crit on a 19?
TALIESIN: I do not crit on a 19.
MARISHA: Fuck. That's a good roll, though,
that's a good roll.
TALIESIN: 18 points of damage.
MATT: Nice. So (three gunshots) you can see now
he's starting to sag as he hangs outside of the
wall with the daggers still held in him by Vax,
both impacts, each blast hitting the side of his
torso, you can see now the wooden-armored exterior
is shattered and there's just this writhing mass
of dark veiny vines holding his torso together.
He's looking pretty rough.
TALIESIN: Lay into him! And I'm gonna run and
try and get some cover on the ent.
In the dead-ent. Dead-ent dead-ent.
SAM: (to the tune of the Pink Panther theme)
Dead-ent dead-ent--
SAM, TALIESIN, and MARISHA: Dead-ent dead-ent
dead-ent dead-ent--
MATT: Grog, you're up.
LIAM: (slightly delayed) Dead-ent.
TRAVIS: All right, can I stand up?
MATT: Yes.
TRAVIS: And I casually walk over so that I'm
standing between Vex and Sondur, right in front of
Vex, like a human shield.
MATT: Right there? Yes.
TRAVIS: And I look up and I'm like, "Jesus,
this is fucking stupid. I've broken some hearts
in my time, but you, stupid Romeo, are taking it
way too far. Guess what? NOBODY CARES." And I take
the javelin of lightning and I throw it at him.
(All cheer.)
MATT: Slick. So let's go ahead and roll for that.
SAM: Javelin of lightning.
TALIESIN: Very very fair.
MATT: Let me see what you have to do for that.
Do you have the item rules there?
TRAVIS: I do have it here.
MATT: What does it say?
TRAVIS: If it hits, they have to make a DC 17
dexterity saving throw. If it hits, it's a 4d6
lightning. Half if they make it.
MATT: Right. So go ahead and roll to hit,
what was the hit?
TALIESIN: And he burned a legendary save.
TRAVIS: It was 24.
SAM: He burned two of them.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: It hits, go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: 4d6.
SAM: He didn't use any sort of legendary thing,
Matt?
MATT: Well, when you hurl it, you don't roll to
hit with it. Five feet wide, it extends out from
you to the target within 120 feet.
Each creature in the line, excluding you and
the target, must make a DC... no, you're right,
I read too far ahead. Yeah, you're good,
so 4d6 lightning damage.
TRAVIS: Nice. Six, eight, seven... 12.
MATT: 12 points of lightning damage?
TRAVIS: 12 points of lightning damage.
MATT: How do you want to do this?
(All scream and cheer.)
LAURA: Fuck, yeah!
MARISHA: Yeah, Grog!
SAM: You got the kill?
MARISHA: Yes!
SAM: You didn't do anything!
TALIESIN: Walking around like an idiot the entire
game.
TRAVIS: Chasing him around the room.
SAM: You fell five times!
MARISHA: You basically killed him with bro-shame.
LIAM: And that cheeky line about romance.
TRAVIS: I know, fuck! I throw it and hopefully get
it to go right in his mouth as he's trying to have
a comeback. And I'll just look bewildered that it
worked.
MATT: As you just shove it upward--
LIAM: Can he use his bonus action to just shove
his sunglasses up at the end?
MATT: As you chuck the javelin, you see it burst
forth with lightning-based propulsion magic.
It sinks into the center of the jaw, which the
eyes go wide, the jaw hangs open loosely,
and you can see the secondary face of Sondur
inside, the javelin pierced through his jaw now,
his eyes wide, and you see the hand reach up to
try and grab the back of the vines. As he does,
the javelin bursts into a shockwave of electrical
energy, scattering his body into a hundred pieces
across the wall, falling off. Vax, you are pushed
back from the force of it, tumbling, manage to
catch yourself in the air with your wings,
still flying, as the rest of Sondur's body just
comes clattering to the ground in chunks.
LAURA: I jump up on Grog's back. What the fuck!
TRAVIS: I honestly did not expect that to happen.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna walk up and grab--
LAURA: Oh my god.
MATT: The javelin clatters to the ground.
TALIESIN: Grab the bow, real quick.
TRAVIS: I go get the javelin, because it's
obviously worth keeping.
SAM: I instinctually throw Keyleth in the air.
MARISHA: And I go for it, too.
MATT: You manage to dig yourself out of your vines
and rush up to Keyleth.
SAM: No, no, with the hand.
MATT: With the hand, oh yeah. The hand darts over,
grabs the fire elemental, and just kinda
(sound of throwing and catching).
MARISHA: Heeheehee.
TRAVIS: Can I run back to Vex and offer her a
healing potion, unless someone can do better?
LAURA: Oh, I can cast Cure Wounds on myself.
TRAVIS: Are you all right?
LAURA: I'm fine. Thank you. I was really
regretting that, attacking him, I thought maybe I
should've just said yes and dealt with it.
TRAVIS: What, become a corpse bride?
TALIESIN: He was terrible.
LAURA: I don't know, I just felt terrible.
MARISHA: I drop my fire elemental form.
TALIESIN: That was a terrible person.
TRAVIS: It's all right.
LAURA: Thanks, Grog.
TRAVIS: You did... you did good.
LAURA: Thanks, so did you.
MATT: A loud impact sounds as Ukurat lands.
SAM: Oh, thank god.
LAURA: I'm gonna cast Cure Wounds on myself before
anything else happens. As high of a level as I
can, which is level three.
MATT: Go for it.
SAM: Does my Song of Rest need to be during a
short rest?
MATT: Yes.
TALIESIN: We have a mansion that's within walking
distance. And if we have to, we will run.
TRAVIS: I'm gonna hand her the potion anyway,
as she's standing there, so.
MATT: Okay. As she finishes healing herself,
Ukurat walks up towards the center of the room
where you're standing next to her, and just kind
of pushes the currently now-smoldering body of the
treant to the side.
"A little late on the call to
arms. I'm just sad I missed most of the fight."
TRAVIS: Didn't want you to miss out on all the
action.
MATT: Got a couple licks in. Well. I guess this
calls us even.
LAURA: Yeah.
SAM: Thanks for coming.
LAURA: Thank you for joining us.
MATT: Be safe.
LAURA: You too.
TRAVIS: Wait. What will you do now?
MATT: "My business is my own. As is yours.
I'll find my people. We'll find a home for us.
"Now. You've done your task.
"Leave before you plummet into any further
unknown dangers, foolish people."
He turns around and leaps
towards the opening that he carved and crawls out
of it and just disappears.
MARISHA: You know, from him I think that was a
compliment.
TALIESIN: It kind of was.
MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: He's so awesome.
TALIESIN: It is sort of sad that we didn't catch
any theater.
LAURA: Well, there's still time.
TRAVIS: Can I try and jump through the hole like
he did?
MATT: You reach over and leap through the hole.
Catch it.
Yeah, it's still open, it's like pulled
open and actually--
TRAVIS: I don't make it all the way in, though,
do I? It's up there.
MATT: Oh, no, the hole that he pulled in was the
entrance you walked in to the base.
TRAVIS: Oh, good.
MATT: So you get there.
TRAVIS: Little colonoscopy?
MATT: Little bit, yeah.
MARISHA: I go up to Vex and I just grab her arm
and I say,
Don't let any man-- or anyone for that
matter-- make you feel like you need them to be
great. Because you don't. I'm not good with
words.
LAURA: That was wonderful, Keyleth. Thank you.
MARISHA: But he was an asshole.
LAURA: No, yeah, he was really... right?
MARISHA: And I don't want you ever dating an
asshole.
LAURA: (laughs) Thank you.
MARISHA: He wasn't good enough, he was mean.
TALIESIN: I'm going to saunter over.
LAURA: What?
TALIESIN: (in an exaggeratedly evil voice) We're a
lot alike, you and I. Bleaaah. (normal voice) What
an asshole, Jesus.
MARISHA: (in an exaggeratedly evil voice) You drug
your friends to their doom.
TRAVIS: Can I walk over to Vax while they're
making a show?
MARISHA: We keep making a show.
TRAVIS: Quietly, I say,
What was he talking about
with the bloody dagger?
LIAM: Sorry, Feywild interference, what was that?
TRAVIS: What was he saying about the bloody dagger
when he was talking to Vex?
LIAM: You know, it's interesting, I understand
exactly zero percent of what the DM was saying
while he was in-character as that particular
character
due to the nature of Skype and
microphones.
TRAVIS: Yes.
LIAM: So I was faking understanding the whole
time, and then picked it up in retrospect
listening to Laura's responses. I missed it.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: Who's this Laura you're speaking of?
(All laugh.)
LIAM: I don't know. I don't know anything.
LAURA: That's okay. It's fine that you didn't
hear. He said nothing about a bloody dagger.
Nothing at all.
LIAM: We should find that dagger. No question.
TALIESIN: Is there anything other than the bow
worth looting on this terrible person, since I'm
rummaging through his...
MATT: Make an investigation check.
TALIESIN: Right.
TRAVIS: Well, let's not downplay the bow.
TALIESIN: I've got it already.
SAM: Hey, guys, I'm still trapped in the vines!
LAURA: Oh, Scanlan! I run over and I start
pulling the vines off of him. Holy shit, Scanlan,
I'm so sorry. Thank you for healing me.
SAM: Certainly.
TRAVIS: Are you in fine form? Should I hit you
until you--
SAM: No, don't hit me. I'll sing more Spice
Girls.
LAURA: That was really lovely.
SAM: Thank you.
LAURA: Spice Girls is so empowering.
MATT: So, you pull the vines from him, as you
inspect around, too, you notice there's not much
really of worth here. This home is mostly natural
in its base. However, the slow trickle of the
black oil-like substance has ceased. Most of it's
grown thicker and stopped, and it just feels like
the whole place went into this sudden stasis,
like the slow crawl of everything nearby,
the vines, everything stopped.
LAURA: We didn't kill the whole forest, did we?
SAM: Little bit.
MARISHA: I drop to my knees and do a Commune with
Nature.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: Do I gather a different energy from the
surrounding plants?
MATT: You still feel the ever-present bloom of
life and life-forces surrounding you entirely.
You do feel a wave of relaxation. There is a sort
of general radial sigh that is slowly trickling
from the center of the tree.
MARISHA: Do I still sense the presence of Sondur?
MATT: No.
MARISHA: Do, last question. Does the tree seem
happier? What is the tree gonna do from here on
out? What are you gonna do, tree?
MATT: Exist.
MARISHA: Exist, cool. Everything seems great.
TRAVIS: Cool. Since I got the killing blow,
can I chop this tree down now?
LAURA: This whole tree?
MARISHA: This big one?
SAM: No, it's just a tree now, I think it's okay.
MARISHA: Yeah, you know, the tree just told me
that it actually feels much better, so.
TRAVIS: I get to chop a tree at some point.
LAURA: You see those trees over there?
TRAVIS: They're already down.
LAURA: No no no, I see it twitching, Grog,
it's definitely twitching.
LIAM: We're going to Vasselheim soon, you can cut
down a lot of trees there. It's cold there,
they could use the firewood. Soon.
MARISHA: Trees that won't take it personal.
TALIESIN: I know that's not nearly as much fun,
but it is available.
TRAVIS: This is true.
LIAM: What are we talking about? Vex'ahlia.
LAURA: What?
LIAM: I'm fucking curious. Pull that bowstring.
LAURA: Well, I don't have it.
TALIESIN: Toss it.
SAM: Are you sure Vex'ahlia should get it?
TALIESIN: I know, I was thinking that.
LAURA: Do you need it, Scanlan, do you think--
SAM: I think maybe I should get it, I fought
bravely in the last fight.
LAURA: You did. Maybe Grog should get it, I mean,
he did get the killing blow.
LIAM: Scanlan, I think you would make a very good
arrow for it.
(All laugh.)
TRAVIS: I could get down with that.
MATT: You hold it in your hand and look at it.
The handle is wrapped with a very tight dark
brown, black leather, and at the cusp of where the
handle itself is and where the arrow is notched is
this nice golden-bronze cap-like metallic inlay.
The rest of the bow itself is this curved,
almost deep verdant green jungle vine-type
texture to it, where it builds on itself like a
series of natural leaf scales. And as it curves
into the ends of the actual recurve bow,
as you hold it, it flexes and shifts on its own.
It actually looks, as you hold it it almost seems
to tighten and then relax, and then as you reach
back an arrow, it goes taut, and the string goes
extremely tight. As you pull the arrow back,
it's like no strength involved at all.
LAURA: What?
MATT: It pulls back on its own, and as soon as you
release, the arrow that you fire shoots off at an
incredible speed and the actual bow itself flexes
with such intensity that it makes this roaring
whoosh sound with each shot.
TALIESIN: Well, that's exciting.
LAURA: That's really badass.
TRAVIS: You wanna shoot me with it?
LAURA: I wanna shoot everything with it.
LIAM: Do you still need muscle strength to pull
it, or is it just easy-peasy now?
LAURA: It's kind of easy-peasy. I guess anybody
could pull this.
LIAM: You're going to have to start doing pushups,
then.
LAURA: (laughs) I guess I did say--
MARISHA: Do you want to hit something? Here,
I'm--
SAM: Do you want to shoot me? I'll be okay.
LAURA: I'm not going to shoot you.
SAM: I'll be okay, you shot me before.
LAURA: No.
SAM: Right here.
TALIESIN: You don't know what it does.
LAURA: Oh, look at that scar, it's beautiful.
TRAVIS: Can we get out of this fucking tree
first?
LAURA: You're right, we should probably get out of
here, maybe.
SAM: Guys. Life needs things to live.
(All laugh.)
TALIESIN: I had not had my coffee, I was tired,
there was no bacon...
SAM: And we are those things. I think we've all
learned a lot today.
LAURA: We've learned so much.
TALIESIN: I hate you so much.
TRAVIS: I walk out of the tree.
TALIESIN: I need fresh air. I'm done.
LAURA: What does it look like outside of the tree?
Is the black muck still black mucky?
MATT: I mean, the whole forest is still just
coated in this horrible thick liquid.
TRAVIS: Did you loot Sondur's body?
TALIESIN: I did, but it wasn't much.
MATT: But when you approached and you inspected
the tree, there was just an ever-constant flow of
it, of this thick molasses-type material,
just slowly drifting down the tree. You look down
and a lot of it seems to have stopped and is
hardening, almost like an amber.
LAURA: Okay.
TRAVIS: Like Jurassic Park.
TALIESIN: This is good.
SAM: (cracks up)
LAURA: Yeah, at least it's not burying the forest
anymore.
TALIESIN: No, we did very well.
SAM: Sweet.
TALIESIN: Let's go home.
MARISHA: You guys ready to go home?
TALIESIN: I'm, well. Do we wanna, is there a
reason to stay or is it time to go home?
LAURA: Let's get out of here.
MARISHA: I think I've seen enough of the Feywild
for now.
TALIESIN: I'm quite pleased.
SAM: We could stop at that hut on the way out.
MARISHA: No, no, no.
LAURA: No no. Not.
SAM: We never found the theater.
LIAM: The theater, the theater! What about the
theater?
SAM: You know what we could do--
LAURA: Sorry, brother, I think we have other
things to attend to.
SAM: You know what we could do, Vex'ahlia,
we could go about 200 feet away from the hut and
you could just--fink!--and see what it does and
then we'll shift out of there.
LAURA: And then we just shoot out of the Feywild.
How about no.
SAM: All right.
TRAVIS: Anybody want to climb to the top of the
200-foot tree to see what the rest of the land
looks like?
MATT: (clapping)
LIAM: I fly up there--
SAM: Oh! Wait, someone's here.
MATT: You hear slow clapping from nearby.
MARISHA: That can't be good.
LAURA: Oh, no.
MATT: As you look off to the side of the tree,
rounding the bend, you see a very tall and thin,
chest-forward, regal-posed, almost elflike but
still exaggerated in the Feylike features.
Long ears that curl past the head. The head
itself is small with a pointed chin, the eyes
almond-shaped and wild, curly orange hair like a
lion's mane that goes down to the lower back,
just up and large, curves up at the very tip.
You see sleeveless silk vestments of blue and
green billowing freely behind him as he walks up
clapping.
LAURA: I instantly case Cure Wounds on myself
again.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: At a level three.
MATT: How much do you heal?
LAURA: 13 plus eight is 25.
MATT: There you go. 25.
LIAM: Garmelie?
LAURA: No, that's wrong. 21.
MATT: Bravo, everyone.
SAM: Who is this?
MATT: Bravo to each and every one of you.
It's been fun to watch. You know, I get so
disinterested in these lands, and I have to say,
I'm impressed. Well. I wish to say adieu.
Good luck on your journeys.
LAURA: Who are you?
MATT: But I am a simple wanderer. An individual
who sees the landscape for artistic benefit.
TALIESIN: I knew it.
MATT: But I'm glad to have made your acquaintance.
It definitely made these past few days absolutely
devoid of boredom, at the very least, and filled
my sketchbook.
MARISHA: Garmelie?
MATT: Is one of my names. I prefer Artagan.
SAM: Artagan?
MATT: But Garmelie suits needs here and there.
I go by many names and many interesting--
TALIESIN: I knew I should've asked for that
portrait.
SAM: What are you?
MATT: I'm afraid the time for questions is done.
As your journey has come to an end, and I have to
be out of here quickly as--
SAM: I cast Otiluke's Resilient Sphere on him.
MARISHA: And I cast Hold Person at the same time.
MATT: (laughs)
TALIESIN: What? What! What! What!
TRAVIS: Nice, Sam.
TALIESIN: No! Oh!
LAURA: What is he? Who is he? What is he?
MATT: All right.
SAM: I don't know.
MATT: What's the DC?
LIAM: He's a deity.
TRAVIS: Hold it, Marisha.
SAM: 19.
MARISHA: 19 for mine as well.
SAM: 'Cause I didn't pull up the Cone.
LAURA: Is he like a god?
MATT: Right. So. The sphere appears around his
form, however, Keyleth, your spell does not seem
to take any sort of hold on him. As it forms
around,
he's still just standing there unmoved,
hands clasped.
"That's adorable. So. Where to
now? Where's your journey taking you? I take it
"this was not your only purpose. Where's your next
destination?"
TRAVIS: We left an empty grave inside, it's got
your name on it if you don't talk.
LAURA: Pfff.
MATT: Please.
LAURA: We go home. And we kill a dragon.
MATT: Good. They are fickle creatures. They need
to be taught a lesson.
LAURA: Any tips?
MATT: (laughs) Don't be eaten. Um. Do not
misunderstand their intelligence. Some are more
bestial. Some are more together. Anyway.
If you'd be so kind,
I'd like to get on with my day.
LAURA: Wait, one last thing. What is this statue
that you tried to steal from me?
TRAVIS: (whispers) Nice.
MATT: Oh, that's a companion. You're welcome to
keep him with you. I just figured since I was
leaving you soon, I'd have someone to wander at my
side as well.
SAM: A companion? What does that mean?
MATT: Yes.
TRAVIS: A statue.
SAM: Does he come to life?
MATT: With the right words, yes.
LAURA, SAM, TALIESIN, and MARISHA: What are those
words?
MATT: (laughs) Well. Take some time with it.
You'll learn them soon enough.
MARISHA: You know, for someone who hates the
theater, you've made quite a show of all this.
(All laugh.)
TRAVIS: Oh man. That was a ten.
LAURA: That was good, that was good, Keyleth.
LIAM: Yep, yep, yep.
MATT: Touche, Keyleth, touche. But no, seriously,
I fucking hate the theater.
You avoided the other one, right?
LAURA: The hag?
MATT: Hag?
SAM: The hut, the hut.
MARISHA: Wodenna.
LAURA: The hut.
MATT: The hut, yes, you avoided the hut?
SAM: She's not a hag?
MATT: She's many things, but she's not a hag.
She's an ex.
LAURA: Oh.
MATT: Anyway. If you don't mind.
SAM: One question.
MATT: (exasperated noise) Now you grow boring and
dreary. I hate boredom.
SAM: Do you stay on this plane or do you come with
us?
MATT: No, I stay on this plane.
SAM: All right.
MATT: Unless I decide to come with you. But that's
of my own volition.
Probably when you least expect it.
SAM: All right.
TALIESIN: Good day to you, Puck. Good day.
SAM: What was your name again?
MATT: Ah, well. Artagan.
SAM and LAURA: Artagan.
LAURA: Thanks for the fun.
TALIESIN: Thanks for the art.
MATT: Thanks for the memories. Ah, memories.
SAM: You know, at some point you should ask
yourself why we didn't just kill you and why we
knew that you were there the whole time.
MATT: What, you think I didn't let you find me?
Think you could've killed me if you wanted?
TRAVIS: Artagan. Did you know Sondur?
MATT: I knew of Sondur, yes.
MARISHA: Did you know Sorudin?
SAM: Who?
MARISHA: Sorudin the Happy?
MATT: Sorudin I did not know, but I was aware of
the enchantment left behind. But who am I to lead
a horse to water when you are so determined to
drink yourself?
LAURA: (laughs) It was great fun.
MATT: That it was. It was great fun. But alas.
SAM: All right.
MARISHA: I have a feeling we'll meet you again,
Artagan.
MATT: I hope so. It does get ever so boring.
SAM: All right, I'll release the sphere on one
condition.
MATT: Yes?
SAM: I believe you have a quill that belongs to
us. Just a single writing implement.
We lent it to you, we want it back.
MATT: It appears in his hand.
"I'm happy to give it to you, but I'm
apparently trapped in this sphere of magic."
SAM: All right, I'll let you go.
MATT: Thank you.
SAM: Thank you. Vax. Was this yours?
LAURA: There's your raven feather. Nice.
MATT: "All right. Travel safe. Stay alive.
And maybe visit. If you get lonely."
And he gives a deep bow and just vanishes.
LAURA: He was fucking cool.
TALIESIN: Dear god, let's get out of here before
something else happens.
LAURA: I really liked him.
MARISHA: Everyone hold hands and say Kumbaya.
SAM: Okay. Let's go back to our plane.
TRAVIS: You don't want to see the ex?
ALL: No.
MARISHA: We've dealt with enough scorned lovers
for one day.
TALIESIN: People get bitchy over here.
LAURA: Where are we popping into?
MARISHA: I guess Whitestone?
TALIESIN: Whitestone.
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: What are we doing, we're warping out?
TALIESIN: Yeah, we're warping out.
SAM: Say bye to the Fey.
LAURA: Hold your hands up, brother, we're holding
your hands.
LIAM: Yeah, but I'm tangling my fingers up,
if she'll let me, with Keyleth.
LAURA: Oh.
SAM: Gross.
TRAVIS: I let go.
TALIESIN: Ew.
MATT: All right.
MARISHA: I take his hand.
LIAM: And say, just quietly to the side,
You know, you've been pretty fucking amazing
lately. As usual.
MARISHA: I say, You haven't been quite bad,
yourself. And then we go to Whitestone.
MATT: To Whitestone. The transition takes place,
you all feel the breath fill your lungs as all of
a sudden your momentum is shot through but a step
forward, and you catch yourself standing outside
of the Sun Tree in the center of Whitestone's main
area.
And that's where we'll end tonight's
session.
TRAVIS: What! Got your bow!
LAURA: Hey!
MARISHA: You got your bow!
TRAVIS: You didn't die!
TALIESIN: You got your bow.
SAM: Ooh, there it is.
LAURA: Ahh, there's the card, there's the card.
MARISHA: Man, that guy tried to act like he knew
you. Fuck that shit.
MATT: Ryan, do you have the--
LAURA: He had so many things wrong.
MARISHA: Oh, dude.
MATT: The item list that you found--
SAM: What does it do, what does it do?
LAURA: Okay, okay. +3 bonus to attack and damage
rolls. 1d4 lightning damage.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
LAURA: I can declare a bramble-shot like you did.
Whoa. Target takes an additional 4d8 piercing
damage, plus they have to make a strength saving
throw or be restrained.
MATT: Restrained means it can't move, all their
attacks have disadvantage, and attacks against
them have advantage, until they break free.
And this is the figurine.
LAURA: Whoa, this is so cool! Once per short rest,
I can use an Oracle Shot.
SAM: What does that do?
LAURA: I can project my sight through my arrow
that I fire from it, for up to ten minutes.
SAM: Oh, Prince of Thieves-style?
LAURA: My god.
TALIESIN: Is that really a thing?
SAM: I don't know.
TALIESIN: Okay.
LAURA: That's awesome.
MARISHA: That's cool, she's like Hanzo.
MATT: It's pretty cool.
LAURA: Imagine from the broom up high how far that
arrow would go. And then when a creature is killed
by an arrow from this weapon, a single six-foot
tree grows out of their corpse.
TALIESIN: Yeah!
MARISHA: Out of their corpse?
SAM: A Christmas tree?
LAURA: A Christmas tree.
MATT: Depending on the time of year, it may be.
TRAVIS: You don't need the Onyx Dog, why don't I
hold onto that.
SAM: Wait, you got the dog?
LAURA: Wait, no, I wanna see what it is.
MARISHA: Yeah, can we talk about that dog? Can we
talk about it?
TRAVIS: You don't need it.
LAURA: I have it.
MATT: (laughs)
LAURA: Travis.
TALIESIN: Roll for it. Roll for it, bro.
LIAM: More animals. More animals for Vex.
LAURA: I don't wanna keep it, I just wanna,
I'm the one holding onto it, man.
TRAVIS: We'll have to tune in next Thursday to see
what it is.
SAM: Sounds good to me.
TALIESIN: Stay tuned for another episode of
Critical Role.
MATT: You're such a terrible person, I love it.
All right, well guys, thank you so much.
That's the end of this episode, we'll be back
next Thursday.
MARISHA: Back in Whitestone!
LAURA: Whitestone!
MATT: To see what adventures befall Vox Machina in
the next arc of the story. In the meantime,
thank you for watching, we're gonna get some
sleep.
Thank you Lootcrate for your awesome
sponsorship.
ALL: Lootcrate!
MATT: Thank you Critters for having patience for
our eleven-plus-hour, 11PM later episode tonight.
Ask you all: Is it Thursday yet?