MATT: Hello everyone, and welcome
to the second episode
of Critical Role, where a bunch of us
crazy voice actor, nerdy types sit here
and play Dungeons and Dragons.
We'll be continuing from
last week's adventure,
so in the meantime, let's
go ahead and show you some
of the character backstory.
TRAVIS: Right, listen up.
If you have ale, then you have
a friend in Grog Strongjaw.
A goliath of towering height and size,
this barbarian has an appetite
for the two great loves
in his life: combat, women, and ale.
(record scratching)
Wait.
Easily the brains of
the group, Grog is often
consulted for his vast
knowledge of shapes, colors,
and shiny things.
Also ale.
In his early years, armed
with his two-handed greataxe,
Grog oft enjoyed proving
his might amongst the ranks
of his family's wandering herd,
but after coming upon an
unsuspecting elderly gnome
in the woods, he objected to the killing
of such an innocent life.
A creature of impulse, Grog
felt only pity for this,
(chuckles) this terrified little thing.
His disobedience cost him dearly.
Beaten bloody and banished
by the herd leader,
his uncle Kevdak, Grog was
abandoned and left to die.
Exiled from his herd, it
was then that the relative
of the very gnome he
fought to save, saved him.
It was the kindness of a
gnome cleric named Pike
that healed Grog, bringing
him back from death's edge.
And they have remained
close friends ever since.
Most nights, Grog can be found
challenging entire taverns
to wrestling matches, ha!
Or accompanying Scanlan
to the nearest house
where you pay for lady favors, huh.
Also ale.
MARISHA: A first impression of Keyleth
would leave you with little information
on the half-elven druid.
You might even think that
her social awkwardness
due to her sheltered
upbringing is kind of sweet.
Of course, it would be
unwise to underestimate her
based on first impressions.
(lightning roaring)
Under that unintimidating, petite frame
is a vicious beast waiting to be unleashed
whose natural powers have
made even the fiercest
of champions pee their
pants, literally. (giggles)
Born to the air tribe
of the Ashari people,
Keyleth was raised with
a deep love of nature
and the elemental magics.
It is her people's inherent duty
to protect the delicate
areas in Tal'Dorei,
where the four elemental
planes begins to bleed
with this realm.
Since she was a little
girl, she had quite a knack
for air manipulation and
beastshaping abilities.
Well, if you consider
kittens and flying squirrels
to be little beasts,
which I do.
(clears throat)
Anyways, it wasn't long before
the headmaster of the tribe,
her father, Kohren, realized
her true prodigious abilities
and she was inveterated to succeed him
as the next headmaster.
Just like that, her jovial
childhood was stripped
and replaced with endless
spell memorization,
teachings from ancient traditions,
and exceedingly high expectations.
Every druid leader-to-be
must embark on a journey
to seek out the sister
tribes in order to introduce
and establish respect amongst
the fellow headmasters.
They call this the
Aramente, or Noble Odyssey.
When her father felt she was
ready, he set her on the path
to truly discovering herself.
Not knowing when, or if,
she will ever return.
As she hikes down the
mountain towards Stillben,
she meditated on the task ahead.
Part of the Aramente is proving
yourself a strong warrior,
a valiant protector, and a
wise and compassionate leader.
With this knowledge, one
thought plays in repeat
in her mind:
Is she even worthy?
TALIESIN: Percy was the third child
of seven children, born to a noble family
who lived far to the north
in the ancient castle of Whitestone.
With so many siblings to
share the burdens of lordship,
Percy turned his attention
to the sciences,
engineering, and naturalism.
One day, a mysterious couple
named Lord and Lady Briarwood
came to court.
During a feast held in
their honour, the Briarwoods
violently took control
of the castle, killing
or imprisoning everyone who
would stand in their way.
Percy awoke chained in the
dungeon, only to be freed
by his younger sister.
Together they fled, chased
by the Briarwoods' men.
As they ran, Percy's
sister took several arrows
to the chest and fell.
Percy kept running, eventually
jumping into a freezing river
and floating unconscious to freedom.
He did not remember waking
up on a fishing boat.
He barely remembered the next two years,
as he slowly made his way
as far south as possible.
Then one night, Percy had a dream.
A roaring cloud of smoke
offered him vengeance
against those who destroyed his family.
When he awoke, Percy began
to design his first gun.
(gun clicking)
(explosion roaring)
SAM: Oh, you haven't heard
of Scanlan Shorthalt?
Well, gird your loins, ladies,
because he has his eye on you.
A talented musician, master of disguise,
and dashingly handsome in his own mind,
Scanlan sings songs almost as much
as he sings his own praises.
Born a poor gnome, Scanlan
used his endless charm
and soaring tenor voice to croon for coin
and support his single mother.
One day he was discovered
by a half-orc promoter,
and joined Dr. Dranzel's
Spectacular Traveling Troupe,
where he learned the ways of the world,
and honed his skills as
a bard extraordinaire.
A loner much of his life,
Scanlan has never quite
come to terms with the
violent death of his mother
at the hands of a goblin invasion.
While his years on the road
provided many, shall we say,
educational experiences
with the opposite sex,
deep down Scanlan yearns for the one thing
he's never known, the true
love of a fellow gnome.
Still, Scanlan considers
himself a lover first,
performer second, and
fighter distant third.
On the battlefield,
he'll support his allies,
but rarely draws blood unless it's
to protect fellow gnome, Pike.
Count on Scanlan for a hearty
laugh, a rollicking song,
and a twinkle in his eye that melts hearts
and makes the females swoon.
ORION: Greetings and salutations.
I am Tiberius Stormwind.
I hail from a town called Ty'rex,
located in the heart of Draconia,
from a politically respected family.
At the age of 15, I succeeded
in passing the Sorcerer's Rite,
showing prodigy-like control of my magic.
The judges and the Draconian
high council were amazed
at how powerful my spells were
for how long I had been training.
At 20 years old, I was the
youngest appointed member
of the magic guild in Draconian history.
For the next few years, I almost went mad
from the malaise of being a guild member,
as it's rather boring.
However, one day I
happened upon a chamber,
unused for quite some time.
In the room were stacks of books and maps
of the surrounding cities and
areas around the known world.
For months I would frequent the chamber,
and learned of artifacts from legend.
After a long period of research,
I made a list of artifacts
that caught my eye.
I brought these findings
to the high council
and was told that all of the
information in the chamber
I stumbled upon was either
believed to be fiction,
or unsolvable mysteries,
and hence were lost forever.
I found those answers to be unacceptable.
A year later I devised a ruse and managed
to convince the city
council to lend support
in me leaving Draconia on a
mission of peace and diplomacy
for the surrounding kingdoms.
Going from town to town and
making friends and allies,
in and for the name of Draconia.
Being a red dragonborn, I had
quite the task on my hands
in that respect, but it
was exactly what I needed,
so I could explore the world
and find these artifacts,
as I felt the truth was out there.
Some may describe me as buffoonish,
but I say poppycock to all that. (mutters)
I am much sharper than
most give me credit for.
I just don't pay attention
to things sometimes.
I've also been known to
be rather cunning, loyal,
happy-go-lucky, and well, dangerous.
I can't help but show my true
scales every now and then.
But overall, I think I'm quite
friendly for a dragonborn.
LIAM: Never entirely
welcome in the company
of elves or men, Vax'ildan
learned at a young age
to skip past formality, preferring instead
to invite himself in your door.
Along with twin sister
Vex'ahlia, Vax was born
by a chance encounter
between elven royalty
and human peasantry.
Raised by their mother
in their early years,
the twins were eventually
sent off to their father
in the elven capital of Syngorn.
But their cool reception among
the elves there never warmed,
and their time in the capital didn't last.
The siblings stole away one autumn night
and set out on the open road.
After a few years of wandering,
they eventually decided
to return to their
mother, and journeyed back
to the lands of their youth.
But instead of finding
their childhood home,
they returned to a pile of rubble.
Their mother was gone,
their home burned to ash.
Pressing the townspeople for answers,
they learned of the day the dragon came.
(loud roaring)
With their ties all severed,
Vax'ildan and his sister
set out to find their fortune
together in Tal'Dorei.
An outsider since birth,
Vax quickly learned
to solve life's challenges
in his own particular way,
often by sidestepping them entirely.
And when his knack for circumventing
adversity isn't enough,
(sword slicing)
the way of blades the
elves schooled him in
more than makes up the difference.
LAURA: Like so many half-elves, Vex'ahlia
has spent most of her life
suffering the cool reception
of a people who don't fully accept her.
Born of a human mother
and an elven father,
who only later in life took an
interest in their existence,
Vex'ahlia and her twin brother Vax'ildan
quickly realized the only
people they could truly rely on
in this world were each other.
It was at the age of ten
when the two were taken
from their mother, and
brought to live in Syngorn,
the isolated elven city
for which their father
was an ambassador.
He quietly took them in, but
always kept an icy distance,
and after too many years
of disdainful looks,
the pair decided to leave
his indifference behind,
and set out on their own.
Vax took to the cities,
stealing small trinkets
and learning the ways of the thief,
while Vex kept to the woods.
She preferred the isolation.
Always the keen observer, she
learned to hunt and to track,
to spy and to shoot.
And through a series of fateful events,
earned herself a companion
in the form of a bear,
her own stolen trinket,
(bear growling)
to fight alongside her
and protect her fiercely.
Also, he is adorable and
gives expert massages.
Welcome back everyone.
So, know that you're a
little more affiliated
with the characters, let's
get this party started.
So as a head's up, I wanna let you know,
once again, we're waiting
for the charity elements
of this stream to open up
again, since the big charity
that happened a couple weeks ago.
Once we do, we're gonna
be taking donations,
half to go to help run the channel,
the other to donate to 826.
Marisha will explain that
here in just a second.
As a head's up, Ashley,
who plays our cleric, Pike,
unfortunately couldn't
make it again this week,
because she's busy filming amazing stuff
with her career being amazing.
But she says she's sad she can't be here.
She loves you guys,
and as soon as Pike can
re-enter the campaign,
hopefully in a couple weeks,
all awesome gnomeness shall double.
So also tonight, there was a goal to try
and hit 1000 subscribers on the channel.
So what we're gonna do is,
we only have 130 people
to subscribe tonight.
If we can get all 130 before
the show ends this evening,
we're gonna do a random selection
of a person within those
thousand subscribers
to win a copy of the Player's
Handbook signed by all of us,
as well as a really, really cool image
that was tweeted out earlier
by Geek &amp; Sundry,
also signed by all of us.
So, go ahead and pull your friends,
see if we can get some more subscribers
before the show's out tonight, so
hopefully that'll be fun.
So, Marisha, if you wanna go
ahead and explain a little bit
about the charity 826 we'll be
plugging in the near future.
Yes, 826 LA is a non-profit
charity organization
that helps kids though
the age of six to 18
with their creative and
structural writing skills,
and they also help teachers and yeah.
Good artsy creative things.
So donate, and definitely
visit the Time Travel Mart.
SAM: Wait, can we donate?
MATT: Tonight we can't donate here.
MARISHA: We can't donate tonight yet?
MATT: It's not available yet.
Start saving your money.
SAM: Not yet.
MARISHA: But you can still go to the
Time Travel Mart in Echo Park
and you can also go to
their website, 826LA,
and I'm sure you can donate through there
if you want to do that.
MATT: Yes, but we'll be getting
that going in the near future.
So, anyway.
Let's go ahead and do a little recap
of what happened last week.
So the party has been
hired by their friend,
Arcanist Allura Vysoren,
in the city of Emon
to head towards the
dwarven town of Kraghammer,
as a good friend of hers,
and one of the members
of the Council of
Tal'Dorei, has gone missing.
This, being a halfling paladin,
named Lady Kima of Vord,
who was on a vision quest
as part of a pilgrimage
and was drawn towards some dark evil
she said was manifesting
somewhere deep beneath Kraghammer
and hadn't been heard from since.
So the party was sent there
to go ahead and seek her.
Upon arriving in Kraghammer,
shenanigans ensued.
They made some friends, made some enemies,
wandered the town.
Brother, sisters, walked
around as if they were married.
LAURA: No!
(group laughs)
MATT: Bears almost got into fights in rings.
And eventually the party made their way
towards the bottom ring
of Kraghammer proper,
talking to Lord Nostoc Greyspine, who is--
ORION: That's right, Greyspine.
MATT: Yes, Greyspine indeed.
Who is the head of the Greyspine Mines
at the bottom of Kraghammer,
where supposedly this
paladin disappeared to.
After having a conversation with him,
a bunch of goblins and ogres
began to spring from the mines
and attacking the workers.
The party swooped down to
aid, realized that the goblins
and ogre's weren't
attacking, they were fleeing
from something else,
of which emerging from
within the mines proper
some strange naga-based
hydra-ish abomination.
The party then proceeded to slaughter it,
final blow dealt by
Scanlan via lightning bolt.
SAM: Hi, Scanlan here, hi.
MATT: Our resident gnome bard.
TRAVIS: Yeah, you did!
MATT: And that's where we pick up.
So, as all of you are
still riding the adrenaline
of the battle, Scanlan feeling
the tingling in his fingers
as the little bolts of
arcane energy kind of
(imitates electricity
crackling) spark throughout,
the rest of the nearby workers and miners
slowly converge in and begin to
walk up to the party.
And someone starts, "That was
great, that was well done!
"Fantastic!
"Where'd you learn that?"
One of them comes up there,
"Ah, I could've done
"better than that."
And they start just
shouting off at each other
and pat each other on the back.
A few moments of this progresses before,
all of a sudden, there's a
hush comes about the crowd,
and you see about five or six Carvers
pull their way through,
Carvers being the guards of Kraghammer,
with Lord Nostoc Greyspine
himself stepping through.
He looks at the rest
of the group and goes,
"All right, so you've certainly
proven yourselves in battle."
ORION: Well, of course we have.
I'm sorry.
MATT: "I would like to continue this conversation
that we had back in my
office if you don't mind."
He turns around and begins to walk back.
MARISHA: Oh wait, Nostoc.
He's not even listening,
he's just walking off.
(group laughs)
Yeah, mmm.
Ooh, shall we turn and follow?
LAURA: Are you still an eagle?
Can you even talk to him?
TALIESIN: Shouldn't you just go caw?
MARISHA: Well I'm not an eagle.
But I am still poisoned.
LAURA: Oh, I can help you.
MARISHA: Oh, that'd be great.
LAURA: Yeah!
LAURA: Hold on, I'm gonna go
up, and I'm gonna cast--
SAM: Cast?
Yeah, I can cast spells.
SAM: You can cast?
LAURA: I can.
I've got plenty o' spells.
LIAM: You can kill?
SAM: All right, fair enough.
LAURA: I'm gonna cast Protection
from Poison on Keyleth.
MATT: Okay.
Essentially go ahead and make
a saving throw with advantage.
This'll be Constitution.
MARISHA: I made the second one.
MATT: What'd you roll?
MARISHA: A 10.
Plus my constitution which
is two, three, thirteen.
MATT: So thirteen?
MARISHA: Yes.
MATT: That'd be enough.
So, after you finish casting the spell,
you feel the poison leave
the rest of your body.
You can kind of take a breath to yourself.
The rest of the miners
kind of look about and
Awkwardly staring back at
Nostoc as he walks off,
kind of looking back like, what
"Are you gonna go?
"Talk to him?"
SAM: Yeah, I guess we should go follow him.
TALIESIN: We have two very important questions.
GROG: Can't we look in the
hole a little bit more.
ORION: No Grog, we need to go do this.
LAURA: We're gonna go in the hole
in just a minute, Grog.
ORION: Then you can smash, you'll be fine.
TRAVIS: You promise?
LIAM: You did that last night.
We need to take care of business.
Let's go talk to the man.
I'm sure it's going to
lead back to the mines.
MARISHA: To the hole.
LIAM: Yes, to the hole.
Everything's back to the hole.
SAM: Percy, do you have something
to say before we go?
TALIESIN: Well, this is good.
We have to find out what that was,
and we have to see if
he'll finally give us
some of that ale,
I think are the two most important things.
LAURA: It was wine, I believe.
SAM: No, it was bloody, bloody beer.
LAURA: Bloodline.
Bloody wine, blood wine.
TRAVIS: Bloodier, ale.
Beerwine.
MATT: It was delicious is what it was.
TRAVIS: It was really good.
LAURA: Let's go talk to Nostoc.
SAM: Let's follow him, let's follow him.
TALIESIN: Okay, this is what's important.
MATT: All right, so as you head back
to the ramp that heads up
from the mine enclosure itself
to the top of the realm,
which is where the Greyspine
Industries mining facility is,
you are brought into the building again,
brought back to Nostoc's office,
in which he's not sitting,
he's kind of pacing behind his desk,
waiting for you as you approach.
As you enter the room, he
stops pacing, turns around,
puts his hand on the desk, and says,
Please, enter and close
the doors behind you.
(loud thud)
ORION: Sorry, I didn't mean to
slam the door like that.
(group laughs)
MATT: "A flatulent dragonborn, eh?"
MATT: "All right."
So as you close the -
(laughs)
Tiberius.
(Orion clears throat comically)
SAM: Sir Greyspine.
Lord Greyspine?
Mr. Greyspine?
MATT: "Lord Greyspine is fine."
SAM: Lord Greyspine, yes.
Why have you summoned us here?
Is it to tell us information
about what just came out
of your mine, I hope.
MATT: "Well let's be clear."
"We dwarves don't need help from outsiders.
"We can handle our own business just fine."
LAURA: Of course.
MARISHA: Speaking of outsiders, you wouldn't happen
to have seen a Lady Kima, would you?
MATT: "As what the discussion
was based on previously,
"you're searching for
her, and last we saw her,
She went down into the mine."
LAURA: We already talked about that, Keyleth.
TRAVIS: Yep, we did.
LIAM: They don't like her,
she was a troublemaker
and she went in.
TRAVIS: You're an eagle.
LAURA: She's in the mine.
We'll go in and find her.
Right?
Lord Greyspine?
MATT: "You're welcome to.
"As far as I know, she's
down there somewhere.
"Hopefully still in one piece."
LAURA: While we're there, would
you like us to take care
of any other problems?
MATT: "Getting to that.
"You see these small
intrusions have been bad
"for meeting our quotas with the
Bronzegrip metal warehouse
"and export shipments.
"Employees have been forced to
"collapse a non-negotiable
portion of our tunnels
"to prevent incursions like this.
"Without my approval.
"And this is a pattern
I wish to stop at once.
"Thus, I have a proposition for you.
"Now, I will give you
free reign to our mines.
"I shall get the proper approvals
to make sure no Carvers
"bother you as you wander
the city's lower ring.
"And I will contract you
to delve past our tunnels
"and investigate the
source of these creatures,
"where they come from, where they live,
"and if there is some sort of a leader
"who gives them their commands.
"Eliminate them.
"For this, I will reward
you with not a trifle sum.
"25,000 gold pieces.
"Plus 250 gold per beast scalp
you provide upon returning."
LAURA: Ooh, I like this.
ORION: Grog, this seems like a
wonderful job, doesn't it?
SAM: Money is wonderful.
We like money.
But we've been charged to find Lady Kima.
We need assurances that we will find her
or at least some evidence
of her in the mines.
MATT: "The brazen halfling bitch went in there
"without my approval and
wandered into the mines,
"not to be seen.
"So if she is down there,
I hope she's in one piece.
"I can't guarantee it.
"But if there's any place to
find her, that's probably it."
LIAM: We're the group of adventurers for you.
I don't know if you've heard
of the heroes Emon, who just recently-
I'm sure you've heard something.
Word travels fast.
MATT: "Not beneath this mountain, it doesn't,
of human closers."
LIAM: We've just done a lot of
good to the ruler of Emon.
MATT: "Great.
How does that help us dwarves?"
ORION: We're saying we
are going to help you, too.
And everything will be fine,
and we'll all be happy.
LAURA: Well, we've discovered, in
our past adventures, however,
is that every realm
seems to be having trouble with
the same sort of creatures,
coming up from the Underdark perhaps?
LIAM: All we're saying is,
help us help you.
What exactly have
you seen before this day?
More of the same? Or other creatures?
MATT: He sits back for a second.
"The types of creatures, I do not know.
"I mostly deal with the business
"and just know that there's
some bullshite going on
"down in the mines.
"You could ask our foreman, Hieris.
"He's dealt with the cleanup each time
"we've had an incursion like this,
"so if anyone has information
on what these creatures are,
"he'd be the one to talk to."
LIAM: Sorry, what was his name again?
MATT, SAM, LAURA: Hieris.
MATT: "He's a foreman at the mine proper."
LAURA: All right.
TALIESIN: I think this seems like the
sort of job we'd want to take.
LAURA, ORION: Yes.
TRAVIS: Will we get paid for the
monsters and creatures
we've already slayed?
MATT: "This deal was not sewn in yet, so no."
TRAVIS: Oh.
MATT: "But we thank you for your aid."
PERCY: It is customary in our
culture to seal a deal
with a drink.
TALIESIN: As I think you are all aware.
LAURA: Truly, truly.
LIAM: See, I wasn't just fucking
with you last week.
(group laughs)
That's a thing we do.
TALIESIN: And since we are about to risk our lives...
TRAVIS: I forgot you did that.
MATT: Make a persuasion roll.
TALIESIN: Yes! Happily.
TRAVIS: Roll good, it's the first one.
LIAM: Come on, Percy!
TALIESIN: 14.
LAURA: Oh.
SAM: It's pretty good.
Not great.
MATT: You can see this long,
distant, angry, dwarven,
mistrusting stare.
Rubs his chin, his well-kept,
blackened beard and goes,
"Huh, but a sip, as it was a gift."
LAURA: Yes!
SAM: (laughs) We'll take it.
He pulls the ale barrel
which you guys provided,
sets it on the side of his
desk with the same spigot
that you had placed in when
you presented it earlier
and says, "Take a bit."
"A bit."
LAURA: (whispering) Put some in a bottle.
ORION: We have to save some for those guards.
LIAM: Let me take care of it.
I'll pour everyone a glass.
LIAM: Oh, thank you, brother.
I take my empty water flask
that I emptied out before,
and am smiling and pouring glasses
and also squirting a little
bit here and there as I want.
I start to just play a
little ditty on the flute.
I thought we could accompany
our sip with a little bit
of music, not to distract you, just to--
(group laughs)
just to sort of accompany us.
MATT: His nose squints at the sound.
(SAM imitates a jaunty flute)
MATT: "Gnomish tunes aren't
to my ears and liking."
However, you do get an inspiration dice.
LAURA: Yay.
MATT: All right, so go ahead and
make a - (laughs)
Make a sleight of hand check on this.
LIAM: Okay.
That's what we do, right?
LAURA: Roll well.
Here we go.
LAURA AND LIAM: Oh, no.
SAM: You have inspiration dice.
TALIESIN: Inspiration dice are d8?
MATT: Yep, you add a d8 to it as well.
LIAM: Okay, and I can add a d8 to this?
MATT: Correct.
TALIESIN: The ale is that good.
LIAM: Oh good.
Now I'm at 19.
(Travis groans in relief)
Hey.
MATT: As he's listening to the gnomish music
and kind of pushing it
away with his hands, like,
"Stop, I don't- no.
"I appreciate it, but I don't."
SAM: All right, there's not accounting for taste.
MATT: As you do that, your
wineskin goes to full.
(imitates liquid sloshing)
Swollen to its brim.
You switch over to one of the cups,
you pass around the drinks.
All of you manage to get
your drinks passed around.
LAURA: Huzzah!
MATT: "To a contract!"
TRAVIS: Aye! Huzzah!
TALIESIN: To a contract.
MARISHA: Contracts.
SAM: L'chaim!
MARISHA: Love contracts.
LIAM: Is that Draconian?
SAM: It's Gnomish.
TALIESIN: To risking our lives. For money.
LAURA: How old is Nostoc?
Just out of curiosity.
MATT: It's hard to tell.
Dwarves live quite a long time.
He would be equivalent
to like a human forties.
Dwarven time, somewhere
in his mid-hundreds.
MARISHA: Smells like its been in the
barrel for a hundred years.
ORION: It has been.
LAURA: This is excellent.
LIAM: Tastes like two buck Chuck.
(group laughs)
ORION: Oh, I know him from Quimdendale.
TRAVIS: What do you know of a
Ballsac up in the tavern?
MATT: "I'm sorry, what?"
TRAVIS: Do I have that right?
LAURA: Ball, ball -
MARISHA: Balgus.
GROUP: Balgus.
MATT: "Ah, Balgus, that's the brand
of what you brought me."
SAM: You know what, I think we
asked about him last time.
LAURA: I think we did.
ORION: Also, may we take a short rest
before we leave this facility?
MARISHA: Yes, could we do that?
Is this considered a short rest?
LAURA: Oh yeah, that actually would be good.
MATT: If you'd like to do that,
that would just be taking
a short rest outside,
probably not in the office proper.
LAURA: Understandable.
MATT: You can leave and just sit down
and get some rest.
LAURA: When we take a rest, can
I look for Hieris?
MATT: You can as well.
So, while you guys are
taking a short rest,
you're able to use any of your hit dice
to heal up naturally.
TRAVIS: We don't naturally heal up?
MATT: That is your natural healing.
Not to full.
It's a continuation, Grog.
SAM: I will sing a song of rest.
And it goes a little something like,
Scanlan make you feel good
Scanlan make you feel real good
ORION: Oh, I feel so good.
SAM: No wait, you get an extra d6
on all your heals.
TRAVIS: I appreciate the slow jam.
MATT: Yeah, on every hit dice,
you get an extra d6.
TRAVIS: R. Kelly would agree.
(Matt laughs)
LAURA: I didn't take any hit points.
I'm at full health.
MATT: So you got a slow jam just
for the sake of the slow jam.
LAURA: That's right.
And it was great.
MATT: All right, roll an investigate check.
ORION: It feels good.
Real good.
LAURA: Okay.
Oh, 25.
MATT: A brief discussion with a few
of the other wandering
dwarf miners that are
in the outskirts of the
buildings' facilities.
Eventually it leads you
over to what is a small,
secondary building
maybe 200 yards off
from the main property.
That apparently is where Hieris resides
and keeps watch over the
entire establishment.
LIAM: I've tagged along.
LAURA: Knock knock knock.
MATT: All right, the rest of you going with her?
SAM: Yeah, we'll go with her.
MATT: Why not! Why split the party?
So the the group makes their way over
to the outskirts of the building.
Opens up and a very nice,
portly looking dwarf
with a big tuft of a chinstrap beard.
Big reddish, ruddy nose.
Leather apron on.
And he opens the door.
"Aye, hello!
Nice to meet you.
What can I do for ye?"
LAURA: Hi. You must be Hieris?
MATT: "I am, I am.
Foreman of this here fine mine."
LAURA: Wonderful to meet you.
I've heard wonderful things about you.
MATT: "Oh, have you! From who?"
LAURA: Uh, from Lord Greyspine himself.
MATT: "Really? Oh. All right.
"Well, how can I be of service?"
LAURA: We were curious.
I'm sure you witnessed all
of those wonderful goblins
and trolls and other nonsense
coming out of the mine.
MATT: "Aye. Nasty lot.
It always makes my weeks
"that much more interesting."
LAURA: Weeks? So this has been
happening for quite a while?
MATT: "Unfortunately, at least five or six."
LAURA: And what kind of monsters
have you been dealing with?
MATT: "Terrible kinds."
He starts rubbing his
chin for a little and goes,
"We generally deal with
the occasional goblin den
"we stumble across when
opening new tunnels.
"That's part of the norm.
"Other nasty underground beasties.
"However, over this past few weeks,
"we've seen some real
nightmarish things slither
"out of the shadows.
"Many goblins stitched together,
"like some kind of ball
of screaming green lint.
SAM: Ooh, god.
MATT: "Slimes and oozes that would mutate
"and change color rapidly
before seeming to dissolve
"on their own.
"Unstable-looking really, in their form."
SAM: Like a goblin centipede?
(Laura, Liam, Travis laugh)
MATT: "If you will, aye aye."
ORION: Sounds more like some
type of necromancy magic.
MATT: "Perhaps, but they're not undead, per se.
"They're still alive.
"At least from what we can tell.
"Whatever agony face them
in their physical form.
ORION: Oh, that's even worse.
MATT: "We even had one brief
run-in with what looked
"like a duergar that had
swollen and sprouted eyes
"and mouths all across his body.
That was a sight."
SAM: What's a duergar?
LIAM: That's a dark dwarf.
They're little fuckers, those are.
MATT: "Aye, duergar."
And he spits to the side.
"Filthy lost souls.
"Dwarves of old that
turned to a darker god.
"Thankfully, they live far
beneath the mountains,
"and usually far north
enough to not worry about it.
"But one of them found its way up here,
"in this strange, awful, maw-covered form.
"It was terrifying.
"And the smell!
"Oh ho ho!
"Anyway, we've even seen a
few creatures from the surface
"that normally aren't
found down here as well,
"which is strange.
"They don't wander down.
"Something's bringing them.
"Weirdest thing."
"Oh! And I just heard we
had some weird,
many-headed serpent thing that
just got killed down there.
LAURA: Oh, we just killed one of those.
MATT: "That was you!"
LAURA: Yes!
TRAVIS: Our hero is right over here.
SAM: (clears throat) Hi.
(group laughs)
MATT: And he steps onto his back
leg, shifting his weight,
and cocks an awkward eyebrow.
"Really?"
SAM: I'm really strong for my age.
ORION: We were all surprised.
TALIESIN: We're as surprised as anybody.
TRAVIS: Fearsome Scanlan.
SAM: Actually, Hieris,
I have a question for you.
You know the mines very well, yes?
MATT: "Aye, I do."
SAM: Far from asking you to draw us a map,
are there any tunnels or
directions that we should avoid
or particularly head towards?
Anything that we should look for in terms
of traps or tricks?
MATT: "Not within our mines.
"They're usually well-guarded.
Or, they were."
ORION: Also, do you have a map?
MATT: "Of the mines?
"Yeah, I do."
ORION: Wonderful.
MATT: He starts going through his notes here.
ORION: I'll take that.
SAM: That's where we're going, right?
TRAVIS: We're goin' in the hole.
MATT: It's kinda haphazardly
scrawled across a piece
of parchment, but he hands it over to you.
MATT: And he says, "So that's the
front part of the mines.
"Unfortunately, half of our
tunnels have been
"relinquished to close off
some of these beasties
"coming through, so we're
gonna have to recarve portions
"of the mine as we progress forward.
"Kind of starting at
square one best we can.
"But that at least is what
we're currently working with.
"There is a subterranean level as well.
"We have an elevator inside
"that brings the various
mine carts to and from."
LAURA: Is there a particular area on that map
that most of the baddies
seem to be coming from?
MATT: "No, we've closed it off each time."
LAURA: Just kind of everywhere?
MATT: "Oh no, we've had a few
tunnels they've come through,
"but we've managed to collapse those
"and make sure they're
not coming through again.
LIAM: And we noticed the, I believed
it was the naga we fought,
it seemed to have several
extra heads stitched on.
Have you no knowledge of these creatures?
It seems very odd.
Is there any connection in
dwarven history or past?
Or this is totally out of the blue?
MATT: "No no, not to my knowledge, at least.
"I mean, most beasts we
find are in one piece,
"not several together.
"It's a bit disturbing to be honest.
"I told my nephew about it
and he was crying for hours."
LAURA and MARISHA: Oh.
ORION: (laughs)
TRAVIS: Do any of the beasts go back into them?
MATT: "Oh no, we've killed them
as they come out each time."
Right, they don't take anything back.
MATT: "Not from what I've seen, no."
MARISHA: Hieris, do you know if
there's any other entrances
into the mine?
Any old secret tunnels,
something that someone
could be using to get in?
MATT: "Not to the mine, this is
all proprietary.
"This is the business we run,
so we don't have any internal
"or secret entrances.
"That would leave us open
to a sort of a thief
to come in and steal our mithril."
LIAM: And what's security like on the mine?
Is there any chance
someone could've slipped in
through Kraghammer without you knowing,
or is that all locked up?
MATT: "Oh, I highly doubt that, not with
"the way our carvers are trained."
LIAM: Understood, understood.
LAURA: They are quite--
MATT: "That's what I'm talking about.
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: "Fine dwarven study."
TRAVIS: Before we go--
LAURA: Strong ale.
MATT: "Finest of military classes, aye.
"Proud of 'em."
TRAVIS: What do you use for the--
MATT: "I had a cousin who was once a carver.
"Raised him there.
"His whole family brought
him up on that side.
"Military weapon training every day.
"Couldn't come out and
play with the rest of us.
"I felt bad for him.
"But he grew up to be a
right nasty dwarf, aye."
LIAM: You say had.
LAURA: Where is he now?
MATT: "Unfortunately, he was slain
in one of the incursions.
"That duergar I was telling you about.
"But, such is the nature
of the fighter, I suppose."
LAURA: A damn shame.
I'm so sorry.
MATT: "I appreciate that.
"To be honest, he was kind
of a bastard, but um--
"don't miss him too much.
"But I appreciate the thought.
"That's very kind of you."
SAM: We won't avenge him then.
MATT: "I mean, still avenge him."
LIAM: Literally or figuratively?
MATT: "I'm not sure.
TRAVIS: He had parents.
MATT: "He had parents.
"We were related somewhat.
"I'm not gonna say too closely."
LAURA: Can I ask a question?
MATT: "Ah, yes."
LAURA: Not to you, to the other guy, Matt.
MATT: Ah, yes.
(group laughs)
MATT: Yes, Laura?
LAURA: When we take a rest, do
we get our spells back
for the day?
MATT: Not a short rest.
It has to be a long rest.
LAURA: All right, cool.
TALIESIN: Which is why we're
gonna take a proper nap.
LAURA: We're gonna take a real nap?
TALIESIN: I think we should go buy
some potions and take a nap.
LIAM: I think so.
LAURA: All right, this could be really bad.
I mean, we're about to put the dungeons
in Dungeons and Dragons.
TRAVIS: Let's go get drunk and go to sleep then.
LAURA: All right.
MATT: There you go.
TALIESIN: And stock up on some potions.
Hieris, you've been so helpful.
MATT: "Of course, I'm happy to."
MARISHA: One last question.
MATT: "It doesn't have to be last.
"You're welcome to stay as long as you like.
I don't get visitors to
often up here in my booth."
MARISHA: You should come drink
with us at the tavern.
MATT: "Oh well, I have to stay here.
"Work, at least for the next six hours."
LIAM: All night, do you get
off in six more hours?
MATT: "Aye.
"But I have some dried fruits.
"I've got some meats inside.
"I've got two chairs and
you could fit in my lap,"
and he kind of pats you on the head.
SAM: I've killed.
(group laughs)
MATT: "Right."
ORION: This one needs a whore, sorry.
(Sam grunts)
MATT: "Fair enough."
Also, apparently my mic's a bit loud.
If you can turn it down
a bit for you guys.
LIAM: What's a mic?
MATT: "Forget that, you heard nothing.
"It's a strange echo in the
caverns of Kraghammer. Anyway--"
TRAVIS: Look at the time.
LAURA: We have to go.
We'll come see you again, Hieris.
MATT: "Of course, anytime.
"When we're not busy.
"But when I'm not busy,
you're welcome to come by."
ORION: All right.
MARISHA: Oh, that'd be nice.
LIAM: Tell you what, when we drag
our asses out of that mine,
we'll come straight to
you and buy you a drink.
LAURA: And we'll have some of that dried fruit.
TRAVIS: We're lying, right?
MATT: "Oh, I'll save a batch for
you, you half-elf lass."
LAURA: All right.
LIAM: Do the wink thing you do.
LAURA: I did, I already did.
LIAM: Oh, you did it already.
She's good at winking.
MATT: "I saw, it was a good wink.
"Aye. Made me tingle in my shoulders."
GROG: Just your shoulders?
MATT: "That might be the diabetes, but--"
(group laughs)
MATT: "But mostly the wink, I think."
TRAVIS: Good.
MARISHA: Oh, we should get him something
other than dried fruit.
That's not good for diabetes.
TRAVIS: Back to the tavern.
TALIESIN: At least it means he's regular.
TRAVIS: Or did you have something?
SAM: No, we're good.
Back to the tavern.
We go back to the Iron
Hearth Tavern, right?
Is that what it's called?
MATT: For those who are asking, that's
West Country, is the accent.
LAURA: Yes.
MATT: Cornwall.
LAURA: What time is it?
Should we buy potions now?
TRAVIS: If we're underground--
LAURA: Oh, is everything open?
MATT: As far as you guys know, it's somewhere
in the neighborhood of
sunsettish afternoon.
LAURA: Are the stores still open?
TRAVIS: It's summer.
MATT: You can certainly check.
SAM: It's like La Vegas, it's always twilight.
TRAVIS:: There you go.
ORION: If you all don't mind, I
suggest we item up a bit,
and before we get too late,
and we get too drunk, Grog,
go back to that lightning --
main-- manor-- lightning cage.
LAURA: Oh, that place.
MATT: House Thunderbrand?
ORION: House Thunderbrand.
(Matt laughs)
TRAVIS: Where do we item up?
Do we get potions and stuff somewhere?
LAURA: Yeah, that's what we're looking for.
LIAM: When you say too drunk, do
you mean "we" the adventurers
or the humans back in Los Angeles?
ORION: Both parties.
Cross-plane.
MARISHA: Cross-Realm.
ORION: And I tell them what happened, again.
SAM: What happened?
ORION: Well, I went to this door because--
SAM: Oh yes, yes, yes, yes.
MATT: You later rested, shot arcane magic
at the home of arcane magic in Kraghammer.
ORION: And if we are to go down into this cave,
perhaps they have some
insight into what's going on
there as well.
Especially at this point in.
LAURA: Let's hurry and try to get them
before they go to sleep.
MARISHA: Maybe they have magical items.
I want stuff.
ORION: And I priorly had luck with more than--
TRAVIS: Like plant stuff or potion stuff?
MARISHA: All stuff.
LIAM: Have you had any luck
finding an arcane--
LAURA: That's what we're talking about.
LIAM: No, I know that.
Did you send any fireballs at doors again
like you've done in the past, or--?
ORION: Yes, I knocked, as I do often do.
And nothing doing.
LAURA: All right.
LIAM: Got it.
TRAVIS: So, magic stuffs.
LAURA: Let's go find them.
TALIESIN: All right.
MARISHA: So wait--
it seems like they really
don't want you in their door.
It seems very heavily guarded.
So what's our plan, we
just going to try again?
LAURA: Well it was nighttime before.
Maybe they'll be more--
SAM: We're gonna do what we always do: wing it.
TALIESIN: We're gonna try it again,
except we're gonna watch this time.
It'll be fun.
MATT: There you go.
MARISHA: Let's do it.
LIAM: I walk back to the door, because we're all
just standing outside the door.
MATT: Correct.
LIAM: I walk back to Hieris's
door and knock on it
and poke my head in.
Hieris, I'm sorry.
MATT: You catch him with a
handful of dried fruit,
"Hmph!
"Hi!"
LIAM: Just a quick question.
We have no fucking idea what time it is.
Because we usually use the sun.
Do you know what hour it is?
Are businesses open at the moment?
MATT: He reaches over and grabs this
really awesomely intricate
piece of clockwork on his desk.
It's this brass, cylindrical
piece that as he pulls out
you hear this (tongue clicking), fring!
And springs and things making
strange whirring sounds.
"Oh, I reckon it's about
two hours from sunset."
ORION: Oh, very good.
LIAM: Are the stores open at the moment?
TRAVIS: Better question.
MATT: "As far as I know, aye.
"Depending on the store."
LIAM: How much time do we have left?
MATT: "Few hours."
LIAM: Oh, thank you, sir.
MATT: "You sure you don't want to stay?"
LIAM: Let's go shopping.
TRAVIS: Thank you, Hieris thank you.
Oh, gotta go, sorry.
MATT: "Goodbye."
MARISHA: It's the mine that never sleeps.
MATT: "Good luck."
LIAM: Byeee!
MATT: You hear the door open behind
you, and he starts waving
at you guys.
"Stay safe!"
TALIESIN: Stay regular.
MARISHA: Eat some veggies!
Fruit's bad for the diabetes!
TRAVIS: Oh, I put my head back
in the door,
and I throw him a turkey leg
and a beef jerky stick.
I gotta get rid of this stuff.
It's been in here for years.
TALIESIN: The fact that you just
checked your inventory
for that worries me.
TRAVIS: We gotta lotta shit in this bag.
MATT: The bag of holding, not so much a freezer.
TRAVIS: I didn't say it was good.
I just want it out.
MARISHA: And then you just throw it at him?
MATT: The mildly rotted turkey
leg (imitates moist impact)
across the floor.
The remainder of what was
once meat, now a slush
sloughing off the bone as it
slams across the stone floor.
TRAVIS: It's really tender.
LIAM: You're a goliath, you'll eat anything.
TRAVIS: Yeah, those are the best parts.
MATT: You see he immediately steps back
and his face squints back.
MARISHA: That's not polite, Grog.
TRAVIS: I gave him a turkey leg.
MATT: "It's the thought that counts."
As he closes his door.
ORION: Hold, hold on.
Before he does that, I
cast prestidigitation,
and I clean it up real quick.
MATT: Okay, that's really kind of you.
ORION: And I hand him a parchment and go,
if there's anything wrong,
just write the message on this,
and we'll come help.
If there's any emergency.
And I hand him a parchment from
the Scroll of Telescription
that I made.
MATT: "All right. Thank you kindly."
LAURA: How many pages is that scroll?
Is it endless?
ORION: I made like
15 tickets right now.
And it takes me an hour to craft.
MATT: He takes it from you with trepidation.
You can see he probably hasn't
encountered dragonborn often,
and he's like, "Thanks."
ORION: Remember, dragonborn, we're good.
MATT: "Right."
ORION: So long.
And I leave.
MATT: "Thank ye."
Closes the door.
LAURA: Do you want to go with him
to the enchanting place
or do you wanna go somewhere else?
LIAM: I think I will go with
him just to keep him
from setting fire to the entire city.
LAURA: All right, shall we all go to the manor?
TALIESIN: We have time, we might as well.
ORION: Are we iteming up first?
TALIESIN: I figure we do that after.
LAURA: I think we'll do that.
MARISHA: I'm gonna go ahead and
turn into a squirrel
and hide in your pocket.
LAURA: I like it.
MARISHA: Okay.
LAURA: Ugh, Grog.
TRAVIS: What, it was a burp!
(group laughs)
MATT: Technically in character.
TRAVIS: Much worse from the
other end, I guarantee.
SAM: Okay, so we're going
to House Thunderbeards?
Thunderbirds?
MATT: You guys head to the House Thunderbrand.
SAM: Brand.
MATT: All right.
So, Tiberius leads you
to where it's residing.
Once again you come upon
what looks like a very out of place,
very well-kept green lawn that
stretches for a good 60 feet
before you see this
really beautiful-looking
alabaster and gold building,
slightly domed with these
four towers to each corner,
with these blue
pointed crystals on top
of each tower.
LIAM: How does the grass grow down here?
LAURA: Can we see any traps or
glyphs that are active?
MATT: He points out
to you as you approach,
there are a series of stone
sigils carved into the stonework
that surrounds the exterior of the lawn.
ORION: Those things!
LAURA: Can we look around and
see if there's any way to,
a bell to ring that's
outside of that area.
MATT: Go ahead and make a perception check.
TALIESIN: Can I assist on that?
LAURA: Yeah, please do, 'cause I rolled a one.
One, baby.
TALIESIN: It's a 10.
LAURA: I failed it hard, I failed it.
TALIESIN: If you rolled a one, there's
nothing I can do anyway.
MATT: What'd you roll?
LIAM: We ain't found shit.
TRAVIS: She rolled a one.
MATT: Rolled a one naturally?
LAURA: I did.
MATT: Best you can tell,
stonework's pretty solid.
LAURA: Cool!
Hey, it's a house.
MATT: Yeah.
MATT: There are dwarves around. No.
TRAVIS: Good.
MATT: As you look about, it's
hard to tell the nature.
This looks just like a lawn
with a well-framed stone exterior.
LAURA: Cool.
MATT: But there's no fence.
There's nothing keeping you from walking
into the lawn and towards the building.
MARISHA: Can I do a nature check
to see what light source
is making all this grass grow,
or if it's like magical growing?
MATT: No nature check required.
There is no light source,
other than the green rocks
that generally permeate
the interior of Kraghammer
to give its kind of strange
luminescent atmosphere.
This kind of dull red glow
that's around the entire city.
Other than a couple of
sparks of lantern light.
There's no light source.
SAM: I wonder what Keyleth is doing.
She's squeaking an awful lot.
(Marisha imitates squirrel)
LAURA: Oh that's right, she's in my pocket.
Hi!
TRAVIS: So we just walk up and--
LAURA: Can I pet her little head.
ORION: No, I don't suggest that, Grog.
I shoot firebolt.
MATT: I forgot that wasn't water. (coughs)
TALIESIN: Did you actually try to walk up?
LIAM: Is there a front door?
TALIESIN: Perhaps you should,
before you do anything. Just try and walk up.
MATT: From what you can see,
There appears to be a large,
almost like beachwood,
Light wood double door in
the front of the compound.
LAURA: Grog's gonna go.
LIAM: I'm gonna use my rogue
abilities to walk up
to the front door, and knock on it.
ORION: Great.
LAURA: Sorry Grog.
TRAVIS: I have one job.
To take damage.
LIAM: Can I see if I detect a bell?
MARISHA: Is that a talent you
picked, is that a feat?
MATT: So, you walk towards the grass.
You step onto the walkway that leads
towards the front of the building.
As soon as you cross into the threshold
where those stone sigils are,
you make a dexterity saving throw.
(Travis laughs)
LAURA: Oh no.
Roll well, my brother.
LIAM: This is really not good
for their business.
[LIAM and LAURA groan]
(group laughs)
LIAM: 12.
MATT: 12.
LAURA: Oh no.
MATT: So, as you pull your cloak
around you and take a few steps
to jaunt upwards, suddenly
there's, you guys hear it.
The strange (tongue clicking) sound,
and a poof, poof of arcane
blue energy kind of,
just pulses around his feet.
You instinctively begin to
pull back, but as you do,
there's a blast of blue electric energy
that (imitates explosion),
streaks out from all around
you, shocking your body
and throwing you about 15 feet back,
straight onto your shoulders.
You (imitates grinding) skid
to a halt (imitates thud).
LIAM: Which one of these do I roll for damage?
TRAVIS: Electrified sound effect.
MATT: You take...
LIAM: Higigigigi!
MATT: 14 points of lightning damage.
LIAM: All right.
ORION: This is as I'm paused
telling him not to do that.
MATT: Yes.
ORION: Don't!
TRAVIS: Should've let me go.
MATT: Your muscles eventually relax.
ORION: As I was about to say,
that was going to happen.
TRAVIS: We have a flying carpet.
LAURA: Hey, we have a flying carpet!
We have a flying carpet.
ORION: Let me try one thing
that I didn't think to do last time.
I'm gonna cast Dispel
Magic on the runestone.
LIAM: Don't tase me, bro.
MATT: Okay.
Go ahead and--
TRAVIS: It's really not that bad.
MATT: Let's see.
LAURA: Pull it out.
TRAVIS: What?
LAURA: Pull out the flying--
MARISHA: Phrasing.
SAM: Going for the handbook.
MATT: Yeah, so we know what's going on.
TRAVIS: Oh, the magic carpet, hold on.
SAM: Guys, don't forget to
subscribe to Geek and Sundry.
LAURA: Oh yeah!
ORION: Oh, and I cast it at my fourth level slot.
TRAVIS: You wanna fly it up to the door?
MARISHA: What are you casting?
ORION: Dispel magic.
MATT: All right, make an arcana check.
LAURA: It can't carry you, you're too heavy.
TRAVIS: I said you, not me.
LAURA: Oh, gimme that flying carpet.
TRAVIS: That's what I said.
ORION: 13.
MATT: 13?
ORION: Yeah.
MATT: Okay.
As you concentrate and these
kind of shimmering bands
of arcane energy wave off your
hands toward the enchantment,
they impact and dissipate without effect.
ORION: Are they fourth level or higher?
MATT: They seem to be.
ORION: Fuck.
LAURA: I hop on the flying carpet.
MATT: Okay, so you pull the flying
carpet, Mary Poppins-style,
out of the bag of holding.
(imitates soft thud)
LAURA: Yes. And see if I can fly up
and over to the door.
TRAVIS: Do you wanna tie a rope
around your waist
in case it goes bad?
ORION: It's a flying magical carpet.
LAURA: Somebody.
Oh.
Is that bad?
Is that a bad idea?
TRAVIS: No, do it.
ORION: It's a flying magical carpet.
SAM: What could go wrong?
MARISHA: I think you'll just, like, hit a wall.
LAURA: What if the flying carpet gets ruined?
SAM: Let's not do that then.
TRAVIS: Oh my God, really?
LIAM: It's not gonna be ruined.
MARISHA: Wait, wait, wait, I'm in squirrel form.
So I go out.
LAURA: Oh, and you're with me.
Let's both fly to the door.
LIAM: I have nine healing potions--
SAM: Hey, hold on, hold on.
TRAVIS: What what, you turned invisible
and walked inside a house last time.
SAM: Yeah, I can do whatever we want.
Do you want me to knock on the door,
is that what we're trying to do?
LAURA: Oh yeah, use your--
SAM: Okay, so yes.
I send an unseen servant
to knock on the door.
TRAVIS: What kind, like a buddy?
LAURA: Oh, he tried it before.
MATT: Where do you create
the unseen servant?
SAM: Where do I create it?
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: Right on the doorknocker.
Like, hanging on the doorknocker.
TRAVIS: Feet touching the ground?
MATT: All right. So the distance unseen
servant can be summoned--
LAURA: Oh no.
MATT: I believe you may be able
to actually summon it
within the boundary of
those arcane sigils.
TRAVIS: I'm just sitting back
here holding the carpet.
I can show you the world
(group laughs)
MATT: 60 feet, so yeah.
You go ahead and you walk
up to where that sigil is,
you finish your spell,
you cast unseen servant.
SAM:  Unseen servant, ho
(group laughs)
MATT: Which he says every time.
SAM: Yes.
MATT: Every single time.
You see this strange shift of air
as some sort of humanoid
form then materializes
in the opposite side of this boundary
and stands at your ready and command.
SAM: We still haven't knocked
on the door, correct?
GROUP: No.
MATT: It's about a 60 foot walk.
SAM: I command the unseen servant
to (imitates knocking)
MATT: It kind of saunters over.
You guys see this kind of shifting,
barely, barely visible form make its way
up to the front door.
In the distance, you
hear a dull (knocking).
Eventually, the door slightly opens.
And you see a hunched figure
with bright white, chalk-white hair,
kind of look out the doorway,
"Oh, where's he come from?"
Looking at the form in front of him.
SAM: Oh, the ghost.
MATT: Yeah.
"That's where you come from.
All right."
SAM: Hello!
ORION: I'm waving.
Hello.
MATT: Opens the door, comes out.
You now see this dwarven
figure hunched, very, very old,
with a long, very, very
well-crafted brass staff,
looks like a black or
purple gem at the top.
Spectacles at the tip of its nose.
And it begins to kind of shift
its way over towards you.
(breathes heavily)
ORION: Watch out for that rune.
It's still on.
SAM: I think he knows that.
(laughing)
MATT: Eventually making its way.
TRAVIS: He's coming towards us?
MATT: Yes. Walks right to the edge of the sigil.
Puts his hand up, and the
unseen servant vanishes.
He goes, "So, you have my attention."
ORION: Well, it's a pleasure to meet you.
My name's Tiberius Stormwind,
and these are my friends.
MATT: He puts his hand up and there's no sound
coming out of your mouth.
(Travis laughs)
SAM: Maybe we should listen.
MATT: "This is the one who would-be
attacked our home abode
not more than a few hours ago."
SAM: He has emotional problems.
MATT: "Apparently.
He needs to learn respect
for other people's property."
LAURA: Yes, he does.
LIAM: We agree wholeheartedly.
He's dragonborn, he's weird.
He's a little weird.
We're sorry to interrupt.
I don't know, it's dinnertime, I think.
I don't know if you've
heard yet, it just happened.
We just fought some sort
of many-headed beast
down at the mines, and Lord Greyspine
is sending us in.
So before we go, we were sent here.
We were told you were
the dwarf to speak to
if we needed--
LAURA: To know about the magical entities.
LIAM: I think it was just to get shit.
(Travis and Sam laugh)
LIAM: To get ready for those entities.
MATT: "If you're looking to but
trinkets and magical oddities--
LAURA: Trinkets!
MATT: "You've come to the wrong place.
"This is a house of study.
"This is where hardworking
dwarves of arcane persuasion
"put their lives towards pursuing--
TRAVIS: Say something!
MATT: "--the magical forms and fields that--
SAM: And we have come to seek your knowledge.
MATT: "I'm sorry."
Your sound is back.
ORION: That's what I'm trying to
say is that I came here
looking to ask about the arcane studies.
I'm extremely interested in that.
When I heard that your house
Was the only one that was
in that particular study,
I was immensely intrigued.
I respect the arcane
arts so much that it's,
well, it's been my life.
And right now, we're in bit of a situation
where we have to go
slaughter a bunch of nasties
in apparently one of your mines.
And we don't know the source.
And it appears to be of
an extreme arcane nature
of the dark sense, and I
figured we could come to you
for help and some kind of guidance.
And I will-- Scanlan, will you stop it!
And it appears that you
very well know something
that we could learn from, with
all due respect, of course.
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
MARISHA: Holy shit. What the fuck.
Breathe.
ORION: 11.
TRAVIS: God, what is with these rolls?
TALIESIN: We've been middling.
LAURA: Terrible rolls today.
MATT: The dwarf gives you
a disapproving brow shift
and goes, "Look, I mean no disrespect.
"But understand, this is a dwarven house
"of arcane practitioning and study.
"Don't see any dwarves among ya.
"I think our business here is concluded."
"If you're looking to buy stuff, we produce
"and sell through the Value
of Valor house of sale."
TRAVIS: Oh Tiberius, can't you become a dwarf?
TALIESIN: Of course, sir, we completely understand
if you're not up to such a challenge.
It makes perfect sense, and
we'll be more than happy to go
and buy some wares somewhere else
if this is too much for you.
MATT: "Bah! Challenge."
ORION: I will send you my associate.
The dwarf turns around
and begins walking away
with his staff.
LAURA: What a beautiful staff that is.
ORION: I'm gonna cast Alter Self
on myself to be a dwarf.
TRAVIS: And jump behind me,
and act like you just--
LAURA: Actually sir, we do have a dwarf with us.
MARISHA: No wait wait wait! Cast it on me!
I'm a squirrel in her pocket.
ORION: Oh shit, I cast it on her instead.
(loud thudding)
LAURA: We have a dwarf with us who wanted
to actually say hello to--
TRAVIS: (whispering) What's your dwarf name?
MATT: Turns around. Saunters back.
ORION: Keyleth, where have you been?
MARISHA: I guess it's Keyleth.
MATT: Looks at you.
TRAVIS: Keyleth Kraghammer.
SAM: You better fucking speak dwarvish.
MATT: Smiles for a second as
he looks at you and goes,
"Ah, how nice to meet you.
"Where are you from?"
MARISHA: (bad Scottish accent) Oh, hello.
(group laughs)
LAURA: Oh, shit.
(Liam speaks in
Swedish-accented gibberish)
SAM: Ya, from Sweden.
TRAVIS: I'm gonna choke on a chip. (coughs)
MARISHA: Keyleth is not good at this.
LIAM: Roll with it player, roll with it.
MARISHA: I hail from the mountains up north.
ORION: She had an accident on the way over here.
We were hoping maybe--
MATT: Roll a persuasion roll with disadvantage.
(all talking and laughing)
MATT: You. Roll with disadvantage.
LIAM: Let the dice act better
than us tonight, please.
(group laughs)
TRAVIS: (high-pitched voice) Oh, hello!
MARISHA: Wait, persuasion--I don't have--oh, wait.
I have a zero.
Eight.
MATT: That's your first roll.
Now roll again.
MARISHA: Oh, I have advantage.
MATT: No, you have disadvantage.
MARISHA: Oh, disadvantage.
So eight.
MATT: Eight.
He goes, "I've been
practicing the arcane arts
"for over 250 years.
MARISHA: And I've been practicing
my Cornwall accent
for five minutes.
Shit.
MATT: He raises his hand,
and the Alter Self spell dissipates.
Where stands Keyleth.
SAM: Oh Keyleth, you've been
lying to us this whole time?
(Travis laughs)
ORION: Who are you?
SAM: We thought you were a dwarf.
LIAM: Vax steps forward, steps in
front of Keyleth and says,
Good sir dwarf.
Clearly we are idiots.
We are--
MATT: "That's the first true thing you've said
"since you've called me out of my home."
LIAM: Stay with me on this.
We are strangers in a strange land.
However, we are working
with Lord Greyspine
to empty your mines and end the evil
that is spewing forth from them.
Now I know that we are a bit stupid--
(group laughs)
--in a number of ways.
LAURA: But we fight well.
LIAM: But we fight well, and we
have the best of intentions,
and when it counts, we're there.
We just need a little bit of
help going into the mines.
And again, Lord Greyspine himself sent us,
so please excuse my--
TALIEISIN: Cornwall?
LIAM: --challenged friends.
TRAVIS: My cornhole friends.
LIAM: We're here to help.
I promise.
TRAVIS: That's a very Disney moment.
LIAM: Wink, wink, wink.
LAURA: I wink twice.
Make a persuasion roll at disadvantage.
LAURA: Can I assist him 'cause I winked?
MATT: No.
LAURA: Damn it.
TRAVIS: It's a powerful wink.
MATT: It's a powerful wink,
but not this powerful.
Not the way this
conversation's been going.
TRAVIS: Yeah, apparently not.
Oh hello!
LIAM: Best roll of the night.
I rolled a 20 and a 17.
So 19.
MATT: 19.
He glares at you two and goes,
"I've said my piece.
Good luck to you all."
(group groans)
SAM: Further.
LAURA: If you had gotten the 20.
LIAM: How about a chocolate-covered mallomar?
SAM: I'm gonna have one more try at this.
MATT: He turns around and starts walking away.
SAM: There must be so many
arcane things down there
that we will discover and bring to you
upon finding them.
LAURA: Good call, Scanlan.
SAM: Things that you could
use for your research.
Historical items.
MATT: As he's still walking
away, you hear him shout
over his shoulder,
"And when you bring them, then we'll talk!"
SAM: Okay, that's fair.
MATT: "Till then, good day, and don't bother me
when I'm eating."
LAURA: Thank you, Lord Thunderclap.
LIAM: This game has consequences.
MATT: At which he shouts again
at a booming, booming
prestidigitation voice,
"It's THUNDERBRAND!"
LAURA: That's what I meant.
MATT: You hear the door slam, boom!
TRAVIS: That was fun.
SAM: That was great!
LAURA: Should we go buy some potions then?
TALIESIN: Yes, let's go buy some potions.
SAM: He gave us a little bit of information.
The valve of valva, what's it? Valor of -
TRAVIS: Vulva?
SAM: The place to place to go buy potions.
ORION: The House of Valor.
SAM: No, the valva--
ORION: It's not the
House of Vulva, Scanlan.
MATT: The Value of Valor.
LAURA AND SAM: The Value of Valor!
TRAVIS: If you want to visit the House of Vulva,
you and I can go later but not now.
LAURA: The Value of Valor, let's go find that.
ORION: (in Marisha's bad accent)
Let's go to the North.
MARISHA: I'm sorry.
I didn't think about the fact that I was
gonna have to do an accent.
I'm not good with that stuff.
LAURA: It's okay, Keyleth.
TRAVIS: Women, fighting, ale, that's my job.
MATT: So after a bit of discussion,
you manage to make your way
around town.
You eventually find your
way to the Value of Valor,
which is a--
LAURA: Terrible.
MATT: (laughs) It's a stone building.
Like reddish brick,
it looks in construction.
With fine purple--
LAURA: Please be open, please
be open, please be open.
MATT: (laughs) Fine purple
tapestries in the front
that show various battles
of old dwarven history
of two glowing enchanted
permalight lanterns
hanging from the front.
TALIESIN: Classy.
MATT: And an entryway that is currently open
and a warmly-lit interior welcomes you.
TRAVIS: Awesome.
LIAM: So easy.
SAM: Hey, before we go in there
and just make asses of ourselves,
As a group, what do you
think we need to get down
into these mines?
LAURA: Potions.
TALIESIN: Healing potions.
SAM: Healing potions.
Some light sources--
ORION: We don't need that.
SAM: Climbing anything?
LAURA: I have climbing gear.
SAM: I have some climbing gear, but--
LAURA: That's included in
the dungeoneering kit, right?
MATT: Yes.
SAM: Oh, what about something for breathing?
SAM: Like what if we get trapped
down there with no air?
ORION: Don't worry about that.
LAURA: She can make plants, and
we'll get plenty of oxygen.
MARISHA: Oxygen's good, although
if we have something
to help with poison, that might be good.
Can we get some antidotes?
LIAM: Vex.
How much gold do we have at the moment?
LAURA: That is a wonderful question, brother.
ORION: By the way, I pull out a bottle of air.
Just an empty bottle and
go: and plus, we have this.
LAURA: We will more than double our
gold if we take this mission.
TRAVIS: So we got like 24,000 gold pieces?
LAURA: Less than that.
TRAVIS: 23 thousand.
TRAVIS: 22 thousand?
LIAM: More than double, that means
it could be one thousand.
'Cause anything is more than double.
LAURA: I don't like sharing.
TRAVIS: Math is stupid.
SAM: All right, we go into the House of Vulva.
MATT: All right.
SAM: Open your vulva!
MATT: That's not what it's called.
(group laughs)
TRAVIS: Are you sure you don't wanna
think about renaming it now?
MATT: It's the Value of Valor guys, come on! (whines)
MATT: All right, so.
TALIESIN: You're tearing the party apart.
LIAM: Tearing me apart, Lisa.
MATT: A giant boulder falls out of nowhere
and crushes Grog.
(group laughs)
MATT: So you make your way inside.
Suddenly, hit with the smell
of heavy incense and jasmine.
This is the equivalent of
a Psychic Eye Bookshop.
ORION: Groovy!
MARISHA: Oh, we were just there.
TALIESIN: We were just there.
TRAVIS: Nag champa.
MATT: You walk inside.
There's not a lot of folks inside
looking about the establishment.
But there is one person
sitting at the front desk,
which is a beautiful long oak table
with a red trim
that hangs to the ceiling.
Not a dwarf, actually.
What you see there appears
to be an elven individual,
sitting at wait, hair
pulled back behind the ears.
Very, very slight, thin build.
And smiles as you enter and says,
"Welcome to my establishment,
may I help you?"
LAURA: We both stand a little taller,
and try to look more noble.
LIAM: Hello.
MATT: "Yes."
LIAM: It's a beautiful shop you have.
It's so startling to find
an elven establishment here
in the middle of Kraghammer.
How did this come about?
MATT: "Well.
"They didn't have one."
(Travis and Sam laugh)
"And I found there was
perhaps money to be made
"in starting one.
"I've been here for over a hundred years."
TRAVIS: Oh sh--
Are you guys that old?
LIAM: No, we are not.
ORION: So business is good?
MATT: "Dwarves have a hard time
"buying from those
who are not dwarves.
"But I've made my established connections
with business individuals.
"So, what can I help you with?
TALIESIN: We're in the market for
some healing potions
to start with.
TRAVIS: Yep, yep.
MATT: "Of which intensity are you looking for?"
TRAVIS:: Level three for this one, please.
Two.
MATT: "So looking for a superior healing potion."
TRAVIS: Yeah, superior.
MATT: "I've only got two of those currently."
LAURA: They're expensive, Grog.
MARISHA: We don't have Pike, though.
MATT: "I can sell you the two
superior healing potions."
MARISHA: I'm still not feeling well.
MATT: "Those will run you 1,500 gold pieces each."
TRAVIS: Fuck!
Really?!
TALIESIN: This is why you buy
medium healing potions.
MARISHA: On second thought, I'll just
read some books tonight,
TRAVIS: I take damage fast.
MARISHA: Refresh myself on my healing spells.
LAURA: Can I ask your name?
MATT: He gives you a keen
look and says, "Tremaine."
LAURA: Tremaine.
TRAVIS: Oh, here we go.
(Liam and Taliesin laugh)
MARISHA: It's what she's good at.
TRAVIS: Everybody take five while we haggle.
LAURA: I'm just saying.
We're heading into the mines.
We are going to encounter very many
arcane objects potentially.
In fact, Lord Thunderbrand
sent us over here.
That's his name, right?
TRAVIS: You got it.
TALIESIN: You did it right.
LAURA: Sent us over here telling
us to find his wares here.
And we've made a deal with him
that if we find arcane
objects we could potentially,
you know, I lost track
of what I was saying,
but you get the idea.
SAM: Oh boy.
ORION: What would you suggest?
And do you know of any
things we should particularly
buy before we leave going into the mines
and encountering nasty naga-type creatures
and other kind of things.
MATT: "Superior healing potions."
TRAVIS: How much are they each, 1500?
MATT: "1500 gold pieces."
TRAVIS: I'll take one for me, thank you.
MATT: "Very well."
LAURA: We'll very much like to
perhaps make a deal with you,
that we'll bring you
objects of arcane nature
for a discount on your wares.
MATT: Make a persuasion roll.
TRAVIS: Oh shit.
I just paid for--
LAURA: Oh, no you didn't.
Not yet.
LIAM: Roll, sister.
LAURA: Oh, come on, no whammies, no whammies.
Okay, well.
15, hm?
TRAVIS: He's an old elf.
MATT: He says,
"And I appreciate this perhaps offer.
"Once you return from your mines--"
LAURA: I know, I know, I know.
MATT: "--with these magical accoutrements,
you are more than welcome
to bring them here,
and we'll make a deal.
LAURA: How many dragons have
you come across, sir?
Are you interested in dragon parts?
TRAVIS: Oh, we have a lot of dragon bits.
MATT: He extends his hand to a shelf on the side
labeled, "Dragon Parts."
LAURA: Oh.
(group laughs)
LAURA: Lovely.
MATT: "And to answer your question, three."
LAURA: Oh, really?
TRAVIS: What about basilisk eggs?
LAURA: What kind of dragons, actually?
MATT: "What was your question, sir?"
TRAVIS: We have also, if you're
interested in trade,
basilisk eggs and parts of an umber hulk.
LIAM: And a troll dick.
TRAVIS: No, that's gone.
(group laughs)
TRAVIS: We flogged him with it
and then it disappeared.
LIAM: I detract my offer.
TRAVIS: It was used very well.
MATT: He gives you a very concerned look.
TRAVIS: I'm a collector of sorts.
MATT: Both of you. And he goes,
And he goes,
"I work in trade, meaning
gold pieces for my wares."
LAURA: Yes.
MATT: "If you have interest, purchase.
"If not, I have other
business to attend to."
SAM: Any other healing potions to buy?
Come on people.
LAURA: Maybe a moderate.
LIAM: All right, well friends,
we're about to descend
into hell itself,
so I reckon we should probably
pay the price.
TALIESIN: Two moderates.
MATT: Greater. In the new edition.
TALIESIN: Greater.
MARISHA: How much are the greaters?
MATT: "The greater healing potions
run 300 gold apiece."
LAURA: Oh, let's get a few of those.
TRAVIS: I need like three of those.
MATT: "So, three?"
TRAVIS: Yeah, three.
LAURA: Do you have any arrows that--
TRAVIS: Well let's do the potions first.
LAURA: Okay okay okay, two for me.
MATT: "So, five."
TALIESIN: Two for me as well.
MATT: "Seven."
TRAVIS: Keyleth.
MARISHA: I'll take one.
MATT: "Eight."
TRAVIS: Tiberius?
MATT: "Anyone else require a
moderate healing potion?"
TRAVIS: Tiberius?
ORION: I could take one.
MATT: Pathfinder to 5E.
TRAVIS: Scanlan?
SAM: Well, do we have ours leftover
from what we had before?
[LAURA, TRAVIS, MATT] Yes.
SAM: Then I'm fine.
TRAVIS: Vax?
LAURA: He's Vax.
LIAM: No, I'm good actually.
TRAVIS: Oh, my intelligence is six.
LIAM: I'm so fast I don't
really use them that much.
TRAVIS: So nine.
LIAM: You'll get to that point as well.
LAURA: Nine potions then.
TRAVIS: Nine times 300, work that out.
MATT: As he pulls up his arcane calculator.
LAURA: So 2500 for all nine then.
TALIESIN: It's an abacus, God, abacus!
TRAVIS: I believe it's 2700 gold pieces?
LAURA: Why would you do that?
I was trying to make him--
MATT: "It is 27."
MATT: He says, "Impressive for a goliath.
"I don't mean to assume,
but in my experiences,
"your kind is--
TRAVIS: It's Professor Grog, actually.
ORION: All right, calm down.
MATT: "2700 gold pieces for your
nine greater healing potions."
LAURA: All right, 27.
Do you have any arrows
that perhaps have magical properties?
ORION: Enchanted arrows is
what she's asking for.
LAURA: Yes.
MATT: He kind of glances over
his shoulder and says,
"Ah, we haven't had much a
request for arrows in a while.
"We have bolts for crossbows,
as that seems to be the staple
"for the carvers of the city.
"I have two sleep arrows,
perhaps, if that is
"of interest to you."
ORION: Yes they would be, very much.
LAURA: And what would you charge for those, sir?
TALIESIN: Ooh, I should build
some interesting arrows.
MARISHA: You should.
MATT: Arrows.
(whispering and muttering)
MATT: "That would run you 250 gold per arrow.
"I have two currently."
LAURA: All right, all right, I'll take 'em.
MATT: "All right, 500 gold.
"With that, that is a
total of 3200 gold pieces."
TRAVIS: Scanlan, underwater breathing
or air, oxygen supplies?
ORION: Dear sir, have you happened upon any--
TRAVIS: Ask with your fancy talk.
ORION: --relic or artifact around here, or heard
of something called the Pale Stone?
LAURA: Sorry, you have to watch us buy things.
ORION: This is a rare artifact
I've been looking for
for quite some time.
ORION: I figured an environment
like this might lend to something.
LAURA: What is it a mess you've made?
MATT: "I don't believe I have, but
should you come across one,
"I would be interested to have a look."
ORION: Oh, you appraise?
MATT: "If you don't mind."
ORION: Very good.
SAM: And do you have anything
for adventuring underwater
or for helping to breathe in tight spaces?
MATT: "Mm, potion of waterbreathing,
I do happen to have."
SAM: A potion of waterbreathing?
MATT: "Yes, I do."
SAM: How much?
MATT: "I have four of them available,
"and they run 500 gold apiece."
SAM: Jesus.
TRAVIS: We'll take it.
We got all this platinum I forgot about.
SAM: Take one, two, one?
LAURA: Don't say that!
TRAVIS: He can't hear--
ORION: I don't need one.
I bring out my bottle of air.
And I go, "I have this."
And I put it back in.
SAM: I'm okay as well.
You want one, Grog?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
SAM: All right, we'll just take one of those.
TRAVIS: Just one?
SAM: Well, I don't need it.
He doesn't need it.
TRAVIS: We'll take two.
SAM: Two.
MATT: "1000 gold.
"That brings us to 4200 gold."
LAURA: Wait, 42?
MATT: "Yes."
LIAM: Have you any elven gear
for a son of Syngorn?
LAURA: Are you taking it off of your pot now?
TRAVIS: Yep.
MATT: He gives you a keen look and goes,
"We don't get many requests for this,
"but I think this may fit you."
And he reaches below and
pulls up a fine piece
of mithril chain, elven in make.
LAURA: That's what I'm wearing.
MATT: Mm hm.
TRAVIS: Show-off.
MATT: He says, "Would you perhaps
"be interested in this elven chain?"
LIAM: It's beautiful.
I am a bit of a light-footed one.
Would it suit me?
MATT: "Hm.
"Chain does make a bit of a racket.
"Might not recommend it, unfortunately."
LIAM: All right.
I'll pass.
TRAVIS: You couldn't buy it for me?
LAURA: It won't fit you, it's for elves.
LIAM: You're gigantic.
TRAVIS: Could go on my pinky or something.
LAURA: All right, cool.
LIAM: Could fit on your left nut.
LAURA: Well, thanks.
TRAVIS: That's an important nut.
MATT: He goes ahead and accepts your gold.
Go ahead and mark off 4200 gold for those.
LAURA: I did already.
MATT: All right, very well.
"Thank you for your patronage.
"I look forward to
hopefully having you back
"when you return with whatever
artifacts you manage to find."
TRAVIS: Thank you, you're very nice.
LAURA: Big expensive artifacts.
TALIESIN: I say, you're one of
the most charming people
we've met so far down here.
TRAVIS: And it smells pretty in here.
MATT: "Well of course, they
come in rare ordinance
in this city, it seems."
You hear under his breath
a little bit of a mutter.
Apparently it's like elves
don't like dwarves, it's weird.
TRAVIS: Do we sleep before we get to go kill shit?
TALIESIN: We're gonna go sleep.
TRAVIS: Well can we go do that?
LAURA: Let's go sleep and then
get up in the morning
and go down and kill things.
TALIESIN: And I'd love to do a crafting roll
right before I go to sleep
just to put together a little thing.
MATT: What would you like to put together?
TALIESIN: I'd like to try and build a
bolo arrow, a trapping arrow.
TRAVIS: Yeah!
MATT: Interesting, okay.
As you guys head back to the inn
where you've rented rooms for the week,
TRAVIS: You clever fucker.
MATT: Which would be at the Iron Hearth Tavern.
TRAVIS: Is Ballsack in there?
When we walk in?
MATT: Balgus is not in the tavern, no.
TRAVIS: He's not?
ORION: He's Balgus, Grog.
MATT: No, sorry.
TRAVIS: Really?
MATT: He's got a home.
TRAVIS: Yeah, but doesn't mean
he have to go to it.
MATT: True.
LAURA: I walk Trinket down into the storage area
that he can stay in.
MATT: [bear noise] Trinket goes down begrudgingly.
ORION: Damn it.
LAURA: I look around for something that can
look like a pillow for him.
MATT: You find a couple of sacks of grain
that can probably work.
LAURA: I put them down and
make them comfy for him.
MATT: Okay, you think they're probably
not gonna last the night
with those bear claws.
But you don't care, it's not your grain.
LAURA: That's fine.
Also, I feed him.
MATT: Okay, Trinket is very happy.
(imitates bear eating)
Tears into some meat.
You guys make it back to the
tavern for an evening's rest.
For you--
TALIESIN: Not a super complicated thing,
but, you know, I've gotta--
MATT: Go ahead and make a Tinker's Kit roll.
TALIESIN: What am I rolling with my Tinker's Kit?
I've never done this before.
MATT: For this, I would go ahead
and make it an intellect
modifier to your roll.
TALIESIN: Intellect modifier?
TRAVIS: Rock that shit, Perce.
TALIESIN: And I'm spending my bonus die as well.
LAURA: Oh, we have bonus die, don't we?
From Scanlan.
TALIESIN: Thank God, because I rolled really badly.
10.
MATT: 10?
You spend and toil away for
the next four or so hours
trying to find a way to
get this trigger to work.
Twice you nearly sprain a finger.
You manage seemingly get it to function,
then the arrow itself splits and shatters.
You can see there being something to it,
but this night it's not
gonna come to you.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna have to try again later.
Okay, that's fine.
It's on the list.
That was a terrible roll.
MATT: It was a terrible roll.
MARISHA: It's been a bad day for rolls.
It's been bad day for rolling.
LAURA: Fresh start in the morning.
SAM: Well, tomorrow is the day that it counts,
because that's when we
begin to crack some heads.
LAURA: When we could die.
TALIESIN: Out with this system, new dice.
MARISHA: To be fair, it's been a long day.
I'm still bleeding everywhere.
SAM: Should we rest and get on with it?
LAURA: Let's do it!
SAM: Or should we visit some whorehouses?
TRAVIS: Nah, let's sleep.
SAM: Let's just sleep tonight.
LAURA: Just sleep and go.
TRAVIS: Oh, they're still tired
from the other night.
SAM: Oh yes, one of them battered me quite--
TRAVIS: I don't know what this is.
SAM: That's me getting beaten
up by a whore dwarf.
TRAVIS: Oh, it's you getting the elbow drop.
TRAVIS: She's giving you the Randy Savage
from the bedpost.
TRAVIS: Oh yeah!
(crosstalk)
TRAVIS: We're sleeping now.
MATT: All right.
So you guys go to sleep.
Wake up the next morning
fully healed, spells restored,
well rested and ready for the day.
You think it's day.
It's hard to tell.
Still, this underground
circumstance is really
messing with you guys.
SAM: Well, should we go plunder some mines
and kill some goblins?
LAURA: Let's do it.
TALIESIN: Let's go plunder some mines.
TRAVIS: So we head down to the mines.
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: To the hole.
TRAVIS:  Takin' it to the hole
MATT: You make your way
down to the bottom ring of Kraghammer.
To the mines proper.
The miners have gone back to work,
and from what you can see,
there's just an all around crazy business
with people cleaning out, still trying
to clean out the ichor
that's on the ground
left over from the battle
you guys had the day before.
You make your way
to the front of the mines,
and immediately three of the
carvers that are standing
at the front approach
as you begin to walk,
and then upon noticing you, kind of like,
step back and put their
weapons to the side.
TRAVIS: Yep.
MATT: Acknowledging the orders they received
from Lord Greyspine.
LAURA: Oh, Trinket's with us.
MATT: Trinket has come along with you.
SAM: Trinket the bear, Trinket the bear.
LAURA: I just saw that, don't forget Trinket.
I didn't forget Trinket.
MATT: I assume Trinket comes with
you unless you say otherwise.
MATT: In general.
TRAVIS: Are they especially bowing
to Scanlan the snake slayer?
MATT: (laughs)
No.
(group laughs)
TRAVIS: No love!
MATT: They're busy working.
MATT: And fair play to the
gnome, but they're dwarves.
SAM: Sure.
ORION: Yeah.
They see that crap all the time.
MATT: You make your way into the mine proper.
It goes back for a good
10 minutes of walking
and of winding.
You can see the actual track
of the minetrack leading around.
You come upon a couple
of dwarves that
look over their shoulders
begrudgingly at you guys
as you pass going, "Hey?
Eh, shh," and go right back into
mining whatever remains
in the inside of this.
It looks like this portion of the mine
has been nearly picked clean.
The dwarves that are in there
are probably just wasting time
to get their pay for the day.
You go further back and
eventually it opens up.
I think I have the map available.
LIAM: I've got it right here.
SAM: It's over there.
MATT: Cool.
SAM: Can you put it so that the people can see?
LAURA: Oh, yeah.
SAM: Is that a thing?
TRAVIS: They can't see that.
MATT: We can put it on there perhaps.
For the most part I'll be
describing it as you go,
so it's not too important.
LAURA: Okay.
TALIESIN: Looks like Italy.
MATT: Yes.
TRAVIS: It's a boot.
MARISHA: It's the boot, yeah.
MATT: Following it, you get
to a portion of the mine
that is very busy.
You can see, since this is
probably one of the portions
that wasn't collapsed
in previous incursions
buy whatever creatures these were,
you get the feeling that
this one has basically taken
most of their workforce to try and find
and carve a new vein.
Or find a new path to pull things from.
You get towards the portion
where all these dwarves are working,
and you notice that some of
the doors have been shattered,
knocked off the hinges.
You imagine whatever creatures
were barreling through before,
this is probably where they came through.
LAURA: All right.
TALIESIN: That's where we're going.
TRAVIS: Make an arcane check.
Somebody with arcane.
LAURA: Oh yeah, can I look around?
Perception.
MATT: You look around.
What are you looking for?
LAURA: I'm looking for, you know.
(group laughs)
TRAVIS: Be specific.
TALIESIN: 15 arcana check.
LAURA: Scratch marks for anything.
MARISHA: I like the idea of magic perception.
TALIESIN: I just wanna see if
there's anything familiar
about the markings,
if I can identify
any signs of something mystical
that's come through here.
TRAVIS: Like a portal or a prison or a--
MATT: That'd be more of an investigation roll.
TALIESIN: Oh, well, alright.
LAURA: I'm gonna look for tracks.
MATT: Okay.
That'll be an investigation
roll for you as well.
MARISHA: I'm gonna assist her,
look for animal tracks.
LAURA: I'm scared, I don't
know which one to roll.
Both my die have been rolling so bad.
ORION: I want to detect magic for a while.
MATT: All right.
(loud thud)
MATT: Aid roll, Keyleth?
LAURA: This one is no longer in service.
TALIESIN: Oh, wow!
MARISHA: Five.
TRAVIS: Well hers is a lot better.
MARISHA: Good.
LIAM: Sorry, I've got the map,
so I'm looking at the mine.
Are we still in the dwarven carved out,
sort of structure portion of the mine.
MATT: You are.
You have just essentially
started on that map.
SAM: So let's go down.
LIAM: Guys, I'm holding a map.
I see one room that
they've scrawled "Supply" on,
so it should be the next right up ahead.
I'd like to just take a peek in there
and see what we can see
before we head deeper in.
MATT: All right, you are--?
LAURA: I rolled a one again.
MATT: A natural one.
LAURA: A natural one.
Vax and I get dressed up
in Sherlock Holmes cosplay,
and we say, "Golly gee, I
think I see some animal tracks
"over here."
TALIESIN: They are staring at their
own footprints on the ground.
MARISHA: "The trail's going cold!"
TALIESIN: Following around in a circle.
MATT: Oh man, this has turned completely back
from the first game.
You guys are failing consistently.
LAURA: Everything.
MATT: Let's turn this around,
let's turn this around.
LIAM: Anyhow, I've got a map, so let's use this.
Stay on point here.
MATT: You make your way
towards the supply room as you
head to where it was.
One of the dwarves is guarding it.
Not a carver, just one of
the miners that was hired
for this purpose is standing there.
Leads you into the door,
kind of opening it for you,
awkwardly going, "All right,
whatever you're looking for, fine.
"Go inside."
Looking inside, there are
just racks and racks and racks
of pickaxes, shovels, utensils
for the purpose of mining
and constructing.
There are wooden boards lying down.
There are just giant barrels
of nails and clipping utensils,
and things that are used
in the continuous expansion
of a mine.
LIAM: I've seen enough.
We should keep going.
(group laughs)
This map says that there's an elevator
a short ways up.
LAURA: That goes down.
LIAM: That goes down.
But then there's a railway
that goes further in
into the caves, so I'm not sure.
LAURA: We should probably go down.
MARISHA: Yeah, I feel like going down.
LIAM: Elevator straight down?
MARISHA: Let's go further, all the way down.
SAM: How many of us can the elevator hold?
MATT: Elevator can pretty much
hold all of you guys.
SAM: Okay, let's go.
LIAM: It's a safe assumption
that Lady Kima did not just
walk to the back of the upper floors,
she probably went down.
SAM: Yeah, let's go down, come on!
LIAM: Get shit done, let's go.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: Let's do it.
MARISHA: Get low.
TRAVIS: Air high five.
LIAM: We have a map to the elevator.
TRAVIS: Make 10.
MATT: As you guys are walking over
to where the elevator is,
you do notice there are
two places in the mines
where there is just large piles of rubble.
And part of the ceiling has collapsed.
You can see that there were portions
where the mine expanded much
deeper into the mountain
that were detonated or
collapsed in the idea
of preventing any further incursion by
whatever these creatures
are pouring through.
You also can see that there
are some dwarven corpses
being loaded out from the mine below,
as well as goblin corpses,
individuals that were caught in the attack
that happened yesterday before it managed
to emerge from the mine.
LIAM: Scanlan, are you all right
around these goblin corpses?
LAURA: We should follow those.
SAM: Any goblin corpse is a good goblin, I say.
I'm fine with it.
I'll just quickly spit on their bodies
as they go by.
MATT: And you do so quite quickly (spits).
It's rapid, it's amazing.
LAURA: So we follow the corpses
and see where they're coming from.
MATT: All right. So that heads away
from the elevator.
SAM: No no no, no no no.
That's being taken to be
buried, let's just keep--
LAURA: No no no, where
they're coming from.
SAM: Oh.
LIAM: So we could either go
to the rear of the mine
on this level and see
where they're coming from.
LAURA: I thought we already went downstairs?
LIAM: No, not yet.
MATT: There's a spiral staircase on the map.
On the lower right hand side.
LIAM: Yes, I see it.
MATT: That's where they're coming from.
LAURA: Does that lead down probably?
MATT: It seems to.
LAURA: Well then let's take
the elevator, whatever.
Let's go down.
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: You should put it under the thing.
TALIESIN: We're good with down.
MATT: You guys go ahead and
approach the elevator.
It's a large wooden platform
with a series of chains.
My terrible, hastily
drawn map there for you.
TRAVIS: It's kinda crap, but it's kinda great.
MATT: Yeah, I know.
It was actually more
designed as a DM utensil,
but you guys needed a map--
TRAVIS: I love it.
MATT: --so I gave you my map.
TRAVIS: There you go.
LAURA: Take it back.
MATT: So I'm taking it back.
(group laughs)
ORION: Give it to me.
MATT: It's-a mine.
No, I'm keeping it.
It's all right.
So you get back to the elevator.
There's a large 15 by 20
platform with a series of chains
and there are two dwarves in the back
that run a giant iron wheel.
As you approach, they kind
of give you a look, like,
"Well, are you serious about going down?"
[Travis, Laura, and Marisha] Yeah.
MATT: "Okay, step on the platform."
LAURA: Let's do it.
The two dwarves grab and begin
to rotate the giant wheel,
as it does you here the winch
and the chain begin to tighten
as it does.
The platform shudders for a second,
begins to lower.
As it begins to lower, you
can feel the actual platform
shake a little bit
as the whole weight
is placed on the chains.
TALIESIN: Guys. We're on an elevator.
MARISHA: This is scary.
ORION: I love elevators.
MATT: As the winch begins to release, it--
LAURA: I pet Trinket, calm him down.
MARISHA: I've never been on
one of these before.
MATT: Trinket is a little nervous.
MARISHA: It's really tight.
TALIESIN: I'm on an elevator with a bear.
MARISHA: It's really dark, tight.
ORION: Oh, light! (snaps)
TALIESIN: Thank you.
LAURA: Are we down yet?
MARISHA: Keyleth's getting a little claustrophobic.
She's never been in this tight of a space.
TRAVIS: Are you claustrophobic?
MATT: As the light spell bursts
out from his staff.
You all kind of have to
cover your eyes for a second.
But the lower area is opened up.
LIAM: Word of warning, Tiberius.
LAURA: Can we see out?
ORION: She said it was dark,
and then I cast my spell.
TRAVIS: Yeah, it's what you do.
MATT: (imitates loud thudding) You
guys hit the bottom floor.
You step off the platform, and you can see
there is a secondary minecart
that leads from this elevator
that curves to the left and leads deeper
into the mine proper.
To the right of you is
the spiral staircase.
And you can see now two
of the other miner dwarves
are dragging a dead body across.
LAURA: Can I look for goblin tracks
down here and follow those?
MATT: (laughs) You can attempt
another investigation check.
SAM: Why don't we just ask the dwarves
where they were getting the bodies?
TRAVIS: You're gonna roll crap.
You're gonna roll crap.
LAURA: Don't curse me.
MARISHA: Please don't do that.
LAURA: What am I, what is it?
That I add it to?
MATT: Investigate.
LAURA: Perception?
But you advantage on the roll,
because you're a ranger, tracking.
LAURA: Oh sweet.
Okay.
SAM: Why don't we just ask?
LAURA: Well that's good, okay.
Let's go with a 17.
MATT: 17, alright.
So as you guys are going
to ask somebody about this,
your ranger gets down and
begins inspecting the floor.
LAURA: Yeah, I see things!
MATT: Where you can see there were struggles
that apparently occurred.
You can see slash marks on the ground.
You can see bodies, or
the impacts of bodies
where some of these dwarves
have been pulled away.
A few minutes later, you can see tracks,
dwarven tracks, of bodies
being pulled and dragged,
not in the direction they're going,
but further down the tunnel.
TRAVIS: Yeah, let's go there.
LAURA: Oh, no.
MATT: As you look and follow that track,
you notice that maybe a good 200 feet
to the left of the cavern,
there is a new tunnel breach
that is currently open.
About a 20 by 15 size tunnel
that is fresh and blasted out
from the other side.
You can see rubble and rocks
strewn across the floor.
LAURA: I hear, I hear birds coming from the--
TRAVIS: It's a fucking trip, right?
LAURA: I know.
SAM: Let's go down there.
Let's go down where it's dangerous.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: Can we see?
TRAVIS: Can we ask one of the guards?
TALIESIN: It's a mine canary.
LIAM: Is it black or is it dim?
MATT: With his light spell, it's fairly bright.
TRAVIS: Nice!
MATT: Otherwise, it's fairly dim.
TRAVIS: I cup my hands over my face
and go, Grog, Grog, Grog. (laughs)
MATT: And it does echo.
Grog, Grog, Grog, Grog.
LAURA: Why would you do that?
TRAVIS: Why not?
MATT: (faintly) Grog-Grog. Grog.
Following the tracks,
you can see the dragging
of the bodies does indeed
go in the direction,
and into the newly carved tunnel.
In this mine network.
LAURA: All right.
MATT: What you do notice is the dwarves' bodies
that are being dragged away:
you can see footprints
of those that are also
pulling them aside.
You kind of figure out the
idea of the pattern
of the footsteps that are
leading in that direction.
LAURA: Big, small?
MATT: Most of them are also dwarven in shape.
LAURA: Oh, okay.
MARISHA: Most of them.
MATT: So, there are, you can gather,
dwarven feet dragging
dwarven bodies deeper inside.
LIAM: Duergar.
LAURA: Dwarven centipede.
LIAM: It's the duergar.
MATT: However, there are two
bodies that are being dragged
with no footprints whatsoever.
TRAVIS: What?
LAURA: Wings.
SAM: They're being used like skateboards.
(group laughs)
MARISHA: Legolas style.
ORION: Who and what are those?
LIAM: This is 2015.
TRAVIS: Is there any residue?
MARISHA: Yeah.
SAM: Wow, if only we had asked some dwarves
what's been going on down here.
LAURA: Is there any residue, blood?
ORION: We already know.
LAURA: Green, red, black.
MATT: From the dragging marks,
there is no blood.
There's no signs of them dragging
dead bodies off, at least.
LAURA: Does it look like they struggled?
MATT: No, there's no struggle either.
TRAVIS: Oh crap, fire.
MARISHA: What about the walls?
How close are the walls?
MATT: The walls here for this tunnel are
about 15, 20 feet in width.
And about 10, 15 feet high.
MARISHA: Are there any scratch
marks or anything like that
on the walls?
MATT: No.
LIAM: Let's stop dicking around
and go into that mine.
TRAVIS, TALIESIN: Yeah.
LAURA: Might as well.
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: We go further.
MATT: You push further in.
(Liam imitates sword being drawn)
MATT: So, this tunnel, pitch black.
There's no light source aside from the one
that you're creating.
You guys push forward.
And push forward, following the tracks.
And push forward.
And the the tunnel winds
and winds and descends.
And winds and descends.
About two hours--
[Laura, Marisha, Travis, and Sam] What?!
MATT: --of following this tunnel
with little variation.
LAURA: Should've grabbed some dried fruit.
TRAVIS: We got a ton.
MATT: Steadily declining and
winding as it progresses.
Three hours go by.
This tunnel goes extremely deep.
Whatever managed to dig its way up here
came from pretty far under this mine.
LAURA: At no point does it look
like the bodies ever moved?
MATT: Nope, no change in physicality.
No sign of struggle.
MARISHA: But there are the drag marks all the way?
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: And two hours ago,
I started stealthing
and taking the lead.
When we're in the dark.
MATT: All right, go ahead
and roll a stealth check.
LAURA: I thought I was tracking.
LIAM: Uh, 29.
LAURA: Whoo, that's a good roll.
Yay, first good roll of the night.
MATT: All right, there we go.
Your luck is changing now.
LAURA: Changing it around.
TRAVIS: Let me touch you.
MATT: You feel pretty stealthy.
You guys look like, wait,
where the hell did Vax go?
MARISHA: Oh shit, I hope he didn't hear
me just say that about him.
Dammit.
LAURA: Oh thank you, brother.
TALIESIN: I'm having a serious
Tom Sawyer island vibe.
LAURA: I found him.
LIAM: Looks fine.
MATT: About four hours--
MARISHA: Are there any drafts?
Do I feel any wind flows
or anything like that?
MATT: No.
It is still.
It is stagnant air.
(Laura coughs)
Even more stagnant now.
Four hours of traveling
deeper into this tunnel's path
until--
LAURA: Anybody else have to go
to the bathroom?
TRAVIS: He rolled, he rolled something.
LAURA: Oh no, he rolled.
MARISHA: And so, that is how I
spent my 12th birthday.
SAM: Great story, Keyleth.
And, yeah.
MARISHA: Let's see, what else.
TRAVIS: Hey Scanlan, you kill me, I kill you.
LIAM: There a great little cave alcove here,
perfect for peeing in.
LAURA: Oh brother, good to see you.
LIAM: For everyone to pee.
LAURA: Am I over here, or am I over here?
Perhaps we could take a pee break here
and proceed further into the mines.
MARISHA: I agree with that.
LAURA: That's a good idea.
LIAM: Do you catch my drift?
MATT: As the four hour mark of travel
into this tunnel presents itself,
the tunnel finally widens and opens.
As the sound of distant water
rushing reaches your ears.
LAURA: Oh no, I have to go to the bathroom.
MATT: As Tiberius steps into this opening,
the light cascades into this new cavern.
A large, beautiful open
space presents itself,
a good 100-foot-up ceiling.
From what you can see,
a roaring river is now
pouring out of the nearby rock,
cascading over a cliffside
into a waterfall down into this deeper,
giant cavernous space.
LAURA: What about the tracks?
MATT: The tracks continue in the
direction of that river.
MARISHA: Into the river?
Like it goes into the water?
LAURA: Do we want to step
into the room fully?
MARISHA: Why don't we send--
LAURA: I'm gonna stealth.
I'm gonna stealth, too.
MARISHA: Stealth twins.
ORION: Do I detect any magic?
Stealth twins, 2015.
MATT: You detect no magic.
You roll stealth.
LAURA: 17.
MATT: Let's go ahead and take a bio break--
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: --as the mystery begins to unveil.
(group laughs)
ORION: I love a mystery.
MATT: Be back here in about
five, ten minutes, folks.
So keep an ear out.
TRAVIS: Quick, quick break.
ORION: I'm gonna pee my face off.
(Liam imitates rushing water)
MATT: We'll be right back.
ORION: Enjoy our butt shots, everybody.
MATT: And everyone runs off to
take care of their business.
TRAVIS: Right, listen up.
If you have ale, then you have
a friend in Grog Strongjaw.
A goliath of towering height and size,
this barbarian has an
appetite for the two--
[audio resets]
TRAVIS: Right, listen up.
If you have ale, then you have
a friend in Grog Strongjaw.
A goliath of towering height and size,
this barbarian has an appetite for the two
great loves in his life:
combat, women, and ale.
(record scratches)
Wait.
Easily the brains of the
group, Grog is often consulted
for his vast knowledge of
shapes, colors, and shiny things.
Also ale.
In his early years, armed
with his two-handed great axe,
Grog often enjoyed proving
his might amongst the ranks
of his family's wandering herd.
But after coming upon an
unsuspecting, elderly gnome
in the woods, he objected to the killing
of such an innocent life.
A creature of impulse, Grog felt only pity
for this, this terrified little thing.
[no audio]
TRAVIS: Right, listen up.
If you have ale, then you have
a friend in Grog Strongjaw.
A goliath of towering height and size,
this barbarian has an appetite
for the two great loves
in his life: combat, women, and ale.
(record scratching)
Wait.
Easily the brains of the
group, Grog is often consulted
for his vast knowledge of
shapes, colors, and shiny things.
Also ale.
In his early years, armed
with his two-handed great axe,
Grog often enjoyed proving
his might amongst the ranks
of his family's wandering herd.
But after coming upon an
unsuspecting elderly gnome
in the woods, he objected to the killing
of such an innocent life.
A creature of impulse, Grog felt only pity
for this, this terrified little thing.
His disobedience cost him dearly.
Beaten bloody and banished
by the herd leader,
his uncle Kevdak, Grog was
abandoned and left to die.
Exiled from his herd, it
was then that the relative
of the very gnome he
fought to save, saved him.
It was the kindness of a
gnome cleric named Pike
that healed Grog, bringing
him back from death's edge.
And they have remained
close friends ever since.
Most nights, Grog can be found
challenging entire taverns
to wrestling matches.
Or accompanying Scanlan
to the nearest house
where you pay for lady favors.
Also ale.
MARISHA: A first impression of Keyleth
would leave you with little information
on the half-elven druid.
You might even think that
her social awkwardness
due to her sheltered
upbringing is kind of sweet.
Of course, it would be
unwise to underestimate her
based on first impressions.
(lightning roars)
Under that unintimidating petite frame
is a vicious beast
waiting to be unleashed,
whose natural powers have
made even the fiercest
of champions pee their pants.
Literally.
Born to the air tribe
of the Ashari people,
Keyleth was raised with
a deep love of nature
and the elemental magics.
It is her people's inherent duty
to protect the delicate
areas in Tal'Dorei,
where the four elemental
planes begin to bleed
with this realm.
Since she was a little
girl, she had quite a knack
for air manipulation and
beast shaping abilities.
Well, if you consider
kittens and flying squirrels
to be little beasts, which I do.
Anyways, it wasn't long
before the headmaster
of the tribe, her father, Kohren,
realized her true prodigious abilities
and she was inveterated to succeed him
as the next headmaster.
Just like that, her jovial
childhood was stripped
and replaced with endless
spell memorization,
teachings from ancient traditions,
and exceedingly high expectations.
Every druid leader-to-be must embark
on a journey to seek out the sister tribes
in order to introduce
and establish respect
amongst the fellow headmasters.
They call this the
Aramente, or Noble Odyssey.
When her father felt she was
ready, he set her on the path
to truly discovering herself.
Not knowing when, or if,
she will ever return.
As she hikes down the
mountain towards Stillben,
she meditated on the task ahead.
Part of the Aramente is proving
yourself a strong warrior,
a valiant protector, and a
wise and compassionate leader.
With this knowledge, one
thought plays in repeat
in her mind:
Is she even worthy?
TALIESIN: Percy was the third
child of seven children,
born to a noble family
who lived far to the north
in the ancient castle of Whitestone.
With so many siblings to
share the burdens of lordship,
Percy turned his attention
to the sciences, engineering,
and naturalism.
One day, a mysterious couple
named Lord and Lady Briarwood
came to court.
During a feast held in
their honor, the Briarwoods
violently took control of the castle,
killing or imprisoning
everyone who would stand
in their way.
Percy awoke chained in the dungeon,
only to be freed by his younger sister.
Together they fled, chased
by the Briarwoods' men.
As they ran, Percy's
sister took several arrows
to the chest and fell.
Percy kept running, eventually
jumping into a freezing river
and floating unconscious to freedom.
He did not remember waking
up on a fishing boat.
He barely remembered the next two years,
as he slowly made his way
as far south as possible.
Then one night, Percy had a dream.
A roaring cloud of smoke
offered him vengeance
against those who destroyed his family.
When he awoke, Percy began
to design his first gun.
(gun cocking)
(gun firing)
SAM: Oh, you haven't heard
of Scanlan Shorthalt?
Well, gird your loins, ladies,
because he has his eye on you.
A talented musician, master of disguise,
and dashingly handsome in his own mind,
Scanlan sings songs almost as much
as he sings his own praises.
Born a poor gnome, Scanlan
used his endless charm
and soaring tenor voice to croon for coin
and support his single mother.
One day he was discovered
by a half-orc promoter
and joined Dr. Dranzel's
Spectacular Traveling Troupe,
where he learned the ways of the world
and honed his skills as
a bard extraordinaire.
A loner much of his life,
Scanlan has never quite come
to terms with the violent
death of his mother
at the hands of a goblin invasion.
While his years on the road provided many,
shall we say, educational
experiences with the opposite sex,
deep down Scanlan yearns for
the one thing he's never known:
the true love of a fellow gnome.
Still, Scanlan considers
himself a lover first,
performer second, and
fighter distant third.
On the battlefield,
he'll support his allies
but rarely draws blood unless it's
to protect fellow gnome Pike.
Count on Scanlan for a hearty
laugh, a rollicking song,
and a twinkle in his eye that melts hearts
and makes the females swoon.
ORION: (clears throat)
Greetings and salutations.
I am Tiberius Stormwind.
I hail from a town called
Ty'rex, located in the heart
of Draconia, from a
politically respected family.
At the age of 15, I succeeded
in passing the Sorcerer's Rite,
showing prodigy-like control
of my magic.
The judges and the Draconian
high council were amazed
at how powerful my spells were
for how long I had been training.
At 20 years old, I was the
youngest appointed member
of the magic guild in Draconian history.
For the next few years, I
almost went mad from the malaise
of being a guild member,
as it's rather boring.
However, one day I
happened upon a chamber,
unused for quite some time.
In the room were stacks of books and maps
of the surrounding cities and
areas around the known world.
For months I would frequent the chamber
and learned of artifacts from legend.
After a long period of research,
I made a list of artifacts
that caught my eye.
I brought these findings
to the high council
and was told that all of the
information in the chamber
I stumbled upon was either
believed to be fiction
or unsolvable mysteries and
hence were lost forever.
I found those answers to be unacceptable.
A year later I devised a ruse and managed
to convince the city council
to lend support in me
leaving Draconia on a mission
of peace and diplomacy
for the surrounding kingdoms.
Going from town to town and
making friends and allies,
in and for the name of Draconia.
Being a red dragonborn, I had
quite the task on my hands
in that respect, but it
was exactly what I needed,
so I could explore the world
and find these artifacts,
as I felt the truth was out there.
Some may describe me as buffoonish,
but I say poppycock to
all that. (stammers)
I am much sharper than
most give me credit for.
I just don't pay attention
to things sometimes.
I've also been known to
be rather cunning, loyal,
happy-go-lucky, and well, dangerous.
I can't help but show my true
scales every now and then.
But overall, I think I'm quite
friendly for a dragonborn.
LIAM: Never entirely
welcome in the company
of elves or men, Vax'ildan
learned at a young age
to skip past formality, preferring instead
to invite himself in your door.
Along with twin sister
Vex'ahlia, Vax was born
by a chance encounter
between elven royalty
and human peasantry.
Raised by their mother in
their early years, the twins
were eventually sent off to their father
in the elven capital of Syngorn.
But their cool reception among
the elves there never warmed,
and their time in the capital didn't last.
The siblings stole away one autumn night
and set out on the open road.
After a few years of
wandering, they eventually
decided to return to their mother
and journeyed back to
the lands of their youth.
But instead of finding
their childhood home,
they returned to a pile of rubble.
Their mother was gone,
their home burned to ash.
Pressing the townspeople for answers,
they learned of the day the dragon came.
With their ties all severed,
Vax'ildan and his sister
set out to find their fortune
together in Tal'Dorei.
An outsider since birth,
Vax quickly learned
to solve life's challenges
in his own particular way,
often by sidestepping them entirely.
And when his knack for circumventing
adversity isn't enough--
(sword slicing)
--the way of blades the
elves schooled him in
more than makes up the difference.
LAURA: Like so many half-elves, Vex'ahlia
has spent most of her life
suffering the cool reception
of a people who don't fully accept her.
Born of a human mother
and an elven father,
who only later in life took an
interest in their existence,
Vex'ahlia and her twin brother Vax'ildan
quickly realized the only
people they could truly rely on
in this world were each other.
It was at the age of ten
when the two were taken
from their mother and
brought to live in Syngorn,
the isolated elven city
for which their father
was an ambassador.
He quietly took them in but
always kept an icy distance,
and after too many years
of disdainful looks,
the pair decided to leave
his indifference behind
and set out on their own.
Vax took to the cities,
stealing small trinkets
and learning the ways of the thief,
while Vex kept to the woods.
She preferred the isolation.
Always the keen observer, she learned
to hunt and to track, to spy and to shoot.
And through a series of fateful events,
earned herself a companion
in the form of a bear,
her own stolen Trinket,
to fight alongside her
and protect her fiercely.
Also, he is adorable and
gives expert massages.
PRODUCER: And back to you.
Welcome back.
Thank you for waiting.
We've all had our fill of snacks, drinks,
and relieving ourselves of
the ones we had earlier.
So, before we return, we
actually want to thank you guys
for having all the subscriptions you have.
Since we started playing, we
hit a thousand very quickly.
You guys are awesome.
TRAVIS: Yeah!
So thank you for that.
Big round of applause.
TRAVIS: Round of applause.
Subscriptions have been awesome.
And as such, we have a winner
for these evening's event.
Hi, Tiberius.
ORION: Sorry everyone.
Tiberius has returned.
So, in character as always.
So, the winner of the
evening is going to win
both a signed photo of
the cast of Critical Role
as well as a signed Player's
Handbook of D&amp;D's 5th Edition
is: (clears throat)
SAM: Visitor.
(group laughs)
No, on the backside.
The winner is Yareth.
Congratulations.
Thank you for subscribing
and paying attention
and being in the chatroom
and being awesome.
We're gonna go ahead and
get your information,
and we're gonna make sure that you
get our awesome first
Critical Role giveaway.
(group cheers and claps)
Well done, Yareth.
Thank you for coming.
MARISHA: Yareth.
(group repeats Yalreth in funny voices)
MATT: All right.
(Marisha speaks gibberish)
LIAM: Enjoy your Player's Handbook 5E.
MATT: (laughs) Hopefully more
to come down the road.
We'll have more fun things for you guys.
So, anyway.
So, bringing it back to the game at hand.
As you've stepped into this
large, cavernous space,
you can hear the rush of water
as the underground river
begins to turn into a waterfall and drifts
into a smaller body of water.
It's just out of sight
beyond this cliff face.
Into this open, cavernous area.
LAURA: Oh, we just stealthed.
MATT: You guys also stealthed, and
what did you roll for stealth?
LAURA: I rolled 17.
MATT: 17, got it.
All right.
LIAM: Oh, less than that.
LAURA: You didn't.
LIAM: Oh, no I didn't, 18.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: You were already stealthed, though.
LIAM: That's true.
MATT: As you guys step into this space,
there are sections of large rock,
portions of stone that just jut out
and block off portions
from your view of this area.
Giant stalagmites and stalactites that
just permeate the entirety of this cavern,
which has been long, just
building and building
with elements drawn from the ceiling,
from the waters that flow through.
You also faintly see a light source--
LAURA: (whispers) Oh no.
MATT: --behind one of those rock
pillars in the distance.
LAURA: (whispers) Should we go
check it out?
LIAM: Do we perceive anything in here with us
before going that far in, yes?
MATT: Make a perception check.
LIAM: 18.
MATT: 18?
LIAM: Yes.
MATT: You hear a very, very faint
sound in the distance.
(sharp noise)
SAM: Jesus.
(laughing)
ORION: Did you hear that?
MATT: That's not the sound.
Tiberius.
ORION: I'm sorry.
LAURA: I have a passive perception of 21.
MATT: Yes you do.
You hear a:
(clicks tongue quickly)
LAURA: Oh, no.
SAM: A skittering.
MATT: (continues clicking)
LIAM: I might hear spiders.
MARISHA: Oh.
LAURA: Ugh.
TRAVIS: Or crab.
LIAM: Or something.
MARISHA: Making it old school.
SAM: Maybe it's a very faint
maraca dance of some sort.
LAURA: What direction is it coming from?
TRAVIS: That would be better.
MATT: It's hard to tell at this
point, it seems to be
just kind of loosely atmospheric.
TRAVIS: Is the light coming from over the water?
MATT: The very, very faint
light you see, no.
It's adjacent to the
water to the right of you.
TRAVIS: Okay.
LIAM: I think we're dealing with spiders.
MATT: (continues clicking)
LAURA: I think you guys should hang back,
and we should stealth over
and see how many it looks like
we're dealing with.
LIAM: The twins will creep forward.
MATT: Okay. You both creep forward.
LAURA: Trinket stays with the group.
Trinket, stay with Grog.
ORION: I'm gonna dispel my light spell.
MATT: Pitch darkness falls upon all of you.
TRAVIS: What did you do that for?
SAM: Because now they don't know
where we are.
LAURA: But we can't see anything.
TRAVIS: They're spiders.
MARISHA: While he does that,
I'm gonna go ahead and
turn into a cave bear.
ORION: Can you not see now?
LAURA: We can see in dim light.
MARISHA: Cave bears have darkvision.
MARISHA: I'm pretty sure.
LIAM: No, dim light only.
MATT: Do they?
LAURA: What'd you turn into?
ORION: It doesn't matter, do you
want me to turn it back on?
TALIESIN: A cave bear.
MARISHA: Yeah, subterranean bears,
they have darkvision.
MATT: All right. So.
SAM: He can just make light again.
MATT: Go ahead and roll a perception check.
LIAM: Turn it back on.
MARISHA: No, leave it off!
ORION: I dispel it again, I'm sorry.
MARISHA: Fuck! Fuck!
MATT: Light, light light, light light.
TALIESIN: How did you do that?
MARISHA: It's been a bad night.
LAURA: Oh no.
MARISHA: 12 total.
LIAM: Clap on (claps), clap off. (claps)
MATT: As you glance about in cave bear form,
you look up and all you can
make out is shifting movement
across the ceiling.
(group groans at once)
MATT: But it's large.
It's not a small creature.
You glance off to your
left and you look up
and you see a second one.
LAURA: Oh no.
TRAVIS: Oh fuck.
MATT: And both dislodge.
LAURA: Oh no!
MATT: All of you hear two
loud, cacophonous,
thunderous slam sounds--
(imitates loud thudding)
LAURA: Definitely hit light now.
MATT: --on the ground next to you--
(screeching noise)
LIAM: I quickly whisper to my
sister, to the boundaries.
MARISHA: And I just go: (roaring noise)
ORION: Light!
MATT: All right.
LIAM: Vex and Vax dance backwards
against the walls.
MATT: There is a surprise round.
LAURA: Oh, no.
(group groans)
TRAVIS: Oh God.
LIAM: But I heard them.
MARISHA: I know.
(roars)
LAURA: Transform back.
MATT: All right.
So you guys are stealthed
off to the side there.
LIAM: That's beautiful.
LAURA: I'm on the other side.
LIAM: Look at that fun map.
MATT: There's Trinket.
LIAM: Thank you, Matt,
for doing all the work
on these maps and shit.
MATT: That's what I do.
So there's the water there,
rushing off into the waterfall
that goes further down.
LAURA: Can I stealth
against the other wall?
TRAVIS: Waterfall is where on that map?
MATT: The waterfall is right here.
TRAVIS: Got it.
MATT: So the river kind of pours over,
falls into the water below.
There are some of these
large rock elements here.
SAM: What are they?
MATT: You cannot tell what's
beyond this area,
which is where the light
source is coming from.
(imitates thudding)
LAURA: Oh no!
(group groans)
(imitates thudding)
TRAVIS: Those look like umber hulks.
MATT: They are.
(group screams)
You've had one brief run-in
with a single umber hulk
in the past.
LAURA: Now we have two.
As two slam into the ground beside you,
dropping from the ceiling portion.
LAURA: Fudge!
TRAVIS: I have their claws still.
LAURA: Wait, do you guys remember--
(Matt growls and snarls)
LAURA: Do they respond to vibration?
ORION: I cast stoneskin
on myself immediately.
You don't have that much
time, unfortunately.
Because they are upon
you, it a surprise round.
TRAVIS: Shit!
LAURA: Do they respond to vibration?
I forget.
TRAVIS: They responded to something.
MATT: They respond to the something.
LAURA: Can we remember with
investigation or insight?
LIAM: Limericks, limericks,
they respond to limericks.
MATT: So this one shifts up over there,
and this one moves up to there.
Gleans past you, as it
does not notice you.
LAURA: Yeah, but it's still big.
MATT: This one comes towards you, Percy.
TALIESIN: Damn it.
MATT: Attacking you with each of its
claws and its mandibles.
The first strike comes
at you with a 13 to hit
with its first claw.
What's your AC?
TALIESIN: Ah, 17.
MATT: You, woomf, just manage
to dodge out of the way
as these giant-bladed claws
sweep next to your face.
The second strike comes to you at a 21.
TRAVIS: Oh shit.
That hits.
TALIESIN: That hits.
I'm going to use a gunslinger's dodge.
LAURA: Gunslinger's dodge.
TALIESIN: Wait, let's see if I can do this.
It's not enough, nevermind, so no.
I just gotta take it.
MATT: All right, so the claw finds
purchase across your torso.
(imitates claw slicing)
The armor catches most of it.
However, the slash does
leave an impact on you,
as you can feel the taste of iron
in the back of your throat.
You suffer nine points of slashing damage.
TALIESIN: Oh, okay.
MATT: And just as you pull back
the mandibles,
time to crunch down upon you.
And that is going to be a 27 to hit.
LAURA: Oh, no.
TRAVIS: Do their eyes do something?
MATT: You take 14 points
of slashing damage,
as the mandibles slice down,
clamping onto your shoulder.
You manage to pull free, but in doing so,
you wrench the pointed
portions of the mandible
across your shoulder,
pulling open the flesh
in this horrible jagged pattern.
TALIESIN: Ow.
MATT: That brings us to the other one,
who is attacking Grog.
MARISHA: Grog!
You're right there in front of it.
The biggest and most
viable visual it can find.
SAM:  No motherfucker, miss
I start singing using my
Cutting Words reaction.
To try to distract him.
MATT: All right, so go ahead and roll your d8
to reduce his attack roll.
TRAVIS: (laughs) No motherfucker, miss.
SAM: d8?
MATT: d8.
SAM: Three.
MATT: All right.
That would have been a 20 to hit.
That brings it to a 17.
TRAVIS: 18.
(group cheers)
SAM: I saved your life!
MATT: So, as you begin singing out,
as it pulls back with--
SAM:  No motherfucker
MATT: --its mandibles to strike at Grog,
it (clicks) looks off to you for a second,
goes back, at which point
Grog has put his axe
up to its face and is holding it at bay.
As its mandibles are
tied in with its blades,
and the handle of the axe
is trying to hold it back.
It strikes at you with
its two claws, Grog.
That is going to be a 27.
TRAVIS: That hits.
MATT: And a 14.
TRAVIS: Misses.
MATT: Okay, then from the
one claw that gets you,
you take six points of slashing damage.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: All right everyone, roll initiative.
(group groans)
LAURA: I'm so scared to roll.
MARISHA: I know, it's been so bad.
SAM: Best one of I've had.
TALIESIN: Ah, not horrible.
LAURA: Oh, good.
TRAVIS: Ball sack.
MARISHA: Uh, it's okay.
MATT: All right, so, 25 to 20?
LAURA: 24.
MATT: 24.
TRAVIS: There you go.
A little redemption.
LAURA: That's right.
MATT: Nice, we got some Vex up top.
20 to 15 anyone?
TALIESIN: 17.
MARISHA: 17 as well.
SAM: 19.
TRAVIS: Ah, yeah.
LIAM: 15, 15.
MATT: All right,
got some Scanlan up there.
17, 17.
LAURA: (whispers) They're both surrounding me
even with my awesome things.
MATT: Percy, Keyleth.
MATT: So 15 to--
LIAM: 15.
MATT: 15.
ORION: 13.
TRAVIS: I'm 14.
Tiberius and I are 13-14.
LAURA: Ugh, come on Grog!
MATT: Wait, uh, 14?
ORION: 13.
MATT: 14.
Grog and Tiberius.
TRAVIS: It's the ghost pepper cookies.
MATT: All right, cool.
Top of the round.
Vex.
LAURA: Hyah!
I am going to shoot the one.
MATT: Before you do that--
SAM: Oh, shit!
MATT: As you're going to
reach back, you look over
into its strange, glistening,
black, dead, insect-like eyes
of the umber hulk, and
you feel this strange wave
of mental confusion
hit your head.
Go ahead and make a--
TRAVIS: I knew it.
MATT: Go ahead and make a saving throw.
This is going to be charisma saving throw.
MARISHA: Is this what confused you
and had you running out the door?
TRAVIS: I fell out a fucking 120 foot hole.
MATT: So you roll d20, add your
charisma saving throw
at the top of your character.
LAURA: Okay, so I gotta do my math.
That's 11, but I get a
plus two from my ring
that I'm wearing for saving throws, so.
MATT: Okay, so it's 13.
LAURA: 13.
MATT: All right.
The wave of confusion
takes hold over your brain.
(group groans)
We're gonna go ahead and
find out what happens.
(Laura groans)
TRAVIS: Maybe he'll ask you to make some cookies.
MATT: All right--
LAURA: You're gonna have me do
nothing wrong?
MATT: You reach for it, and you
space out for a second.
Your hands fall to your side.
And you stand there.
TRAVIS: Aw, fuck.
MATT: Trinket is looking
for some sort of cue
from you of what to do.
LAURA: Does he look confused too?
MATT: No, but Trinket's looking to you
for some sort of direction
and is getting none.
This is a very clustered space, too.
Can barely see you over this.
MATT: That brings us to Scanlan.
LAURA: But I was stealthed, though.
SAM: Don't worry, I'll help you
my dear.
MATT: I know. Doesn't matter
if you're stealthed.
He couldn't see you,
but you could see him.
SAM: I'm gonna take a
step back behind Trinket.
MATT: Okay.
(Travis Laughs)
LAURA: Good call.
SAM: Actually, wait. How
far am I from my furthest--
MATT: Are you averting your gaze
from the guys,
or are you looking at 'em directly?
SAM: No, averting my gaze.
But how far am I from my--
LAURA: Nobody look at them.
SAM: --my furthest fellow?
Oh, I'm 60 feet, okay.
And I sing my counter-charm song.
Magic magic, go away,
come again another day
So all of us have
advantage on saving throws
for the charming spells.
If they are charming us.
I don't know if they are.
MATT: This is confusion.
SAM: No, what?
MATT: I don't think--
SAM: Frightened or charmed,
it's not the same thing?
MATT: Mm.
This is technically a confusion effect.
So yeah.
SAM: Okay.
LAURA: Oh, wait. Oh, no.
MATT: So as you finish your
song, you're like--
SAM: It did not work.
MATT: Doesn't seem to be having
an effect unfortunately.
SAM: Okay.
And then as my bonus
action, who got hit first?
You did?
I'll just throw a healing word to him.
MATT: Okay.
Just go ahead and roll, feeling him.
That's a d4 plus five.
Yeah, you got it.
Percy.
TALIESIN: Mm.
MATT: You heal--
SAM: What is this?
MATT: It's a four.
SAM: Oh, that's a four.
Okay.
MATT: So you heal nine hit
points, and it's your turn.
What do you got, Percy?
TALIESIN: Up to 58, let me just
fix that, there we go.
Okay, where am I on the board?
MATT: You are right here in front--
TALIESIN: Okay, so
there's no getting away.
I'm gonna-- I can basically without--
I remember I'm not supposed
to look at these things.
I know where this thing is.
I can pull my gun and
just take a shot, right?
MATT: So averting your gaze,
you take a shot.
You are at disadvantage
on the attack roll.
TALIESIN: How much?
MATT: Just disadvantage.
TALIESIN: I'm just disadvantage?
MATT: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Well okay, that's fine.
I'm gonna spend a grit
point for a deadshot,
so I'm gonna get a plus one to hit.
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: Come on, Perce.
TALIESIN: Aha!
That will be a-- with the plus
one, that's a 28, 29, 30 to hit.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: Get after it, nasty!
MATT: Roll again, as you
have disadvantage.
Because you're not looking at it directly.
LAURA: Ugh, please be good.
TALIESIN: That's still 25 to hit.
MATT: That hits.
TALIESIN: 26, actually.
MATT: Go ahead and roll damage.
TALIESIN: And then I get extra damage
because I did deadshot.
So that's plus one, so that will be a--
it's a 2d8 plus five plus
ice, because I'm hitting
with my ice shot.
And that's seven, eight, nine, 10, 11, 12.
14 points of ice damage.
MATT: 14 points of ice damage.
Nice.
TALIESIN: And then I have a second shot
and I'm just gonna take one
more shot at him really quick.
MATT: Okay, also at disadvantage.
TALIESIN: I fail.
In fact, my gun jams.
(group groans)
MATT: Okay.
So as you go to fire, it's
like you-- (imitates gun firing)
fire the first shot averting the gaze.
LAURA: We're all gonna die.
You spin the barrel, go back
to go ahead and fire again,
as you do (imitates gun clicking)
You pull the trigger for a
second, and you feel a slight
(imitates fizzled explosion)
inside the barrel.
TRAVIS: Damn it!
MARISHA: Oh, no.
MATT: And you feel the actual
metal get extremely cold,
and you have you have to shake
it out like, aw, damn it.
TALIESIN: Since I can't move,
I'm gonna--
my movement, my minor is gonna
be just fixing my-- yeah, so.
MATT: Okay, so your action is
just trying to fix the gun?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: All right.
That brings us to--
TALIESIN: Damn.
MATT: Keyleth.
LAURA: Keyleth, don't look at them.
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: Just as a note, your
inspiration dice that you give
can be used on saving throws as well.
SAM: Okay.
But I haven't given any.
MATT: No.
MARISHA: Um, I'm a bear right now.
MATT: You are a bear, which I
will, for the sake of this,
give you the kitty.
MARISHA: Bring out Minxie.
TRAVIS: Minxie.
MATT: Minxie is the form,
but you are a bear.
MARISHA: Okay, first and foremost,
I'm gonna go ahead--
and I don't know if this is gonna help.
But I'm gonna throw up a fog cloud.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: Maybe.
MARISHA: No?
MATT: So fog cloud.
The entire space, it's a 20 foot radius?
I believe, if I recall from
the one he did yesterday.
MARISHA: But it screws our vision,
though, doesn't it?
LAURA: Well, yeah.
MATT: Everybody gets obscured vision.
MARISHA: But I mean, we
wouldn't be able to see them.
Would it help with the
confusion is what I'm hoping.
LAURA: That could help, that could help.
SAM: Do your thing.
Do what you do.
MARISHA: Or would it be bad?
LAURA: Try it.
Do it, Keyleth, go with your instincts.
TALIESIN: Don't think about what's the worst
that could possibly happen.
MARISHA: I'm bursting out a fog cloud, and then--
MATT: Well to cast, you have to get out
of creature form, remember?
MARISHA: Oh, that's right.
I didn't throw a bow.
MATT: So you're a bear.
MARISHA: I'm a bear.
Nevermind, I'm just gonna
do a full round of attacks.
LIAM: It's go time, go time! (claps)
MARISHA: That one right there.
LAURA: Keep your eyes closed.
MATT: All right, so you move up to there.
Go ahead and do
your full round of attacks.
MATT: I am doing multi-attack.
MATT: Okay, are you averting
your gaze or not?
MARISHA: I'm a cave bear, I'm blind.
I'm like a blind fish.
I have darkvision and, like, cataracts.
MATT: Darkvision means you
can see in the dark.
MATT: But it doesn't mean
that you don't see.
(Sam laughs)
MARISHA: Well I'm a bear.
MATT: You are a bear.
I'm eating at his leg.
I'm not looking at his eyes.
I'm not, like, waxing
poetically at how sexy he is.
MATT: No.
MARISHA: Not whispering sweet nothings
in his ear.
MATT: I know.
MARISHA: I'm gnawing at his leg.
MATT: That's true.
LIAM: Go for the kill!
MATT: Make a charisma saving throw.
MARISHA: Make a charisma saving throw?
MATT: Yes.
(Travis laughs)
LAURA: Next time just avert your gaze.
[Taliesin And Marisha] Oh!
MARISHA: That's good.
16.
MATT: 16?
You can feel the oppression
of the umber hulk's gaze,
but you shrug it off, your
bear mind not affected
by the measly tricks and traits--
MARISHA: Urgh, I'm a bear!
MATT: -of these strange underground entities.
MARISHA: Okay.
Now I'm attacking.
MATT: Roll for your four attacks.
MARISHA: First one probably misses.
With my claw, 14.
MATT: 14 misses.
(group laughs)
ORION: She got a pizza.
MARISHA: With the claw attacks, do
I have two claw attacks,
do I roll for both?
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: Okay, so the first one is 19,
MATT: Hits.
MARISHA: Second one, second claw attack is 18.
MATT: Also hits.
MARISHA: Okay.
So I am doing 2d6 plus five twice.
So six plus--
TALIESIN: It's 11.
MARISHA: Five, so 11.
TALIESIN: Ooh.
MARISHA: Plus 17--
20 damage.
MATT: 20 damage. Nice.
TALIESIN: 25.
MARISHA: Oh, 25.
Sorry, 25.
MATT: All righty.
TALIESIN: Yes.
MARISHA: 25 damage.
MATT: So, as you shake off the
effect, you reach for it,
lashing out, two large strikes.
The second one gets a
distinct carve into the back
of the umber hulk's hide.
You can see a portion of
its chitinous back armor
gets kind of pulled off in a chunk.
And it (snarls), reels
back from the impact
and readies itself for a
second round of attacks.
MARISHA: Me and Trinket.
MATT: There you go.
MARISHA: Going at this.
(Matt laughs)
MARISHA: Bear style.
MATT: They go.
This one turns towards and
moves this way to focus
on the cave bear that just
thrashed against its hide.
While this one turns and
moves in towards Grog.
But now turns and sees the-- actually no.
It stays there, fixed to Grog.
So making its multi-strike
against you, Keyleth.
That is a 26 to hit.
MARISHA: Hits.
MATT: That's mandibles.
17 to hit with its claw.
MARISHA: Hits.
MATT: And 18 to hit with its claw.
MATT: All right, so you take six
points of slashing damage
from the first claw.
Eight points of slashing
damage from the second claw.
And then the mandibles deal fifteen points
of slashing damage, as the
umber hulk just turns to you,
and as a reaction to your assault--
MARISHA: What was the last one?
MATT: The last one was 15.
Just unleashes an array
of strikes against you.
(Matt growls)
LIAM: Hit it in the face.
MATT: That brings us to the other
one who's attacking you, Grog.
MARISHA: Back at him, yeah.
MATT: That is a 12 to hit.
Pretty sure misses.
TRAVIS: Misses.
MATT: Another 12 to hit,
'cause it likes to roll fours, apparently.
TRAVIS: Give me another four.
MATT: For the mandibles, it's a 20.
TRAVIS: 20 hits.
MATT: You're taking damage, fool.
That is 18 points of
slashing damage against you.
TRAVIS: I have a half damage to
all bludgeoning, piercing,
and slashing damage?
MATT: You haven't raged yet.
TRAVIS: So I'm not raging?!
MATT: You haven't raged yet!
It isn't your turn yet.
TRAVIS: But I'm so angry.
MATT: I know.
You're about to be so angry.
TRAVIS: 18 points.
MATT: You're gonna be so angry.
18 points of slashing damage.
The mandibles crush down on your body,
and you can feel them
pierce into your chest.
Your exposed musculature is
then torn in a jagged form
as you feel the blood begin
to pour down the front
of your torso.
TRAVIS: It's all right, it's okay.
LAURA: That's brutal.
TRAVIS: My turn's coming.
MATT: That ends their turn.
Vax.
LIAM: So I can see what's up.
I saw what it did to my sister,
so I'm gonna jump on its back.
I'm gonna swivel my daggers around
and just stab it in the face.
LAURA: But keep your gaze averted.
LIAM: Yeah, I'm seeing the
back of his fucking spine or head.
I'm gonna stab
him in the face twice.
MATT: Go for it.
LIAM: Okay.
LIAM: Nine--
20.
MATT: That hits.
LIAM: Okay.
So then I'll do damage.
The other one's an 18.
I rolled in advance.
LAURA: That counts, that counts!
MATT: That one, that's the one!
LIAM: So, 10, plus sneak attack damage, right?
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: Yeah, okay.
MATT: He doesn't know you were
there, you were stealthed.
LIAM: Okay.
One. Four.
Eight.
Nine.
13, 26, 36 damage from the first dagger.
MARISHA: Whoo!
LIAM: Face, in his face,
and the next was an 18.
MATT: Not in his face.
Not in his face.
LIAM: Not in his face?
MATT: It's back.
LIAM: But I wanted I wanted
to do this to his head.
Okay, whatever works.
TRAVIS: The reach around?
ORION: The old reach around stabbing.
LIAM: The reach around, the reach around.
That what I was going for.
And then, where's my four, 1d4.
One's a three, but no, just three.
MATT: Three, okay.
LIAM: With my flametongue dagger
which I don't know if
he likes or dislikes,
but that's what I've done.
MATT: Okay, so, as you leap on its
back, grab purchase
on one of its chitinous
plates, bring your first dagger
forward and jam it into
the side of its head,
as it pulls back, you hear a (snarling)
as it reacts to the immediate pain
and begins to
reach one of its claws
to try and knock you off.
As you do, you put the
blade back into your belt,
grab with your other hand,
pull your other dagger,
and slam it into the
other side of its head.
TRAVIS: Yeah!
MATT: This time it shrugs you off,
and you manage to just
land on your feet barely,
behind it, still faced away from you.
That brings us to Grog.
(Travis grunts)
Rage.
MARISHA: Rage!
TRAVIS: Now I'm angry.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: I would like to rage,
and not only rage,
I would like to go into a frenzied rage.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: For three full attacks.
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: While I'm raging so hard,
that I pop all the capillaries
in my eyeballs, so I can't
really see that well.
And I just swing a lot.
MATT: All right, I'm gonna check
one thing real fast.
LAURA: Oh, no.
TRAVIS: Oh, shit!
Don't check, look, I'm rolling.
(Marisha and Laura laugh)
30.
LIAM: There once was a bard from Nantucket.
(group laughs)
LIAM: Who got his flute caught--
TRAVIS: I gain one level of
exhaustion with a rage hit.
LIAM: --in a bucket.
MATT: I will say, situationally,
because of the fact
that your rage that you have
advantage on the saving throw
against the confusion effect.
[Marisha and Laura] Oh.
Your mind is so filled with aggression.
TRAVIS: I got that big, like, nasty thing.
MATT: So make charisma saving throw.
TALIESIN: Oh, what a good idea.
TRAVIS: Is that a 20?
MATT: Yep.
LAURA: Plus one.
TRAVIS: 11.
MATT: Roll again, you have advantage.
LIAM: Better, better, better, no.
TRAVIS: Five.
LAURA: Oh no!
MATT: Let's see what happens.
LAURA: No!
ORION: Roll a two.
MATT: So--
(group groans)
LAURA: Now he's raging, too.
MATT: --as you rage--
MARISHA: No, dammit.
MATT: --you feel the influence
of the umber hulk's gaze
pierce your eyes and the fury fills you,
and you reach out and slash with your axe.
However, it does not
reach for the umber hulk.
Go ahead and roll an attack, Grog.
LAURA: Oh no, who's he hitting?
TRAVIS: A one!
(group cheers)
SAM: Finally!
MARISHA: Yes!
MATT: There's a loud clanging
sound, as a giant, angry,
swooping bladed greataxe misses
Tiberius's head by inches.
ORION: Oh!
Grog, what are you doing?
MATT: Before slamming into the stone
right up against the side of the wall.
You can just see now this
kind of loose, crazed look
in his eye. (growls maniacally)
MATT: Foam begins to gather at
the side of his mouth.
ORION: Oh, now you're all screwed up.
LIAM: We have a problem.
LAURA: Yeah, this could be bad.
LIAM: We have an angry Grog.
MATT: Tiberius, you're up.
ORION: Damn it, Grog.
TRAVIS: It's my turn?
MATT: No, that's your turn.
TRAVIS: Oh, that's my turn.
MARISHA: Tiberius, help.
LAURA: At least your rolled a one.
TRAVIS: I did.
I didn't hurt anybody yet.
ORION: I look at Grog, and I'm
like, will you stop it!
I cast Dispel Magic on him.
(Travis snarls)
MATT: Cast Dispel Magic?
ORION: Yeah.
LAURA: On Grog?
MATT: Okay.
SAM: I don't think it's magic.
ORION: Yeah, he's being controlled by it.
TRAVIS: He can do whatever.
LIAM: It's more natural,
it's creature-based.
TRAVIS: She's also being controlled.
ORION: I know, but you're a
big, hulking, crazy mofo.
MATT: No, it is a magical force.
ORION: Yes, it is.
MATT: Forced to make a save.
TRAVIS: Save me, save me.
MATT: Go head and make an arcana check.
(Sam and Laura sing along
with tense background music)
ORION: Uh, 17.
MATT: 17.
The chaotic influence in your
brain begins to dissipate,
and the rage-filled gaze begins
to fill your eyes once again,
this time clarifying on the
umber hulk in front of you.
LAURA: Thanks a lot, Tiberius.
SAM: Thank god.
ORION: I'm not done yet.
I slap him.
Just get on this, will you?
(Travis snarls)
ORION: I use two SP points to
do quickening spell.
I cast Grand Column under
myself. (imitates rock moving)
Fifteen feet up in the air.
MARISHA: Nice.
(Orion spits)
MATT: So, the stone beneath
Tiberius's feet rises up,
creating a column fifteen
feet above the rest.
He is now raised on a platform.
I'll put him right there.
Looking down upon the battlefield.
ORION: (clears throat) that is my turn.
MATT: All right, Vex, you're up.
LAURA: Oh, do I have to cast a saving throw
or am I fine?
LIAM: Be a badass, be a badass.
MATT: Are you looking at it, or
are you averting your gaze?
LAURA: No, I'm averting my gaze even though
I'm confused apparently.
MATT: Well, the confusion only lasts one turn.
LAURA: Okay, good.
I am not.
What's that thingy behind me?
MARISHA: Oh, we've got these.
MATT: This here?
LAURA: No.
LAURA: Yeah, what's that?
MATT: This is rock.
LAURA: How high is it?
MATT: This is about 25, 30 feet up.
TRAVIS: Use your laser pointer, dude.
MATT: And this is where the light
source is coming from.
You can't look over that way.
LAURA: All, right cool.
I avert my gaze
but I listen very carefully to the sound
of where it's coming from.
(Taliesin whistles)
LAURA: And I shoot in that direction.
MATT: Okay.
(Taliesin and Marisha imitate birds)
MATT: So go ahead and make your
attacks against this fellow.
TRAVIS: That's some Hawkeye stuff.
MATT: You shooting this one?
LAURA: Let's do the one that is surrounded
so I get like, what,
flanking bonus or something.
MATT: For ranged, you would not get a bonus
for that unfortunately.
LAURA: Lame. All right.
MATT: So are you shooting
at the one behind you?
This one?
LAURA: Sure.
Okay.
LAURA: No, no, no, no, the other one.
MATT: Okay, all right.
So, make your attacks with a disadvantage,
as you're kind of keeping your eyes back
and shooting in its general direction.
MARISHA: Big money, no whammies.
LAURA: 12, both of them were 12.
But plus 11.
MATT: Plus, eleven?
Hits.
LAURA: Yes!
Oh, and I get two attacks, right?
MATT: You do, yes.
LAURA: Okay.
Still disadvantage?
MATT: Yep.
LAURA: 15 plus 11, hits.
MATT: That also hits, yeah.
So both attacks hit.
LAURA: Yes!
MATT: Did you want to use your
bonus action for anything?
LAURA: Oh yes, Hunter's Mark.
MATT: All right, so you throw Hunter's Mark
on this umber hulk there.
LAURA: Yes, I do.
MATT: But you're like, you're my quarry, ugh.
Keeping your eyes back.
You go ahead and pull your
first and second arrow,
(imitates bow firing
arrows), letting them loose,
kind of letting a little bit of faith
take your arrows to the wind.
Both finding purchase on your foe.
LAURA: Can I use bloodseeking bow on that one?
MATT: You can, yes.
LAURA: Sweet.
All right, cool.
So that's 15, no, 11.
And then 15.
(group laughs)
LAURA: It was good so I kept it.
TRAVIS: She dropped it,
but it was a good roll.
ORION: Yeah, take the drop.
LAURA: Plus bloodseeking, which is 10 damage,
plus Hunter's Mark, which
is a six, which is 3.
MATT: So total damage of...?
LAURA: Oh, I have to add.
(Matt laughs)
LAURA: 15 plus 11 plus 3.
26, 29 damage.
MARISHA: Woo!
MATT: Nice!
(Liam imitates arrows firing)
MATT: So, as your arrows sink into him,
one blasts into him.
Fire cascades up the side,
you can see the middle
of its plates beginning to burn
and torch the cinderous glow.
It reels back, gets its claws ready,
now fixated on you 'cause you
just announced your presence to it.
LAURA: I'm looking again, so.
MATT: All right.
Anything you wanna do with...?
LAURA: Trinket?
MATT: Trinket.
LAURA: Oh, yeah.
Can he run up and attack the other one?
While keeping his eyes down?
MATT: He would have to use one
of your attacks to do that.
LAURA: Oh okay, well then he's just
hanging out.
MATT: Trinket's just hanging out.
LAURA: He's protecting Scanlan.
(Matt imitates bear growling)
Yeah, big old bear protecting your gnome.
LAURA: Protect the gnome!
LIAM: Gnome coverage.
[Marisha And Taliesin] Gnome coverage.
MATT: No healer this week.
What could possibly go wrong?
MARISHA: Gnomewatch 2015.
MATT: Scanlan, you're up.
SAM: Scanlan.
LIAM: Ride the bear, Scanlan.
SAM: Ride the bear.
TRAVIS: Oh my God.
SAM: I will just step forward a little,
and I will cast polymorph
on our big friend
that we're surrounding.
And I'll turn him into a snail.
MARISHA: A snail? Aww!
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: Can you do that?!
SAM: Yes.
MATT: What's the DC, the difficulty
class on your spells?
SAM: Through the horn of clarity or whatever.
So it's 17.
MATT: 17, alright.
SAM: Or no, 19, sorry, 19.
MATT: 19.
SAM: It's plus two.
MATT: So, as the two umber hulks are there,
the one that's in the center
of the group, (snarls).
LAURA: Oh, Tiberius.
LAURA: Rears back, beginning to
unleash its series of attacks,
and then (sharp hiss),
into this tiny--
TRAVIS: What?!
MATT: --snail form on the ground.
LAURA: Awesome!
LIAM: Don't touch the snail until the--
LAURA: Why?
LIAM: 'Cause he'll poof out into
the fucking big guy again.
SAM: Don't hurt the snail.
LIAM: Leave it, leave it.
SAM: Don't pick up the snail.
Just be nice to the snail.
LIAM: Leave it alone.
Hit the other one.
ORION: Don't do anything.
I'll take care of the snail.
(talking over each other)
MATT: There's a tiny, tiny little
snail on the ground now
that looks very confused.
LAURA: That's confusing.
MATT: Very confused, which is
ironic for an umber hulk,
to feel confused.
SAM: As a bonus action,
I give dice to--
who's coming up next?
Who's coming up soon?
MATT: Next'll be Percy.
SAM: Percy, you get dice.
TALIESIN: What dice do I get?
MATT: d8.
SAM: A d8 for inspiration.
TALIESIN: A d8? All right. Excellent.
MATT: Percy, you're up.
(Sam imitates flutes)
Gotta do my app.
MATT: Do your app, fuck it up.
ORION: Do the app.
SAM: No, it's not ready.
(group laughs)
TALIESIN: I'm gonna take one of my
two actions to clear my gun.
TRAVIS: Yeah, the jam.
TALIESIN: Clear the jam.
And then set up for a fire shot.
And I'm gonna take a fire shot.
Am I at a disadvantage?
(tinny electronic music)
MATT: You're inspired.
SAM: It's so weak, it's so weak.
TRAVIS: You've gotta get it better.
MATT: So, who are you shooting?
TALIESIN: I'm shooting our friend over there.
I've just sort of turned, and I'm firing.
TALIESIN: So am I at a disadvantage?
MATT: Averting your gaze?
TALIESIN: I'm averting my gaze, but
I know where it is.
MATT: Right. So go ahead
and fire at disadvantage.
SAM: You got the dice, you got the dice.
TALIESIN: Okay.
14 with the disadvantage.
MATT: 14 with the disadvantage
will miss, unfortunately.
(imitates gun firing)
The fire shot arcs off into the distance--
TALIESIN: Oh oh, actually--
MARISHA: Oh yeah, inspiration.
MATT: Add the inspiration dice.
TALIESIN: 17.
MATT: 17 will just barely hit.
(group cheers)
TALIESIN: Well done, well done, ha ha!
ORION: Good shot!
LIAM: Good stunt work, Tiberius.
TALIESIN: So, that's gonna do--
ba-bumpa-bum.
ORION: I have to wait to figure
out when to open which one.
TALIESIN: That's 17 fire damage,
17 fire damage.
MATT: 17 fire damage, nice.
Okay, you hear the shot hit,
and you hear a cracking
sound as one of its plates
actually freezes and
shatters off of its body,
exposing kind of a fleshy undercarriage.
MARISHA: Nice.
[Orion And Marisha] Undercarriage.
MATT: This umber hulk is starting
to look a little rough.
That brings us to the top of--
Do you want to move
or stay where you are?
TALIESIN: I'm going to step back to--
bring me back two to three
steps, just like, back away.
MATT: Back here.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
Just like, here.
LAURA: Avoid the snail.
SAM: Yeah, don't step on the snail.
TALIESIN: I'm not stepping on the snail.
TALIESIN: Yeah, that's good.
MATT: There? Okay, good.
All right, that brings us to--
LAURA: I'm using it!
MATT: Laser pointers, we have use.
Keyleth, you're up.
KEYLETH Okay, after seeing Grog
get confused, I turn,
and I go straight for his throat.
And I'm trying to drag him into the creek.
TRAVIS and LAURA: Ooh.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: I wanna take the umber hulk
into the creek right behind me.
MATT: Okay, so go ahead and roll for a grapple.
MARISHA: All right.
TRAVIS: Come on, cave bear.
MARISHA: How do I grapple as a bear?
LIAM: Bear hug, man, bear hug.
LAURA: Yeah, just take him.
TALIESIN: How does one grapple as a bear?
It is a strength check, I guess.
MATT: Does anyone else--
Can I have the book real fast?
Just to be sure we know
how we're doing this.
TALIESIN: Have you noticed
there's a rhinoceros in here?
MARISHA: I can be a a rhinoceros.
MATT: It's a contest, yes.
TRAVIS: Why have you not been
a rhinoceros yet?
MARISHA: It just hasn't been useful yet.
SAM: She usually picks a bird of some sort.
MARISHA: I'm waiting for the right time.
LIAM: She can only turn into
things she's seen.
SAM: I'm a squirrel and a bird!
You should be a rhinoceros.
TALIESIN: We're just waiting for you to
scream, "It's morphin time!"
It's morphing time!
Bear!
MARISHA: Oh my god, can you make me
smoke bombs that smoke,
and I say, "It's morphin time"?
MATT: So you can make a grapple attempt
in place of one of your attacks.
MARISHA: Okay.
That's what I want to do.
MATT: All right.
MARISHA: So I just strength check then?
MATT: So it is an athletics check.
MARISHA: Oh. I don't have stats, I'm a bear.
MATT: No, you use the bear's stats.
MARISHA: But all I have are the basic six.
MATT: Right, what's the strength?
MARISHA: Five.
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: So that's what I do.
MATT: Yeah, roll the dice, add plus five.
(group cheers)
ORION: It's 20!
MATT: Natural 20.
(clapping)
You reach forward and latch onto it
with your claws and your teeth,
onto the umber hulk.
MARISHA: Going for the throat.
MATT: Alright.
So that's your first attack.
You can go ahead while it's grappled
and attack with the other strikes.
MARISHA: I'm taking him underwater.
MATT: Okay.
You pull.
LAURA: Oh god, you're doing it, Keyleth.
MARISHA: Pulling him underwater.
LIAM: It's a waterfall, oh.
MATT: (imitates thudding) You both plunge
underneath the water's surface.
Take a big old breath right beforehand,
and I'm going underwater.
ORION: Wait, can you let him
go and let him drown?
LAURA: Yeah, let him go, 'cause it's a waterfall.
MARISHA: No, I'm holding on to him.
LAURA: But Keyleth, there's a waterfall.
It's fine.
MATT: It's now its turn.
It's going to try
and break your grapple.
MATT: Make an athletics check.
MARISHA: Against his strength, I guess.
Ah, 20.
MATT: 20, okay.
You maintain your grip on the umber hulk.
It's thrashing in the
water trying to get its way
to the surface. (snarls)
Still slashing about.
So it's gonna make its
attacks against you.
MATT: That is a 14.
MARISHA: Hits.
MATT: 14 hits you?
MARISHA: I'm a bear, my armor
class is 12 right now.
MATT: Well no, you keep your armor class.
MARISHA: I keep my armor class?
MATT: I'm pretty sure.
LIAM: Yes, the answer to that is yes.
TRAVIS: Yeah, you do.
LIAM: Definitely yes.
MATT: Nah, let's see real fast
actually on this one.
SAM: Keep subscribing
to Geek &amp; Sundry everybody.
MATT: Exactly.
SAM: We're going for 1200 subscribers tonight,
and if we reach that number...
good for you.
(group laughs)
MATT: Here we go.
LIAM: Sam will write a ballad.
SAM: I will.
MATT: You gain the scores--
SAM: By the way, this music is just great.
MATT: It's 12 plus-- it's whatever the 12 is,
plus your proficiency modifier,
I think is what it is.
For now, we'll say it hits.
'Cause I don't wanna hold this up.
TALIESIN: There once was a player--
SAM: In Nantucket?
LAURA: Don't.
MATT: No, you gain its armor class.
MARISHA: I do gain its armor class.
MATT: Yeah, you do.
MARISHA: So it hits.
MATT: Yeah, it hits you.
All right.
Second strike.
That's also gonna hit you.
All three hit you.
You take six points of slashing damage.
11 points of slashing damage.
And 6, 11, 17--
MARISHA: It's okay guys.
MATT: Total of 26 points of slashing damage.
MARISHA: I am no longer a bear.
MATT: So you lose your grip
as your form reverts.
You are now back to
Keyleth's form in the water.
SAM: And you're in the water!
MARISHA: Can I cast a concentration
spell on myself?
MATT: No, because you used your
actions to grapple it.
MARISHA: And that's it.
MATT: So you're now just back in
the Keyleth form, underwater.
You catch your breath and
realize you're now underwater
in near darkness with an
umber hulk right on you.
MARISHA: Hey brah. Sup?
Fancy meeting you here.
MATT: Vax, you're up.
LIAM: Okay, so first thing I do is lean down
and pick up the snail
off the ground and say,
"Hey, um, go fuck yourself."
And then I throw him into the waterfall.
SAM: Oh Jesus!
MATT: Over here?
LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: All right.
Go ahead and roll a ranged attack.
So just roll, add dexterity.
LIAM: Okay.
LAURA: Oh gosh, okay okay.
LIAM: Great great great.
Dexterity you say? 18.
MATT: 18?
LAURA: No, it's higher than that, yo!
ORION: No, it's fine if he drowns and dies.
LIAM: Oh sorry, yeah, that's 21.
22, 22.
MATT: You throw, it arcs over.
Lands in the water.
(imitates water sucking)
Goes under into the waterfall.
LIAM: Toodle-oo shitface.
SAM: Hey wait, he (stutters) he swam away?
MATT: No, he threw the snail over the waterfall.
SAM: Hey!
Bye-bye!
LIAM: Now, that seems like a
bonus action to me, right?
(group laughs)
MATT: That's an attack.
LIAM: So then that's an attack, okay.
MARISHA: (laughs) That's an attack.
MATT: It's the world's easiest grapple throw.
TRAVIS: You threw him forever.
LIAM: Then I'm good.
LAURA: That's it?
LIAM: Well, that's my action, right?
MATT: Correct.
LIAM: And I only have one.
SAM: You can move, you can move.
LIAM: All right, so then,
I'll hop through, through
Percy and my sister.
And run up behind the shithead
who's fucking with Keyleth.
MATT: Make an acrobatics check,
try to tumble through them.
LIAM: Yeah, that's easy.
ORION: He's in the water, though.
LIAM: 16 (mumbles) 29.
MATT: Yeah, you're fine, and
where do you wanna go?
LIAM: Right up behind shitface there.
And do I have anything left?
Or do I just get there and stop.
MATT: Well, it was the attack to throw it.
You would have your second off-hand.
LIAM: Second attack.
Well let's stab him in
the ass then, right.
MATT: Well, you have disadvantage
'cause it's currently
in the water thrashing about,
and it's hard to see.
Well, that's not very good.
15.
MATT: 15 misses unfortunately.
So as you slash down with
your dagger into the water,
it's just too hard to really make out
what that form moving is.
LIAM: I still feel pretty good about that round.
TRAVIS: Yeah, it was pretty good.
MATT: Grog, you're up.
TRAVIS: Am I? (grunts)
With my frenzied rage renewed,
I run towards the water,
haunted by nightmares
of Sebastian in the Little Mermaid,
and I leap into the water and
start slashing and slashing.
MATT: Go ahead and make your
three attacks, Grog.
(Liam sings opening
notes to "Under the Sea")
TRAVIS:  Le poisson, le poisson,
hee hee hee, fuck you bitch
(Matt laughs)
TRAVIS: 18 plus... that's 26.
MATT: 26 hits.
TRAVIS: Okay, good.
Second attack.
26.
MATT: Hits.
TRAVIS: Okay. 25.
TRAVIS: Good.
MATT: Go ahead and roll damage, Grog.
As you come charging
forward, just (grunts),
leaving bits of foam cascading
off the side of your mouth.
Your eyes just glazed over with white.
You bring the axe down into the water,
form towards where the splashing is.
Keeping mindful that Keyleth
might be in there somewhere.
But you're very much see the
larger form in the field, so.
TRAVIS: It's all about sushi right?
MARISHA: Oh, I'm fine.
MATT: Yeah, so damage on the first strike?
TRAVIS: Eight, second one is 16.
MATT: Eight, 16, that's 24.
TRAVIS: And 17, thirty.
What's 24 plus 10?
LAURA AND MATT: 34.
MATT: Grog.
34 points of damage.
As your axe comes down,
slam once into the water.
You see one of the claws
start pulling itself up
out of the surface.
It's head's still under the water.
You slam the axe down.
You see the arm actually snaps
and begins to drift down the river.
As it looks up at you, its eyes open.
Before the gaze can meet
yours, the axe comes down
and plunges itself
directly into the forehead
of the umber hulk with a
shunk sound.
As it does, its body goes limp and begins
to float down the water.
(group cheers and claps)
LAURA: Well, that was easy.
SAM: Was it?
LAURA: I walk up and try to help
Keyleth out of the water.
MATT: Okay.
You help Keyleth out of the water.
At this point, the snail form,
which doesn't have a
whole lot of hit points,
has taken enough damage
to alleviate itself
from the polymorph.
As the spell fades, as the
snail form is destroyed,
the other umber hulk
begins clawing its way
up the side of the mountain,
burrows through the actual stonework--
LAURA: Ah, balls.
MATT: --(imitates explosion) and
bursts out of the ground
right behind you, Vax.
(imitates explosion)
VAX: Oh, fuck a duck.
TRAVIS: Come on, drop this thing.
LAURA: This is why you shouldn't
have thrown the snail.
MATT: But that's its turn.
LIAM: I thought it would get
washed all the way out.
Down the toilet, all the way out.
MATT: All right, that brings us
to the top of the round.
Tiberius.
MARISHA: It was at least badass.
LIAM: Elegant.
MARISHA: It was very elegant.
TALIESIN: I'm sure it was
a wonderful thought.
ORION: Firebolt.
MATT: Okay, roll for it.
Roll for the attacks.
LIAM: Just past it, please.
MATT: Yep, any directed spell like that
you have to roll and add
your spell range modifier.
ORION: Sweet, that does not hit.
MATT: What'd you roll?
ORION: Uh, 11.
MATT: Disadvantage, so.
You rolled an 11 total?
ORION: 10.
MATT: Yeah, you miss.
So, as you aim your firebolt
(imitated fire shooting)
You're just averting your gaze,
and it jumps over and arcs
through the rest of the carvern,
lighting it as it goes like a flare.
ORION: Good cavern.
MATT: That leads to Scanlan.
SAM: Scanlan?
MATT: Actually no, Vex is up
and then Scanlan, sorry.
LAURA: Me?
MATT: You, you.
LIAM: Kill it before it kills me.
Okay.
LAURA: I am gonna keep my gaze
averted, but I just heard it,
and I'm gonna--
ORION: That rhymed.
LAURA: I'm gonna attack it.
WIth some arrows.
MATT: Go for it.
So two arrows, notched.
(imitates arrows firing)
Disadvantage on each attack.
LAURA: Oh, okay.
LIAM: Don't let it eat my head, please.
LAURA: Yeah, it's the same. 18.
No, lying.
20.
MATT: 20 hits.
Go ahead and roll for the second attack.
LAURA: 19.
MATT: Both hit.
LAURA: Okay, good.
MATT: Go ahead and
roll damage on each.
LAURA: Is this the one
that I Hunter's Marked?
No, the other one Hunter's Marked.
MATT: The other one was, yeah.
LAURA: Okay, that's fine.
10 plus 13 is 23.
MATT: But you could switch
over your hunter's mark.
LAURA: And I switched over my Hunter's
Mark as my bonus action.
MATT: With your bonus action.
LAURA: So I add the-- oh, one.
MATT: So a total of?
LAURA: 24.
MATT: 24 points of damage.
All right, got you.
(imitates arrows flying)
The arrows end up piercing
part of the armor.
Each sink in a good, solid
six, seven inches or so.
It angrily (wet snarling) at the impact,
but it wasn't enough force
to send it back at all.
But it knows exactly where you are.
That brings us to Scanlan.
SAM: Scanlan's gonna move
right in front of where--
I believe that's Percy?
LIAM: Save the day, Scanny.
LAURA: Oh yeah, I should've ran Trinket up there.
LIAM: Repeat, just like last week.
SAM: Toss another dice to Percy,
he seems to need them.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
SAM: And I'm gonna cast
lightning bolt at the thing.
Who's wet from being in the water, yes?
So electricity is gonna
be pretty bad on him.
MATT: All right.
So, because you're kind of averting
your gaze to look away--
SAM: Disadvantage.
MATT: No, because you don't roll to attack.
But it gets advantage on its saving throw
because of that aspect.
MATT: So, it rolled natural 20 for its saving,
so it takes half damage.
But go ahead and roll your 8d6,
it's the lighting bolt.
SAM: 8d6.
MATT: Arcs out from your fingers.
(imitates lightning)
SAM: 8d6, 8d6.
8d6?!
TALIESIN: Yeah.
SAM: 8?!
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: Yes.
SAM: Shit!
(group laughs)
Uh, six, seven, eight, nine, 10, 11, 12.
13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19,
20, 21, 22 (mutters softly)
28!
MATT: 28, okay.
14 points of damage to the umber hulk
as the bolt of lightning
cascades through its body.
It lights up for a second as you see
the crawling fingers
of electricity kind of
shoot through its plates.
SAM: I like crawling fingers.
MATT: Indeed.
ORION: That was the name of
the one girl, wasn't it?
SAM: Yes.
MARISHA: Oh, I loved Crawline, she was so nice.
MATT: As the bolt grounds itself,
the rest of the water on
its form evaporates
from the sheer force of the electricity.
You see the umber hulk still standing.
Angry, in pain, and
standing, although it's still
looking a little worse for wear.
You don't wanna do that to an umber hulk.
(group laughs)
SAM: You're right.
MATT: Percy, you're up.
TALIESIN: Taking my shot, I'm averting my eyes, so.
SAM: Use those dice, use those dice.
MARISHA: Whoo!
TALIESIN: 24 to hit.
MATT: That was the disadvantage?
TALIESIN: At the disadvantage.
MATT: Awesome, that hits.
TALIESIN: That's 1d8 plus five.
That's, ugh, that's terrible.
That's six points of damage.
I'm taking my second shot.
MATT: All right.
LIAM: Shoot it in the mouth.
(clapping)
MARISHA: Oh wait, but it's disadvantage.
TALIESIN: I rolled twice.
So I rolled a 19 and a 20, which means--
MARISHA: Which are both your critical, right?
Which are both my criticals.
So a critical at a disadvantage.
TRAVIS: Sick, nasty.
TALIESIN: Just point, nyah, nyah!
LIAM: Yes Percy.
Critical on a disadvantage!
MATT: Well done.
TALIESIN: So I'm also gonna spend my die.
LIAM: Whatever your last name is again.
SAM: The die is for the attack.
MATT: It's for attacks, skills,
and saving throws,
not for damage.
TALIESIN: That's, uh...
five, six, seven, eight,
that's 11 points of damage.
TRAVIS: Finish him.
MATT: 11 points of damage from the first one.
TALIESIN: 11 points of damage from the second one.
MARISHA: But that one's critical.
So it doubles, right?
TALIESIN: It's just 1d8 becomes 2d8, right?
MATT: Correct, yeah.
TALIESIN: Yeah that's-- yeah.
MATT: Okay, it's 11 points damage.
Gotcha.
So, as you rear back
your shot (imitates gun firing)
it resounds.
It hits the plate, shatters
it on the other side
of its chest.
You can now see this
weird purplish goo
beginning to spill from its wounds.
You see it's holding itself up,
and it's having a hard time
keeping physical form there.
Keyleth, you're up.
MARISHA: Oh. Um, cool.
(Liam laughs)
ORION: Word.
MARISHA: Word.
I'm still a person.
I'm gonna go ahead and also
do a call lighting spell.
Bam, call lightning right on its head.
'Cause he's wet.
MATT: Call lighting it is.
MATT: So, as you begin to complete your spell,
you can see now the upper arch,
the 100 foot archway, the
ceiling of this area begins
to fill with this strange
cloudy, thunderous booms,
as a raincloud is created
and summoned across the rooftop.
At which point, Keyleth frees her hand up
and pulls down as a single
bolt streaks through the air,
slamming into the same
lightning bolt wound
that you left previously on it,
where the edges of its
armor are still glowing
from the heat.
Go ahead and roll damage.
MARISHA: Got him right in the ass.
It just gets straight damage?
MATT: Yeah, it gets a bonus on
its saving throw, though.
Or advantage.
Which it makes.
MARISHA: I get 3d10.
MATT: 3d10.
All right, go for it.
MARISHA: 6, 7--
MATT: It is no longer outdoors-only.
MATT: It gets a bonus for being outdoors.
MARISHA: 11 damage.
MATT: 11 damage to the umber hulk.
Which is halved.
He made a saving throw, to a six.
MARISHA: Saving throw, mm.
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Finish him.
Cause you're having to avert your gaze.
You're trying to
work out this whole thing
where you're all basically
at a severe disadvantage
fighting this thing, unless you want
to be completely fucked over.
All right.
SAM: Should have created sunglasses
for him or something.
TRAVIS: We have two of its eyes.
MATT: It's now its turn.
LAURA: Ugh, it's still alive.
MATT: It turns and runs past,
to the one who shot it
with the angry lightning bolt.
(Travis laughs)
MATT: The tiny gnome that now
is a delicious morsel
in the mandibles of an umber hulk.
It comes running forward
like a giant armored gorilla. (grunts)
LAURA: Oh, no.
MATT: Reaching back with both of its claws,
swiping at you Scanlan,
that is a 23 to hit.
SAM: Oh, yeah.
MATT: 25 to hit.
MATT: Its mandibles are 24 to hit.
SAM: That hits three times.
MATT: Yep.
You take 13--
LAURA: Oh, no!
LIAM: But you're so little.
MATT: 24.
SAM: Ooh!
MATT: 38 points of slashing damage.
This is the sound I make.
(high-pitched wail)
(group laughs)
MATT: As it just strikes you,
all of its form now,
you're almost pinned to the ground,
blood oozing from your face
as gashes, slash wounds
are across your entire body.
It's looming over you, ready to try
and finish you off next round.
LAURA: Ugh!
MATT: That brings us to Vax.
LIAM: Okay.
So, he's now got his back turned to me.
I'm just gonna stick both
knives into his guts and say,
"No one touches the gnome!"
LIAM: Right in his guts, that's shit.
So, fuck that.
And this one is way better.
So that's 27.
MATT: 27 hits definitely.
LIAM: Okay, this is the flametongue.
MATT: It is considered flanking,
because Scanlan is there.
Oh yes.
LIAM: Four plus two is six.
(Sam sings along with dramatic music)
LIAM: Two, three, fuck, four, fuck, seven,
nine, 18, 24 damage.
With the second knife, sneak
attack into his ball sack.
MATT: How do you want to do this?
(group yells triumphantly)
LIAM: I stick it in the back
of his his spider nads.
And rip it out his bum
and out the back of him.
LAURA: Gross!
LIAM: And just spill it all out the bottom.
(all talking at once)
SAM: I'm right next to him,
it might spill on me.
LIAM: That's all right,
that's all right.
MATT: As it's looming over
Scanlan who's on his back,
it's tearing into him and
starting to gut him best it can.
He's screaming from beneath.
You rush underneath, tumble,
bringing your dagger up
and slam it right under
the bottom of its abdomen.
LAURA: Balls.
MATT: As you do it, (snarls),
looks down towards you
and right before its gaze can meet yours,
you yank back with all your might,
basically scissoring and
jagged drawing the blade
up the back of its body.
As you do it, (imitates vomiting)
leaps forward.
It's now-soft torso and belly left open
from the armor plates being shot off,
spills a number of its warm innards
right onto Scanlan's body and form.
SAM: Ugh, no!
It went in my mouth!
(Travis laughs)
MATT: And then it collapses on top of him..
SAM: Ah!
(group laughs)
MATT: You take six points of crushing damage
as the umber hulk collapses on top of you.
TRAVIS: I run over and shove the
umber hulk off of Scanlan.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: Ugh! Ah!
LAURA: Oh my gosh.
SAM: What just happened?
MARISHA: I go over to Scanlan, and I just,
I just lay my hands on him,
and I cast Cure Wounds in a level 2 spot.
LIAM: Nobody touches my man-wife.
(group laughs)
SAM: What's that spell do?
MARISHA: You do-- it's 2d8 plus 10 healing.
SAM: You roll, right?
TALIESIN: Yep.
MARISHA: Do I roll or does he?
MATT: For which spell is this?
MARISHA: I'm doing Cure Wounds on him.
At level two.
MATT: Cure Wounds, level two?
2d8 plus five.
MARISHA: Do I roll?
MATT: You roll.
MARISHA: So you heal, 16, 20 points.
SAM: Thank you.
MATT: So, as you heal him,
touch him with the spell,
you wipe the umber
hulk ichor off of your hand.
ORION: I cast prestidigitation
and clean everybody up.
LAURA: Maybe you should jump
in that water, Scanlan.
TRAVIS: You should get in the water
and clean yourself off.
TALIESIN: We have running water.
Use running water.
SAM: I think I wanna keep it on.
(group laughs)
ORION: He's clean already.
TRAVIS: As a badge of honor?
SAM: It's a badge of honor.
LIAM: Like the walking dead,
you're gonna sneak by the rest of 'em?
SAM: I think I'm gonna keep the blood on me,
if you don't mind.
LAURA: Alright.
MATT: That's, uh... okay.
TRAVIS: Gross.
SAM: Warning to others.
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: So, you still hear the rushing
of the water down below.
You now stand at this
portion of the cavern,
the dull glow in the distance
of some sort of light source
in that direction.
The rest of the caverns opens up this way.
LAURA: Ugh.
TRAVIS: Let's go towards the light.
SAM: Can we take a short rest and heal up?
TRAVIS: No, I run.
LAURA: Short rest, short rest.
TRAVIS: No, running.
LIAM: Running?!
(Sam laughs)
SAM: Why don't you let some people heal?
MATT: Grog goes running.
Grog, who's interested.
TRAVIS: I'm frenzy raging.
SAM: Oh God, Grog!
Grog, no!
TRAVIS: It's a bright, shiny thing.
I'm going there!
LAURA: He is frenzying.
LIAM: I'm unscathed, so I run after Grog,
just to give him backup if he needs.
MARISHA: I'll follow after Vax.
MATT: All right, you guys head out.
Eventually, you come
around the corner to see
what looks like a campfire.
ORION: I follow as well.
TRAVIS: Aww.
MATT: It looks like a setup
with a small bundle of,
what looks like bedding.
There's a campfire set up.
It's mostly out at this point.
Like there's still a little
bit of a flame flicker
to it, but it's just
embers for the most part.
Does not appear--
TRAVIS: I start hacking away at the bedding.
Just chopping the shit out of it.
SAM: Jesus!
(group laughs)
MATT: Grog starts hacking away
at the bedding.
(Travis grunts)
LIAM: I'm just watching and shrugging.
LAURA: No, look and search around
and see what's in the bedding.
LIAM: I try to keep like six or
seven foot difference--
MATT: (arrows whooshing)
SAM: Oh, no!
LIAM: Fuck!
MATT: Three crossbow bolts come
flying out of nowhere--
LIAM: You dick!
MATT: --two hitting Grog.
(Marisha laughs)
LAURA: Why weren't you stealthing?
LIAM: I am now.
TRAVIS: Somebody likes their bedding apparently.
LIAM: I rolled a 29 of stealth as
soon as the first arrow flew.
MARISHA: That was a Coleman, alright?
(group laughs)
That was a very expensive sleeping bag.
TALIESIN: Never attack the bedding before
you know the thread count.
TRAVIS: It was 3000 count Egyptian.
TALIESIN: God.
MATT: Grog, you take seven
points of piercing damage,
which is halved to four
because you're raging.
TRAVIS: Right. (grunts)
MATT: As you can see
what looks like three small--
LIAM: Duergar.
LAURA: No, they're dwarves.
LIAM: Yeah, that's duergar.
That's dark dwarves.
LAURA: Oh!
LIAM: I consider myself a nerd.
MATT: And some strange beast
you've not seen before
seems to be accompanying one of them.
LAURA: Is that a brain?
MATT: It looks like an oversized, swollen brain
with a set of claws.
LIAM: It's hanging brain.
SAM: Krang?
MARISHA: Brain?
MATT: It's just like a large brain
with a set of arms and legs
like a panther.
LAURA: What?
TRAVIS: It's the brain bug from Starship Troopers.
MARISHA: That can't be good.
ORION: Take that out first.
MATT: Going off the same intiative order.
They've gone.
LIAM: I rolled a 29 stealth.
MATT: Yes, I know.
So you haven't been seen, and
you have the first action.
TRAVIS: Are they on the same level as us?
MATT: They are, yes.
LIAM: So I can dash and still attack?
MATT: If you'd like to.
LIAM: I would love to.
I would love to, uh--
where's this thing?
LAURA: Go for the brain.
LIAM: Yeah, of course
go for the brain.
I'm gonna hang brain.
I'm gonna run over--
MATT: Well if you dash as your action--
LIAM: Oh, I can't stealth?
So to stay stealth, I
need to go normal speed?
MATT: Well you can dash as your action,
but dash is your, basically a double move.
So you move and use your
action to move as well.
LIAM: And that's it.
MATT: That's all you'll be able to do.
LIAM: Um, I'm gonna-- no.
I'll you what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna go-- hey, god.
I'm gonna move over here, stealthily.
And go for ready.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: That's what it's called, right?
And wait?
MATT: Just wait.
LIAM: And the trigger is
when this asshole duergar
moves forward, I'm gonna stick
him in the back of the neck.
MATT: Okay. All right.
MARISHA: Nice.
MATT: Tiberius.
You hear Grog go, "Ugh!"
ORION: Oh, it seems like there's
trouble over there.
(group laughs)
What has Grog gotten himself into?
MARISHA: I don't know.
(Travis moans and strangles)
ORION: I saunter--
TRAVIS: You saunter?
SAM: Saunter.
ORION: Yes.
MATT: You jump off your pillar.
ORION: Oh.
MATT: Saunter over here?
ORION: Yeah, I would go around there to--
That's good, I suppose.
What's in between the--
between him and that.
Is that a boulder?
MATT: It's a giant raised stalagmite.
ORION: I see, how tall is that?
MATT: It's about 25 feet tall.
ORION: Oh crap, okay.
MATT: All you see is Grog standing
with three bolts
sticking out of his chest now.
LAURA: Oh no!
(Travis imitates wood breaking)
ORION: I can't do anything too much.
LIAM: Grog, I've got the hiccups.
MATT: Anything else, Tiberius?
Gotta keep this moving.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: The bolts.
TRAVIS: Right.
ORION: I'll just cast stoneskin on myself.
Okay, Stoneskin cast on you.
That brings us to Vex.
LAURA: All right, I can hear them
screaming so I'm gonna run over.
Call Trinket as I'm doing it.
TRAVIS: Who's screaming?
LAURA: You, you screamed.
TRAVIS: No, I'm not screaming.
MATT: Do you want to use
your full round to move?
Cause that's as far as
you can move currently.
Actually you can move two more.
LAURA: Can I see anything from that point?
MATT: All you see is Grog over there.
LIAM: They're covered
and he's around the bend,
so I'd run in further.
LAURA: All right, I'll run in further.
Can I run in and stealth or is that it?
MATT: Uh, you can attempt to.
LAURA: I'm gonna try to stealth
as I'm going in.
MATT: You're at disadvantage
on the stealth roll,
but go for it.
LAURA: Oh, a 20.
Aw!
17, okay.
Plus my stealth, which is five.
MATT: All right, so we'll say
you're pulled off
to the side there.
The stealth twins over there
being all stealthy-like.
No one can see what's going on with them.
It's like they're related.
TRAVIS: What's all this stealthing?
Where's all the killing?
MATT: That's your turn.
LAURA: I can't attack anything.
MATT: Scanlan.
SAM: Okay, I'm gonna move right there
into the room as far as I can.
MATT: You can go that far.
SAM: Okay.
And cast Stinking Cloud right there.
(Travis laughs)
It's gonna smell like just ass over there.
(group laughs)
MATT: Okay.
Best you can see, and
you haven't really seen
where they are, so
you're kind of like, oh,
you have the idea that perhaps
they're over in that vicinity
on the bolts around there.
So you can cast over in this
area, which is the only thing
you have view of.
SAM: Oh, oh, because that's
a big rock in my view there.
MATT: This is a big rock right there, yeah.
SAM: Okay, so yeah.
I'll put it right where you're
saying, right there, yeah.
MATT: Okay, that's about where you can go.
All right, so (hisses),
a giant--
TRAVIS: Ass cloud.
MATT: --green, ass cloud--
ORION: Scanlan, are you
doing an ass cloud again?
MATT: --begins to fill this space here.
As it does, they all
begin to hack and cough.
You can hear this now
between the rest of you,
echoing throughout.
TRAVIS: I'm slightly aroused.
(group laughs)
ORION: I was just going to say.
TRAVIS: I'm drawn to the smell.
SAM: (imitates flute) --stinks.
MATT:  Constitution saving throws.
Everything in the cloud.
SAM: (imitates flute) --stink.
MATT:  All them are failing.
ORION: Doing stink magic.
MATT: All right. You hear a cacophonous
amount of hacking, coughing,
as all of them drop their attack stances
and begin just retching, nearly vomiting,
in the middle of this green cloud of gas.
TRAVIS: Outstanding.
SAM: I'll also take a great heal potion?
Is that what they're called?
Not moderate.
MATT: Yes, greater.
SAM: Great, greater, okay.
I'll do that by myself.
You keep going.
MATT: Okay, greater heal
potion is 4d4 plus four.
SAM: Thank you.
MATT: All right, that brings us to Percy.
TALIESIN: I'm going to start
crawling around the--
I have a little thingy.
Someone took the thingy.
Oh, laser pointer.
Thank you.
LIAM: Hello, hey.
TRAVIS: It's a black light.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna start heading
down this direction,
and I'm going to actually
spend a movement,
spend my action and move
a little further down,
about, yeah, about there,
so I can start getting
a good look of what's up.
MATT: Okay, good.
All right. That brings us to Keyleth.
MARISHA: Okay, so I am going to take this
and move up to about here, I guess.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: Is where I can see.
And then I'm gonna
take this little block
of stone right here, this stalagtite
or mite or whatever it is--
MATT: Correct.
MARISHA: --and I'm gonna use Wall of Stone.
And instead of creating a wall,
I'm just gonna take that one
and I'm gonna push it (imitates thudding)
against that wall and
try and crush those guys.
TRAVIS: Whoa!
MATT: Wait, you're gonna use
Wall of Stone to try
and push that back?
MARISHA: I'm gonna take this wall,
and I'm gonna go crunch.
MATT: All right.
SAM: Oh my God.
TRAVIS: Can you do that?
TALIESIN: That's kinda harsh.
MARISHA: I don't know.
We'll find out.
LAURA: I like that that's the most
common quip.
"Can, can you do that?"
SAM: You can actually do that?
ORION: It's like earthbending.
MARISHA: I'm trying to earthbend this wall.
SAM: Hey Grog. Did you ever write down
our underwater spell,
potion thingies, whatever
those were called?
TRAVIS: We got two of 'em.
SAM: Yeah, did you right it down, though?
'Cause I didn't.
TRAVIS: What they were?
TALIESIN: She's got waterbreathing, so.
MATT: So how it works is, Wall of Stone,
you can create a wall
of stone, but it cannot
occupy the space of a creature.
So you will not be able to
push them back, unfortunately.
But you could lock them into an area,
if that's what you wanted to do.
SAM: The man telling us what
we can and can't do.
(group laughs)
MATT: It's the nature of the spell, guys.
MARISHA: Yeah, that's a waste of time.
Instead, I will--
I still got a Call Lightning going.
Fuck it.
I'm just gonna lightning
bolt some bitches.
MATT: All right.
You don't have view of any of
them right now, unfortunately.
MARISHA: Well, then I move to where I can.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: Yeah good.
Cop attitude with the DM.
TRAVIS: Yeah, yeah.
SAM: The man in charge of our fates.
TALIESIN: That always goes really well.
MATT: That'll be your turn.
SAM: Because of the attitude.
MATT: You moved twice.
You had to get a long distance.
MARISHA: Did I?
MATT: Yeah, because you were back here.
LAURA: Yeah, dude.
It was really far away, yo.
I've got a decent speed, okay, fine.
That's my turn then.
MATT: Sorry.
LIAM: Fuck those Wizards of the Coast, man!
I do what I wanna do.
MARISHA: Fucking Seattle assholes.
MATT: All right, so.
ORION: I love Seattle.
LIAM: So do I.
MATT: And what's the DC again of your spell?
SAM: Ah, oh.
SAM: Spell save DC, is that right? 19.
MATT: 19. All right.
All three of the-- and you
can now get a view of them.
They are dwarven, but their
skin is ashy and grey.
Their eyes are white and pupil-less.
And they are all on the
verge of vomiting right now.
They're both just keeling over.
One of them tries to bring a crossbow up,
and (imitates vomiting) has
to put it back down again.
They are unable to act this turn.
The weird brain creature, however--
MARISHA: That's awesome.
TRAVIS: What, has no nostrils?
TALIESIN: There's nowhere for him to retch from.
MATT: It moves out of the cloud,
looks over at you Grog.
SAM: Oh, no.
MATT: And just bears down for a second.
And you feel this...
intrusion in your mind.
TRAVIS: On my professor-torial mind.
MATT: Go ahead and make an
intelligence saving throw.
SAM: Oh, those aren't good for you.
MARISHA: Oh, no.
(Travis laughs)
TALIESIN: Well this, this ends poorly.
TRAVIS: Oh good, my modifier's negative 2,
so yippee-kye-ay-eh.
Six.
MATT: Alright.
ORION: Good roll.
TALIESIN: Good roll.
MARISHA: That's a good number.
MATT: You suffer nine points
of psychic damage
as there's a sudden blast
of excruciating pain
in the center of your brain.
It actually shakes you
a moment from your rage,
which then fills your mind once again.
TRAVIS: Like Kenny G music
coming through my brain.
TALIESIN: Someone needs a
Juggernaut helmet.
MATT: Also, you suffer--
MARISHA: He needs a Magneto helmet.
TALIESIN: Yeah, he needs the full Magneto.
MATT: --8 points of intelligence
damage technically.
You immediately fall unconscious.
(Laura gasps)
MARISHA: What?!
MATT: Your intelligence is brought to zero.
TRAVIS: Ah!
But I was at six!
LIAM: You gotta kill that thing.
LAURA: Oh no!
TRAVIS: I turn into a turnip?
MATT: That brings us to--
(Matt laughs)
Tiberius.
ORION: Tiberius, I mean--
MATT: Yes, you're Tiberius.
ORION: I say--
MATT: You just watched Grog just go (groans)
and fall to the ground.
Almost into the campfire.
LAURA: Oh, no.
TRAVIS: It's like when I tried to read
50 Shades of Grey. (groans)
ORION: Okay, I'm gonna--
TALIESIN: Around the bear.
ORION: Okay, I'm gonna go
right up to where Grog is.
MATT: All right.
ORION: Right there, right in front of him.
Now can I see the brain fucker?
MATT: Yes, you can from there.
MARISHA: The brain fucker.
MATT: The brain fucker's official name.
TALIESIN: Brain lover, brain lover.
ORION: Ooh, you're a nasty one.
MARISHA: He's a lover, not a fighter.
ORION: I'm gonna fire a glacial
blast at this dude.
MATT: Okay. Single targeted beam.
TALIESIN: Lobey.
MARISHA: Lobey.
TALIESIN: We're gonna name him Lobey.
MARISHA: Let's call him Lobey.
(Laura laughs)
MATT: Makes its saving throw.
TALIESIN: "Lobey, no!"
MATT: What's your DC?
ORION: My DC is 17.
MATT: It just rolled a 17, yeah.
It makes the saving throw.
So half damage.
TALIESIN: Take him everywhere.
ORION: Four, six, and 8d6.
TALIESIN: Our little Lobey.
MARISHA: Can we call him Jeff, Jeff Lobey?
SAM: Is that campfire still firing?
TALIESIN: Jeff Lobey.
MATT: It's embers, yeah.
21, 22, 23.
24, 26, 27, 22.
29 damage.
MATT: 29 damage?
(Taliesin laughing)
MATT: As you put your arms out,
you focus this blast of just
freezing cold arcane energy
that slams into the side
of this brain creature.
TALIESIN: Jeff Lobey, thank you.
MATT: As it does, you see it begins
to freeze its entire body.
As it reaches up and tries
to climb up it solidifies
and then shatters into a
hundred million pieces.
(group cheers)
SAM: Oh, the brain's dead.
TALIESIN: You killed Jeff Lobey!
MARISHA: You killed Jeff Lobey.
SAM: Lisa Loeb?
MARISHA: Lisa Lobey!
(group laughs)
They just keep going!
MATT: Lisa Loeb and then the
nine intelligence damage.
All right.
So the brain just (imitates
shattering) cascades
across the ground.
LIAM: Lisa Lobey.
MATT: And thank God.
Vex, you're now seeing three dwarves
retching and coughing over,
kind of looking about very nervously.
LAURA: Can I move to where I can get
a line of site on that one?
MATT: On this one here?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: Yeah, you can move to there
and get a line of sight.
LAURA: Okay cool, then
I'm gonna shoot him.
Oh wait, no, I can't.
SAM: Why?
LAURA: Yeah yeah yeah, I'm gonna do that.
LIAM: You still have a little bit of cover.
LAURA: I'm gonna do-- it's fine, I got it.
I'm really good.
LIAM: Just be a badass, okay?
That's your job.
LAURA: Okay.
27.
MATT: That hits.
LIAM: Are you alright, big guy?
LIAM: "Muh!"
LAURA: Oh, I should've tried to-- it's okay.
LIAM: "Muh! Muh!"
SAM: It's weird, Grog weirdly seems
smarter now than he was before.
LAURA: Hunter's Mark on that guy.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: Beep boop.
MATT: Good remembering.
MARISHA: Professor Grog's
having a hard time.
LAURA: 11.
MATT: 11, all right.
LAURA: 11, and then I'm gonna
hit him again.
And that's a 23.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: And that is nine damage for that arrow.
And then the six for a
Hunter's Mark is five.
MATT: So a total of...?
LAURA: Oh jeez-louise, 30 plus five is...
35.
MATT: (imitates arrows flying) "Ugh!"
The hacking, coughing duergar
dwarf is like, (coughs)
One in the shoulder,
and the other shoulder.
And it looks like that
you, (inhales sharply)
As it inhales a big old whiff
of horrible stinking cloud gas,
the arrow (imitates arrow flying)
through its throat
and out the back of its head.
Falls flat on its back.
LAURA: Yeah.
(group cheers)
MATT: The other ones look nervously about.
MARISHA: Get him a pillow! What!
MATT: One of them's just coughing out,
saying something in Undercommon.
(speaks in angry gibberish)
MATT: Anyone here speak Undercommon?
LAURA: I do!
MATT: You do?
SAM: You speak Undercommon?
LAURA: I do.
TALIESIN: Oondercommon.
LAURA: I knew we were gonna be
going down into some--
MATT: You hear him say,
"Quick, there's our exit!
"Back, back to the master."
LAURA: (whispering) Back to the master!
TRAVIS: Who's the master?
LAURA: You're unconscious.
MATT: All right.
That brings us to Scanlan.
SAM: Ah, shit.
I did not understand them, right?
So I don't know that they're going to run.
MATT: No.
TRAVIS: Let 'em run back to the
master and we'll track 'em.
SAM: I didn't learn that they're running, so.
Can I call out that I heard them?
Say, "Don't let them run!"
MATT: No, this happening
just as you heard them.
SAM: Okay, well.
I don't have a good line of sight on them,
so I don't even know that
they're there really, right?
I just hear coughing in the distance.
MATT: Yep.
Then I'll just move further
into the cavern there.
And I don't know that this works,
but I'll try to cast Dispel Magic on Grog.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: I don't know if that, if it's magic.
I have no idea.
MATT: So you go ahead and you
focus, you cast Dispel Magic
in Grog's vicinity.
SAM:  Wake up, Grog
MATT: You see the shift of arcane,
waving energy.
TRAVIS:  If I only had a brain
MATT: It does not seem to have an effect.
SAM: It doesn't do it!
Damn it!
Then as my bonus action,
can I still give him an inspiration dice
to do on like saving...?
MATT: You think at this point,
Grog isn't unconscious.
Grog is catatonic.
Grog has no intelligence.
There is nothing home.
You see him, on the ground,
drooling, eyes glazed over.
There is nothing there.
TALIESIN: You can't inspire a cantaloupe.
LAURA: What are we gonna do?
TALIESIN: The cantaloupe,
it's not gonna feel better about itself.
SAM: Okay, then I give my dice to Vax.
TALIESIN: I've tried insulting a cantaloupe,
you just don't get anywhere.
SAM: Vax, I've just inspired you.
(imitates flute)
MATT: I think the chat room's catching on
for those who know D&amp;D well.
LIAM: Okay, I hear a little
shithead grey-skinned dwarf--
SAM: Wait, it's not your turn.
I just gave you dice.
I thought you said Vax.
Okay, sorry.
MATT: It's all right.
So that ends Scanlan's turn.
Percy.
LIAM: Damn it.
TALIESIN: Laser.
I'm going to take my laser.
MATT: Your laser? Point your laser?
(Liam imitates ray gun)
TALIESIN: All right, I want to crawl forward
to the other side of Grog over there,
so I can see this little jerk.
MATT: It's a tough call, he has cover.
You can still see him.
TALIESIN: I ignore cover.
It's one of my magical things that I do.
LIAM: Three-quarters cover
according to the new rules.
MARISHA: Yeah, he's got a gun.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I ignore half
or three-quarters cover.
MATT: Then you can ignore three-quarters cover,
which he has. So, yes.
TALIESIN: Okay, I ignore it.
I'm also going to take a penalty
to my attack bonus
to attempt to do some damage
and to not kill, but injure, if possible.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: I wanna leave one for questioning.
So go ahead and roll
disadvantage on this attack.
Or do you want to just do subdual damage,
which is what you're doing?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
All right, so you're gonna aim in a way
that doesn't do lethal damage.
Go for it.
MATT: It's a normal attack,
there's no penalty to it.
TALIESIN: Just my penalty for extra damage.
MATT: Mm hm.
TALIESIN: Aha!
I crit!
So that's fun.
Let's roll damage.
9, 10, that's 25 points of damage.
LAURA: Yeah!
MATT: 25 points of damage.
All right, you run around the corner,
pull the gun out,
and aim at this like-- (coughs)
Where you look now, you see this
ghastly looking, evil, female-looking
grey-skinned dwarf.
Looks over at you and (gasps)
reacts and goes for her weapon.
As you do, you let loose and fire straight
into her shoulder, blasting
through most of her shoulder,
exposing bone.
It's not a deahtblow, but you see
she has been incapacitated.
ORION: Nice.
TALIESIN: That's my turn.
LAURA: I call out, "Let one of them live,
so I can question them."
TALIESIN: That's-- we got one.
MATT: Keyleth, you're up.
MARISHA: We got one?
TALIESIN: We got one.
MARISHA: Well, then.
MATT: That dwarf survived.
With one hit point.
MARISHA: If we got the guy we need.
I will move over a bit.
Yeah.
And... (imitates energy firing)
MATT: All right, go for it.
LIAM: Vines?
MATT: First off, make a constitution save,
'cause you stepped into a stinking cloud.
Unless you wanna move back here.
There you go.
MARISHA: Not having control.
MATT: Laser pointer.
MARISHA: I do (mumbles).
Okay.
So that is...
what is that?
22?
MATT: 22 points of damage. All right.
So the bolt streaks from
the cloud in the sky,
slamming into this other duergar.
As it sparks into the ground,
you see bits of stone
get thrown up from the
sheer force of the bolt,
doing a sincere amount of damage to it.
Not enough to finish it, but
it looks very, very fucked up.
You can see part of its face
is charred now,
and it's reeling from the blast.
Probably blew out its eardrums
from the cacophonous blast of the thunder.
MARISHA: That's my turn.
MATT: That's your turn.
It's now both of their turn.
They both failed their
saves with a two and a four.
They're both still hacking and coughing
in the stinking cloud.
Uh, go bards.
Vax, you're up.
LIAM: Okay, and there's a big cloud
of poo stink around them, so--
MATT: Correct, so all here.
ORION: "The poo cloud," Keyleth calls it.
LIAM: God dammit. All right.
MARISHA: Do I? "The poo cloud."
LIAM: Fuck it.
SAM: Just go in there, man.
LIAM: I'm gonna hold my
breath, and I'm gonna go
one, two, three, four, five,
and grab this guy around the neck
and hold my daggers to his neck.
And just hunker down and
try to hold him hostage.
MATT: Okay.
Go ahead and make a constitution check.
TRAVIS: A dirty mafia check?
LIAM: Is that a, is that a--
MATT: With advantage, because
you're holding your breath.
LIAM: Okay.
14.
TRAVIS: Just breathe it in.
SAM: Use the dice! Use the dice!
LIAM: What did you give me?
SAM: A d8.
LIAM: 22.
SAM: No, it's not an eight. A d8.
You gotta roll it.
MATT: Roll a d8 to add to it.
LIAM: 15.
(group laughs)
LIAM: It came up a one.
TRAVIS: 22!
MATT: So, as you rush in the cloud,
(breathes deeply)
you run in, pull your daggers out,
and because this isn't a natural cloud,
the arcane force puts it in your nostrils
and you can't help yourself. (coughs)
Your turn immediately ends
as you begin feeling your lunch
retching up into your stomach.
TRAVIS: Puke on him.
MATT: Okay. That brings us to Grog.
You are a--
TRAVIS: Oh, I got it.
(blows raspberry)
MATT: You are brain-dead.
(group laughs)
Tiberius, you're up.
LAURA: So sorry, Grog.
SAM: Can we heal him, what is it?
What do we need to do?
MARISHA: We'll figure that out when
we kill this guy, I guess.
LAURA: Restoration?
LIAM: Can you dispel that shit?
SAM: I tried, I tried.
MARISHA: He can't dispel it,
It's not magic.
But I might be able to
cure him afterwards.
LIAM: Tiberius, can you dispel that shit?
ORION: It's the same spell.
LAURA: It's a restoration spell,
it's not a dispel.
MARISHA: I might be able to.
ORION: So, the guy knocked down
over there is--
let me see that pointer.
This guy, that's the one that
we knocked out with the arrow?
TALIESIN: Yeah, that's the dead one.
ORION: The dead one
or the one we knocked out?
TALIESIN: He's dead.
ORION: Who do we have incapacitated?
TALIESIN: That's the one we shot.
MARISHA: That's the one Liam has.
LAURA: Let one live.
ORION: And the one right here is...?
LIAM: The one by me is weak.
MATT: Both of them are pretty
weak right now, actually.
ORION: I think I can step next to Percy
without stepping into that cloud.
MATT: So you can step over Grog,
get around here, you mean?
LAURA: (laughs) Honk.
TRAVIS: That's-- come on.
ORION: Sorry, excuse me, Grog, pardon.
I will shoot a firebolt
at the butthole across the way.
MATT: There? All right.
Go ahead and roll for the attack.
ORION: 14.
MATT: 14.
Unfortunately does not hit.
You aim, and it manages to
just pull out of the way.
LAURA: Oh my gosh.
MATT: Vex. You're up.
LAURA: Me?
MATT: Yes.
LAURA: I step over, and I try to shoot
the one that he just--
I stay out of the stink.
MATT: There you go, yeah.
Pull back-- (imitates bow shooting arrow)
LAURA: All right.
MATT: Roll to attack.
LAURA: 23.
MATT: That hits, go ahead and roll damage.
LAURA: 8.
MATT: That's enough.
As the arrow (imitates arrow flying),
careens off, slams into the chest.
(groans) It catches itself, steps back,
and plummets off the side of the cliff
onto the lower floor about 20 feet down.
Smack, onto the ground.
LAURA: And I ask Scanlan
to dispel the stank cloud.
TALIESIN: Dispel the stank.
LAURA: And I yell--
Can I yell out "surrender" in Undercommon?
MATT: You yell out, (speaks angry gibberish)!
(Laura speaks angry gibberish)
MATT: Make an intimidation check.
TRAVIS: That was a very good Klingon translation.
LAURA: Klingon.
(Liam speaks angry gibberish)
Whoa! Okay.
Um, eight.
MATT: Eight?
LAURA: Eight.
LIAM: What is with the dice tonight?
MATT: It rolled a one.
(group cheers)
MATT: It looks around and its
circumstances being extremely dire.
It drops its weapons, falls to its knees.
At your mercy.
That's where we'll end the game tonight.
SAM: Oh!
TALIESIN: Hey!
TRAVIS: What?!
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: You're, you're-- yeah.
SAM: Grog is brain dead.
MARISHA: I was gonna say, can I
go over and heal Grog before we end?
TRAVIS: I'm Vanilla Sky right now.
MATT: Nope, we're picking up next week.
LAURA: Oh no.
LIAM: Just five more hours, Matt.
Just five more hours.
MATT: We'll say for the circumstance here,
you go ahead and spend
a healing spell on him.
His wounds mend, no effect
on his catatonic state.
(group groans)
SAM: We have to wait a week.
MATT: Well guys, that's episode two
of Critical Role.
(laughs)
MARISHA: Damn it.
MATT: I hope you enjoyed it.
Remember to tell your
friends to come watch.
We'll be back next week, Thursday at 7:00.
I know the schedule said seven to nine.
We usually run a little later.
Because D&amp;D and why not?
LAURA: Oh, is this seven to nine?
MATT: It says seven to nine in the schedule,
but we consider seven to ten.
But yeah, hope you guys had fun.
Thank you so much for watching.
Hope we will have our
donations up next week.
Feel free to check it out.
This is Zac, our amazing
master of all awesomeness
on this Twitch channel.
Hey Zac, what's going on?
ZAC: Hey, good job, guys.
MATT: Thank you, thank you.
ZAC: You got a thousand subscribers.
(group cheers)
ZAC: Crazy, that's like, two weeks in.
MATT: Yeah, I know.
You go, Nyal.
We'll get you your stuff.
MARISHA: Yeah, you get a
Player's Handbook. That's lucky.
ZAC: We'll get you your shit!
I gotta print that photo so
you guys can all sign it.
MATT: Yes yes, let's go do that.
ZAC: No, it'll probably be
sent to you next Friday,
'cause we'll have you guys
sign it next Thursday.
LAURA: Sounds good.
MATT: Okay, cool.
TRAVIS: Zac, do you have any renew
intelligence potions on you, by chance?
ZAC: For you?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
ZAC: No.
TRAVIS: Shit.
MATT: Sorry buddy.
ZAC: So we're not going offline
for the night yet.
These guys are gonna head out
and Lucas and I are gonna play
some Hotline Miami 2.
For an hour, hour and a half.
MATT: There you go, rock it out.
ZAC: You know, just to close out the night
with a subscriber-only chat
to say thank you to our
thousand subscribers.
And tomorrow night we will be back
with So You Don't Have to,
which is a show where Hector and Becca
play the weirdest games
they can find online,
so you don't have to.
MARISHA: Nice.
(Matt laughs)
ZAC: And then we finish off tomorrow night
with Gather Your Party,
which is just a big party
where we're going to be celebrating
getting 1000 subscribers,
playing some board games.
We have a band coming in to play.
MATT: Awesome.
ZAC: It's gonna be a good time.
We might even have a DJ spinning some--
I don't know.
How do you say it?
Spinning?
TRAVIS: Some tunes.
MATT: Spin tunes.
TRAVIS: Dropping some dope beats.
ORION: On the ones and twos.
Ones and twos.
ZAC: So thank you guys again.
Lucas, if you wanna go ahead
and roll those videos,
and we'll get you guys out of here.
MATT: Thank you guys for watching.
ALL: Bye!