MATT: Hello everyone, and welcome to tonight's
episode of Critical Role, where a bunch of us
nerdy-ass voice actors sit around and play
Dungeons and Dragons--
ALL: (cheering)
MATT: -- you assholes.
MARISHA: Der 'n' Der!
MATT: Welcome. Tonight should be an interesting
episode, but, before we begin, let's go ahead and
get through our announcements for the evening! So,
welcome, and, first and foremost, tonight we are
sponsored by our friends at Loot Crate.
ALL: (cheering) Loot Crate!
MATT: Thank you, Loot Crate, for being amazing
sponsors.
Sam, did you want to tell us a little
about--
SAM: Okay! I haven't done this in a while,
so I'm falling back on
an old crutch, an old beloved character--
Rhodey Slater is back to do another round--
MATT: (laughing) Oh my god.
SAM: Gotta get in character.
(in surfer voice)
Yo-ho-ho, it's me, Rhodey Slater, with another
message from our sponsor, Loot Crate. Whether
you're dropping in on a party wave in Uluwatu or
even Tamarindo, you won't look like a paddle-puss
if you haul your tres gnarly gear from El Crate-o
del Loot-o. This month's theme is Build,
featuring sick brands like Power Rangers,
hang ten; Batman, wax it up; Lego, mondo
bitchin'; and Tetris, shaka.
(all laugh)
SAM: So don't get raked over
by a wiper, point your nose to
Lootcrate.com/CriticalRole and use promo code
"criticalrole" for 10% off your subscription.
You'll be radder than Tom Curren nailing a 360
air reverse rodeo. You'll be cooler than a tight
on-shore breeze at Malibu. You'll be more
authentic than a sad voice actor searching for
surfing terms on Yahoo Answers at 5 pm--
(all laugh)
SAM: -- when he should be really spending more
quality time with his children, as their youthful
lives pass by without their father, precious
moments ticking away until one day they're adults,
and you're standing at their wedding, thinking,
"Oh my god, I missed so much, I missed so very
much, and for what? A Loot Crate ad?"
Anyway, ride that tube and subscribe today,
(shouting) bonzai!
(all laugh and cheer)
TRAVIS: I mean, he's a whole new echelon.
It's a whole new--
TALIESIN: You just Inception'd a Loot Crate ad.
MATT: Thank you for that!
TRAVIS: Incredible!
MATT: Sam.
MARISHA: You took, like, a failed Californian
sketch and turned it into Oscar-winning material.
MATT: That is, thank you very much.
LAURA: It hurts, it hurts.
LIAM: I didn't know Rhodey's, Rhodey's a father,
that's an interesting development.
SAM: Yeah.
MATT: Indeed.
SAM: Many. Many.
MATT: Just a heads-up, guys, we've done a couple
of these and we're going to do a couple more of
these upcoming For Honor streams, where a few of
us are going to be guesting on here for a number
of hours to play For Honor and beat the shit out
of each other and other people, as various
historical warriors of old. And then a number of
us are actually, I think, a voice in the game.
TRAVIS: Yeah!
MATT: But yeah. So tomorrow, joining the Nerdist
team from 9 am to 12 noon Pacific Time, we have
Liam and Travis--
TRAVIS: Woo!
LIAM: Tarvis!
MATT: --to jump in on there, and then, on
Saturday, from 12 noon to 3 pm, that's going to be
Travis, Taliesin, Sam, Marisha, and myself on
there--
MARISHA: Hey-oh.
MATT:-- all playing the game, getting crazy.
LAURA: Woah. Really?
TRAVIS: Yep.
LAURA: Why aren't I there?
TRAVIS: 'Cuz you suck.
LAURA: Oh man.
LIAM: He's right.
LAURA: I know it!
LIAM: He would know. He would know.
MATT: (laughs) So yeah, it'll be here on the
Twitch, check it out, I'm really excited,
I haven't played the game yet? And everyone I
know who's talked about has said it's ridiculously
fun and amazing. It's like, the upgrade of Dark
Souls combat and I'm really excited about it.
TRAVIS: I have to, like, show up an hour early and
learn how to play, or we're going to get.
We're going to get killed a lot.
MARISHA: Yeah, I'm probably going to.
TRAVIS: We've got to work on our death sounds.
LIAM: What, I'm Leet, man, you're going down,
and stuff.
TRAVIS: (belches)
LAURA: Leet!
MATT: (accented voice) Going down.
TRAVIS: No. No. You... are the one falling,
in the opposite direction of up.
LIAM: (in Christopher Walken voice) It's important
to point out, we're not doing Walken anymore--
(all laugh)
LIAM: --we're doing our impression of Troy,
doing an impression of Nolan doing Walken.
MATT: Oh, wow.
TRAVIS: It's a quad lay-up.
MATT: The chain goes deep.
LAURA: Yeah, it does.
TRAVIS: (Walken voice) Quad. Lay-up.
LAURA: Woah. Just woah. (laughs)
LIAM: I don't even know what Walken sounds like,
it's come through a daisy-chain of assholes.
MATT: It's true, it's true. That's our next shirt.
"Daisy Chain of Assholes." I'm okay with that.
TRAVIS: Critical Role: It's About Scientology--
MATT: Also, don't google that phrase!
TRAVIS: -- and a Daisy Chain of Assholes.
MATT: All right! Next up, we have (quieter) me,
breaking my pen. Uh--
LAURA: Oh, no.
MATT: April 1st!
TRAVIS: April 1st!
MATT: WonderCon!
TRAVIS: WonderCON!
MATT: Save the date. We have--
SAM: We're allowed to say the date now?
MATT: We do now. That's all the information we
have so far, but April 1st, WonderCon. Critical
Role and Talks Machina live, in their--
LAURA: Be there or be squared!
MATT: -- big room, it's gonna be good.
TRAVIS: Anaheim.
MARISHA: Big room, did I say square?
SAM: It is not an epic April Fools' Joke--
MATT: No.
SAM: -- this is really happening.
TRAVIS: It's really happening.
TALIESIN: It's really happening.
SAM: Okay.
TRAVIS: And it's going to be a big, big,
rowdy room. So if you're like, "Aw, I don't want
to go, there's not going to be any seats."
There gon' be seats.
MATT: There's plenty of seats.
LIAM: Yeah, it's--
TRAVIS: Bring it, if you can.
LIAM: --It's April Fools', we're not going to be
there.
TRAVIS: I can say that.
SAM: You know what?
LIAM: We're not going to do that.
SAM: I will promise that I will play at least one
April Fools' joke
on one of you, during that panel.
LAURA: Ooh.
TALIESIN: I'm excited by this.
LAURA: Can I vote for Brian?
LIAM: I'm not.
SAM: Sure, of course.
TALIESIN: I think that's a great idea.
TRAVIS: He's not listening to this right now.
MATT: We should have a poll in the community for
which member of the team Sam gets to prank.
(all laugh)
MATT: Don't actually do that, please. 'Cause we
all know that's going to be--
TALIESIN: I'm a big fan of Brian, I have a feeling
that's a good bet.
MATT: Also!
MARISHA: Man, we're being so transparent.
MATT: Isn't it, though? All right! Next up--
LIAM: Wow.
MATT: Signal Boost has returned. Marisha,
if you want to talk about that.
MARISHA: It has returned--
TRAVIS: Oh, snap!
MARISHA: Oh, my goodness, you guys! The amazing
Darin De Paul, already. He kicked off the season.
TRAVIS: DDP!
LIAM: So good.
TALIESIN: It was crazy.
MARISHA: Yes. Yeah, he kind of set the bar really
high.
TALIESIN: It was crazy.
MATT: He's awesome.
MARISHA: You guys know Darin as the voice of
Reinhardt from Overwatch,
and many other things. But--
MATT: He's also the main villain, Ardyn,
in Final Fantasy XV
and a bunch of other games. Super talented--
LAURA: He's blowing up! He's in everything now!
MATT: He's incredible.
MARISHA: He's great.
SAM: I don't care for him.
(All laugh)
TRAVIS: I think he's rude. And he smells funny.
MATT: There you go.
SAM: He didn't want to come on my show, Siggle
Boost.
MARISHA: (laughs)
TRAVIS: Siggle Boost?
SAM: Siggle Boost.
MARISHA: Wow, I haven't heard of that one.
TALIESIN: Do you guys just like draw weird
circles?
SAM: Yup. Yeah.
TALIESIN: Right, okay. I was just checking.
MATT: And people correct you for mispronouncing
it.
LAURA: It's called Sigil Boost.
MARISHA: Sigil Boost.
SAM: That's true, that's true.
LIAM: Let's run the GIF (hard g) of that now,
please.
TALIESIN: It's pronounced siggle.
MARISHA: Yes, it's back. You should watch it. Yup.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MARISHA: People.
MATT: Yeah, Erika Ishii just did hers--
MARISHA: On Tuesdays.
MATT: --and then Amy Dallen's up next, right?
MARISHA: Amy Dallen is up next and--
MATT: Awesome.
MARISHA: Yeah. It's good people coming up.
TALIESIN: Yeah, you drain Erika Ishii's blood.
It's pretty great.
MARISHA: Yes. We do. Yeah.
LIAM: Yeah, but you can only do it once, though.
MARISHA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: It's a great trick. You can only do it
once.
MATT: Laura, do you have a merch update?
LAURA: Do I? Do I? Do-
TRAVIS: Do I?
MATT: It's on the list.
LAURA: We watched Galaxy Quest last night.
TRAVIS: So great.
LAURA: So good. Again. For, like, the hundredth
time. You know, I mean, there's merch in the store
right now. These dice bags that I'm holding in my
hand. I literally just happened to be holding it
as you asked me that, which is crazy. There's a
very small amount of them left, I happen to know.
SAM: In the hundreds? In the fifties? In the
tens?
TALIESIN: Baker's dozen.
LAURA: In the barely hundreds.
SAM: Wow.
MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: It's a lot.
MARISHA: They went fast.
LAURA: Which, you know, could be a lot or
couldn't. Depending on if you want them.
SAM: Wow.
LAURA: There's also shirts! And hats! And patches
and--
MATT: (singing) Things, oh God!
LAURA: -- other stuff coming up that I'm real
excited about,
and I'll show it to you when it's here.
TRAVIS: Yep.
MATT: (clicking dice) Such a beautiful sound.
TRAVIS: (sniffing) Allergies. (groans)
TALIESIN: You watched Galaxy Quest.
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: You don't need that-- he can have that
many. You have too many.
TALIESIN: You know they have the dubbed version of
the alien language on the DVD?
LAURA: No!
TALIESIN: (alien noises) The whole movie,
the entire movie-- You can watch it, if you're
drunk enough.
LAURA: It's just so good.
MARISHA: (laughs)
MATT: That's pretty great. All right!
LIAM: I'm ready.
MATT: Anything else anyone wants to talk about? Or
are we good? I think we're good.
TRAVIS: We're good.
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: So we're going to hop in, and start off
tonight's episode of--
LAURA: Oh God.
MATT: Critical Role.
(All cheer)
MARISHA: That's right.
[opening credits]
MATT: Hello everyone, and welcome back.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: Well done.
MATT: So, to get you up to speed with our current
story: Vox Machina, having just completed the
destruction of the Chroma Conclave, a scourge of
ancient chromatic dragons that have terrorized the
countryside. They are victorious, yet in the
process lost a couple of lives. Percy returned and
Scanlan, his lifeless body brought back to
Whitestone. They completed the ritual correctly,
and he came to life; however, he remains
unconscious in a pseudo-coma. They left him in
Whitestone, hopefully to recover. While beginning
to finish up some of their last business they've
been unable to with the current rush of this
current arc. They made a journey to Vasselheim,
where they walked through the Abundant Terrace
and into the Birthheart itself, the temple of
Melora within Vasselheim, spoke with one of the
various worshippers there, and buried a box of
ashes, apparently, of Senokir's wife--
MARISHA: "Apparently"
MATT: --as a thank you for when you guys journeyed
and met him in the City of Brass on the Fire
Elemental Plane. Upon doing so, you then began to
scatter about the city to do some business.
One of the elements of which: Grog Strongjaw,
along with Pike, made their way to the Trial
Forge, which is the Kord section of the city.
Returning to the Trial Forge, the temple to Kord,
and upon walking to the center of the strangely
empty temple structure, you saw, down in a once
previously traversed sandpit, there stood
Earthbreaker Groon, the high priest of Kord,
who then turned to you--
TRAVIS: My palms are really wet.
LAURA: (laughs)
MATT: --and asked you to "show him what you had
learned." After slamming his feet into the sand
and preparing himself for conflict, he beckons you
towards him. And that is where we left off. So--
LAURA: Oh god, oh god, oh god.
MATT: --as you're standing up there on the edge of
this pit, Groon just stands there with his hand
beckoning towards you.
TRAVIS: I reach into my Bag of Holding, and I pull
out a small drawing of the letter "G". This.
This is what I have learn-- That's not it.
That's not what I wanted. And I take out
the Dwarven Thrower and I jump into the sandpit.
MATT: All righty. (jumping sound) (impact thud)
There, as you land in the sand, the bottoms of
your boots sinking but a couple of inches into the
soft surface. Pike gets ready to leap down after
and Groon puts his hand up. "No...."
TRAVIS: Oh, shit.
MATT: This fight is for us.
LAURA: Oh, god.
LAURA: Yeah, we're here, we're watching it,
right?
MATT: You guys didn't say if you were catching up
with them last time.
LAURA: Yeah, we said we came in the temple with
them.
MARISHA: Uh, no, we're totally watching this.
TALIESIN: We're here, we're here.
MATT: So then you guys rush in afterward,
hoping that--
Morpheus is fighting Neo, you guys--
(all laugh)
MATT: You all rush in on the outskirts here to
watch. I'll put you in over here to keep an
eye on the sidelines. Grog, I need you to roll
initiative.
LAURA: Oh my god!
TRAVIS: (blows raspberry)
SAM: Big roll, big roll.
MARISHA: Big roll! Big money, no whammies.
LIAM: Now we attack on the count of three.
TRAVIS: I get advantage on my (mumbles)
TALIESIN: Jenga.
LIAM: Get 'im.
TRAVIS: That's shit.
LAURA: God, oh god.
MARISHA: Come on, come on.
TRAVIS: That-- that's one worse.
TRAVIS: Five!
LIAM: Oh!
MATT: You're going second.
TRAVIS: Hey! You can go away.
LAURA: (laughs) You're in jail.
MARISHA: You know, second has its advantages
sometimes.
MATT: (clears throat) So.
MARISHA: Sometimes.
TRAVIS: Mm-hm.
MATT: As you land and ready yourself with the
hammer at the side, knowing that all of your
friends are up on the outer edges of this watching
you, you look up at Groon, who just, his hands at
the ready, puts them down at his sides and
just.... (slow steps)
TRAVIS: Awesome.
MATT: Just walks up towards you... And just stands
there. Your turn.
SAM: Like a matador.
TRAVIS: What a dick move! What a dick move! Right.
(clears throat) I, uh. I bow.
SAM: Oh!
TRAVIS: And say... Kord's strength be with you.
And I smash the Titanstone Knuckles together.
MATT: All righty! (laughs) Off to a start.
SAM: (sound of impact)
LAURA: (whispers) Oh my god.
I wish we had popcorn!
MARISHA: Oh, yeah. Is
there popcorn in the studio?
DENISE: (off screen) No.
LAURA and MARISHA: Damn it!
MARISHA: Damn it, Denise.
TALIESIN and LAURA: (laugh)
DENISE: (off screen) Sorry!
(all laugh)
MARISHA: Always the bearer of bad news, that one.
MATT: All right.
TALIESIN: Don't say her name three times,
then your rolls won't come true.
TRAVIS: I would like to move backwards three
squares.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: That's my turn.
MATT: All right. On his turn he stands there.
LAURA: Ahh!
MATT: He stares right at you.
TRAVIS: Fucking knew it!
MATT: Arms at the side--
TRAVIS: What is-- It's a test already!
MARISHA: Waiting for you to go first?
TRAVIS: I hate the SATs! I hate Scantrons,
I hate number two pencils, I hate all of it!
(all laugh)
LIAM: Don't blink, don't blink. Roll with it,
player.
TRAVIS: MM-hm, mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
MARISHA: It's totally--
TRAVIS: I start in that same distance from him,
the same radial distance, I start walking to my
right. My full speed.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: That's my turn.
MATT: He turns with you as you move and just
rights himself and stares at you. Your turn.
(all laugh)
SAM: Worst chess game ever.
LAURA: I know, right?
LIAM: Smash cut to two hours later.
(all laugh)
MATT: I know.
TRAVIS: All right. Okay.
SAM: "What do you want me to do!"
LAURA: "Are you hungry? I'm kind of hungry."
TRAVIS: I would like to rage.
MATT: Okay. (woosh) So--
TRAVIS: And I do so by taking the...dwarven
thrower and smashing it against my chest.
And then I chuck it at him.
MATT: All right. As you slam it into your chest,
you can feel the impact, and there's that brief
sharp bit of pain as the metal clashes against the
muscle, slamming against the bone and your rib
cage. And that pain just kind of shoots through
you like exciting electricity and you harness the
pain as your eyes blur for a moment as you feel
the rage overtake you, your muscles flexing and
tensing and with that fury now flowing through
your body, you take the hammer. I need you to go
ahead and make a wisdom saving throw.
SAM: Oh no.
LAURA: Oh shit.
TRAVIS: (whispers) I knew it. (louder) I mean,
I didn't know it.
SAM: Oh no.
TRAVIS: Which is a minus two, right?
MATT: Yes.
TRAVIS: That's a six.
MATT: As you go to throw, the strength leaves your
arm and it just hangs limp at the side.
The attack is lost.
TRAVIS: Any reason why?
MATT: You don't know.
TRAVIS: Not that I'd know. Cool. Do I have another
attack?
MATT: Yeah. You have two attacks.
MARISHA: He just Jedi mind-tricked you.
TRAVIS: I shake off the random numb arm,
and I toss it over to the other hand like,
"C'mon, Betsy!" And I throw it with that hand.
(all laugh)
MATT: Okay. Roll another wisdom saving throw.
TRAVIS: I don't know D&amp;D enough to know what the
fuck's happening right now. Ooh! 16?
MATT: Uh, 16, actually let me see this real fast.
TRAVIS: I have a modifier of zero. Minus two.
LAURA: Minus two.
TRAVIS: I rolled an 18.
TALIESIN: Monks are not in my wheelhouse.
MATT: Monks are fun.
MARISHA: I feel like this guy's special, too.
TRAVIS: He's not even here. This is a dream.
LIAM: Slowly, Raishan uncurls like a Xenomorph
from the ceiling.
MATT: What'd you roll?
TRAVIS: 16.
MATT: Nope. This time, you do manage to push
through and throw the hammer, but you end up
throwing it way wide. Like, 20 feet away from him.
Like, you're looking at him and just go (whoosh)
(all laugh)
MATT: It comes back, and you catch it, and you're
like, something's just messing with your mind.
There's something about his presence right now
that is
oppressing your ability to actually attack
towards him.
TRAVIS: All right. All I have is my bonus action.
MATT: Well, you used your bonus action to rage,
right?
TRAVIS: Oh I did, yeah. I don't have a bonus
action. That's my turn.
MATT: All right. He turns towards you. Walks
forward--
TRAVIS: No, I don't.
MATT: --very, just, carefully and intently.
That's his turn. You go.
TRAVIS: God dang it!
LAURA: Oh man. What does he want-a!
TALIESIN: (whispering) Popcorn.
LAURA: (whispering) He wants popcorn.
TALIESIN:  (whispering) He wants popcorn.
TRAVIS: I try and hit him with it with both
hands.
MATT: Okay, so you you're using both hands--
TRAVIS: Yeah, both hands.
MATT: Go for it. Roll a wisdom saving throw.
(laughter)
LIAM: Look at his little boy smile.
TRAVIS: Six!
MATT: You go to swing and he seems to blur for a
moment, your eyes blink and as you swing with the
hammer, you swung far to your left and it's almost
like your arms are intentionally missing and
almost fighting your directoral sense.
LAURA: Shut up, Brian Wayne Foster!
MARISHA: Awesome! Brian Fostah.
TRAVIS: This is so stupid! Okay, I keep the hammer
in one hand but I just try and punch him with the
Titanstone Knuckles out of frustration.
MATT: Okay. Make a wisdom saving throw.
TRAVIS: What? No weapon in my hand?
MATT: Mm-hm.
TRAVIS: Nine!
MATT: You go to punch and by the time it gets to
his chest there's so little force behind it that
your fingers just kind of unfold open against him,
almost breaking your wrist in the process,
and you pull back, and he's just staring right at
you. "Show me you have the will to fight.
Come at me!" Are you going to move or are you
going to stay where you are?
TRAVIS: I'm going to stay within his attack range,
but I'm going to 180 around him.
MATT: Okay. That's easy enough to get around here.
All righty.
TRAVIS: And I'll stay there.
MATT: All right. For his turn, he turns around--
TRAVIS: No he doesn't. Come on. Come on.
MATT: Your turn.
TRAVIS: Oh, this is a nightmare. I just want to
hit him!
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: All right. All right. Maybe it's all
about love!
And I try and give him a bear hug!
MATT: Okay... make a wisdom saving
throw.
TRAVIS: No!
LAURA: You got this.
Natural 20.
TRAVIS: That's a zero.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: I rolled a two.
LAURA: Two zero, exactly.
MATT: You go to grab him, and you
reach, and you feel this physical form in your
grasp, and then your arms all of a sudden touch
nothing, and you realize that he's standing where
he was. You grabbed what was almost like a mirage
or an illusion, it's almost like your brain is
playing tricks on you. That's one attack.
TRAVIS: (surprised grunt)
LAURA: You can do it, Grog! I don't know
what he wants, but figure it out!
TRAVIS: I look so pathetic right now.
SAM: Yo, how does it look to the rest of the
gang?
MATT: It looks hilarious.
(all laugh)
LIAM: What did we just see?
MATT: It's
hilarious, and it's disconcerting, because you're
watching as Grog, in the middle of his rage,
most of his attacks are amateur, far too wide
away from the target, or by the time they get
close, he is holding himself back. And you don't
know why. Something is messing with his will and
preventing him
from being able to follow through
with his attacks.
TRAVIS: Okay. (sighs)
MATT: Second attack?
TRAVIS: Second attack. I just want to touch him
with my finger. Just, like, a boop.
MATT: Okay. You reach out and your
finger touches his chest
(cracking sound),
and you feel--
TRAVIS: He's real?! He's there?!
MATT: He's real. The skin's there.
TRAVIS: Thought you might be a dragon.
Wisdom saving throw?
MATT: That wasn't an
attack.
TRAVIS: Oh! I touched him!
MATT: You touched him.
LAURA: Great job, Grog!
MARISHA: We believe in you, Grog!
LIAM: Okay, now ramp it up!
(all laugh)
MATT: He smiles at you and goes,
"And with gentleness there comes clarity."
TRAVIS: (heavy breathing)
SAM: I think
you're going to have to fuck him, Grog.
(all laugh)
MATT: And that's your turn?
TRAVIS: That's my turn.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: (quietly) What? With gentleness there comes--?
MATT: "With
gentleness there comes clarity." And he smiles
through his big, white-grey beard. And then the
smile fades, his eyes flash, and he is going to
attack you with a flurry of blows.
LAURA: Oh no.
TRAVIS: Wait, I haven't learned the lesson yet. I'm still--
MATT: The lesson's just begun.
TRAVIS: Oh no.
MATT: All right, that is-- ooh.
33 to hit.
TRAVIS: (squeaky voice) Mmm, yep.
MATT: That is a 24 to hit.
TRAVIS: (squeaky voice) Yep.
MATT: That is a natural one.
So that is a failure. And it's a 32 to hit,
so he hits you three times.
LAURA: Jeez Louise.
MATT: So you're raging, so you take half damage
from these, because they're bludgeoning,
since he's punching you.
TRAVIS: Mmhmm.
MATT: His eyes flash, he rushes up and pummels
you once in the chin, elbows you in the sternum,
goes and grabs your shoulder and leaps over
behind you and then kicks straight back into the
middle of your shoulder blades and (pained gasp)
you feel the breath almost get kicked out of you.
That is 15 bludgeoning damage, halved to--
TRAVIS: Seven?
MATT: We'll say eight.
TRAVIS: Eight? Yeah.
MATT: That is nine, reduced to five,
and that is 13 reduced to seven. There you go.
TRAVIS: Oh shit, that's 20 points of damage.
Cool.
MATT: That's his turn. You're
up.
TRAVIS: Uh, yeah. Sweet, sweet anus.
MARISHA: That's a really good British
candy.
TRAVIS: What do monks do? Can I, like,
use my magic powers? And I want to keep my eyes
closed, and I'm gonna swing around behind me,
knowing that I just got kicked in the back there.
MATT: Okay, go ahead and make an attack with
disadvantage.
TRAVIS: Oh! No wisdom saving
throw?
MATT: Nope.
LAURA: With gentleness comes clarity.
You touched him, maybe if you'd've shaken
his hand.
TRAVIS: With disadvantage?
MATT: With disadvantage, because you have your
eyes closed.
TRAVIS: Uh, 23.
MATT: That just barely hits.
(all gasp)
MATT: Go ahead and roll
damage.
TRAVIS: (mumbling) Okay, with a ten.
SAM: So what did we learn from that?
TRAVIS: I
should've done it reckless. No, I don't want him
rolling reckless, holy shit! God, I'll die in a
second.
MARISHA: His AC's 23.
SAM: No, that-- close your eyes-- or, how
does this... what?
LIAM: It might be touch.
SAM: I'm so confused.
LIAM: You're unconscious.
TALIESIN: You've got the touch.
TRAVIS: That's 18 points of damage.
MATT: 18 points of damage, gotcha.
That's your first strike (hitting sound).
You feel the weapon behind you make contact with
a form, and (cracking noise), you see a little bit
of sand out of your peripheral this side go
(scattering sound) as his form gets pushed about a
foot, kind of setting some of it off.
TRAVIS: So
it goes (low hitting sound). I close my eyes
again. I swing around the other way, and I try to
connect.
MATT: Okay, roll again with disadvantage.
TRAVIS: That's not bad. 14 and 20,
uh... 29.
MATT: That hits, yes.
TRAVIS: Yes, okay. Damn, same thing, so
18 points of damage.
MATT: 18 points of damage. All righty.
As he takes both impacts, kind of parrying them
with his forearms with each impact. They're still
hitting him, and he's still taking the brunt of
the attack and the pain, but with each hit you can
feel the force of his forearm is almost stopping
still the hammer blow as you're throwing it behind
you, and you can see him gritting teeth with each
impact, but he's just staring right at you again
as you kind of spin around, open your eye again to
see what you did.
He kind of gives you a bit of a
narrowed glare--
TRAVIS: Stink eye?
MATT: Little bit of a stink eye.
TRAVIS: Fuck.
MATT: But like an intentional kind of connecting
point and just says--
TRAVIS: Pink eye?
MATT: No, that's a whole different--
that's a different monk path.
(all laugh)
LAURA: Like that little hobbit.
TRAVIS: Be nice.
MATT: Let's see
here.
TRAVIS: I'm a student here.
LAURA: What's the lesson? What's the lesson?!
MATT: Okay,
he's going to go ahead and attack you twice.
(punch sound) Two punches, straight to your back
of your shoulders and neck as you're turning
around to look at him. That is a 17, misses.
No, that does hit.
TRAVIS: That hits, yeah, it's my AC.
MATT: And a 23.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: So both hit you. That is...
16, so eight damage.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: And that is ten, so five damage.
MATT: And he's going to spend three ki.
TRAVIS: Three ki?!
MATT: Yeah, three ki points.
So, the first punch hits you across
the chin. The second one, he slams his fingers,
curled up, right into your sternum as you turn
around to face him (whack), and as it hits you,
you feel these kind of vibrations, ripples,
carry through your body, and then slowly fade
inside. And you feel this tingling, this very
faint, brief numbness that just kind of lingers
throughout your body. You can feel it gathering at
the edge of fingertips and toes, almost like
ripples through a lake, and he steps away.
You get to make an attack of opportunity if you'd
like.
TRAVIS: (strained) I would.
MATT: Don't forget, you can use your reaction to
get an attack back because of
your retaliation ability.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I've totally forgotten that,
I'm just totally stunned at this point.
That's good, that's 32.
MATT: 32 hits.
Go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: (sing-songy noises) That's a ten.
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: All
these sounds are in game, in character.
TRAVIS: So 20, 25.
LAURA and LIAM: (gibberish)
MARISHA: (laughs) When Grog becomes Popeye.
MATT: All righty, and he just stands across the way,
and just kind of beckons you towards him.
Your turn.
TRAVIS: And I feel all shake-weighty
at the moment, right?
MATT: Yeah. You're not quite sure.
You don't feel bad, it's just this
kind of uneasiness in your body.
TRAVIS: Can I take a step towards him?
MATT: Mm-hm, take a
step forward.
TRAVIS: Does anything happen? Do I
shit my pants?
MATT: Nope.
(all laugh)
MATT: Not yet.
TRAVIS: Can I take the other four steps
of the five step exploding heart point technique
thing?
MATT: Seems fine.
TRAVIS: Cool.
MARISHA: What would you have done if you shat
your pants on that fifth step?
LAURA: Oh my god,
that would have been amazing.
TRAVIS: Just
explosive shat. I'd be, like, kill me now.
Kill me now, take it away.
MARISHA: Just lost
your bowels.
MATT: (laughs) I'd have to bring
out the cone template for that.
MARISHA: Like a
very dedicated marathon runner.
LAURA: (laughs) Area of effect?
TRAVIS: Can I close the rest of
the distance to him?
MATT: Sure.
TRAVIS: I want to try the bear hug again.
I want to grapple him.
MATT: Okay. So, go ahead. And I think it's your
athletics versus his--
TRAVIS: So I can touch him
now.
MATT: (mumbling) Acrobatics, I'm pretty
sure.
TRAVIS: The wisdom saving throw was
something in the beginning.
LAURA: Yeah, I think it was,
you have to shake his hand or do
something, like, gentle to him.
LIAM: I like the idea that it's silent in here and
we're just hearing sand get kicked around
and Grog breathing like a bull.
LAURA: I like to think that Earthbreaker
Groon has, like, mood music for his fights.
MARISHA: Agreed, yeah.
TRAVIS: There's
frustrated grunts happening.
LAURA: He's got a sound system.
MATT: So, make an athletics check.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MARISHA: Like war drums, yeah.
TALIESIN: Like taiko. (low drum sounds)
LAURA: Ooh! That'd be sick.
MARISHA: (joins in on the drum sounds)
Totally.
TRAVIS: 24. Plus 16 plus
eight.
MATT: Yeah, okay, so you go to grab him and he
just (fwish) slips out.
TRAVIS: Damn. My
athletics versus his? Judo?
MATT: He just kind of like parries it to the side,
ducks under and
rights himself, just out of your grasp.
TRAVIS: Cool, that was nice. Do I have a second
attack?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Two-handed great weapon master, please.
MATT: Okay, go for it.
TRAVIS: That's not going to hit. 24.
MATT: 24 hits.
TRAVIS: Oh, it does?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Oh, 23, that's right.
LIAM: 23 was the threshold.
TRAVIS: Thank you, god. No it doesn't, 24 minus
five.
MATT: Oh, minus five. So, as you go to swing,
both of your hands on the hammer, (grunts) giant
downward arc. As it slams downward, you see his
form (whoosh) shift, and suddenly he's two feet to
the right. He moved so fast with the side step,
and you slam it down into the sand. You guys
watch as this crater emerges (boom), and the sand
shoots off the sides from the impact of Grog's
blow on the ground. Groon seemingly unaffected.
TRAVIS: That ends my--
MATT: You're not frenzied yet, right?
TRAVIS: Nope. That ends my turn. Yep.
MATT: Okay. At the end of your turn, he's going to
go ahead and make an unarmed attack on you.
TRAVIS: Unarmed attack?
MATT: That's just his punch as a part of his
legendary action here. That is a 27 to hit.
TRAVIS: Oh, that hits.
MATT: You suffer another ten points of bludgeoning
damage, reduced to five.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: Now it's Groon's turn.
TALIESIN: Two lair actions.
MATT: He's gonna go ahead and make another series
of attacks on you. That is an 18?
TRAVIS: Yeah, that hits.
MATT: 17.
TRAVIS: Hits, also.
MATT: All right. So that is nine plus eight.
That'd be 17.
So, say nine points of bludgeoning.
TRAVIS: Nine?
MATT: And then--ooh! 18. So another nine points of
bludgeoning damage. I need you to go ahead and
make a constitution saving throw.
TRAVIS: Damn, Gina.
LIAM: Nice pull.
SAM: I don't get it.
TRAVIS: 21.
MATT: 21, okay. As his first hit is a long round
haymaker punch across the chin, he comes from
underneath and goes for an uppercut that hits you
right in the jaw. Right at the side where usually
it would snap and really mess with somebody's
ability to stay either conscious or control their
atmosphere. You just manage to maneuver out of the
way where it hurts, but the impact doesn't hit its
intended place, and you resist the effect.
TRAVIS: What was the effect?
MATT: You don't know.
TRAVIS: God damn it.
SAM: Diarrhea.
LAURA: Instant knockout.
TRAVIS: I'll shit my pants before this fight is
over with.
LAURA: The button.
TRAVIS: On the button?
LAURA: It's the button.
TRAVIS: It's the brown note.
MATT: It's your turn.
TRAVIS: My turn. I am so tired of this slippery
shit. I go into a frenzied rage!
MATT: Okay.
(unenthused cheering)
TRAVIS: Yeah, thank you. I would like to Great
Weapon Master
try to hit him with the Dwarven Thrower.
MATT: Go for it.
TRAVIS: Not reckless.
No. (crying) I don't know what the lesson
is. 32 minus five is 37.
MATT: 27?
TRAVIS: 27!
MATT: That hits.
TRAVIS: Yeah. 32 minus five is 37! 35.
MATT: Okay. This one cracks him right across the
side of his shoulder and pec area (wham),
and you watch as for the first time since this
battle started, he loses his footing, and he has
to catch himself behind. His head looks back and
he turns around towards you and a big smile goes
across his face as he goes, "Good. Keep showing
me."
TRAVIS: I was encouraged until he got creepy with
the talking.
LAURA: Maybe he just likes getting hit.
TRAVIS: All right, I hit him again!
MATT: Go for it.
TRAVIS: That's gonna hit. That's a 31 minus five
is 26.
MATT: Yeah, go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: 22... 32.
MATT: 32. Nice.
LAURA: He's got like 5,000 hit points. More than
last time.
TRAVIS: Last one. Reckless.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: (gasps)
TRAVIS: What's life without a little spice?
MATT: Sure.
MARISHA: Ask him.
TRAVIS: 18, not quite. 34 minus--29.
MATT: That hits, yeah.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Close to what I wanted. This is 33.
MATT: Okay, cool. All right, so, as you unleash
your next series of blows against him, you saw him
topple from the first hit. The other two,
he pulls his arms in and takes them, one to the
shoulder, and the other one hits him in the
stomach (air getting knocked out) and he grabs
your arm, and pushes off. Jumps in the air and
lands about five feet from you.
TRAVIS: Is he bruised? Is there a slap mark? I
mean, is there any blood? Anything to tell me that
I might be doing a good job?
MATT: He looks, more so than the previous fight that
you had with him,
it looks like he's starting to take some hits.
TRAVIS: Good! Yeah.
MATT: He's gonna use Legendary Action to take a
hit on you.
LIAM: A Legendary Action?
MATT: That is a 30.
TRAVIS: (squeaks) Hits.
MATT: Actually it's with advantage because--
TRAVIS: Yep.
MATT: So that is another nine points of
bludgeoning damage.
TRAVIS: Sweet.
MATT: Not halved. That is what it is halved.
TRAVIS: Okay. Because it's legendary--
MATT: Because it would be 18, yeah.
TRAVIS: Right.
MATT: Okay. His turn. He slowly walks around you.
And says, "Your size is useful for those who know
not how to use it against you." And he rushes
down, beneath your large standing form, and goes
into a series of strikes against the inside of
your knees and your legs
and we'll see how the last blow hits.
TRAVIS: I've been forgetting to roll my enlarged
damage.
MATT: That's a 30 on the first hit.
TRAVIS: Yep.
MATT: That is a 21 on the second hit.
TRAVIS: (high pitched) Yeah, sure.
MATT: That is a 29 on the third hit.
TRAVIS: (laughs) How many hits are there?!
LAURA: Four.
MATT: And natural 20 on the fourth.
LIAM: Natural 20 to the gooch.
LAURA: To the chode hit?!
TRAVIS: Wow, had to Reckless, huh?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Cool.
TRAVIS: Vegas is a short trip this time.
MATT: So that is 18 reduced to half; that's nine.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: 14 reduced in half is seven.
MATT: That is a nine reduced in half is five.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: And final strike is a 20. Reduced in half,
that is ten.
TRAVIS: Can I use my Stone's Endurance on that
last one?
MATT: Sure! Go for it.
TRAVIS: All right.
LAURA: Nice.
TRAVIS: That's 12. Plus my constitution,
which is five, so 17.
MATT: And I would like you to make another
constitution save.
TRAVIS: Shit! So do I add 17 hit points back?
MATT: No, you reduce the attack, which was 10
damage?
TRAVIS: Yeah, so just wipe it out?
MATT: Yeah, it does none.
TRAVIS: Okay, cool. I'm getting down there.
LAURA: Really?
SAM: He's down to triple digits now.
TRAVIS: Constitution saving throw. 18.
MATT: 18.
TRAVIS: Ten plus ten minus two is 18.
MATT: Okay. You feel from that impact, all of your
muscles seize up. He goes for the same strike zone
on the other side of the chin and hits and you
kind of (groans) as you pull back. And then,
feel all of a sudden this pulse (throbbing
sound). The pulse (louder throbbing sound) and all
your muscles tense up. You're stunned until the
end of your next turn.
TRAVIS: Shit! (laughs)
LAURA: What does being stunned do? You can't
move?
MATT: Can't move, can't do anything, you're
considered incapacitated.
TRAVIS: He Vulcan Pinched my ass.
LIAM: Groon's in Vegas and your ass just came up
pineapples.
LIAM &amp; TRAVIS: (slot machine ringing)
LAURA: I'm gonna pull an arrow out and just stand
there and get ready in case Groon does anything.
MATT: Okay. Groon is thinking to go ahead and step
back to there.
TRAVIS: What?
MATT: Which would be there.
LAURA: He's waiting for you to become unstunned.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: And as he darts back, you guys watch as he
runs to the back. As he does, his feet barely
touch the sand (fast, light footsteps). You see
these very faint little plumes behind each
footstep, as this giant man has almost no weight
across the ground--
TRAVIS: Like a jackrabbit.
MATT:--as he runs with such speed. And as he lands
and finds his footing (loud boom), the weight
seems to kick in once more, and you watch as the
sand (scattering sound) shoots out behind him.
He stands his ground and crosses his arms,
and just watches. So Grog, it's your turn.
You're stunned. You end your turn, you're no
longer stunned. It's now back to him.
TRAVIS: (whispers) Fuck.
MATT: He puts his hand up. Puts it up towards
you.
SAM: Oh, no.
MATT: Closes his fingers
TRAVIS: Oh, no, I've seen this before.
MATT: And you feel this (pulse) in your chest,
right in the sternum right where he hit you
earlier. I need you to go ahead and roll a
constitution saving throw again.
TRAVIS: 23 minus two, 21?
SAM: Ooh?
MATT: 21!
SAM: Ooh!
TRAVIS: Constitution I have a lot of. For my
saving throws.
MATT: That (pulse) sound ripples out (rapid
impacts) and you feel the muscles begin to tear,
the ligaments begin to burn from the inside.
You manage to, through the sheer force of
physical constitution, shrug off what would've
been immensely more deadly circumstance,
but you still do take 10d10 necrotic damage.
(everyone groans)
SAM: It would've been 20d10?
MATT: No, you would've dropped to zero hit points.
LAURA: Oh shit.
TRAVIS: Is that the palm thing?
MARISHA: Quivering Palm?
MATT: It's the Quivering Palm. He's not holding
back this time.
LAURA: Oh no!
TRAVIS: Oh, I mean, don't make any special
exceptions on my part. Fuck.
LIAM: Vax is watching; he just leaked a little
bit.
LAURA: Gross!
MATT: 18... 26.
SAM: (whispers) Quivering Palm...
LAURA: No one will ever notice, the armor already
stinks.
MATT: Take 51 points of necrotic damage.
TRAVIS: 52?
MATT: 51 points of necrotic damage.
TRAVIS: 51. Okay.
LAURA: How much damage?
MATT: 51 points of necrotic damage.
TRAVIS: I'm out of the triple digits guys.
LAURA: (gasps)
SAM: Oh, man.
LAURA: Does Grog look all bloody yet, or is he--
MATT: You guys watch as Grog is standing there,
his body shakes and shimmers, and you watch
various veins that usually bulge in his rage and
enhance blood flow of his combat just (bursts and
splatters) bursts in places. And blood just seems
to spray out of him from multiple positions on his
body.  And you see the blood now leaking all over
him. He's just covered in his own crimson.
He slowly turns around, prepares himself for the
next round of combat.
LIAM: That is some North Star shit.
MARISHA: Oh, my god.
TALIESIN: Nice.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Yeah. Okay. (exhales) Good deal.
Tight. Wow, distance doesn't help. Okay.
LAURA: Can you talk to him? (louder) Can you talk
to him?
TRAVIS: I just look up, covered like Carrie,
in the movie. Just dripping with fake blood.
LAURA: Never mind! You're doing great, Grog! Keep
going. (whispers) He looks like shit.
MARISHA: (whispers) He does.
SAM: Sometimes music calms the savage beast.
You could sing to him.
TRAVIS: I would try Intimidating Presence,
but he'll just shrug it off because he's amazing.
LIAM: It's fine, it looks like he's going to
rally. Here it comes.
TRAVIS: I just take off straight for him.
MATT: Okay, you turn around--(counting) You just
get into melee with him.
TRAVIS: Cool. Awesome. I am going to take all
three attacks at Great Weapon Master at him.
NOT Reckless.
MATT: Okay! Go and make your attacks at
disadvantage.
LAURA and TRAVIS: Why?!
TRAVIS: Because I'm covered in blood?
MATT: No. Because he used his Patient Defense.
SAM: Patient Defense.
MATT: Essentially with each blow that you--
LAURA: Oh, that's fun.
MATT:--swing towards him, he's just prepared
himself from a defensive position, to prepare
himself. And he's using your own momentum against
you to sway every attack away from him. So make
all of your attacks at disadvantage.
TRAVIS: So that's pretty smart. I threw that
literally into the holder and it was on an edge.
Shit. That's a natural 20 that's going to be
replaced by a not as great (inhales sharply).
23 minus five. So, it'll be a dud.
MATT: Nope. So the first blow swings wide.
He grabs the actual side of the hammer with both
hands and just (whooshes) throws it off to the
side.
TRAVIS: Okay, okay. 31 minus five. 26.
SAM: Ooh.
MATT: 26. He attempts to parry this one, however,
your sheer force of strength manages to push past
his grasp, and you bring the hammer down towards
his clavicle. Go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: (exhales) Oh, thank god. (high pitched) I
like it when I hit them. (normal voice) That's 28
plus enlarge. Which I've been forgetting. 20.
MATT: 20!
LAURA: 18 and 10? Because of your--
TRAVIS: 18 plus 10 for Great Weapon Master. 28.
30.
LAURA: 30? You said 20.
TRAVIS: I said 20 I meant 30.
LAURA: It's 30.
MATT: You mean 30.
TRAVIS: My apologies. He is hitting me really,
really hard.
LAURA: Yeah. And your brain is already so little.
TRAVIS: It's actually large, it just doesn't do
much.
MATT: And if you're using your bonus action,
you can get one more strike in.
TRAVIS: I would like to. At disadvantage.
MATT: Go for it.
TRAVIS: That's a one.
MATT: Nope. So, the second one does hit the
clavicle, and it cracks and he (grunts).
You see a little bit of blood spill out the
corner of his mouth down his chin. And he looks up
at you, and for a second there, the whites of his
eyes seem to almost dim ever so slightly into a
moment of humanity you haven't seen in him yet.
He's been this godlike entity and this is the
first point where you see that pain show just a
hint of any sort of weakening. And he kinda looks
right up into you. "Good. Good." And as you go for
your third strike he literally puts up his hand
and (heavy impact) catches the hammer in place.
TRAVIS: Oh, god, it's so awesome!
MATT: He just holds it there as he stares at you.
TRAVIS: (groans) Yeah, I'm checking reflexes.
MATT: Good.
TRAVIS: I want you to know I'm not afraid to go
down.
MATT: That is the first lesson. Let's see if your
words can be put into practice.
TRAVIS: Oh shit.
MARISHA: Good night!
LAURA: No! No!
MARISHA: We'll see you in the morning, sleep well
friends.
TRAVIS: I hope you get a popcorn kernel in your
teeth.
MATT: He is going to, let's see...
LIAM: Go Cobra Kai on your ass.
TALIESIN: Cobra Kai.
TRAVIS: Sweep the leg, Johnny!
TALIESIN: Never dies.
LIAM: Put him in a bodybag!
MATT: Yeah, he's going to go into a flurry of
blows against you. That's a natural 20.
TRAVIS: (groans)
MATT: That is a 18?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: That is a 26.
TRAVIS: Okay, all hit!
MATT: Yeah, those all hit, okay. So the first one
is 18, reduced to half, is nine.
TRAVIS: Nine, okay.
MATT: That is a nine, reduced to half, five.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: That is a 12 reduced to six.
MATT: And that is a 13 reduced to seven.
TRAVIS: Sweet. Real excited.
MATT: And he's just going to go ahead and rotate
around you to the opposite side. As he turns
around (punch sounds), hitting you as he goes with
each hit.
TRAVIS: (grunts, spurting blood noise)
MATT: I need you to go ahead and make a strength
saving throw.
You have advantage on these because
you're raging.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I know. But I still have minus two
to them.
MATT: This is true.
LAURA: Minus two?
LIAM: It's going to knock the beard off your
face.
TRAVIS: That's better. 23 minus two, 21.
MATT: 21, okay, yeah. So, the last blow,
as he comes round (punch noise), does a
roundhouse kick and brings back and goes for a
huge double-fisted
kind of earth-side punch into
your torso.
TRAVIS: Not the double fist!
MATT: It's about to push you backward, but you dig
in your feet (grunts)
and resist it and hold your place.
LAURA: Yeah!
TRAVIS: Look who's catching who now.
MATT: Now it's your turn.
TRAVIS: He didn't have a quip back for me, okay.
Right. I would like to turn so I'm facing him.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: I want to pick him up and try and bodyslam
him.
MATT: Okay! Go ahead and make an athletics check.
TRAVIS: Okay. 24.
MATT: No, that's a 30 acrobatics.
(everyone gasps)
MATT: You go to grab, and he steps back with his
arms still crossed, leaps onto your hands as you
reach out for him, and just jumps in the air,
looks down at you before he comes landing right
on top of your hands (bam), forcing your fists
into the dirt.
What are you going to do for your
next attack?
TRAVIS: I almost drop out of my rage because that
was a real dick move, just dunking on me.
LAURA: He's jumping and crossing his arms--
TRAVIS: He did the Kill Bill on my hands.
I want to try one more time.
MATT: All right, roll again.
TRAVIS: 20.
MATT: Remember, you have advantage on these
because you're raging.
TRAVIS: It doesn't matter.
MATT: Okay, that's a 24 acrobatics. As you pull
your hands up out of the dirt reaching out for him
with these giant Titanstone gauntlet-encrusted
fingers (groans), and the sand burst goes upwards,
you reach, and find nothing but sand. And as the
sand fades, he uses his-- Is this the end of your
turn, because you still have a bonus action.
TRAVIS: I still have a third one, yeah.
MATT: Okay, so as the sand is still cascading,
now you can see his shape through it, what are
you doing with your third strike?
TRAVIS: I just want to try and grab a hold of the
slippery bastard.
MATT: Okay, one more time.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Strength, advantage or just natural
roll?
MATT: Advantage on your athletics.
TRAVIS: Okay.
LIAM: God, it probably looks like he's running in
circles to us.
TRAVIS: 26.
MATT: He only rolled 24.
LAURA: (gasps)
MATT: With the sand there, kind of coming down
from the impact of you pulling your fists out,
you reach out and finally they find purchase on
the sides of his arms. And doing so, you (boom)
pull him in, and grasp him right to your chest.
The hammer still clutched in your right hand,
and you watch as he (grunts) gets pulled in now,
and he is firmly in your grasp,
he is currently grappled.
TRAVIS: Cool. I don't say anything, I'm just
really stoked that I actually got him.
(everyone laughs)
TRAVIS: I'm like, take a picture! Whatever that
is!
LAURA: Draw it! Draw it! Quick, Percy! Should I
flash him? Should I flash him?
TALIESIN: It couldn't hurt.
MATT: You want to make this into a bodyslam?
TRAVIS: Could I?
MARISHA Couldn't hurt the rest of us, either!
MATT: I'll let you, sure. Okay.
TRAVIS: I was thinking initially I'd like to
remove one of his five hits that he takes on me,
but, four, who gives a shit.
MATT: We'll say for the purposes of this,
since your intent was to bodyslam him, go ahead
and roll an attack with disadvantage.
TRAVIS: Okay, attack with disadvantage. That's not
that great. Oh, regular attack!
MATT: It's without your weapon bonus. It's minus
3.
TRAVIS: Yeah, 22.
MATT: 22. You grab him and you lift, and it's like
he's anchored to the ground. He's much smaller
than you, and you can lift things far larger and
denser than him, but for some reason, he won't
budge an inch. He's just staring up at you,
with his arms pressed to his sides.
MARISHA: I want to learn that trick.
TRAVIS: I've still got him grappled at least.
That's it.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: You have to be crouched down in order to be
grappling him?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MARISHA: It's like the possum trick.
TRAVIS: Let's just assume that I picked him up.
I'm just holding him grappled.
Or am I squatting?
MATT: You're squatting down and grappling him.
You went to lift him up but (grunts) he wouldn't
budge.
TRAVIS: Hugging Santa's little helper.
LIAM: He's friggin third Hokage, man. He's not
going anywhere.
MATT: As you're holding him, he closes his eyes.
TRAVIS: He closes his eyes?
MATT: And you watch as this kind of warm
orange-ish white energy begins to just emanate--
LARUA: (gasps) He's going super saiyan!
MATT: --from various parts in his body. Just here,
in the middle of the forehead a little glimmer
opens here, a little glimmer in the shoulder--
MARISHA: He's over 9000!
MATT: --his various chakra points begin to glow.
And you watch as many of the bruises and
bludgeons that you put upon his body, and cuts
begin to heal up.
LAURA: Shit.
LIAM: I want to be at level 21.
SAM: That's 20 more levels.
LIAM: Four more years of this.
MATT: (laughs) And he can't move, he's currently
grappled. All right, so that's his turn.
You go ahead.
TRAVIS: I still have him grappled?
MATT: You still have him grappled.
TRAVIS: I still want to try to get him to the
ground. I want to try and get him prone.
Can I try a leg wrap, so I'm gonna wrap my right
leg around his, and dive forward. Trying to push
him off-balance on to his back.
MATT: I'll say go ahead and make another athletics
check.
TRAVIS: Okay. 24.
MATT: 24, he got a 21. So we'll say for this,
you go ahead, you'll be releasing the grapple,
but you slam him on the ground and make him
prone. So you manage to just (grunts) rip him off
of whatever weird center of gravity he's forced
himself into, lift him over your head, and just
pile-drive him into the ground.
TRAVIS: Great.
MATT: (boom) Once again, you see sand and dust
kick up, and then you see these two legs sticking
up as you've basically planted him in the ground
like a carrot.
And he is currently prone on the
ground, yes.
TRAVIS: Great! When he's prone, do I get advantage
on attacks?
MATT: When he is prone, attack rolls against the
creature have advantage
if you're within five feet, so yes you do.
TRAVIS: Great. Great Weapon Master, dwarven
thrower, and I say
I want to know the answer to the lesson!
(everyone laughs)
TRAVIS: 29 minus five, 24?
MATT: 24, that hits.
TRAVIS: Okay.
LIAM: Get him, big man!
MARISHA: Give him the chair!
TRAVIS: 35.
MATT: 35.
TRAVIS: Plus the enlarge damage.
MATT: Nice! Okay, that's your second attack.
TRAVIS: Uh, 28 minus five, 23.
MATT: 23 just hits.
TRAVIS: 9, 24, 34, 38.
MATT: 38, oof! All righty. So as you're shouting
this the first blow comes down (whack), you're not
even seeing him or seeing the impact, all you're
seeing is sand and fury. The second and final
blow, you bring up, and as you bring it down you
feel something (crack) crack underneath.
And you watch as you pull the hammer up again,
he pushes off, and he's gonna actually use it at
the end of your turn-- are you going to move?
TRAVIS: (laughs)
MATT: It's up to you, you can stay where you are.
TRAVIS: No, I would be right there, just entranced
that he's actually in the ground.
MATT: Okay. So at the end of your turn he's going
to go ahead
and use a legendary action to attack you.
TRAVIS: I meant 'I run'!
MATT: It's a 30. So it hits you. All right,
that's 18, halved to nine,
take nine points of damage.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: And I need you to make another constitution
saving throw.
TRAVIS: Okay. Natural 20!
MATT: Sick, okay! As you pull up from the hammer,
you can see now, there's quite a bit of blood now
out of his mouth, and there's a part of the chest
where it's pushed in, and you can see where the
impact has caused heavy bruising and parts of the
skin have broken open from impact. So now he's
bleeding in places. You're bleeding all over the
place.
TRAVIS: Yeah, yeah!
MATT: So it's just this mess of two somewhat
dressed humanoid men
covered in their own blood. It's delightful.
TRAVIS: And blood and sand.
MATT: Yeah, blood and sand. It's encrusted
everywhere.
MARISHA: Be careful, that's how blood diseases are
transferred!
TALIESIN: Very filthy.
MARISHA: Be careful!
SAM: Sepsis!
MATT: He pushes off and manages to hit you in the
sternum once again, the same place where the
vibrations hit. However this time you grab his
hand as it gets there, and it still hits you,
but the gauntlets absorb the impact and prevent
it from spreading through your body. That ends
your turn. It's now his turn. He stands up from
prone.
TRAVIS: Goddamn, he did that to me on my turn.
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: (laughing) That's fucked up.
(everyone laughs)
TRAVIS: Holy shit. Natural 20 on my turn,
saved my life.
MATT: Okay, he's going to go ahead and hit you
twice (punch sounds). That is an 18?
TRAVIS: Hits.
MATT: And a 20. So yeah, so the first one--I need
you to make a constitution saving throw.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: And you take 14 reduced to half, seven
points of bludgeoning damage.
TRAVIS: Uh, 13 on my constitution saving throw.
MATT: 13.
TRAVIS: What was the damage? I'm sorry.
MATT: Seven.
TRAVIS: Seven.
MATT: You feel your muscles lock up once more,
and you're stunned now.
TRAVIS: Awesome.
MATT: That allows his attack, and since you are
stunned, attacks against you have advantage,
and you are incapacitated, so hits that are
against you are technically all crits.
TRAVIS: Oh, fuck!
MATT: So the next hit that went against you is six
plus eight--
TRAVIS: Can I smile before he hits me?
MATT: Sure, you go. So you feel as your body locks
up, the next hit (whack) goes right into the same
place where he keeps hitting you in the sternum.
You can feel the bruising, now you hear the
(crack) crack inward as you feel the cartilage
there pop inward. That's the second hit.
He goes in for two more strikes now as you're
stunned. (whoof) The next one, the third one,
that's going to be a 27? That is eight plus
eight, you take eight damage because it's halved.
So take eight bludgeoning damage. And his final
hit, that is going to be a 30. That is going to be
a 6, 12, 20, reduce that to ten bludgeoning
damage.
TRAVIS: Cool! Great!
LIAM: Still standing.
TRAVIS: My math is probably wrong but I'm getting
down there.
MATT: Okay. He's going to stand right there.
Your turn.
TRAVIS: He is.
MATT: Yep.
LAURA: Oh my god.
MATT: What are you going to do?
TRAVIS: Did he just stand there, and he had a
turn?
MATT: He just went. He got up from prone,
that's half his movement, and he's not going to
move around you, he's staying right where he is.
What do you do?
MARISHA: Show him what you've learned! None of us
know what you learned though! We can't help you!
TRAVIS: I feel like he's doing that Patient
Defense thing again. Yeah, fuck it. I'm going to
go for broke. Because we're pretty close anyway.
I'm gonna make
all three attacks reckless, Great Weapon Master.
MATT: Okay! Go for it.
LIAM: Tripling down on the barbarian.
TRAVIS: (laughing) I don't know any better,
I don't know.
MATT: Oh no, actually, you're stunned this turn.
TRAVIS: Oh!
MATT: I just remembered that.
LAURA: Fuck!
MATT: So, you grin, and then (grunts) your body
just won't respond.
TRAVIS: Is there a small fart at least?
LIAM: (high-pitched fart noise)
MATT: It's about that.
TRAVIS: Yep. It's not even like something to be
proud of. Just a little squeaker.
LAURA: Oh, did you just poop your pants?
LIAM: You turtle a little bit?
TRAVIS: (Scottish accent) A little turtle head
poking out. (Normal voice) So I'm stunned--
MATT: You're stunned until the end of your turn.
Your turn ends, at the end of your turn he's
going to use one of his legendary actions to use
Like The Wind, and he gets to move his speed
without attacks of opportunity.
LAURA: What does he want from you?
TALIESIN: For you to show him what you learned.
MATT: He just (whoosh) slips back and he's on the
opposite side, and just goes.
TRAVIS: Cool. I look back, and do this.
SAM: Ooh! He learned to be a dick!
(everyone laughs)
MATT: That's your turn?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: Okay. He begins to rotate. Over there...
and that's his turn.
SAM: You have a healing--
MARISHA: Everyone is doing their Keanu
impressions.
TRAVIS: I have no healing anythings.
SAM: Awesome.
TRAVIS: I do if I
short rest, but that's it. All right--
SAM: Ooh, take one.
LIAM: I do to Keyleth.
TRAVIS: How
far can I throw this fucking thing? Long range of
60 feet. The long range of 60 feet means that it
would be a disadvantage throw?
MATT: Correct.
TRAVIS: That's not great.
MATT: Short range
is 20?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: Just get up within 20 feet of him.
TRAVIS: Yeah, let's be honest.
Could I get to him in 50 feet?
MATT: You wanna try?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'd like to try.
MATT: (counting) You just barely get up to him.
TRAVIS: God! I just wanna keep staring back at
him but I don't-- There's no point to it.
I can't do anything. It's not like I can psych
him out or--
LAURA: Tell him what you learned!
(all laugh)
MATT: What are you gonna
do?
SAM: Vague words of encouragement!
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: Yeah, going for broke again.
Reckless, great weapon master, all three.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: You have
disadvantage on them because of his Patient
Defense, so they're just straight rolls.
TRAVIS: Spatial-- Patient Defense.
MATT: Patient Defense, yes.
TRAVIS: Also known as
spatial defense in the barbarian world.
LAURA: Totally. (gasps)
TRAVIS: Natural 20.
MARISHA: Ooh.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: Just two more of those, please.
TRAVIS: So I double the damage die-- or I
roll two more damage dice after this.
LAURA: Are you supposed to roll
10's or 12's?
MATT: 10's for the hammer.
LAURA: Okay.
TRAVIS: 42.
MATT: 42 points of
damage on the first one, ooh.
LAURA: (quietly) That's good, that's good.
TRAVIS: Second one.
MATT: Second attack.
TRAVIS: That's a 31 minus five, 26?
MATT: 26 hits.
TRAVIS: (counting) 35.
MATT: 35 points
of damage?
TRAVIS: Yep.
MATT: Oof.
TRAVIS: Last one.
LAURA, SAM, and MARISHA: (clap)
MATT: Last attack.
TRAVIS: I'm buying a ticket to the
no pants dance after this. 20, 22.
MATT: 22, no.
LAURA: (groan)
TRAVIS: Oh no no, that's not
minus five-- it is minus five.
MATT: Yeah,
it is minus five. So, you go bounding up towards
him (boom boom boom). He just sits there waiting,
his arms up. The first strike, he goes to parry
but as you hit (crack), his arm gets knocked out
of the way, preventing him from parrying the
second strike as it comes down right across the
side of the face (boof), hitting him, you watch as
blood (splattering sound) across the sand and you
see his jaw's kinda momentarily dislodged,
his beard just kinda crusted in his own blood.
As you come up with a giant over-the-head blow
and as it comes down, he (crack) slaps it from
both sides and stops it mid-action. You see his
hands shaking as he's holding it, and he just
kinda looks up in your face,
"Good. Good."
TRAVIS: You keep saying that!
LIAM: That
was so metal.
MATT: It's now his turn. As he throws the hammer
back over your head, which puts you off-balance,
he's gonna go into his first two strikes. The
first one is a 21 to hit?
TRAVIS: (strained) Yes, I believe that hits.
MATT: That is gonna be ten, reduced to five.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: Second one, uh-- on the first one, I need
you to make another constitution saving throw.
TRAVIS: Okay, same damage?
MATT: Same damage, yeah.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: But he's gonna do--
TRAVIS: 23.
MATT: 23.
TRAVIS: Nope, 21.
MATT: 21, that's right, yeah. So you manage
to resist, the effect of the stunning strike.
He's gonna go for the secondary attack.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: Which was seven plus 13,
it's 20, so that still hits you.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: You take 18, reduce that to nine.
TRAVIS: Oof (laughs).
MATT: Make another
constitution saving throw.
TRAVIS: Cool (laughs). We in the single digits,
kids.
(all gasp)
MARISHA: (quietly) No.
TRAVIS: 22 minus two is 20.
MATT: 20, you just barely shrug off
the effect of the stunning strike.
(all sigh in relief)
SAM: Clutch.
MATT: He is gonna go in for his flurry of blows
'cause he knows you're on the edge.
LAURA: No!
MATT: He knows you're on
the edge.
SAM: He just has to miss four.
TRAVIS: Yeah, yeah.
MATT: That's a
natural 20.
(all gasp)
MARISHA: No.
TRAVIS: (laughs)
SAM: Just has to miss three.
MATT:That is 16 plus 8, that is 24 points of damage
reduced to half to 12.
TRAVIS: I am unconscious,
but! I use my relentless rage.
SAM: (growls)
MATT: Right! Oh shit, okay.
MARISHA: You're coming back.
MATT: I forgot about that.
TRAVIS: Which, it's a flurry of blows,
and he only did it on the first one.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: So, I'm like (long groan,
rewind noise) Oh shit! (long groan).
(all laugh)
MATT: Well, you need to make a
constitution saving throw.
TRAVIS: I do, yes.
MATT: The DC of 10.
TRAVIS: I do.
MARISHA: C'mon.
SAM: Phillip!
TRAVIS: If I can't make a DC of 10, I don't know.
LAURA: Go Phillip!
LIAM: Phil!
TRAVIS: Uh, 21.
MATT: Okay, so the third hit, the first couple
just kinda loosen you up (pop pop)--
TRAVIS: This is gonna get interesting.
MATT: The third hit, he leaps in the
air, kinda Troy style (whack)
and hits you right square in the face--
LAURA: Superman
punch!
MATT: -- up in the air and (ringing punch sound)
you kinda pull back as you feel
your vision
begin to darken, and then you feel that surge of
white hot rage in the back of your skull (crack)
bring you back, and you (grunt) pull back up as he
lands, and you watch as his expression goes (huff)
and he darts downward and goes for a low to high
ground uppercut dragon punch style.
LIAM: Look out, Guile, look out.
MARISHA: Oh god.
MATT: That's gonna-- oh, that's an 18 plus 13,
that's a 31.
(all groan)
MATT: You take nine points, reduced to five.
TRAVIS: (electronic
shut down noise)
LAURA: No!
(all laugh)
MATT: (boom) Hits you right underneath the chin,
now make--
TRAVIS: However, I use my relentless rage, now at
a DC 15.
MATT: Correct.
SAM: Whaat?
LAURA: Ooh, shit.
MARISHA: Come on, come on.
LAURA: C'mon, c'mon, c'mon, c'mon,
c'mon.
LIAM: Game that system, do it.
SAM: Come on, come on.
LIAM: Pull out a squeaker, Travis,
c'mon.
TRAVIS: 27.
SAM: Ohh!
MARISHA: (claps)
LAURA: (cackles)
MATT: 27. As it knocks you into the air,
almost onto
your feet but you manage to catch yourself and
(groans) right back up as he lands (cracks) turns
around and looks at you and goes,
TRAVIS:
Good?
MATT: "I see what you've learned."
(all laugh)
MATT: It's your turn.
TRAVIS: It's my turn?
SAM: Kill him.
TRAVIS: All three, reckless, great weapon
master! Chewing my tongue off while I do it!
(all laugh)
MATT: Go for it.
LIAM: (deep voice) Show
me what you've learned.
TRAVIS and MARISHA: (deep voice)
Show me--
TRAVIS: 29 minus five, 24.
MATT: 24 hits.
TRAVIS: Yep. So the first one is... 23, 33, 34.
34 points of damage, first one.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: Second one, nine, damn it.
TALIESIN: (high-pitched
groan)
MARISHA: (whispering) Kill him.
LAURA: 22.
TRAVIS: No, but it's minus five so it's
20.
MATT: 20.
TRAVIS: Misses.
MATT: So the first one hits (whack), it hits him
in the side of
the head, the other side, it rights his jaw
strangely but knocks him down onto three points.
He's down on his hand and his two knees in the
ground, his other arm's still up, clenched in a
fist.
He's breathing heavily, like he's on the edge.
TRAVIS: Oh.
MATT: Second strike,
you go--
LAURA: Get him, Grog!
MATT: -- to swing down and he rolls out
of the way
(fwish, crack), hits the ground with no effect.
You're going for your third and final strike.
TRAVIS: I am, yeah.
MATT: Go for it
MARISHA: Come on, come on.
LAURA: C'mon, c'mon, c'mon.
TRAVIS: (strained) That's pretty good. That's a
30, minus five is 25.
MATT: 25
hits. Roll damage.
(all cheer)
MARISHA: Come on, come on.
TRAVIS: Fuck you, Master Splinter.
LIAM: Oh man, Vax is just--
TRAVIS: Yeah, I haven't forgotten
it now--
LIAM: -- perched on the wall, pulling feathers
out.
TRAVIS: -- 23, 33, 37.
LAURA:
Oh!
MATT: Okay, how do you want to do this?
(all cheer and clap)
LIAM: That was Vox Machina's
real reaction.
TRAVIS: Okay, so the first one hits, right?
MATT: The first one hits, the second one, he
rolls out of the way and you pull back--
TRAVIS: Right, I reach back for the third
one and I go, who's good now? (whack)
MATT: (crack) You guys watch as he knocks
him clean 15 feet in the air
from the blast of the blow. He ends up
landing on top and the outside--
TRAVIS: Yes! (laughs)
MATT: -- of the arena (boom) landing strewn across
the steps that lead to the edge of the sand pit,
and there's just quiet in the chamber.
TRAVIS: (heavy
breathing)
MATT: As he stands there breathing heavily,
covered in blood.
There's spatters of blood all across the sand and
Groon's just lying there, unconscious, breathing.
LAURA: We're just
screaming our asses off.
MATT: You guys are yelling.
MARISHA: Aaaah!
TRAVIS: Wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait. Stay there.
LAURA: What?
MATT: At this point, there's the opening at
the top of the temple.
TRAVIS: Right.
MATT: There's... a rumbling sound, a
(rumble), from up above. And there's a small spark
of energy that (cracks) up above, (cracks) streaks
down and hits Groon--
LAURA and MARISHA: (gasp)
MATT: -- like a very faint lightning bolt,
just (pfft) out of the sky and Groon rises up on
the side, his eyes just vibrant bright, almost
glowing, and he stands back up, and he's still
covered in his own blood, he's wrecked. You can
see parts of his body where the muscle is swollen,
one arm appears to be almost ruined, but he lands
right in front of you.
TRAVIS: Little bit of pee comes out.
MARISHA: Uh-huh.
LAURA: (laughs)
Everybody's peeing.
LIAM: Join the party.
MATT: "You've learned much... and Kord smiles
upon you."
As you look up and you hear the roiling again,
and two bolts come streaming out of the top of
the temple down towards Grog. And slamming into
your body, you instinctually pull down and hunker,
as an animal in a thunderstorm would, but you
feel the warmth as your gauntlets all of a sudden
flash with electrical energy. And you look down as
the runes on all the sides, and the chains are now
glowing with divine energy.
SAM: You're a magician!
TRAVIS: Awesome!
MATT: As the roiling kinda comes to a close you
hear the (thunder noises) of thunder begin to
subside, and you feel the smell of burnt sky and
ozone around you begin to subside, still looking
down at the energy pulsing through the gauntlets.
Groon is still standing there,
looking up at you, and just goes:
"Continue with your journey."
And just looks at you, waiting for some kind of
response.
TRAVIS: I walk over to him. I bow. And then I
reach out one of the Titanstone Knuckles.
Kord's strength to you.
MATT: And (slamming noise) slams and pulls you in,
and with an intensity you feel his fingers crack,
even through these newly-imbued gauntlets you feel
the tension as his grip is still, strangely...
You expect he could be powerful enough to crush
the gauntlet with his bare fingers. He just pulls
you in from your giant form. The strength is
immense and you (grunt) kinda pull down into his
form. He looks you straight up, face to face,
but an inch away.
"What have you learned?"
TRAVIS: That without the love of my friends,
life has no meaning, and I would be nothing.
MATT: And how will you utilize this knowledge?
TRAVIS: I will make their strength mine,
and my strength their own, and in turn,
I will try to make the world a better place than
I found it.
MATT: His grip pulls off, and he withdraws his
arm, and he releases you
back to your full standing pose.
Now, at your enlarged form, gargantuan in the
center of this temple space, his once very
intimidating form, diminutive by comparison to
Grog's full structure, looks up and nods.
"I thank you."
GROG: I mean, I really-- I thank you.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: I've never gone that far in a battle
before. I didn't even know that was possible.
This was incredible. I'm talking a lot,
aren't I? I have a bit of a man crush--
MATT: Yes. Yes you are.
TRAVIS: Okay. Uh. Thank you.
And I turn, and I walk back to my friends.
MATT: As you make your way back, Groon steps and
leaps back out onto the opposite side, and you can
see, on the opposite end of the platform,
of the sand pit, there is a silver, somewhat
tarnished, but still functional, bell. And he
walks over to the side of it, grabs the rope,
and just-- (tolling of a low bell). And you
watch, from all the different corners of the empty
temple, all the priests of Kord begin to wander
back in, who had exited previously, as was the
request, it seems, of Earthbreaker Groon,
knowing that you were coming.
LAURA: (whispers) Oh my gosh.
MATT: They all just silently enter and kind of nod
and bow in your direction as you make your way
towards your friends. You acknowledge it,
but it doesn't slow you, doesn't stop you,
they are still your focus. And you guys watch as
Grog approaches, bloodied, beaten, barely
conscious,
one eye, the lid is kinda drooping a bit.
And even though he's strong in his stride,
there's still a shake with his knees, but he
doesn't show that weakness. He keeps pushing
towards you with a slight smile through his
bearded face.
TRAVIS: Guys-- (cough) if we could just make our
way out of here, in as cool a way as possible...
If I fall, just pick me up like Weekend at
Bernie's, okay?
(all laugh)
LAURA: Pike stands next to him and says,
Don't worry, you won't fall. And she casts, um,
Cure-- whatever, fucking--
(all laugh)
LAURA: I don't fucking know what the spell is.
MATT: Cure, Cure Things!
LAURA: I'm not even looking at them-- Cure--
MATT: You have the spell!
LAURA: He-- no, no, no, I gave them back to
Ashley!
MATT: No, I mean--
TRAVIS: Vex.
MATT: Vex has the spell.
LAURA: Yeah, but as Pike, Cure-- okay, but Pike,
she can do it better than Vex can.
TRAVIS: You have the spell!
MATT: Sure, I rolled it for you. You heal eight
hit points.
LAURA: That way you're standing and you don't have
to wobble out.
TRAVIS: I'm back at nine.
LIAM: Let's get you some ale, big man.
TRAVIS: That sounds great.
LAURA: Grog.
TRAVIS: Yeah?
LAURA: That was fucking amazing.
TRAVIS: Right? I mean, I got struck by lightning,
guys.
LAURA: Wait! Look at your gauntlets!
TRAVIS: What?
LAURA: They're glowing!
TRAVIS: Oh shit, they are.
LAURA: What does it mean?
MARISHA: Is that lightning available to you all
the time?
(all yell)
SAM: Piece of paper.
LIAM: Just for clarification, that all took place
in Super Nintendo graphics, right?
MATT: Oh, yeah.
LIAM: 16-bit.
MARISHA: As we walk out, Keyleth throws a little
gust cantrip to kick up the dust behind us.
It just looks really dusty and epic as we walk
off into the sunset.
MATT: As you guys walk off, the silhouetted
most-of-Vox-Machina with one giant Grog form
stepping through. You exit the Trial Forge into
the rest of Vasselheim. We'll take a break there.
TRAVIS: Wow.
LAURA: What's it do, what's it do?
MATT: Yeah, what does it do?
TRAVIS: In its Exalted form, my strength now
becomes 26, so plus eight, right?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: And when I use Enlarge now, I gain
resistance to
fire, cold, lightning, for ten minutes.
LAURA: Oh shit, imagine if we had done that before
we went after the dragons.
LIAM: You should've fought that guy before the
dragons.
TRAVIS: Hey, you know?
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: A little drama's good for everybody.
LIAM: You barely eked out that victory, by the
way.
TRAVIS: I know, and double damage.
MARISHA: Wait, fire, lightning, and what?
TRAVIS: And cold.
MARISHA: Lightning, fire, and cold, and double
damage?
TRAVIS: Yeah, so --
MATT: Well, not double damage.
TRAVIS: Double damage on objects and structures.
MATT: He had that previously.
TRAVIS: But that's a lot of resistance to a lot of
things. And 26 is... that's really strong.
MATT: 26 is good. It's two more than what you had,
so everything goes up plus one damage to hit.
LAURA: Damn.
LIAM: My armor does that too, but it only makes me
smell bad, it doesn't affect me.
TRAVIS: That was awesome.
MATT: All right, guys. We're gonna take a quick
break, hit the restroom, get some snacks,
and we'll be back here in a few minutes.
Thank you again. See you in a second.
[break]
MATT: Hello everyone, and welcome back to Critical
Role.
(all laugh)
MATT: So, picking up where we left off, Vox
Machina is now exiting the Trial Forge into the
Braving Grounds, Grog with the recently reinforced
Titanstone Gauntlets by the strength of Kord
through your duel with Earthbreaker Groon.
TRAVIS: Yeah!
LAURA: Sick!
MARISHA: What do they do Grog? What do they do?
TRAVIS: I dunno. You know what, we'll probably
have to fight somebody to find out, let's find
the first person outside of here.
MARISHA: Well, I mean, okay
SAM: Sure to one-hit them.
LAURA: Maybe we can find an old building and you
can just destroy it.
TRAVIS: I'm at nine.
TALIESIN: It's just a kitten going-- (mimes
punching a kitten)
LIAM: Old woman!
MATT: Red mist.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: (exploding noises) Oh shit.
MARISHA: And that's how Grog was beaten to death
by a purse.
TALIESIN: It is technically one point. He may go
down.
MARISHA: Yeah, an old lady trying to cross the
street and takes out Grog.
TRAVIS: I'm at nine hit points.
TALIESIN: Nine hit points?
LIAM: He did just take down an old man so our
streak against the elderly is going strong.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: You have the hit points of a kitten right
now.
TRAVIS: Right, well, I do-- I am fond of cats.
MATT: I'm pretty sure a kitten has less hit points
than that.
MARISHA: Yeah, like five.
TALIESIN: Five.
MATT: Who would've had a level one character with
less hit points then a kitten. That would be the
saddest thing ever.
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: We worked it out at one point.
We worked out the math at one point.
MARISHA: Yeah.
LIAM: Five is way too many. At level one you can
have five hit points as a person.
TALIESIN: It's like two hit points, it's going to
be a very tough kitten.
LIAM: It'd be like 0.1.
MARISHA: I mean if you're a wizard.
MATT: What we're saying is 'kitten' is the
baseline hit point counter in Dungeons and
Dragons, everybody.
SAM: Can we count hit points in kitten strength
for now?
MATT: All right, I'm going to use three hit dice,
I'm at 12 kittens.
LIAM: Jewels, gems, golds and kittens.
And that's what the air machines run on.
TRAVIS: Man. Thanks for not jumping in on that.
It was very personal.
LAURA: It was really hard to not.
TALIESIN: Anytime. You're welcome.
TRAVIS: Yeah, thank you.
LAURA: For a second there, Grog. For a second.
Well, a couple of seconds.
Well, no, I did, did you not see?
TRAVIS: I missed it.
LAURA: Your back was turned for so much of the
time.
TALIESIN: It was amazing.
TRAVIS: Encore!
LAURA: Well, I mean, we're outside. All right.
TRAVIS: Don't.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: I'm so sad Scanlan wasn't here for this.
LAURA: I know, he would've loved that.
TRAVIS: Yeah seriously. (sniffs)
LAURA: I feel like we should go celebrate and
drink, but it wouldn't feel right without him.
TRAVIS: No, I need like a million potions,
and maybe some attractive naked women to heal me
back to my full health.
LAURA: Right.
MARISHA: It has been a while for you, hasn't it,
Grog?
TALIESIN: Potions or women?
TRAVIS: Yeah. Yeah. I'm real cranky so I need
bandages,
and maybe some bondage, and just all the women.
LIAM: Bandages upon bondages.
MARISHA: Those things go together!
TRAVIS: Good!
MARISHA: That's great.
TRAVIS: Like a B &amp; B right?
MARISHA: Yeah.. that's exactly what B &amp; B means.
TRAVIS: That's what the letters for those words
are.
(all laugh)
LIAM: How long has Scanlan been out for?
MATT: Uh, at this point in time Scanlan's been out
for almost a day.
SAM: (making dying noises in the background)
LIAM: Gosh. I'd like to go get him, but I really
want him to wake up on his own accord.
MARISHA: I mean, we can try head back to
Whitestone and get Grog
healed up and check up on Scanlan.
LAURA: I think that would be good. Maybe get some
potions before we head out here, because
everyone's low. I'll just stop by the store and
pick some health potions
from where we got them before.
TRAVIS: There are nice stores here, and we haven't
even proper shopped in a while.
MARISHA: It's true. Vasselheim hasn't been
touched, right?
LIAM: Yeah. That's good thinking.
MATT: From what you know of the Conclave, no.
LAURA: I mean we've got fucking shit to sell--
MARISHA: (sneezes)
TALIESIN: Bless you.
MARISHA: Sorry.
LAURA: -- and stuff to buy, but that's kind of a
thing.
TRAVIS:  Or we should check out the stuff that we
got out of the den where Raishan was.
MARISHA: We should definitely do the research.
LAURA: That creepy-ass book we need to look at.
LIAM: Is Scanlan sleeping it off? I mean,
we're in Vasselheim, we've just bamfed across
miles and miles. We're here.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: I know!
SAM: Hmm, yeah, it's fine.
LAURA: No, yeah, it's fine, it's fine, I'm just
fucking sitting here, no big deal.
SAM: No, it's fine, I'm having a great dream.
TALIESIN: I wonder what Scanlan would say if he
were here right now?
SAM: Fucking come back and get me!
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: Yes, yes.
MARISHA: He's asleep.
TALIESIN: Very asleep.
SAM: (snores)
MARISHA: In a coma.
LAURA: Shit.
TALIESIN: Do quick shopping and then head home and
look at all the things.
LAURA: A quick buying of potions, I just wanna see
if I can get some stuff.
MATT: Make an investigation check.
LAURA: I should've just shaken that instead of
just--
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: Yeah. 14.
MATT: Okay, with a cursory glance of the area of
the Quad Roads which you previously went to for
the acquiring of various tonics and salves and
healing liquids, you do find a new nice
establishment that's just recently been built.
And as you enter to check in, the gentleman at
the front looks up at you, and is familiar
looking, and he goes
"Can I help you-- No! You are not welcome. Leave.
Now. Out. Please." (snaps fingers)
SAM: Who's this guy?
MATT: And these two bouncers kind of step--
LAURA: Are you the cart guy? Fucking who--
MATT: Please. No. Not her. Please!
LAURA: I didn't abuse him. Everyone else abused
him. I was very kind to you.
MATT: Your business is not welcome here, goodbye.
TRAVIS: Excuse me, has anyone seen my friend Ve--
You.
MATT: You?
TRAVIS: -- beautiful salesman, carrier of all
delightful things.
LAURA: See! We're friends, we're all friends
here.
TRAVIS: Was he uncomfortable seeing you or
something?
LAURA: Yeah. Said he didn't like me very much.
TRAVIS AND LAURA: I can't imagine why?
MATT: What do you want from me?
LAURA: Just some potions.
MATT: We don't have many.
TRAVIS: Whatcha got?
MATT: We can do business. We cannot.
LAURA: All right, I'll just stand next to him
while you do business with him.
MATT: You're not welcome in my establishment.
TRAVIS: I'm really hard of hearing. Like,
I've been working--
MATT: I can yell!
LAURA: Could you understand that?
TRAVIS: It was like (mimics Matt)
MATT: (groans)
LAURA: Yeah, yeah, it's just muffled, it's just
muffled for him.
MATT: (huffs) "Well, our stocks have been running
low since last time you came through,
we don't have much!" He puts up a small leather
case and opens it.
TRAVIS: It is such a shame. Did you tell him
already that we have a whole kingdom's worth of
jewelry and gold to spend, and I'm really tired
of carrying it.
LAURA: Stuff to sell.
MATT: Blah, blah, blah, blah.
LAURA: It is so unfortunate. We are saviors of
Emon,
saviors of the world, really, and he doesn't
even care.
TRAVIS: I thought I'd lighten this backpack a
little.
MATT: I really don't care. I have four healing
potions and one greater. That is all I have.
LAURA: Oh, is it?
MATT: That's it. You want it? No? Then good day.
LAURA: You know, I don't like him, I don't even
want to buy it from him.
MATT: Perfect.
TRAVIS: You go ahead and leave.
MATT: Please!
LAURA: No, Grog, please don't. Don't shop without
me.
TRAVIS: I'm just gonna yell at him really loud.
LAURA: No, no, I'm standing here. I can't let you
do this.
MATT: Could you please just escort them out--
TRAVIS: No, no, no, we'll take it. We'll take it.
How much?
For the four healing potions and the
one greater?
MATT: 1500 gold pieces.
TRAVIS: Cool!
LAURA: I don't know, me personally, if that is a
good amount. But Vex would know, is that a good
amount or is that a shit amount?
MATT: Based on your previous dealings with this
individual,
the fact that you are getting a price
at all--
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: --is good.
LAURA: But it's not a good price.
MATT: It's not a good market price, but it's also
a buyer's market right now.
TRAVIS: I know how to do this. I take a bag of
gold--
LAURA: No, Grog! Grog, Grog, Grog.
TRAVIS: -- pour it onto the desk. Just a pile of
gold.
LAURA: Grog, do not do this. Please, please,
please.
TRAVIS: 1500 gold pieces.
LAURA: I just scoop it back into your little--
hold out your pouch.
TRAVIS: Do you not want healing potions, or what?
LAURA: Huh?
MATT: He starts putting them back into the leather
case. (huffs)
LAURA: I don't want his healing potions.
I think those aren't even real healing
potions, I think those are probably water
colored--
TRAVIS: Well, I mean, clearly I have to say they
have worked.
MATT: Probably yes, you're right. They are colored
liquid of no particular worth. You're right,
leave. Begone.
LAURA: Right.
TRAVIS: They've worked every time.
LAURA: But we can-- Grog, please.
TRAVIS: Vex. We are so rich.
LIAM: I lean in the door and say, you've been in
there long enough to pay rent, what is going on?
TRAVIS: Vax, will you come in here a minute?
LIAM: Uh, yeah.
TRAVIS: Will you please tell your sister that we
have enough money to fund several townships,
and that this guy wants 1500 gold for four
healing potions and we have almost none.
LAURA: And a greater healing potion! Five healing
potions really.
LIAM: Is she being a pain in the arse?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I mean, c'mon, Vax.
LIAM: We're not begging in Stillben. Will you give
the guy some fucking coin
so we can get the fuck out of here?
LAURA: Yeah, but this guy's mean!
LIAM: My time is valuable. Will you pay him so we
can go, please?
TRAVIS: You're also royalty, so you should show
peasants how to act.
You know, stiff upper lip, pip-pip.
TALIESIN: So glad I'm not in this room.
LAURA: That's true.
MARISHA: My time is valuable.
LIAM: That was Liam.
MARISHA: I know, I know.
LAURA: I am a lady, and ladies treat merchants
well, and they don't hold grudges, I hear,
because they are ladies and they are above it.
So here. Take this 1500 gold. I'm going to count
it out for you, Grog. It's below him, it's beneath
him to count this gold, he's also a Lord.
There you are. C'mon Grand Poobah.
LIAM: All he hears is fart noises, and I grab her
by the mouth and I drag her out the door.
LAURA: Oh my god.
MATT: He hands the potions over to Grog.
"Very well. Enjoy your day, and I'd be wary of
keeping her as your business contact. She's a bit
abrasive."
TRAVIS: Yeah, I noticed. You've moved up in the
world, this is really nice.
MATT: I'm sharing it with a few folks, it's sort
of a partnership, but yes.
TRAVIS: Is it working out for you?
MATT: Well, I've had to hire bodyguards,
if that's any indication.
TRAVIS: If I wanted your name, like if I wanted to
call on you later, 'cause it seems like-- As far
back as I can remember, we've run into you quite a
bit, and I'm kind of fond of this--
LAURA: No, just a couple of times. Just a couple
of times.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Do you have a name?
MATT: Cidrick Gillsman.
TRAVIS: I will not remember that.
MARISHA: Oh, this guy.
TRAVIS: By the way, did you have any--
LAURA: It's the guy. That took advantage of Grog
MARISHA: That took all the money from him?
LIAM: It's why I'm saying nothing.
TRAVIS: --limited exclusive items and, like,
top shelf. Your most elite, (clicks tongue)
paying customers only?
MARISHA: Did you say 'a leek'?
MATT: I just generally run the realm of healing
balms and salves.
TRAVIS: Right.
MATT: My partner does a bit more than that,
but he is out currently picking up a shipment and
will be back in a few days. Try back then.
MARISHA: Where's his shipment from?
SAM: Are you there?
MATT: Who are you?
MARISHA: Did he come out? I thought he came out.
ALL: No.
LIAM: No, he walked into the door with Vex.
MARISHA: No, sorry.
SAM: You're at the window. When's he coming back?
TRAVIS: Where's he getting his shipment from? Do
you trust your partner? This new guy?
MATT: I do, and I don't trust you enough to tell
you this information.
TRAVIS: I give him ten gold for the information.
MATT: Thank you, that is very generous. I don't
know.
TRAVIS: Oh.
MATT: He gives the ten gold back.
TRAVIS: Oh! I thank you for your time, Poobah out.
And I leave.
(all laugh)
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: Look, I know that was hard for you.
LAURA: Grog.
TRAVIS: He was very apologetic.
LAURA: Was he?
TRAVIS: Yup. He was-- yup.
LAURA: Grog, he took advantage of you before--
TRAVIS: No, he didn't.
LAURA: -- and I didn't like that.
TRAVIS: No, look, his hands were on that side of
the counter the whole time.
LAURA: Oh?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: Really?
TRAVIS: Mm-hm.
LAURA: Well, all right then.
TRAVIS: Yeah, here, these are for you.
LAURA: Thanks, darling.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: Which one do you want?
TRAVIS: No, I don't want any, I need more of the
hands-on healing, you know what I'm saying?
LAURA: I cast Cure Wounds on him. Level four,
bitch!
MATT: All right.
LAURA: Whoa.
MATT: 4d8
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: 4d8?
MATT: 4d8 plus your wisdom modifier.
LIAM: What does that mean?
TALIESIN: It's like if you gave him an ice cream,
you see me running around on a sugar high for the
rest of the day. Never gonna burn that off.
LAURA: 14, 19.
MARISHA: Yeah, the Makey Mace-- the Mickey
Mouse-shaped one?
TALIESIN: Forgot the ears.
MARISHA: Those were great, with the ears.
LAURA: 22.
TRAVIS: 22
TRAVIS: 31 hit points.
LAURA: So... who needs the greater?
MARISHA: I'm all right. Give it to others.
TRAVIS: I mean, we could take a short rest and let
me heal up for a second. Once we land somewhere.
LAURA: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
MARISHA: We're going home, right?
LIAM: You wanna rest in the tavern?
TRAVIS: I mean, maybe.
LIAM: For an hour?
TRAVIS: But didn't you need to go somewhere?
LAURA: Percy. Greater?
TALIESIN: Thank you.
LAURA: Then I pass out the other healing potions
between--
LIAM: Where I have to go is a little more
involved.
TRAVIS: Oh.
LIAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: Are you gonna slide by the temple?
LIAM: I scoop you by the arm and take you off for
a minute. You know, I want to come back here,
sometime. One, I would love to go to the Velvet
Cabaret again. You know, just like a date night.
MARISHA: Oh, that was great. Yeah, that was fu--
LIAM: Yeah, but without somebody trying to kill
us.
MARISHA: -- oh my gosh, that was before we were
together. That was good times.
(all laugh)
LIAM: I'd like to go back without somebody trying
to murder any of us, though.
MARISHA: Right, yeah.
LIAM: That aside, I do have to go to the temple,
but I don't want to go.
MARISHA: Why are you saying it like you have to go
to the toilet?
LIAM: 'Cause that's kind of what it's like.
MARISHA: Does it feel like that? Yeah. Okay.
Yeah.
LIAM: Yeah, there is another shoe that's gonna
drop, probably, eventually.
TALIESIN: You should probably pass that, I think.
LIAM: I wanna get back to--
MARISHA: (laughs) As Percy walks by.
TALIESIN: No, I don't walk by. I just-- I'm amazed
that no one remembers
that we can hear everything
over these earpieces.
LAURA: No, you have to be touching your ear.
LIAM: No, you have to hit send, my friend.
MARISHA: (laughing) You have to hit send.
TALIESIN: Carry on, carry on.
(all laugh)
LIAM: Her other shoe is gonna drop, eventually.
And I'm not ready for that.
MARISHA: What are you afraid of? What do you think
she's gonna ask of you?
LIAM: I don't know.
MARISHA: You think she's gonna cash in on that
bargain?
LIAM: Why wouldn't she?
MARISHA: I thought you already considered paid up
in a way. I don't know.
LIAM: I don't know.
MARISHA: Sure.
LIAM: But I feel like being a little selfish and
taking a little time, and when she wants me--
'cause she's not talking to me at the moment--
when she wants me,
she'll call. So I'd like a little time.
MARISHA: Okay. What are you asking of me right
now?
LIAM: Just to come back, down the road.
MARISHA: Later?
LIAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: Do you wanna go now?
LIAM: No.
MARISHA: While we're here?
MARISHA: You're sure?
LIAM: Very sure.
MARISHA: So, just getting this straight.
What you're proposing is a Raven
Queen-slash-Velvet date night visit back to
Vasselheim?
LIAM: Well, I don't know what's gonna happen at
the--
MARISHA: Like, you go to church and then we go to
the casino?
LIAM: I'd probably do it the other way around?
MARISHA: Sure.
LIAM: Because I don't know what's gonna happen at
church. I'm talking months. Unless she rings,
okay? I just want to spend some time with you,
before I have to do whatever the fuck she wants.
She's going to collect.
MARISHA: Mm-hm.
LIAM: My sister is walking around and breathing.
Still.
MARISHA: Okay.
LIAM: Shocking as that is.
MARISHA: I mean, the fact that any of us are still
doing that is impressive at this point.
LIAM: Anyway.
MARISHA: Okay, so that will be-- that's a good
date night to look forward to.
Let's go home, I guess.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Let's at least go see if little
lover boy has woken up.
LAURA: Yeah, we've got our potions.
LIAM: Way down the line.
MARISHA: Way down the line.
MARISHA: Sure. Are you sure you don't wanna just
hop in the Raven's Spa, tonight?
LAURA: Hey, Keyleth?
MARISHA: Uh-huh?
LIAM: Jesus.
LAURA: Sorry, I just--
LIAM: Who is that?
LAURA: -- finished buying those potions.
MARISHA: Yeah.
LAURA: So, do you wanna get back to Whitestone?
MARISHA: Are you okay? You're a little-- you look
a little sweaty.
LAURA: No, I'm fine. I'm fine. I'm fine.
LIAM: That little vein on the side of your
forehead--
LAURA: You know what? We've made a lot of money,
and--
MARISHA: Yeah, you've got the Julia Roberts vein
going. (laughs)
LIAM: Who?
LAURA: (laughs)
MARISHA: Don't worry about it.
LAURA: I really do get that thing, though,
I really do. But no, I'm okay. We're fine.
Everything's fine. Except Scanlan's still
unconscious,
so maybe we should go see if he's all right?
MARISHA: You're right, you're right, all right.
LAURA: All right.
MARISHA: Let's go. Let's go. Everything's fine
here too, by the way.
LAURA: Good, good, you guys didn't seem awkward at
all while I walked up.
MARISHA: No, we're never awkward.
TRAVIS: How do we get back?
LAURA: Maybe we should go.
MARISHA: Huh?
LAURA: Tree. A tree? Can you still do a Tree
Stride?
MARISHA: I could do a tree.
LAURA: Let's do a tree.
TRAVIS: We gotta leave the city, though,
right? Out of respect.
LAURA: No, I don't think we have to.
TRAVIS: Oh.
LAURA: Druid magic's different.
MARISHA: Huh?
LAURA: It's not like-- It's not like showy wizard
magic.
TRAVIS: These rules confuse me, but okay.
LIAM: The wizard magic is like Broadway musicals?
LAURA: Yeah. It's like jazz hands. And druid magic
is like modern dance.
TALIESIN: Community theater.
MARISHA: Yes, yes.
LIAM: Brechtian theater. (pained groans)
MATT: (laughs)
MARISHA: If wizardry is Bob Fosse, druidism is
Twyla Tharp.
MATT: There you go.
TALIESIN: Wow. We went there.
TRAVIS: That was good.
MARISHA: I might know my modern choreographers.
Okay? Let's go back to Whitestone.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: All righty. So you find your way back to the
Abundant Terrace,
where you find a similar-sized tree,
to what you arrived in. Using Transport Via
Plants, you transport yourself back to Whitestone,
stepping out of the Sun Tree. Make your way--
LIAM: Pfft.
MATT: Where else, you would like to within
Whitestone?
MARISHA: It does not make that sound. That's what
you're trying to do. It does not sound like that.
LAURA: Like a little fart?
MARISHA: That is not canon.
LIAM: Trees don't fart out here?
MARISHA: They don't. Trees don't fart, they poot,
okay.
LAURA: I just start heading--
LIAM: (loud pooting sound)
LAURA: -- towards the castle.
MATT: It's the air ashari, man. So what were you
saying?
LAURA: I start heading towards the castle.
TRAVIS: On the way there, I ask Percy, Percy!
Percy.
MARISHA: The Cantrip Gust.
TRAVIS: I know this city's, like, being rebuilt
and everything--
TALIESIN: Yes.
TRAVIS: -- but do you think there will ever be
like a pleasure hall, or a house of, you know,
bosoms. I mean, I just want to put out like a
couple ideas as a city, bound up.
TALIESIN: Of course it has one. Do I happen to
know where it is, or do I not?
MATT: I mean, it hasn't been--
TRAVIS: Nope, yeah, it's pretty empty right now,
I know this.
MATT: -- really functional for a while.
TALIESIN: I feel like it would be the sort of
thing
that would have just existed for fuck all ever.
TRAVIS: No, no, no, yeah.
MATT: Whitestone has had-- there's generally--
There were two brothels, one was destroyed,
in the Briarwoods' run.
MARISHA: Is one called the House of Bosoms?
SAM: Better be.
MARISHA: It's like the House of Cards of porno.
MATT: As one of the titled masters of Whitestone,
it could very well in the near future. Just tell
me so I can add it to the campaign guide.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: I'll come up with something better.
SAM: International House of Bosoms
TRAVIS: Yes.
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: Thank you.
TRAVIS: With all the flags on it.
TALIESIN: Would I possibly know this?
TRAVIS: And six different syrups to choose from in
each room.
SAM: Ahh, the silver dollars.
TALIESIN: I don't even know if I would know this.
MATT: You know what? Make a history check.
TALIESIN: A history check? That's so-- okay.
A natural twenty.
TRAVIS: Is it really?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: That's a natural twenty, with my history
is--
SAM: Whore check!
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: -- is a 30. That's a 30.
LAURA: Percy knows knows.
MATT: You've never been to it, but you recall one
of your older brothers who is of age did return
and tell stories of a house of--
MARISHA: IHOB
MATT: -- flesh and pleasure.
TRAVIS: Thank god.
MATT: You don't recall its name, but you know that
it existed somewhere on the western side of this
city, and within a short period of time,
you could lead him to it.
TALIESIN: Okay.
SAM: And also that they serve a pancake with--
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: There's a pancake brunch.
TRAVIS: Smiley face?
SAM: -- some chocolate chips and a smiley face.
LIAM: The ancient Sumerians would pay for sex with
silver dollars.
TALIESIN: I'm honestly not sure, Grog. I really
have to think about it.
I don't know if such a thing exists.
TRAVIS: But I'm just saying, you know, if you need
to lean on me to develop that sort of the economy
again, I'm here for you buddy.
TALIESIN: That's good to know.
TRAVIS: Okay.
TALIESIN: That's good to know. Excellent.
TRAVIS: Let's go find Scanlan.
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: I wonder if he's awake yet.
SAM: Search for him. Wherever he might be.
LAURA: Where did we leave him, again?
TRAVIS: I think strapped up and covered in
mayonnaise.
TALIESIN: Pudding. Pudding.
TRAVIS: Pudding.
LIAM: "Pudding."
MATT: So you guys find your way back to castle
Whitestone, upwards to Scanlan's room. The door's
partially ajar. On the inside you see Kaylie is
actually asleep. She's sitting on a stool next to
the bed and her head's down, and she's very
lightly snoring. And there, in the bed, as you
left him, is Scanlan.
LAURA: His arms are still up?
MATT: Well, he's been turned.
LAURA: Okay.
TALIESIN: We've had people taking care of that.
LAURA: Jeez.
TRAVIS: And Kaylie's sitting in the chair,
or is she leaning back on?
MATT: No, she's leaning back in a chair and is
passed out. Scanlan is still on the bed.
TRAVIS: Can I please knock the legs of the chair
out?
TALIESIN: There's seven children in this family,
I think they're used to some tomfoolery.
LAURA: It's up to you, Grog.
TRAVIS: Yeah. I walk over and I just kick the back
leg of the chair out so she falls down.
MATT: (falling sound) (yelps)
TRAVIS: Oh my god, these chairs are so old.
Are you all right?
MATT: Oh, I'm gonna remember that.
TRAVIS: Oh right, I forgot, you'll speed bag my
nuts later, sorry.
LAURA: How you doing, Kaylie?
MATT: She looks groggy and slightly hung over and
is like,
"All right. So, you've all come back? He hasn't
really done nothing"
And she kinda smacks him in the side of the face
and wipes some of the pudding off. You hear,
just ever so faintly, as you kinda are coming out
of your stupor, you hear what sounds like voices
muffled, and it comes to, you hear what sounds
like Grog, and then what sounds like Kaylie,
and then something hits you in the cheek and you
feel a slight tinge of pain like a flick.
But your eyes begin to blink, and you guys watch
as Scanlan begins to stir.
LAURA: How long has he been like this?
LIAM: Why is he covered in pudding?
LAURA: Who did this to him?
TALIESIN: I have no idea.
SAM: What's going on?
MARISHA: Keyleth takes a little bit of the gunk
off and what is it?
LAURA: Gross.
MATT: It's like a vanilla custard.
LIAM: Thank God.
LAURA: That's fucking foul, Keyleth.
MARISHA: Look. How do you think druids discover
things, okay? Someone has to figure out what's
poison and what's not.
LIAM: Sour.
TALIESIN: They lick them apparently.
MATT: It's a little sour.
MARISHA: This is funny. This is funny, was this
you? This is funny!
SAM: Hello. Hello?
MATT: You guys hear Scanlan talking.
SAM: Hello? What's going--
LAURA: Scanlan! (gasps)
SAM: Hi.
LIAM: Hey, buddy.
LAURA (sing-songy) Welcome back!
SAM: What-- where am I?
TALIESIN: You missed all the fun.
SAM: What's going on, where am I?
LIAM: This is the afterlife, Scanlan, you've gone
to the good place.
MATT: Your hands are bound up over your head
currently, and you are dressed in a nightgown and
your room and yourself are, there's spatters of
pudding everywhere.
SAM: What's going on? Why am I like this? Where am
I?
LAURA: You don't remember?
SAM: No. Is the dragon alive?
LAURA: No, you killed it, and then we all
celebrated, and you had a big orgy.
TRAVIS: Yeah, you proposed to this woman
downstairs and this was your bachelor party.
MARISHA: You clearly have some very intense
dreams, Scanlan.
SAM: I feel like you're fucking with me.
(all laugh)
MATT: And you hear Kaylie's voice,
"Oh, you think that? Probably right true."
SAM: What are you doing here?
MATT: Well, apparently your friends brought me
along to
make sure that you woke up nice and right.
SAM: They brought you here?
MATT: Aye.
SAM: Where are-- are we in Whitestone?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: We're in Whitestone.
LAURA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: And the dragon is very dead. Very,
very dead.
LAURA: But you are not. And that's very important.
SAM: Kaylie, could you excuse us a moment?
MATT: "Aye, but at the very least--"
And she reaches over and undoes the bindings on
your wrists. Your fingers are a little numb.
You pull back and kind of rub them instinctually.
She goes,
"Don't take too long. I've a mind to speak to you
in a minute."
LAURA: Kaylie?
MATT: Aye?
LAURA: Thank you.
MATT: "Sure." She just kind of storms past and
pushes, a little gnome figure pushing through the
crowd of Vox Machina, and out of the room.
SAM: I'm sorry I... fell again. Can someone answer
me one thing, though?
Who got Kaylie? Who brought Kaylie here?
TRAVIS: Vex did.
LAURA: I sit down on the bed with you.
Well, it just seemed like the logical thing
to do, dear.
SAM: Why the fuck would you do that?
LAURA: Right. Well, 'cause you said that--
SAM: I promised her that I wasn't going to die,
and you showed her my dead body.
You thought that was a good idea?
LAURA: What! Would you rather she just discover it
on her own? This way she--
SAM: No! I'd rather she never know.
LAURA: Scanlan. She came here. She helped bring
you back. You know what that means, right?
SAM: Yes, I do, unfortunately.
LAURA: You think it's bad that she cares about
you?
SAM: I think it's bad that she thinks that I'm an
oathbreaker,
that I am weak, that I failed in my
promise to her.
LAURA: Scanlan.
SAM: That everything she thought of me when she
found me is confirmed now. That I can't be
trusted, and I can't protect her.
LAURA: Scanlan. She thought nothing of you when
you met her, all right? The fact that she showed
up here and saw that you gave your life for a
greater cause? That's so much more important than
any promise you made.
SAM: I hope that's true.
LAURA: I think it is. She didn't run away.
And after the fact
she stayed here and looked after you!
LIAM: You should have heard her play.
SAM: I did. I think. I heard music. I heard Pike.
LAURA: Wait. You heard?
SAM: I heard voices. I heard Pike saying a poem.
I heard someone playing music.
TRAVIS: Was that it?
SAM: Yes.
LIAM: All your daughter knows is that you stood
against great evil overtaking an entire continent.
That's nothing to sneeze at, Scanlan.
SAM: She also knows that I fell and that my
friends thought it would be funny to put me in a
fucking nightgown and spread pudding all over me.
TALIESIN: That was me.
SAM: And bring back my lifeless body and show her
how weak her father is. That's what she saw.
I made a promise, and I broke it, and you proved
it to her. And I wish you hadn't meddled in my
affairs. I don't have... I don't have many things
that I care about,
and I don't have anything that cares about me.
LAURA: That's a lie.
TRAVIS: That is bullshit.
MARISHA: Definitely not true.
LIAM: That's full bullshit.
SAM: What? You think you care about me?
TRAVIS: Yes.
LIAM: Yes, asshole! Yes.
SAM: Yes, I'm sorry, you're right. You like me
because I make jokes, and I play songs, and I give
you a warm place to stay at night, and I feed you
fucking chicken, and I heal you in battle.
But you don't really care about me. Come on.
Let's be honest with each other. You don't really
give a shit about me.
LIAM: I've changed my outlook on life because of
you! What the fuck are you talking about? Of
course we all love you--
SAM: Prove it.
LIAM: -- you could crush me in a second.
LIAM: How?
LAURA: What do you want us to do?
SAM: We traveled into the fucking nine hells to
get Pike a set of armor. We went and battled a
city of vampires so Percy could feel good about
his name. We fought goliaths for Grog. We've
traveled across planes of existence so you could
fix your fucking daddy issues. But you've never
done anything for me. Ever! You've never risked
anything, you don't know me, you don't know
anything about me. What's my mother's name? What's
her name? Easy question. Died in front of me.
Killed by a goblin. Biggest part of my life.
What's her name? My father. Is he alive or dead?
How old am I? Where's my fucking dog?
LAURA: We did get the dog.
SAM: You don't care about me.
LAURA: We did get your dog.
SAM: Did you?
TRAVIS: No, we didn't.
LAURA: We did, I searched--
LIAM: I've asked your age.
LAURA: I thought I did the magic search.
Fucking hell.
SAM: It's fine. I'm just a little hungover from
being dead, and I just have been thinking for a
while, and, you know. Grog has Pike. Vax has
Keyleth. Percy has Vex. But Scanlan has no one,
and I had one chance at one real relationship
with my daughter, and I feel like you've gone and
fucked it up, too. Because you don't really know
me, and you don't really know what my relationship
is with her, and what I've promised her,
or anything, really. And it's fine. When I met
you all, I was just a funny little man playing
songs, and that's all I'll ever really be.
And that's okay, because I can take care of
myself.
LAURA: You don't have to, Scanlan. Nobody knew
that any of this was going on. How many times have
we asked you if you're all right and you just
laugh and joke? We can't help you if you don't
tell us what's going on.
SAM: I don't need your help.
LAURA: Well, apparently you do, darling.
SAM: I don't like that very much at all.
LAURA: Get used to it. Nobody likes needing
someone.
MARISHA: Scanlan, do you think any of us could
have gotten here without each other? I thought you
knew that more than the rest of us. Maybe we just
thought
you didn't need us as much as you felt
like we didn't.
LIAM: I thought you were the only one who had
everything figured out.
MARISHA: I did too.
SAM: Well then, I must be a very good liar.
MARISHA and LAURA: You are.
LIAM: I thought for months, what haven't I got
figured out that Scanlan has got figured out? I've
been trapped in the mud for months, wondering what
I could do to get where you are. Scanlan,
you fucking saved the world with us. If your
daughter can't see that,
then she can't see anything.
SAM: Yeah. If you really respected me, you
wouldn't pick me up like some sort of dwarf and
pick me up and put me down and take off your
fucking armor and treat me like a fucking child.
LIAM: You've thrown some of us like baseballs.
I don't know what that is.
MARISHA: Scanlan. Do you wish we wouldn't have
brought you back? Should we not have done that?
SAM: I just wish you wouldn't have brought her
into this.
MARISHA: Scanlan--
SAM: I had one shot with her, and now how will I
ever show her that I can be trusted? How will I
ever show her that I can protect her?
LAURA: Well, maybe you should fucking talk to
her.
MARISHA: Yeah, you're a better father than most of
us have ever had.
SAM: You're right. I should talk to her.
LAURA: You should!
SAM: I should! I should. And I will.
LAURA: Don't treat her like a fucking sacred
object, treat her like a daughter, Scanlan.
SAM: Fine. You're right. I will. I will.
I'll talk to her. Listen. I don't know what
adventure we're going on next, but I think you
should go without me.
TRAVIS: Really?
SAM: Vex is right. I should talk to her.
I should be here for her. I don't know why I
wasn't with her in the first place. I didn't need
to go with you to kill the dragons. I should've
just been with her in the first place. Probably
just scared to.
I should just be her father and stay.
TRAVIS: Can I ask you a question?
SAM: Yeah. No, I will not go whoring with you one
more time.
TRAVIS: No. I was gonna ask you what your mother's
name is.
SAM: It was Juniper.
TRAVIS: I'm sorry I didn't know that.
SAM: Thank you for asking.
LAURA: Is your father still alive?
SAM: I don't really know. He makes things.
Made things, I don't know. His name is Vicou.
TRAVIS: I'm glad you're back. Whatever you want to
do now that you are... it's up to you, mate.
MARISHA: I'm sorry if we had selfish intentions.
TRAVIS: We did have selfish in--
MARISHA: Yeah. Grog knows what I'm trying to say.
TRAVIS: We didn't think about those things.
We didn't. We thought about what you meant to us.
It may not feel like much, to us it feels like a
bit, but now that you're here...
MARISHA: Scanlan, as much as you can say that you
were just the funny guy who played music and made
jokes, I don't think you realize how desperately
we need that. That's nothing to scoff at,
that's not a talent that many of us naturally
possess. You've taught me so much about the
brightness of the world, and to look at the light
side of things.
SAM: I guess it's just easier to laugh at the
world when you don't care about it.
MARISHA: That's not true. You do care.
SAM: I know.
LAURA: That's why he's an asshole now.
LIAM: We've never had one conversation, you and I,
about my mother. Where my sister and I came from.
Did you know Thordak killed her?
SAM: I think that's come up.
LIAM: We've never talked about it. Not once.
Because I didn't want to talk about it.
I didn't push into your private life. If you
wanted to talk to me, and you did, about your
daughter. We did. We talked in the sewers of
Westruun about your daughter because you wanted to
talk about her. We love you, Scanlan, and if you
want to talk about your mother or your father,
we will. You have not been exactly forthcoming.
SAM: That's fair. I haven't been. But I also
don't-- I don't have anyone.
I have to take care of myself. That's all.
LIAM: We have survived a fucking hellscape.
All of us.
SAM: (quietly) I didn't.
LIAM: You are standing before me, talking to me.
You did.
SAM: I did not. I died. Twice.
LIAM: That's fucking semantics, Shorthalt.
SAM: In a row.
LIAM: You've been brought back. You're standing
here. Your daughter is there and needs you.
SAM: I'm being kept alive by some fucked-up weird
magic. Before I met you people, I would have
never-- the worst I would have gotten in is a bar
fight. And I would have won. 'Cause I would have
been a liar and a cheater. And now, I didn't help
any of you in the last fight. I didn't do
anything. The fight before that, I didn't do
anything--
LIAM: What about the fight before that?
SAM: -- I'm useless!
LAURA: (tiredly) No, you're not.
SAM: -- I'm out of my league. I'm out of my
league. Listen, it was fun. It's fun. It really
has been fun to travel with six legends. It's fun.
It's fun to say
that your friends are legendary fighters.
It's fun!
LIAM: Excuse me! Speaking as someone who has been
fucking depressed for a long time-- Look me in the
eye. I was shit for months. And you are one of the
main reasons I am out of that now. We would be
dead, all of us, if it weren't for you. The first
time we fought Raishan, we would all be dead.
You are in a pity party right now, and I know
you're hurting, and I'm sorry you're hurting,
and I love you. But you are lying to yourself,
that you have been no use to us. You are lying to
yourself.  If you wanna retire, if you wanna go
off with your daughter, that's fucking wonderful.
I encourage you to do it. But don't lie to
yourself.
SAM: Well, that's just it. I'm a really good
liar.
LIAM: (pleading) Scanlan.
SAM: Just give me some time.
MARISHA: (timidly) Hey-- hey, guys? We're friends,
right? Are we friends?
TALIESIN: Worse, family.
LIAM: Family.
MARISHA: That's fair.
TALIESIN: And for fuck's sake, sir, I will say I
died in that fight too.
SAM: It's not fun, is it?
TALIESIN: No. And let me tell you something.
Whatever lie you were trying to feed your
daughter out there about the man she thought you
might be, that you just thought you could tell her
and then she would walk away and never actually
meet you or get to know you. So that maybe she
would never see what a shit you can be. And you
can be a shit. That fucking girl out there is a
shit too. She's a miserable, lying shit.
And for fuck's sake, the thing that brought her
back here was the things about you that you don't
like about yourself. And don't think that they
don't count, either. You're a shitty person,
we know! That's not the fucking point. The point
is for just one moment-- one moment-- once in a
blue bloody moon... You come through in a way that
others can't. And you do it, and we love you for
it, and you are worthwhile, there's a reason we
just nearly went mad trying to bring you back.
And it was not pity. And we didn't bring her-- we
brought her here so that maybe she would snap you
out of wherever the fuck you were going to.
And I know you're not out of there yet,
I've been where you are and I know it's shit.
And I would really recommend, as somebody who
misses an awful lot of people, that you are honest
with that girl and maybe discover that she
actually likes you. As a person. Because you are
actually likeable as a person! I know, it's coming
out of my mouth. I can feel the shit from it but
it's true. And for fuck's sake, get to know her
and stop making false promises that you can
protect her, and you'll always be there.
'Cause you can't and you won't. No one can.
And you're fucking lying! And it's sick.
Be a man. Be a man. I've seen you be a man,
I know you can fucking do it. And when you're done
with that, and we will leave you with that fucking
shit girl, I would like you to look up my parents'
name. You can find it on every fifth hallway in
this fucking city. And then I'm out.
MATT: (hoarsely) You leave the room?
TALIESIN: Mm-hm.
MATT: (clears throat) Okay. As you push the door
open-- it's still partially ajar-- and as you push
it open, leaning against the wall just by the door
is Kaylie,
and you can see she has tears streaming
down her face.
TALIESIN: I give her a big hug, a kiss on the
forehead--
MATT: She doesn't let you. As soon as you go for
it, she just kind of smacks it away--
TALIESIN: (makes an air kissing noise)
MAT: --turns into the room, and just kind of walks
past everyone and grabs her bag off the ground.
Slings it over her shoulder, grabs her violin
case. "So, you coming?"
SAM: ...Yeah.
MATT: "Grab your things. Be waiting for you
downstairs." And she walks out.
LAURA: Really? Just like that?
SAM: I have to.
MARISHA: Where're you going to go? What're you
going to do?
SAM: I'm just gonna be a Shorthalt for a while.
And I'm just gonna figure out what that means.
And... it's great being part of a team,
but you gotta know who you are first. So I gotta
go figure that out. And I gotta go figure out what
she is, too. And when I do, I'll come back and
find you. And if you really need a place to stay,
I'll advise you to buy some tents, 'cause you
won't have a mansion anymore. I know you'll be
fine 'cause you all have each other, but for now,
I just need to have me for a while. I love you
all. I even love Percy... and his parents,
Frederick and Johanna. And I'll go with Kaylie.
TRAVIS: Wait. I reach into the Bag of Holding and
I grab my salt-lick rock and I toss it to Scanlan.
SAM: What's this?
TRAVIS: It's yours now. When you miss us-- I know
you will-- give it a lick.
SAM: (choked) All right, I will.
LAURA: I grab the Gatestone off the end table
where
we left it with him and hand it over to you
as well.
SAM: You'll need this.
LAURA: I'd rather it go to you.
SAM: When Vex tries to give you something,
you take it. All right. Don't die.
LIAM: Scanlan... We'll miss you.
SAM: (exhales) I hope so. And... well, you said I
was right. Let's pick up that conversation later.
I'll go out the door.
MATT: Okay. As he walks down the hall, you hear
his feet across the stonework echo quieter and
quieter until you can't hear it anymore,
and you all
stand in stunned silence in the chamber.
LIAM: (draws in a breath) Fuck.
LAURA: I just pick up a pillow and throw it at the
door.
MATT: It opens slightly. The pillow lays on the
ground smattered with vanilla pudding.
TRAVIS: Did he take all his things with him?
MATT: I would say he would've grabbed his things
as he left, yeah.
LAURA: Well, that didn't go like I thought it
would.
MARISHA: No. No it didn't.
LAURA: Kinda wish we would've gone drinking in
Vasselheim now.
TRAVIS: We might've missed him if we had.
LIAM: (wearily) We saved the continent, why does
everything feel like shit?
TRAVIS: He's alive. That's what really matters.
LIAM: But he's our liar, Grog.
LAURA: (tearily) And he hates us, now.
MARISHA: He doesn't hate us.
I just... think we've all just discovered
that maybe we have a lot more secrets about
ourselves than we've all ever let on.
TRAVIS: He needs time. We have that.
LAURA: (angrily) Fuck him! Fuck him for not saying
anything sooner.
MARISHA: I dunno.
LAURA: And fuck us for not asking. (sniffs)
MARISHA: I think Percy's right. We're worse than
friends, we're family. And family leaves.
LIAM: Yes. They do.
MARISHA: Can we not be family? Can we, like,
redact that?
LIAM: I don't think so. I think it's too late.
TRAVIS: I step out into the hallway. Do I see
Percy at all?
TALIESIN: I'm around the corner, up on the--
MATT: Yeah.
TALIESIN: I'm outside of-- If you went far enough,
you'd see me.
MATT: You eventually find Percy, yeah.
TRAVIS: Hey.
TALIESIN: Hi.
TRAVIS: Rough one, that. Question:
TALIESIN: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Do you have any, like, sneaky people in
your employ here in the castle.
TALIESIN: 'Course.
TRAVIS: Wouldn't you feel better if we had
someone just keeping an eye on them? Bit
explosive, the two of them together.
TALIESIN: I'm torn. I don't know if he'd like
that.
TRAVIS: I don't know if I care. (laughs)
TALIESIN: I don't know if I do, either. I keep
thinking, I could just shout right now and half a
dozen guards would stop them.
TRAVIS: Yeah. It'd be half a dozen dead guards,
though.
TALIESIN: Well, what's half a dozen dead guards
these days?
TRAVIS: Good point.
TALIESIN: There's tale of a brothel in the west
end of Whitestone. I don't know if it still exists
but I'm sure if you go drinking in that area,
you might find something. Sorry.
TRAVIS: No, yeah. Yeah. I'll go give it a look.
TALIESIN: When you're in the mood.
TRAVIS: Now's good. Yeah, I'll be back after
nightfall. Gonna go out for a bit.
TALIESIN: Grog.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
TALIESIN: I know we don't always agree, and I know
that I can be unkind but...
you know you're family, right?
TRAVIS: I don't know much, but I do know that.
TALIESIN: It's nice having an older brother again.
TRAVIS: I leave.
MARISHA: So what, just-- the half-elves are left
alone in a room covered in pudding?
MATT: Yeah.
(all laugh)
MATT: Yeah, basically.
TALIESIN: Way to paint a tableau.
MARISHA: Crying.
MATT: Yeah. Crying in your pudding.
MARISHA: Angry.
TALIESIN: I think 'crying in your pudding' is
actually a British saying.
MARISHA: Do you think that if we would've not
covered the room in pudding,
that he would have stayed?
LAURA: I start cleaning it up.
Well, he seemed
pretty pissed that I went and got Kaylie,
even though he ran away with her at the first
chance he had.
MARISHA: And you had to stay in a shitty BnB,
a brothel and-- (laughs)
MATT: You see that Pike is still kinda shaking her
fist in the corner right now. She doesn't say
anything during this whole exchange.
LIAM: Pike--
LAURA: Pike, are you okay?
LIAM: How you doing, Pickle?
MARISHA: Oh, right, Pike. Right.
MATT: He needs to do this... Right? He needs to do
this.
LAURA: He says he does.
MATT: What do we need to do?
LAURA: I have no fucking clue.
MATT: I need to get a drink.
MARISHA: Yeah. We could always go back to
Vasselheim and pick up on that little drinking.
LAURA: I'm not gonna go anywhere, Keyleth.
MARISHA: Yeah.
LIAM: I don't wanna go back to Vasselheim.
MARISHA: I mean, we can drink anywhere. Vasselheim
doesn't have to be in that equation.
MATT: Where else do we have to go? Away from here.
I just want to be away from here.
LIAM: Pike--
MARISHA: I have to go to the water ashari.
I have to.
LIAM: And before too long, we have a demon who
wants you and I
dead in the night. We have to deal with it.
MATT: All right. Anything else?
MARISHA: Pike, you know the Ozmit Sea. You've
sailed it, yeah?
MATT: It's been a while, but yeah.
MARISHA: We might need you for the water ashari.
MATT: I can do that.
MARISHA: Seems like-- I guess all of us are
picking up on
our own individual paths from here? I guess.
MATT: Why can't we still help each other out?
LIAM: We can. Of course we can. Pike...
MATT: His path is his own. He has to do his thing
alone. We don't have to be alone.
LIAM: No. No, we don't. We just wanna slow things
down for a while.
It's been a long couple of months.
MARISHA: Is Scanlan right? Have we become too
close to each other? Do we need to all take our
individual time like we've done in the past?
LIAM: No, we just need to not have our lives on
the line every day. For a little while. Or ever.
Retirement's not a terrible idea. I mean,
what's the takeaway here, from Scanlan? Can't
hold anything in. Fuck. You know that I've always
looked up to you, for everything? That I've tried
to model myself after you. Do you know that? And
you.
You know that she's my best friend,
right? You know that.
MARISHA: 'Course.
LIAM: You know that I'm madly in love with her,
right? You know that, right? We don't need to
joke about it or dance around it anymore.
You know that I'm in love with her, right?
LAURA: Obviously.
LIAM: Obviously.
MARISHA: What are you getting at, Vax?
LIAM: I just don't-- He left because he felt like
we didn't know him. I'm scared to death about what
I have to give to a fucking god, eventually.
I'm scared of that. I don't want to do that,
but it's going to happen, and it's destiny.
I'm scared about that. There. That's out.
Do you have anything that you're holding in?
You're in love with Percival. We all know that,
right? It's plain as day, right?
LAURA: My take-away from Scanlan is that we all
talk too much. And I leave the room.
MARISHA: And then I look at Vax and Percy,
and say--
TALIESIN:  Oh, I'm not there.
MATT: Percy's not there
MARISHA: Oh, sorry. Vax and--
MATT: Pike.
MARISHA: --Pike, and say: And my takeaway is that
maybe we were forgetting who we were before we all
banded together. And then I leave the room.
SAM: They're all individually going to the room
next door.
(all laugh)
MATT: Yeah, they're all just congregating in the
next chamber.
LAURA: And that's where Scanlan's waiting.
TALIESIN: It's like a Black Mirror episode
SAM: Everyone's reading highlights.
LIAM: Crack out the aerator, yo.
TRAVIS: Highlights.
LAURA: Blacklight.
MARISHA: It's the basement in Westworld.
We all just go catatonic.
MATT: Pike kinda walks up to you as they walk out
of the room and puts her gauntleted hand on your
shoulder and just says, "We all make mistakes,
I make 'em a lot."
LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: You have a lot of other people to look up
to, aside from just me.
LIAM: I've learned that.
MATT: His path is his own. And he'll come back.
Right?
LIAM: I don't know. But he's our friend.
I like having him around.
MATT: Me too. (sighs) Let's get a drink.
LIAM: What?
MATT Let's get a drink.
LIAM: Let's get a drink. You wanna go in town?
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: All right.
MARISHA: I chase down Vex, and we do the same
thing.
MATT: You guys all individually find your way
through the rest of the afternoon to discuss,
cope with and ruminate on the separation of
Scanlan. Going through all the different emotions
you feel that are necessary, and whatever
activities you proceed to distract yourself with.
Grog.
LAURA: (laughs) Crying in a corner.
LIAM: (mock-crying)
TRAVIS: Crying on bosoms. (mock-crying)
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: I'll pay for this.
MATT: Yes, you will. That's extra.
(all laugh)
MATT: And strangely not uncommon.
LIAM: He's wrapping up the show, I can tell.
So I came to give Sam a hug.
LAURA: He's not! No, he's not!
MATT: He's not, actually. I don't know where you
got that idea.
LIAM: Well, I was just getting in a mid-game hug.
MATT: There you go! (laughs)
TALIESIN: This is awkward.
MATT: You guys still got shit to do.
LAURA: Guys, no. Stop it.
MATT: You guys made promises, you're still on a
timeline for some things.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: You still have things to do.
MARISHA: No, we know.
TALIESIN: We know.
LIAM: We know.
MATT: Don't take that as Sam closing the curtain
here. Still got shit to do.
LIAM: I know, but... I craved that, so I took it.
MATT: No, that's okay. Cross-table hugs are fine.
TALIESIN: That was weird.
MATT: The next morning comes around, you're all in
various states of hungover; should you have chosen
to imbibe with the rest of the party.
LIAM: Heavily.
MATT: Grog eventually wanders in, less hungover
but more meek about how his previous day was.
TRAVIS: Not my best night.
MARISHA: I see Vax the next morning and I say,
Look, your sister gave me one of her blue
feathers. It's because this is the darkest
timeline.
LAURA: I come back and I take that off. I'm like,
No, Keyleth, you took that from me when you were
drunk last night, actually.
MARISHA: It's because this is the darkest timeline
and I stole it from you.
LIAM: Pike and I come in wearing fun buns,
hungover. My face hurts.
LAURA: How is everyone?
MATT: She slaps you.
TRAVIS: Amazing.
MATT: Does it still hurt?
LIAM: Yeah, and also my face hurts as well.
MATT: Good.
LAURA: Percy.
TALIESIN: Good morning.
LAURA: Morning.
MARISHA: What did you do last night?
TALIESIN: Worked.
MARISHA: Worked? You were productive.
TALIESIN: Well...
MARISHA: You made the rest of us look and feel
like shit?
TALIESIN: I think we all have our ways of
coping.
MARISHA: What did you make?
TALIESIN: Just some sketches.
MARISHA: Did you bake a cake? I hope you baked a
cake.
TALIESIN: There's no cake.
MARISHA: I really want coffee cake right now,
Percy.
TALIESIN: There are people for that.
LIAM: You look like me.
LAURA: Squish-squish. Squish-squish.
LIAM: You look like me. Why do you look like me?
LAURA: You're still drunk. Sober up. It's a new
day.
LIAM: That's boring.
LAURA: (laughs) Oh, shit! He could've broken his
nose just then, I swear. Oh my god.
MARISHA: Is it a new day?
LAURA: It is.
MATT: It is.
MARISHA: I thought it was still yesterday.
TALIESIN: Oh hey, I've got all my hit dice back.
That's nice.
MATT: Yeah, spells are back, you guys are healed.
MARISHA: My staff is charged.
LAURA: You're up from nine points.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: Hey, wake up, fuck. Wake up. It's a new
day. Open your eyes. Hey.
MATT: Pike casts Restoration on Vax.
LAURA: Hey, you're not drunk anymore, look at
that.
LIAM: I feel good.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: All right. So, what? First step is the
most important one, right?
TALIESIN: Well, as far as I know we have three
things still on our plate.
MATT: Which ones?
TALIESIN: We've got a hand.
LIAM: Hotis.
TALIESIN: We've got the ashari, and we've got a
demon.
MARISHA: We also have research we have to look at
that we got from that lair of Raishan's.
TRAVIS: What's the hand?
LAURA: We have to give Ripley's hand to those guys
in Marquet. I think that's the easy one.
LIAM: That seems like the quickest.
MATT: That's definitely the quickest.
TRAVIS: Let's try that.
LIAM: My mental acuity's on point.
MARISHA: I feel like if I teleport I'm gonna
puke.
MATT: Pike grabs a bucket.
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: I run to the kitchen. I put together
something that is not quite, but probably a hot
sauce, with half a raw egg, and shot of something
that is quite possibly
but not quite some sort of
fantasy variant of tequila.
MARISHA: You are not--
TALIESIN: Swirl it all up.
MARISHA: -- frat-boy one-shotting me this.
TALIESIN: This is a thing.
LIAM: That's science. Listen to Percy. That's
science, you need that and you need a traditional
Whitestone breakfast.
LAURA: It's super good, Keyleth, really.
TALIESIN: Yeah, just get it down, just get it
down.
MARISHA: Why this?
TALIESIN: Don't look at it.
LIAM: Just listen to the science guy and
chug-a-lug.
TRAVIS: Bottoms up.
TALIESIN: I was kidding. You shouldn't actually
drink that.
MARISHA: Fuck you, motherfucker!
TALIESIN: Can I get a roll damage?
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: I've done something very similar to that
on many a morning.
MARISHA: We need to look at this research.
We need to figure out what Raishan had going on.
LAURA: My brain hurts from crying so much
yesterday.
MARISHA: I know. Are my eyes puffy?
TALIESIN: Yes.
MARISHA: Do I have bags under my-- thank you.
TALIESIN: You're welcome.
LIAM: You wear it well.
MATT: So what's the plan. What's up first?
TALIESIN: Let's take a quick look at what we got
from the cave.
LAURA: Maybe bring Allura and Gilmore in here,
because
we have that book that seemed very
nefarious.
MARISHA: I help Percy figure things out.
MATT: Okay. From the things that you gathered
off, a lot of them were candle-holders, there were
various reagents, some of them rotted or dried
out, a number of books and tomes, some that deal
with poisons, various alchemy. Actually, a similar
book to the one that you found earlier in your
travels, but an older version of it. And there is
the one large tome that you acquired that had the
more nefarious-looking leather-bound exterior,
the thicker piece.
TRAVIS: I'll read this.
LAURA: No, don't touch it, Grog, I don't trust it.
I want Allura or Gilmore to look at it first.
MATT: The easiest person to find here would
probably be Allura, in the castle. Well, no,
because Allura's off in Emon helping with the
destruction. Gilmore would be the only one you
could really speak to currently.
LAURA: Or Eskil.
MATT: Or Eskil. But he's a little wary of you at
the moment. (laughs)
LAURA: I just keep making people wary of me.
MATT: All right, so you go ahead and you bring
Gilmore in?
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: Okay. And it's easy enough to bring in.
He's just waking up. (yawns)
"So, what can I help you with?"
LAURA: Hi.
TALIESIN: We found this. Be careful, it was with
Raishan.
MATT: He takes it, he sits down and places it on
his lap, and tugs on his braided goatee.
"This smells like shit."
TALIESIN: Several things have died on top of it.
LIAM: I give my armor a sniff.
MATT: Smells-- different kind of shit, but shit
nonetheless. He takes a look over it.
"This has a very faint magical essence to it.
Let me go ahead and--"
He looks over it for a second, his eyes glow with
that same
arcane purplish energy that flares when he does
the Identify spell. Looks over it.
"This is an evil book. Reading this would be
informative, but would certainly have a cost."
TRAVIS: Like, money?
MATT: Soul-money.
LAURA: Soul-money.
TRAVIS: Do we have any of that in the bag of
holding?
LAURA: I don't think we do. Not anymore.
MATT: Wouldn't recommend it, Grog.
TALIESIN: What do you recommend we do with this
book?
MATT: Well, if you ever feel like you want some
light reading. Or find somebody who's foolish
enough to read it. Or at least has the willpower
to push through
its dark enchantments. I have no idea.
TRAVIS: Oh, shit.
LAURA: Let's just keep that in a--
TALIESIN: Going to vault that for the moment.
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: You're saying somebody could read it,
but they'd
have to make it all the way through the end.
MATT: I don't want to look into it, I'll put it
that way. But somebody with a strong enough mental
aptitude to be able to not be corrupted by its
dark magics.
It's my recommendation at the very least.
TALIESIN: Not anyone in this room, is what he's
saying.
TRAVIS: Right. What else have we got?
TALIESIN: I say hand. It's simple, to the point.
LAURA: I agree.
LIAM: I agree. One and done.
TALIESIN: And we can find the ashari on the way
back.
MARISHA: Yeah, we can.
TRAVIS: All right.
LAURA: This feels wrong.
TRAVIS: It feels different.
LIAM: Ah, it feels wrong.
MARISHA: That's not on us, though, it's on him.
LAURA: Can you scry?
MARISHA: Me?
LAURA: Yeah. See where he is, what he's doing.
MARISHA: I pull out the scrying eye. Can I hold it
out in front--
this is kind of flavor-- and I let it
levitate in front.
MATT: It locks itself in place and slowly
rotates.
MARISHA: Can I open it like a fortune-teller's
spying sphere type of crystal--
LAURA: And just like project it on the wall behind
her so we can watch it like that movie.
MATT: The vision comes to you. It doesn't quite do
that.
MARISHA: That would be really awesome.
TRAVIS: Can I make it Imax?
MATT: I want that HD download, not the SD.
MARISHA: 5.1 Dolby digital surround.
LIAM: Whoa, it's all around me!
MARISHA: Oh my god, so many lagging issues.
TRAVIS: What's he rolling for?
LAURA: To see if he senses it, maybe.
LIAM: You don't know.
MATT: So what's your wisdom modifier?
SAM: Me?
MATT: Your wisdom saving throw.
SAM: Negative two.
LAURA: Wait, what did you roll?
MATT: What'd you roll?
SAM: I got a two total. But I get advantage
against magic.
MATT: You do.
SAM: That's a 17.
MATT: Plus your-- what's your wisdom saving throw
bonus?
SAM: I mean, that's 19, my wisdom is negative
two.
MATT: Oh, minus two. Got you. And your spell DC
is--
MARISHA: Oh, I'm spying on those bitches.
MATT: Okay, so. You get a brief view of what looks
to be Scanlan,
wearing his regular outfit and armor now.
MARISHA: He took his armor off? He's just regular
clothes?
LAURA: No, he walked out in a fucking nightgown.
MATT: He walked out in a nightgown.
MARISHA: Oh, right, yeah.
MATT: Through this whole emotional circumstance,
he was in a nightgown. But he is currently,
he's walking through the Parchwood Forest that
surrounds Whitestone. He is on the path south.
MARISHA: South of Whitestone?
MATT: Yeah. South of Whitestone. To his left is
Kaylie, and they're both with their sacks over
their shoulders, and they're just hiking through
the forest. They're, at the moment, not talking,
but they're both slightly smiling. Just kind of
enjoying the journey, and the company. And you
just watch them walk for a little bit through the
thick tree canopy above, the well-worn path that
heads south and out of the Parchwood.
MARISHA: He looks content. Happy, even.
LAURA: That's good.
LIAM: Yeah, good on him.
TRAVIS: Can you yell at him?
MARISHA: I feel like he's like flicking off a
bunch of trees now.
I don't know. He was always an odd one.
LIAM: To be fair, he did that about seven times a
day.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: He did, yeah.
LIAM: For no reason.
MARISHA: I never knew his animosity toward trees.
MATT: You never know.
SAM: Just in case.
MARISHA: I don't know.
(all laugh)
LIAM and LAURA: Just in case.
MARISHA: Just really hates oaks.
LIAM: Raven Queen, demons, you never know who's
looking over your shoulder.
LAURA: We should've invited Kaylie to come with
us. They could've stayed--
LIAM: They don't want that.
MARISHA: I have a feeling there's little chance we
could talk him out of it. Well! All right.
He's living a nice, happy, content, low-key life
now. Let's continue on.
LIAM: Yeah, and why shouldn't he, he earned it.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MARISHA: Yeah, he did
LIAM: He earned it.
TRAVIS: (quietly) Dick. (louder) Sorry, what?
LAURA: Yeah, right.
MARISHA: He saved the world, what more could we
ask of anybody?
TRAVIS: Let's go. What clears the brain better
than travel? (sniffs) Or sex.
LIAM: Wait, stop, stop. I was about to say you
sounded very wise, don't fuck it up. Just, period.
TRAVIS: Period.
LIAM: Travel and sex. Done.
MARISHA: You know, there's merit to that.
All right, let's go.
LAURA: As we head to the tree, I pull Grog aside,
and I ask him: Are you all right, Grog? I mean,
I know, I know you got your lady favors out of
the way and all that, but... Scanlan was your
bestie, right? Outside of Pike.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'm just bummed, because I'm glad
he's alive--
LAURA: Well, yeah.
TRAVIS: I think that's what keeps us from being
terrible. But like-- (sniffs) I only trust like a
few people in the world. You, Scanlan, and Pike.
And now it's just you and Pike.
LAURA: Me and Pike?
TRAVIS: No, I mean I trust the others, right,
but like... I know you on a more intimate level.
LAURA: Cause you saw my titties?
TRAVIS: Pretty much.
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Um.
MARISHA: That's literally it. I don't know if
they've ever had, like, an in depth conversation.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: So.
LAURA: Right.
TRAVIS: That's all. I just-- I just feel a little
more sad on the inside. But I'm all right.
LAURA: I'm sorry, Grog.
TRAVIS: Yeah. I'm glad he's okay.
LAURA: Me too.
MARISHA: Show him your titties again.
LAURA: Do you want to see them? Would that make
you feel better?
TRAVIS: No, it's not right, right now.
LAURA: Yeah, no, it didn't feel right, I just
wanted to... all right.
TRAVIS: Yeah, you know. It's... mmm. You know.
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: I appreciate the offer.
MATT: As you walk your way down to the center of
Whitestone, to the Sun Tree--
LIAM: It's so touching and ridiculous at the same
time.
MATT: I know. You recall that in the center of the
city itself, Ank'harel, as it acts as one of the
largest oases in the center of the central Marquet
desert, there are a number of larger trees of
various types, and there's one not too far from
the Suncut Bazaar, that you recall. You make that
your designated tree, and upon casting the spell,
you watch the Sun Tree, tear open the doorway,
and you step across--
MARISHA: As I cast the spell, I just say, Hey,
Sun Tree? Watch over Scanlan and Kaylie,
okay? And then go though.
MATT: You step through. Okay. You all emerge on
the outskirts of the Suncut Bazaar. At this point
in time, it would be the beginning of-- just past
dusk. The sun has gone down in Ank'harel.
But you can still see the oranges and reds and
purples of the recent sunset in the distance.
The city is bustling. Lanterns are alight all
throughout. The bazaar itself and all the various
multicolored towers and structures and buildings,
the beautiful city just stretch up in all
directions around you. You can see the bazaar
itself is lively with carts that are open,
shouting as various barkers are peddling their
wares. It's a very upbeat atmosphere, and one
that's a stark change to the Whitestone you just
stepped away from.
LIAM: And the sun is going down, you said?
MATT: The sun has already gone down.
LIAM: After we just woke up.
MATT: Yes.
LIAM: Jet lag.
LAURA: We fucked up.
MATT: Yeah. Other part of the world.
TALIESIN: Jet lag.
LIAM: Yeah. What?
TALIESIN: Tree lag.
MARISHA: Tree lag.
LIAM: It's a bitch.
MATT: (laughs) Tree lag.
MARISHA: It's the worst.
MATT: You guys begin making your way toward
the Debt's Respite, which is the tavern
that housed the Scarbearers. This is where Treev
Bonebreaker was when
you last discussed the return of Ripley's
hand--
LAURA: Right.
MATT: -- as the assassin that killed one of their
own. And you're returning this hand to absolve
yourselves of implication in this murder.
MARISHA: Yes.
MATT: Since you discovered the body.
TALIESIN: I'm, for the record, not wearing the
cloak when we do this.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA and MARISHA: Hey!
MATT: Good point!
TALIESIN: And just for the record, I know I'll get
yelled at for twitter on this. I have informed my
sister where I'm going and what's going on.
Not just going willy-nilly.
MATT: Right, right, Cassandra is aware. All right.
You guys walk through, you catch a few eyes as
you are not just outsiders walking through
Ank'harel,
but you're all adorned in, you know,
beautiful artifact armor--
LAURA: Right, we didn't put on our--
MATT: Magical weapons--
LIAM: God wear.
MATT: God wear, essentially. And as you walk
toward the Debt's Respite tavern, on the
outside you can see, there's what looks to be an
eight-and-a-half-foot tall, humanoid, golem-like
metallic construct. It looks similar to a golem,
but it's smaller. Like the iron golems you've
fought before, but it's smaller in scale.
LIAM: Like the one we fought in J'mon's.
MATT: Yeah, J'mon's, but much smaller. It's less
bulky, and more just a functional, tall,
metallic humanoid-type construct.
LIAM: Protocol droid.
MATT: Yeah. You see it's clutching--
MARISHA: (gasps) It's basically the Vision?
MATT: A little more ramshackle in construct.
MARISHA: Ah, okay.
MATT: It's clutching a leather tome in one hand
that is open, and is holding what looks to be a
quill in the other, and it's just standing there
quietly. To the front of it you see, almost
waiting outside the tavern in the process of
thumbing through some satchels, you see a handsome
human male. Late 30s or so, with shoulder length,
feathered, dirty blond hair and blue-green eyes,
a well groomed goatee adorning his dashing smirk
as he turns and looks across you and very quickly
the eyes very overtly take in and categorize your
decor, your dress, your stature. And the smile
grows even wider. His frame is svelte, he's
adorned a set of polished, immaculate breastplate
armor with numerous satchels all around him,
and he carries a silver helmet under his arm that
shines with many, many embedded gems: diamonds,
opals. Just an opulent-looking figure who's
wearing what looks to be barely used, or at least
very well-kept armor and jewelry and adornments.
Immediately catches their attention.
SAM: You there!
LAURA: (gasps)
SAM: You lot! Hello! Wow! Who are you all? Look at
this, magical items from head to toe. Why,
I've never seen anything quite like it.
LIAM: Pouring it on a little thick, friend.
What's up?
SAM: Doty, come here, will you? Take this down.
MATT: (stomping and creaking sounds) And you watch
as the giant construct takes a few steps forward
and begins writing into the book.
SAM: In my travels through--
LAURA: Fuck! It's a kleenex, it doesn't work! You
piece of shit!
LIAM: God dammit.
MARISHA: That couldn't have been more uncanny!
LAURA: Fuck! I didn't want to throw something hard
at him.
MARISHA: Hoooly shit.
LIAM: Fucking. Hell. (bangs table)
SAM: Doty. Doty, take this down: In my travels in
Anh'karel, I have never seen so many magical items
in one place. But then I saw them, walking up to
me, and I knew I had met some very special people.
That's it for now. Hello! Nice to meet
you all. The name is Taryon Darrington.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: Darrien Darriton?
Sam: Tary-ann-- Taryon Darrington.
MARISHA: Darrington.
SAM: My friends just call me Tary. And I'm a bit
of an adventurer. I've been traveling around this
continent for a while, trying to tick off things
off of my list, and I've had a few scraps and
scrapes. And I'm looking for more adventure.
I was travelling with a band of ne'er do wells
that I had hired and, well, let's just say many of
them were killed. Heh. SO. I was looking to employ
a ragtag group of people, elves, whatever you
are.
To accompany me, sort of be my side men,
if you will.
LAURA: (disgruntled) Oh.
SAM: How much would a band like you cost for a
day?
LAURA: 50,000 gold.
SAM: Oh. That's nothing. Would you--
TRAVIS: An hour.
SAM: I'm sorry?
LAURA: 50,000 gold an hour.
MARISHA: It's like our retainer fee.
LAURA: (quietly) Good thinking, Grog.
SAM: Well, I tend to employ people on a
month-by-month basis, and you get a cut of the
treasure as we go, of course. We can work out the
particulars, but are you in fact, guns and-- or,
not guns. Swords-for-hire?
TRAVIS: What, are you going after treasure?
SAM: I'm going after many things. I have a long
list of things I want to tick off.
TRAVIS: Are you famous?
SAM: Of course I am. You haven't heard of...
Well, you haven't heard of me yet because my book
hasn't come out yet. Doty here is recording my
legendary
adventures as I travel around the continents.
TRAVIS: How thick is the book?
MATT: It's pretty thick. Make a perception check.
TRAVIS: (surprised) Oh.
LAURA: Wow.
TRAVIS: 18!
MATT: Okay. It's a pretty thick book, but it looks
like Doty is maybe a third into it. A fourth.
TRAVIS: Lots of scribbles in that book.
SAM: Yes, I haven't settled on a title yet.
It will either be-- "Tary's Adventures". It's sort
of lame, sort of lame. Or it could be "Daring
Adventures of Darrington" or it could be "Tarry On
with Taryon". Or something like that, I'm working
on the title, I have a while to finish it.
LAURA: (sarcastic) They're all very clever.
TALIESIN: The Daring Trial and Tribulations of
Tary Darrington.
SAM: That's fantastic! Doty, please write that
down.
MATT: (creaks and squeaks)
SAM: I knew you were special when I ran into you
all, my goodness.
LIAM: Hey, buddy boy, we have to go to the Nine
Hells
in the not too distant future, are you down
for that?
SAM: Well.  Hold on, let me check my list....
that is on the list. It was... lower down, but,
it's another thing I have to tick off before I'm
a real adventurer!
So, I'm up for anything if you are.
LIAM: Hm. I do not like you.
MARISHA: This fucking asshole, am I right? This
fucking asshole.
TRAVIS: Can I insight check Asshole?
MATT: Yes, you may.
LIAM: Look at this willing accomplice
motherfucker!
MARISHA: I know!
LAURA: You piece of shit, both of you.
MARISHA: You're all pieces of shit.
LAURA: I'm so angry at everything right now.
TRAVIS: Is it perception or what on that?
MATT: Insight.
TALIESIN: It feels weird. New dad is wearing old
dad's skin,
and trying to do an impression of him and--
MARISHA: (yelling) I don't like change!
LIAM: Who cares about the whisper, what's going
on, Sam?
MARISHA: Bullshit.
TALIESIN: Tell us about the LootCrate, Sam! Tell
us about the LootCrate.
LAURA: How dare you, Samuel? (gasps) He has a new
character sheet. I'm going to cry, again.
TALIESIN: Ah! Mother lied. Ah.
LAURA: I'm going to cry again. Nope. I hate Tary.
He's a dick.
TRAVIS: We are actually--
MARISHA: You're going to make Laura cry.
Look what you've done.
TRAVIS: We are currently under--
TALIESIN: Dick.
MARISHA: (yelling) Fuck you, Ryan Green! Fuck
you!
LIAM: This show is breaking apart because of you,
Sam!
MARISHA: You were part of this too!
LIAM: Show me on the character sheet where the bad
DM touched you.
MATT: So, bringing it back to current conversation
at hand.
TRAVIS: We are currently employed right now.
We're on a very, very dangerous mission.
LAURA: A super important mission.
TRAVIS: However, it ends here. So, if you have the
coin, and maybe if you prove yourself not to be
too much of a lag-behind.
Percy, what do you feel like--
TALIESIN: I'm just saying, look, it's not like we
don't have business right now. You seem...
what does he seem like?
MARISHA: Yeah, what do you do, Tary?
SAM: I'm an adventurer!
TRAVIS: He's an adventurer.
(all laugh)
TALIESIN: You seem like a person, and that's
great.
TRAVIS: Like Kenneth Branagh in Harry Potter.
LIAM: He seems like a prat.
TALIESIN: I'm trying not to judge at the moment,
and--
LIAM: That's what you do.
TALIESIN: I know. I've had a bad day.
MARISHA: We trust you to judge.
TRAVIS: What does he do?
SAM: That's my biographer, Doty.
TRAVIS: Does he just write stuff?
SAM: If I tell him to. He also has other skills.
LAURA: What does he have?
SAM: Many things. I can grant powers to many
people.
For instance: you, Little Elf Girl,
what's your name?
TRAVIS: (laughs) (quietly) I'm gonna move over
here.
MARISHA: Hell no. Oh-ho-ho-ho.
TALIESIN: I take it back, I like him.
LIAM: Wait, I'm stealthing.
MATT: Flames on the side of my face. Fire.
Heaving breaths.
MARISHA: Keyleth uses a fog cantrip and just fades
into the alleyway.
LIAM: I rolled a 33 on stealth, I'm gone!
TALIESIN: And I just hex into the shadows.
MARISHA: It's like we're in a Western when they
cut back to the tavern and everyone's gone.
MATT: Basically.
LAURA: I walk up to him. What kind of adventurer
are you
if you've never heard of Vox fucking
Machina?
SAM: Ooh! Is that a band of evildoers, is that a
roving goliath horde?
LAURA: Where the fuck have you been? Who are you?
No really, who the fuck are you?
SAM: My name is Taryon Darrington, I am an
adventurer,
and I have more recently set out on my
journey, that is true.
LAURA: This armor looks very new.
SAM: I have not seen so many real battles yet,
but I have fought many beasts.
LAURA: Mm.
SAM: There was one, it was a smallish beholder,
and my men took it out into a field for me and
sort of roughed it up for me, and then when the
time was right for the kill, they said "Come on in
and kill it!" And I came in and used my powers and
killed it and I checked it off the list.
LAURA: Oh, I see.
SAM: Yes. It was so thrilling.
TRAVIS: Your men, are you--
LAURA: The ones that died.
TRAVIS: Oh.
LAURA: Right?
SAM: They also perished, that was a different
group, yes.
LAURA: Wonderful.
SAM: But they were well-paid before they went,
and I'm sure they sent some of the money home.
Some of them, I think they do that, typically.
TRAVIS: What else is on your list, what're you
looking for?
SAM: I've got a long list of beasts and animals
I'd like to slay--
TRAVIS: Just give me one.
SAM: Uh, naga, I think that's how you say it.
LAURA: That is how you say it.
TRAVIS. It's actually nah-jah.
SAM: Okay.
MARISHA: (laughs) Nah-jah!
SAM: I've already gotten a smaller beholder.
Someday I'd like to see a dragon, maybe have a
crack at it or two.
LAURA: Oh, I'm sure you'd take it out in no time,
dear.
TALIESIN: Right.
MARISHA: Man, I fucking hate this guy.
SAM: I feel like you're condescending to me! I'm
not, I'm not a dullard, here. I can do a lot of
things! My wealth has bought me many different
artifacts from my travels,
and they all do majorly magical things.
TRAVIS: What kind of weapons does he have on him?
SAM: I have a rod.
LAURA: An Immovable Rod?
TRAVIS: Is it movable?
SAM: No, it's whatever I want it to be. Sword!
MATT: You watch as the rod all of a sudden
transforms into this sudden liquid, metal-like
visage, and then solidifies into a longsword.
SAM: Fire!
MATT: It bursts into flames.
TRAVIS: Now that is fucking great.
SAM: It's fucking cool, isn't it?!
LAURA: How much money did that cost?
SAM: Oh, like, 400,000 gold or something? It was a
lot of money. I don't quite... Doty keeps the
facts and figures. Doty, can you show me that
piece of the book?
MATT: (mechanical squeaks, pages turning,
squeaks). Turns it around.
SAM: That's embarrassing.
MATT: Shows the page to you and you glance through
it, and the actual construction of the item cost
you upwards around 65 to 70,000 gold.
LAURA: That's it?!
MATT: It's a lot of money.
LAURA: Well I know, but--
TRAVIS: So wait, you want to come with us,
or you want us to come with you?
SAM: I don't have a current adventure right now.
Fire off.
Still getting used to some of the
contraptions.
LAURA: Tell you what, Tary? 50,000 gold and you
can follow us right now as we finish this very
adventurous errand we're running.
MARISHA: What! Vex!
TRAVIS: Yeah!
MARISHA: What?!
LAURA: 50,000 gold. Small fee.
SAM: What kind of adventure is this, again? You
mentioned
you're going to do something very dangerous.
LAURA: It's so dangerous.
TRAVIS: So dangerous.
LAURA: We're going into this dangerous--
SAM: Can you tell me what it is?
LAURA: I'm afraid I can't, it's very--
TRAVIS: It's a test of your reflexes, on point,
how you handle things you're not quite ready for.
SAM: I could limber up, sure.
LIAM: I stealth up behind Keyleth and rest my chin
on her shoulder and just say
Whaaat the fuuuuck.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: And I just say
I knoooow.
Um, Vex.
LAURA: What?
TALIESIN: One moment, sir. Huddle.
MARISHA: Huddle. Is 50,000 dollars worth dealing
with this annoying piece of shit?
LAURA: While we go drop off a hand?
MARISHA: Look, it just feels like when your guinea
pig dies as a kid and then you immediately get
another guinea pig to replace it? This doesn't
feel good.
TRAVIS: You don't like him, right?
LAURA: You think he's replacing Scanlan?
MARISHA: No! I just, I don't want another guinea
pig!
LAURA: This piece of shit would never replace
Scanlan.
MARISHA: He's a fabricator! He gets ghostwriters
to write all of his books, I bet he does!
LIAM: He's a schmuck.
TRAVIS: He probably does. Keyleth, you don't like
him very much, right?
MARISHA: I don't like new people right now,
as of yesterday!
TRAVIS: But like, 50,000 gold and we have ourself
a very flamboyant distraction if we need it.
LAURA: Think about it, for 50,000 gold, we're only
15,000 gold away
from getting one of those fucking
flaming swords!
SAM: While they're talking, I'm working on my rod.
Battleaxe!
LAURA: Look at how fucking cool that rod is!
TRAVIS: He's in. He's fucking in.
MARISHA: No!
TRAVIS: Look at the battle axe! Holy shit!
MARISHA: You guys, he's like the worst alter-ego
version of Percy!
He's a rich kid who just buys all of his
cool toys. No offense, Percy.
TALIESIN: None taken.
(all laugh)
MARISHA: It's true though! He's not legit!
LIAM: I don't like him either, but I'll just say
two words: Hotis bait.
TALIESIN: Yes, that's my thought.
LAURA: Maybe he is Hotis.
MARISHA: Oh yeah, what if he is Hotis?
TRAVIS: He's not.
MARISHA: How do you know, Grog?
LIAM: He hasn't tried to seduce me.
TRAVIS: I'm a dark wizard.
LAURA: I've always known.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
TALIESIN: I'm not going to pretend I'm not mildly
entertained by the distraction at the very least.
We just have to drop off a hand.
MARISHA: And then he's gonna take credit for
dropping off a hand,
like it's some crazy, miraculous thing!
LAURA: Let him take credit for the hand.
TALIESIN: Do you want credit for dropping off a
hand?
MARISHA: No! I don't care. It's the principle of
the matter!
TRAVIS: Is there a fighting arena in Marquet,
or anywhere
we could find a scrap if we wanted to?
MATT: I mean, I believe there is. Let me find the
name of it real fast.
TALIESIN: We also could report in to a certain
dragon about things that have happened.
LAURA: We actually need to because we promised
Jarett we would talk to J'mon.
LIAM: So many things to do.
TALIESIN: Let's just--
LIAM: While Grog's thinking about that, I pull him
aside and say
Did I ever show you I know how to
summon a dragon, d'you know how to do that?
TRAVIS: No.
LIAM: Watch and learn from my hand symbols.
What do you think of that, big guy?
TRAVIS: And I grab his hands with the Titanstone
Knuckles--
LIAM: Ow! Ow!
TRAVIS: -- and squeeze.
LIAM: Jeepers creepers, you've killed my dragon!
MARISHA: Grog! Grog!
TRAVIS: Don't --
TRAVIS: -- summon the dragon. Uh, what?
MARISHA: Grog, no, no, let go, Grog drop it,
Grog drop --
TRAVIS: -- baby dragon
MARISHA: Drop it, drop it, good boy!
LIAM: See if I ever do anything nice for you
again! Jeez!
TRAVIS: Well, I thought you were being taken over.
D'you need me to make sure you're all right?
TALIESIN: Very proud of you Grog.
LIAM: Will you kiss it? I thought so. And I walk
away.
MARISHA: Grog.
TRAVIS: He comes. C'mon.
LIAM: We are fucking slap-happy.
TALIESIN: C'mon then.
TRAVIS: Besides I wanna see him get in a fight,
let's audition him at least.
TALIESIN: Vex, let's let the money tag along.
LAURA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: It'll be fine.
MARISHA: Okay, but I'm--
LAURA: C'mon, pretty boy, let's go.
MARISHA: -- gonna be pouty about this.
SAM: Doty, take this down. As the group turned
around, I knew I had them.
(all laugh)
SAM: And our adventure was about to begin.
End chapter.
(all laugh)
LAURA: I hate him so much!
MARISHA: I hate him so much!
TRAVIS: I love him.
LIAM: I miss Scanlan!
(all laugh)
MATT: As you guys decide against your better
judgment to
accept your companion for the time being--
LIAM: Don't like that word!
MATT: -- you make your way into the Debt's Respite
Tavern to meet with
Treev Bonebreaker and deliver the right hand.
LAURA: Wait, wait, I wanted that gold up front!
SAM: Oh! I don't carry 50,000 gold with me on my
person!
LAURA: Well, you carry platinum, how much do you
have?
SAM: I-- not--
LAURA: Doty, how much platinum does he have on him
right now?
SAM: Doty, go ahead and speak.
MATT: No response.
SAM: Go ahead, Doty, speak.
LAURA: Doty!
SAM: Oh, that's right, Doty can't speak.
Doty's a machine.
LAURA: Doty, show me the ledger. How much platinum
does he have on his person right now?
MATT: There's no response.
LIAM: (robot beeping sound effects)
SAM: Doty only listens to me. If you had some sort
of a pet, you would understand.
TRAVIS: (gasps) Oh, I'm gonna love Tary so much!
MARISHA: Vex! Vex, kick his ass!
TRAVIS: I'm gonna love him so much.
MARISHA: Kick his ass, Vex!
LAURA: Gold up front or you don't join us.
SAM: How about this? I'll give you a little
present, just for you, little elf girl. And I flip
her a silver coin that I have put a spell into.
I've put--
LAURA: I don't catch the coin.
MARISHA: You're like all the bad things about the
internet as a character.
LAURA: It's a piece of shit silver coin,
I don't need your stupid silver coin.
SAM: It's a special coin, you should pick it up.
TALIESIN: Did he flip the coin at her?
MATT: He did.
TALIESIN: I was thinking of intercepting it anyway
so--
MATT: Okay. It would be easy to do with your
Gloves of Missile Snaring.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I have Gloves of Missile Snaring.
I intercept it.
SAM: Well, that was for the elf girl but all
right, sure, you can use it too. When you need it,
if you just hold that coin up, you'll turn
invisible.
TRAVIS: Seriously? An invisible-making coin?
MARISHA: No! Grog, no! Do not show satisfaction in
the things he says.
TRAVIS: This is just my gut reaction though.
MARISHA. Even if you're impressed, we pretend like
we're not. Pretend like you're not impressed.
TALIESIN: I'm not saying I can't be bought--
LIAM: You said that very loud.
SAM: Hey, big man.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
SAM: Look at this. Heavy crossbow!
TRAVIS: It's the most amazing thing!
MARISHA: Grog!
TRAVIS: I mean, hold on! Not impressed.
SAM: You can shoot it!
TRAVIS: I wanna shoot it!
(all laugh)
TRAVIS: (bvvm!)
MATT: (tsoo!)
TRAVIS: Yeah, oh shit, take it back.
MATT: You have no idea where it went, it arced way
out of your line of sight.
SAM: That was pretty good.
TRAVIS: That's cool.
SAM: Yes!
TRAVIS: He stays.
TALIESIN: Let's get the hand to its final
destination.
LAURA: Ugh!
TRAVIS: Or you can kill him and take the weapon
later.
LAURA: I will.
LIAM: He's slow. None of the rest of us like you,
so fucking watch it, all right?
LAURA: We're such dicks!
SAM: And with that we embarked on our new
adventure! The adventures of, what was it again?
TALIESIN: (sighs)
LIAM: What a dillweed!
SAM: This is going to be fun, fun, fun!
(all laugh)
MATT: As you walk into the Debt's Respite Tavern,
we're gonna end tonight's session there and pick
this up next week.
(all cheer, groan, yell)
LIAM: You break our hearts and then pull that
asshole out?
LAURA: You asshole! How dare you? How dare you?
TALIESIN: Unbelievable!
MATT: Oh, it's beautiful.
LAURA: I am so angry at you!
MARISHA: You were on the Critical Role wikia last
night weren't you?
TRAVIS: Tary berry.
TALIESIN: Yes, he was, he has it all--
SAM: Tary Darrington.
LIAM: You ain't know all our characters' mothers'
names, you motherfucker.
SAM: I know all of your parents' names.
LIAM: After Googling that shit!
SAM: Because I love you!
LAURA: Whatever!
SAM: I love you so much!
LAURA: Sam you're the least-- you don't care about
any of it!
SAM: I am the most sincere!
LAURA: You're a dick!
TRAVIS: That was amazing.
LIAM: It was amazing, it was amazing.
TALIESIN: I love that-- I wish that everyone could
see that the crew is in
utter revolt behind us right now.
MARISHA: Yes! Get him! Get him!
TALIESIN: And they've all got nerf guns!
LAURA: Get him! Get him! He deserves it!
LIAM and TALIESIN: You're tearing this family
apart!
SAM: No, I'm Tary-ing this-- Tarying this--
MATT: Tary-ing this family apart, oh my god!
(all laugh)
MATT: Thank you Loot Crate for sponsoring us.
You guys are awesome. Much love to you guys,
have a wonderful week. We'll see you soon.
Is it Thursday yet?
TALIESIN: Big hand for Sam Riegel, holy shit!
[ART]