LIAM: Hello there! And welcome to an episode of
Critical Role!
(cheering)
LIAM: Where a bunch of us-- man, that was good,
that was like a wall of sound and every note of it
was foul and disgusting. Welcome to the show where
a bunch of us nerdy-ass voice actors sit around
and play Dungeons and Dragons.
(cheering)
LIAM: Yeah, things don't look like they
normally do-- for us either, Matt's over there!
He's sitting right there!
MATT: It's very weird from this perspective.
LIAM: You look so little, over there.
MATT: Yeah!
LIAM: Yeah?
MATT: You look about the same size to me.
LIAM: Oh. Well, we have a shit-ton of
announcements. I'm really excited to be a
jackass. So let's get through them! First of all,
thank you everybody for the survey. 44,700 of you
answered, and we can't thank you enough. Yeah.
We're hoping to have something fun for you guys
soon because of it, so really, thank you for
taking the time to do it. And we will take that
data, and I will eat it. Merch! I'm going to throw
it to Laura, because that's what you do, you throw
merch to Laura.
LAURA: (muffled) Hi. I'm eating a piece of pizza.
We have merch in the store. We're all out of dice,
but yo, we've got the t-shirts, we got some hats,
we got patches and vinyl stickers. We got all
sorts of shit.
TRAVIS: See, our store go hard.
LAURA: Go to the store!
LIAM: Pop some tags.
LAURA: I know it's 4/20, the store kind of looks
like a weed dispensary. But it's not. It's a
straight-up Geek and Sundry store.
TRAVIS: We should look into Critical Role
cannabis.
SAM: Oh, that'd be so good.
MARISHA: Weed and Sundry.
LAURA: Oh! That's good.
ASHLEY: That'd be pretty tight.
LAURA and MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: We're getting fired.
MARISHA: Everyone knows it's true. Everyone
in this building knows it's true.
MATT: We just lost Jeff Sessions as a fan. Sorry,
Jeff.
LIAM: Is that available as merch, by the way?
SAM: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Just see me out back.
TRAVIS: Cash me outside.
(laughter)
MATT: Oh no.
LIAM: Oh god, how do you herd seven cats?
MATT: I don't know! How do you do it, Liam?
LIAM: I don't know how.
(laughter)
LIAM: Hey, Taliesin, tell us about this Wednesday
Club thing you do.
TALIESIN: Oh yeah. This week on Wednesday Club, we
thought it would be fun to delve into manga!
That's right, there's a new camera here, that's
crazy.
LAURA: Oh wait, no, I was looking at the wrong one
because it's so bright.
TALIESIN: I know.
LAURA: That's the one we're looking at.
SAM: Yeah, we'll have to flag that off, probably.
TALIESIN: Yeah, it's like the HAL 9000.
LIAM: And the cameras feel like eavesdroppers.
TRAVIS: It's fine. You're a baby.
MARISHA: We can turn it down more. Can we tilt
down this red light more? So it's not in their
eyes? Okay. Keep going.
TALIESIN: We're going to be talking about manga.
It's going to be a lot of fun. Join us, we may have
a guest, we may not, I'm not entirely sure. I've
just been so delighted by this, I've ignored
everything else in my life. Wednesdays at noon on
this very channel, where you are right now. Come
check it out.
MARISHA: Woot.
LAURA: Woot!
LIAM: On to you for Signal Boost?
MARISHA: Angie Hill was on this week. Holy shit.
She's a badass MMA fighter who always shows up to
her weigh-ins in cosplay. She's dope.
MATT: Yeah, she showed up as Dhalsim to a weigh-in.
It was like the best thing ever. It was amazing.
MARISHA: She's rad.
MATT: Like a very accurate outfit.
MARISHA: Yeah, she came out, she drove up from San
Diego, yeah. She's cool. So she was on the show.
And guess who's up next week?
TRAVIS: What, high school awkward pose?
SAM: Marisha Ray?
LAURA: Is that you?
MARISHA: No. Liam O'Brien.
LAURA: Oh, okay.
ASHLEY: Liam O'Brien!
MARISHA: That guy!
SAM: He's taking over all the shows.
LIAM: Yep. Yes, I'm doing Wednesday Club. I'm the
President of Nerdist as well!
TALIESIN: Liam and Sundry.
LAURA: (laughs) Liam and Sundry.
LIAM: Hey, also, Marisha, Taliesin, and Matthew
here, are going to Momocon! For my birthday
weekend, on May 25th through 28th. I won't be
here.
LAURA: Hey. We share that birthday weekend, don't
just call it yours.
LIAM: (whispers) I'm sitting in the chair, Laura.
(laughter)
LIAM: Okay, so go see them if you're in the
vicinity of Atlanta, Georgia. Also, I think this
is the time for you to give us an announcement
about a project you're working on?
LAURA: So, it just got announced! A new game that
I'm working on called Farpoint! Got a story
trailer for it, it's a VR game for Sony
PlayStation VR, it's totally cool. I tweeted out
the story trailers, if you want to go check it
out. It looks super awesome, and it was so fun to
work on, and the story was really awesome too. And
then last week, we released a cinematic trailer
for Uncharted: The Lost Legacy! And got a release
date for it, which is August 22nd, which I'm very
excited about, as well!
TRAVIS: Air punch it.
LAURA: Woo woo!
LIAM: Boy, everybody feels really 12 tonight.
That's good! That's perfect. Also, Talks Machina
is live on Tuesday nights. 7PM on Twitch. Don't
forget to submit your gif and fanart of the week,
use TalksMachina@gmail.com. Matt, you had
something you wanted to throw out?
MATT: Yeah, when we did the charity drive, where
we played Mansions of Madness, about a month or so
ago, one of the things that I said off-the-cuff
was that if we got a certain point, a certain
donation list, I'd do a two-hour hangout Q and A,
and then Brian Foster said that if we make even
more, he'll do it in a silk robe. Well we hit both
those goals, we finally scheduled it. I know,
yeah, yeah you get to talk to him about that
today.
ASHLEY: He has so many silk robes, so it's fine.
MATT: (laughs) Oh, I ordered one. It's awful. It's
going to be great.
LAURA: Is it purple? Tell me it's purple.
MATT: It's red. It's bright red.
LAURA: Ooh, nice.
MATT: It's heinous. But, next Tuesday, from 4 to
6PM, here on the Twitch channel, it's going to be
a date with me and the chat. For two hours.
MARISHA: It's going to be awesome.
MATT: I'm going to have wine, and a nice robe, and
it's going to be kind of like--
MARISHA: We're going to have dinner-- no, he's
going to have dinner in like POV.
MATT: Yeah, we're going to figure that out. I'm
hoping to do that. What was the Christopher Walken
character? With the wine?
SAM: Oh, the Continental?
MATT: I'm hoping it's something like that. It's
kind of what I'm going for. But anyway, during
that time also, I'm going to finally make up on
those promises even on an older charity, where I'm
going to work with the chat to create an NPC for
Critical Role and create a possible future
encounter.
SAM: So we should watch that so we know--
MATT: (sings) You should not watch that at all,
you guys are banned from it or I'll kill your
character.
(laughter)
MATT: That's next Tuesday, at 4 to 6PM Pacific
here on Twitch. Thank you, Liam.
MARISHA: So, it's going to be you and then Talks
at 7PM?
MATT: And then Talks at 7PM, yeah, so it's going
to be a nice little transition.
LIAM: Almost through these. There is also going to
be a new Tabletop promo airing during the break
that we're pretty stoked about, so don't walk off
and pee immediately. And then lastly, I need to do
a couple of thank-yous. You guys have been seeing
them all week. These miniatures here. I have two
people or organisations that I want to thank. One
is heroforge.com. If you haven't already heard of
Hero Forge, you can go to heroforge.com and design
and tweak a miniature just the way you want. You
make it tall, you make it short, you can make them
an elf, you can make them a human, you can give
them guns, you can give them a sword, and then
they 3D print that shit, and they mail it to you.
And that's what happened with all these guys, they
recreated my lovely dork friends as miniatures.
I'm very happy with them. And I want to thank
Emerald Knights Comics and Games. They're a local
comic shop and game shop that Matt and I frequent,
at least just you and me, and they're @ekcomics on
Twitter. I will tweet all this stuff out, either
later tonight or tomorrow. But I wanted to mention
these things. Matt and I get asked about these a
lot, and they've been a part of our campaign since
pretty much the beginning. I just associate them
with Dungeons and Dragons. But they're hard to
come by, and everyone's always asking where we get
them. And Julian Rodriguez at Emerald Knights.
Well, first of all, Julian painted these for me,
so thank you Julian, they're beautiful. And Julian
and Emerald Knights are responsible for these
things. They've been out of stock for a while.
They're going to be back in stock in May, and
you'll be able to find them probably in your local
store, but if not, on the Paizo webstore. I've
been asked a hundred times about thesel
LAURA: How do you spell Paizo?
MATT: P-A-I-Z-O.com.
LIAM: Thank you.
TRAVIS: I have a question about those, are they
edible like the ones in Fraggle Rock?
LAURA: (gasps) Are they made out of radishes?
LIAM: If you try hard enough.
TRAVIS: I have wanted to eat those my entire
life.
MATT: Oh yeah, dude. Dude, those structures are
legit!
ASHLEY: I forgot about those!
LIAM: So you might have a half-elf ranger in your
party who is obsessed and will do anything and
everything to fucking fly. Boom. Done. There you
go.
MARISHA: Okay, because when I bought those for
you, way before we even thought about having a
show, back when we very first started dating, I'm
pretty sure they just custom-made those. Julian
custom-made those himself and just sold them.
MATT: And just sold them in a box in the store.
MARISHA: And now, I think, because--
MATT: Like, the whole internet explosion in media,
D&amp;D.
MARISHA: Yeah, they're starting to make them on
mass scale.
LIAM: They will be readily available in May, and
I'll make sure to update Critters as that happens,
so thank you. Thank you Hero Forge, and thank you
Emerald Knights. Gorgeous. Boink.
SAM: I have something to say, Liam.
LIAM: (whispers) Let's hear it.
SAM: I don't have an announcement, and neither
does Ashley. So Ashley, how you doing?
ASHLEY: I'm great, how are you?
SAM: I'm pretty good.
ASHLEY: You know, just, second week in a row, just
here.
LAURA: Just to hang out.
MATT: Yeah. Got more coming?
ASHLEY: Yeah.
MATT: Yeah? You going to be here a while?
(cheering)
LIAM: With so much new information to process.
Well. God, I don't know what I'm doing. Let's play
the game, all right?
(cheering)
LIAM: And dive into a little Critical Role.
[dramatic music]
LIAM: It was good. It was weaker than the first
attempt.
MATT: You know, this is my first chance to
actually do this to you, and I keep getting
completely swarmed by everyone else, so it's
good.
LIAM: Well, they're all pros.
TRAVIS (laughs) The uncertainty.
LIAM: Pee pockets? Is that what I heard?
MATT: Not from me.
LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: No. I had a good one.
LIAM: Sam! Let's you and I talk for a moment.
SAM: (gasps) Does everyone else need to leave?
LAURA: No. Do not make us get up right at the
beginning.
LIAM: You.
SAM: Sam Riegel.
LIAM: Are dreaming. You are seeing visions that
make very little sense to you. You're at work,
back in one of the countless recording studios
you're in week after week. No biggie. Only the
dream all goes to shit. You see colleagues torn to
pieces. A massive serpent's tail. A great and
terrible god creature looming over you for an
instant, and then gone. A dog. An angel. A
comedian's corpse. And a tower. And at a certain
point, you come to realise that you are in fact
dreaming. Within the dream. You are in that
in-between moment, aware that what you're seeing
isn't real, but you don't want to wake up yet.
Grasping at slumber still. But uncomfortable.
Something is pressing into your back, a little
painfully. The dream fades,
and you try to hold on to--
SAM: It's not a dick, Laura.
LIAM: It is, in fact, my dick.
(laughter)
LIAM: The dream fades. You try to hold onto your
sleep state, but that pain in your back-- which is
definitely not my dick-- and the humidity. You
feel sweaty. You become aware of how hot and
sticky the air is you're breathing. Finally, as
your eyes flutter open, you squint just a little
bit against sunlight shining down through a thick
tree cover. You're in a jungle. There it is. Then
you're trying to figure out if you're lying inside of
what looks like a massive, hollowed-out tree
trunk, for a second? But no. Out of place with the
rest of the dark, mottled, reddish-brown tree
cover far above are four rusted, vine-entangled
beams rising up around you. You're in the middle
of what seems to be a square, dead-center, with
these four metal beams stretching and ending in
the air. But they're not bare; they're wrapped
around with plant life and vines, and there's
vines hanging from beam to beam, and it's almost
like you're in a canopy bed with no top, covered
with green. Also, scattered around, you see a few
lumps of knotted wood here and there. Or maybe
gourds? You don't know. Oh, your vision doubles
for a second, and you feel a strange pulling
sensation on your eyeballs, your head, as the air
almost seems to pulse for a minute. You feel a
brief wave of nausea, but then it passes. Oh shit,
your back hurts. The next thing you notice is what
you're lying in. You see what looks like a large--
all around you, unfurled, rind, or petals of some
sort of plant. You are in a plant. And there's a
large hump of brownish-red plant matter rising
from the center of this thing, and there's small
little tendrils climbing up around your leg.
They're not moving, but they are roped and snaked
around your legs. You give a little tug, and you
are held in place. And the other thing you see are
two sleeping little kids.
SAM: Oh. That's nice.
LIAM: They're in the same predicament. There's
little tiny miniature vines, almost, whitish
color, coming out of the center of this
reddish-brown plant holding them.
SAM: Are they my kids?
LIAM: They're not your kids.
SAM: Oh, thank god.
(laughter)
MATT: Fuck them, they can die.
MARISHA: Yeah. They're not my kids.
SAM: First of all, I appreciate you making this
all about me, as it should be.
TRAVIS: Number one on the call sheet.
SAM: I'm going to try to stand up. Is that a thing
I can try to do?
LIAM: You can certainly try.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: The first one!
ASHLEY: Yeah.
LAURA: How's it feel, Matt?
MATT: It's great.
(laughter)
LIAM: You did this!
MATT: You're doing good! Keep going!
LIAM: What do you want to do there, buddy?
SAM: Can I sit up in my weird four-poster?
LIAM: You are able to sit up. Your legs can't
move, but you sit up, and the pain finally--
whatever was poking you in the back is not--
SAM: Well, I'm looking, what was poking me in the
back?
LIAM: Ooh, there's a really small canine
skeleton.
SAM: (gasps) Bixby! Did he have a collar or
anything that I could identify?
LIAM: I mean, the bone is bleached white.
SAM: Is it about the same size as little Bix?
LIAM: Pug-sized?
SAM: Yeah.
LIAM: Kind of.
LAURA: Liam O'Brien killed a pug!
[no audio]
SAM: How far are the children from me?
LIAM: I mean, you could probably reach one of them
if you wanted to. You could reach both of them.
There's a girl and a boy. The girl looks, I don't
know, ten or 11. The boy's younger.
SAM: Are they asleep? Do they look like they're
alive and asleep?
LIAM: They're breathing.
SAM: Okay, I'm going to try to stir one of them,
whoever's closest.
LIAM: Which one?
SAM: Who's closer?
LIAM: They're both equidistant.
SAM: The older one.
LIAM: Oh.
SAM: The girl, right?
LIAM: Okay, yeah. Laura, you feel like a poke,
poke, poke at your legs.
LAURA: I knew it! Ow.
LIAM: Your eyes flutter awake, and you see a
really fucking bizarre jungle and some little kid
poking at your foot.
SAM: Wait, I'm a kid? (whispers) Oh, we're kids!
Muppet Babies!
MATT: (sings) Crit Role Babies, it's time to play
some shit.
LIAM: The little blond angelic boy sleeps
peacefully as you guys whisper to each other.
SAM: There's a little blond boy?
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: Wait, who are you?
SAM: I'm Sam!
LAURA: You're Sam?
SAM: Do we know each other?
LIAM: You just fought dead Conan O'Brien.
SAM: Do I recognize her?
LIAM: Kind of?
LAURA: Sam?
SAM: Sam Riegel! TV's Sam Riegel!
LAURA: Sam, you're a kid! What are you talking
about?
TRAVIS: You're that kid from Les Mis!
(laughter)
SAM: Who are you?
LAURA: Your face is smaller but your teeth are the
same size!
(laughter)
SAM: Who are you?
LAURA: I'm Laura!
SAM: You're too fat to be Laura!
(laughter)
LIAM: Taliesin, you're stirred awake by the sound
of children's voices arguing over your body.
LAURA: You dick. Wait, who is that?
SAM: Well, that's Taliesin.
(laughter)
LAURA: Oh, it's that kid from that commercial.
SAM: Yeah, I saw him in Mr. Mom. He looks the
same.
LIAM: He does, if either of you have seen Mr Mom,
he does look precisely like he did in Mr. Mom.
TALIESIN: It's basically Butters Stotch. I'm
screwed.
MARISHA: You totally were!
MATT: You were Butters Stotch!
TALIESIN: You're figuring that out now?
LIAM: Just for your benefit, and for the audience,
we're going to be hearing all of the usual
Taliesin verbiage and sayings, like "okay" and
"this is going to be fun," except please imagine
it in a small, piping widdle voice.
TALIESIN: Can I have a moment to myself?
(laughter)
LIAM: He's still Executive Goth. He's just
seven-ish.
LAURA: We're children! What the fuck happened?
SAM: We were just fighting Conan, we beat him.
TALIESIN: Sam?!
SAM: Yeah, hi. I know, my teeth are really big. I
haven't gotten any work done.
TALIESIN: No, I've YouTubed you. This makes sense.
What, and--
LAURA: Hi.
TALIESIN: Laura!
LAURA: Yeah!
TALIESIN: Where's everybody else?
LAURA: I don't know! Where's Bixby?
SAM: I'm going to pull out the skull. Huh?
LIAM: That's too big.
LAURA: But he's a kid!
SAM: Oh yeah! Little hands.
LIAM: Oh, bring it back up!
(laughter)
LAURA: Wait, how old are we? We don't know.
LIAM: You don't know. You're older than both of
them.
LAURA: Fuck yeah, I am. I'm so in charge.
SAM: I think the dog died, when we got younger
somehow.
LAURA: This is so weird. Where's Travis? (gasps)
SAM: Oh gosh.
LAURA: Oh god, what if he's still an adult? This
is so weird!
(laughter)
LIAM: You guys don't see anything. You are,
again-- you saw this, and you guys are just coming
to and noticing your surroundings. You're in this
square, which doesn't make sense, because you're
in the jungle, right? But you're in this square
canopy plant room, almost.
LAURA: How the fuck do we get out of here?
SAM: Here, hold my hand, and we'll pull each other
and try to pull each other up and out of here.
TALIESIN: Okay. I'm grabbing it.
SAM: We'll all make a weird kid triangle.
LAURA: And try to pull towards each other.
LIAM: Everybody make a strength check with
advantage.
LAURA: Wait, what do we add to it?
LIAM: Nothing.
SAM: I got an 11.
LAURA: Ooh! I'm so much older than them. I got an
18.
TALIESIN: I got a two-- ten.
LIAM: A two ten?
TALIESIN: I got a ten.
LIAM: A ten. Okay. All right. Well, the little
blond kid, barely able to rip any of the plant
away from his feet, but this bigger kid grabs you
both and pulls both of you out, and it just rips
away. It's not too bad, with you guys working
together. And now you're standing, the three of
you, in a little circle, standing in this little
chapel in the jungle.
LAURA: What do we do?
SAM: We've got to look for our friends and figure
out what the hell's going on.
LAURA: Yeah.
SAM: And last thing I remember, we were doing a
voiceover session
and all hell broke loose, right?
LAURA: Yeah!
TALIESIN:There was Conan O'Brien!
LAURA: And we fought him, and we killed him.
SAM: Yeah.
LAURA: And you almost killed Travis!
SAM: He cut my arm off!
LAURA: Where's Travis?
LIAM: The air around you hits you with
another (whump), and you feel your skin and bones
kind of shake a little bit, and your stomach just
feels like it drops. The feeling passes.
SAM: I let go of her hand, because girls are
icky.
LAURA: Was that a time shift? Did we just shift
through time? Are we older?
TALIESIN: Looking around, we're still in that
cube, right?
LIAM: Yeah, again, you can see out. These metal
beams going up that lead to nothing, and are just
sort of mangled.
LAURA: Wait, give me a boost, I'm going to climb
up the beam.
LIAM: Okay.
LAURA: I'm going to try to climb up the beam,
because it's covered in vines, right? I can grab
on to something.
LIAM: Absolutely.
LAURA: Okay. I'm going to try to climb up to the
top.
SAM: Okay, we'll help.
LIAM: Make an athletics check.
LAURA: Do I add anything to it?
LIAM: Add two. I'm making that up.
LAURA: 15!
LIAM: Yeah, totally! You climb your way up there.
It takes you, like, a minute? You don't want to
fall down, you don't want to cut yourself on this
rusty beam. You make your way up, and you grab
onto the twisted top of this beam. It's all caked
over with plant, and a little bit of mud, even,
but you can see where there used to be bolts, sort
of sprung open on the top. And you pull yourself
up and over. No, that's better. And you can
finally see out and over and the jungle stretches
out in every direction. You can see here and
there, on other trees-- and when I say trees, the
trees are more brown and red than anything, and
they're wet, and they have sort of a bulging
sausage feel to them? And they do have leaves, but
the leaves are, again, mottled brown and red. And
the whole jungle you're in, sunlight does come
down and in, but it's pretty dim overall, and
everything is tinted with that color. And you see
these lumps of hardened, what look like-- they
don't have the texture of coconuts. They have the
texture of a chestnut, maybe. But they're just
growing out of spots on trees. Some are hanging
from a vine on different trees. And you can't see
where to go. Everything looks the same in
different directions, although it is more open
from this view, because down below, between these
four beams, it's all wrapped around. And you see
two little kids going like this.
LAURA: And I don't see any other sign of life?
LIAM: Make a perception check.
LAURA: Do I add anything?
LIAM: Add a Laura Bailey plus three.
LAURA: 18.
LIAM: Oh wow. Yeah. About a hundred feet that way,
you see another opened plant on the ground. It's
obscured by a tree, but you can see it behind the
tree. And you see a jean leg and a sneaker, and it
looks bent badly and bloodied. And then you see
another leg with a shoe, poking out the other side
of the tree.
LAURA: (gasps) Well, I climb down and I say, I saw
a body, and we should go find it!
SAM: Okay, let's go.
TALIESIN: Contention point, are we wearing kid
clothes? Are we wearing kid clothes or tiny
versions of our old clothes?
LIAM: You're wearing clothes that seems to fit.
TALIESIN: Okay. Just checking.
LIAM: This is science.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Kind of curious.
SAM: All right, let's go!
TALIESIN: All right.
SAM: But wait! We don't know anything about where
we are, so we should look and stealth, maybe? And
sneak over there?
LAURA: Sure!
SAM: So as not to awaken a beast?
LAURA: Yeah, but we should get over there quickly,
because that's Travis!
SAM: Okay! Oh, you know? Okay!
LAURA: It should be. I think it's Travis!
SAM: Let's go!
LIAM: All right, so after you scuttle down and
have this little mini child argument. It's not too
hard, I mean, you just pull apart vines and
plants, and you can push your way through.
LAURA: Be careful of the bulging sausages!
LIAM: Everything is slick to the touch, and you
grease by it all--
LAURA: Of the wet, bulging sausages!
TALIESIN: I think that's sound advice.
LIAM: Hashtag. Are you stealthing there?
LAURA: Yeah, yeah, we're sneaking.
LIAM: Well make a stealth check, motherfuckers.
SAM: 13.
LAURA: Oh. What do we add? Ooh, that's good.
TALIESIN: 19.
LAURA: That's a pretty die.
TALIESIN: Thank you. Yeah, it's nice.
LIAM: Laura.
LAURA: Seven.
LIAM: Seven. Okay. She's a little bigger. She
tromps round a little more than you little
light-footed--
LAURA: Plus I'm really worried.
LIAM: Yep, got to get to your adult husband,
waiting on the other side of this tree. All right, so
you creep along. There's insects, and you can hear
stuff out there, but nothing happens, nothing
shocking or scary, and you make your way, in just a
couple of minutes, over to where this plant is,
and you come around the tree, and you see three
kids. One kid is really dead. What you couldn't
see on the back of the tree that was blocking the
view, has splintered off and fallen on a child,
and that child is crushed like the Wicked Witch of
the West's sister. All you see is one mangled leg
coming out the bottom and an arm coming out the
other side.
MATT: It'll be me, so I don't get a chance to
play.
(laughter)
MATT: Sorry.
MARISHA: Thanks for coming.
LIAM: And a little bit of spaghetti marinara. But
you also see two kids in here. There is another
older girl, looks a little older than you, brown
hair, dark hair, and there's a kid that looks like
Vern from Stand By Me. He's a little chunky kid in
a polo shirt, and he is snoring, now that you're
closer and you can hear.
LAURA: Does it look like I would know what Travis
looked like when he was a kid?
LIAM: Yeah, you know what your husband looks like.
You know what the child version of your husband
looks like, and that's your BFF, Ashley, except
she looks like a rebel in middle school.
(laughter)
LIAM: And they're sound asleep, and Verno is just
(snores).
LAURA: (gasps) Travis! And I go slap him awake.
How old is he? How old are you? Do I look older
than you?
LIAM: You're in your 30s, right?
TRAVIS: Yeah!
(laughter)
LAURA: Oh wait. You-- no, you're still a kid,
you're a kid too.
TRAVIS: Oh. (higher) Yeah.
LAURA: Baby!
TRAVIS: Who are you?
LAURA: You know what I look like when I'm a kid,
man! I'm your wife! You're my husband.
LIAM: He's taking this really well that you're
both children.
TRAVIS: Why are my hands so small? Why do I look
like Vern from Stand By Me? Where is this gross
polo coming from? And my tiny 80s shorts?
LAURA: You know you wore shit like that, don't
even.
TRAVIS: Why are my socks all the way up to
the bottom of my knees?
(laughter)
LIAM: That is canon!
TRAVIS: Why do these shoes have velcro straps on
them?
LIAM: Ashley, you're shaken awake, and you're
looking at a bunch of fucking children around you,
and you're in a jungle, and everything is wet!
LAURA: Ashley?
ASHLEY: What's going on? How do you know my name?
LAURA: Ashley, it's us.
ASHLEY: Who is us?
SAM: That's Laura and Travis.
TRAVIS: Why are you calling her Ashley?
TALIESIN and LAURA: And Taliesin!
SAM: From I Shot The Sheriff's Mom or whatever it
was?
TALIESIN: She's the Sheriff. Did you not watch
television as a child? Good god.
ASHLEY: Butters Scotch.
(laughter)
LIAM: Ashley, the last thing you remember is
falling asleep watching a movie on a plane from
New York City to LA.
ASHLEY: I was on a plane! I fell asleep and now
I'm here! I was watching-- what was I watching?
TRAVIS: What were you watching?
ASHLEY: Moana.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: So good.
LAURA: It was really good!
ASHLEY: And now we're here. Oh, man, this is
weird.
LIAM: Your voice is a little higher than you're
accustomed to.
ASHLEY: Why is my voice higher than it usually
is?
LAURA: Because you're a kid! You're like you in
What Women Want.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: How old am I?
LIAM: I don't know. You're a little older than
this one. You're much bigger than these two.
You're a little bigger than this one.
MARISHA: So maybe What Women Want?
LAURA: No, younger than that.
MARISHA: Oh, Annie era?
MATT: We'll just go through your imdb and just
pick the right time.
MARISHA: Just google Ashley real quick, hang on.
LIAM: She's probably brushing into her teens.
MATT: Okay.
ASHLEY: So it's punk Ashley.
TRAVIS: (voice breaking) Should all of our voices,
like, be--
SAM: Yeah, let's do that for the next three
hours.
ASHLEY: Okay! What have you guys seen so far?
LIAM: The air around you trembles, and you feel
that same push of energy and your skull seems to
rattle, and your gut goes (noise) and you feel
yourself pushing-- nothing happens.
LAURA: I run over to the other body, and see what
kid it was. Do I recognize him?
LIAM: I mean, if you could do a backwards time
lapse of the skull being crushed down into the
ground by the tree, you might know.
LAURA: I hope this isn't anybody we knew.
ASHLEY: Can we tell if boy or girl?
LIAM: You don't know. What do you want to do?
MARISHA: Are you Bones?
TRAVIS: Are there any pockets that aren't covered
in--
LIAM: It's not bones, it's just all that's poking
out is a leg and spaghetti marinara from where a
head was, and--
LAURA: And it's a kid body?
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: That's fucked.
TRAVIS: Can I search the kid's pockets?
LIAM: Sure.
TALIESIN: I'll help. Yeah.
LIAM: (whispers) You kind of feel a wiener through
the pocket.
LAURA: Oh.
LIAM: (whispers) Kind of.
ASHLEY: What is it? Anything in the pocket?
TRAVIS: Is there anything in the pocket?
LIAM: Just the wiener.
TRAVIS: Just a little-- nope! Not a thing!
Nothing.
SAM: You touched a wiener?
LIAM: You guys all hear, now, off in the distance,
a whumping sound, just like (thudding)
way far away.
LAURA: Do we have our weapons from before?
TALIESIN: We don't have anything from before.
SAM: Find sticks!
LAURA: We've got to find some sticks! Everybody
get a stick!
SAM: We're going to look for sticks and rocks.
LIAM: Okay. Sure, they're everywhere.
ASHLEY: Can I get a strong vine?
LIAM: Yes. Make a strength check real quick.
You've got to pull it off of a tree.
ASHLEY: Do I add anything?
LIAM: You can add one.
ASHLEY: 19.
LIAM: 19. Oh man! You snap it, and as soon as
you do, the break point goes (raspberry) and you
look like you just got sprayed in the face with
horror-movie blood, your face just went
(raspberry) as soon as you did it. It burst like
an angry zit as soon as you broke it, but now
you're holding this mostly solid, but with a
little bit of give, and slick as hell.
ASHLEY: Do I look scary?
LAURA: Yes, you do!
TRAVIS: (cries)
ASHLEY: Oh no! Hey, don't cry!
LAURA: Don't cry.
ASHLEY: Don't cry, it's okay.
TRAVIS: I haven't seen an R-rated movie at this
point. (cries)
(laughter)
LIAM: You are still you.
TRAVIS: I know, I ran out of Jurassic Park in the
theater!
LIAM: I mean it's accurate. You're really scared
of scary movies.
TRAVIS: Yeah I seriously am. (cries)
LAURA: We're still adults, Travis. We're just in
kid bodies.
TRAVIS: I don't feel adult.
LIAM: Boom, boom.
SAM; Wait, we're hearing things.
LIAM: Boom.
LAURA: (gasps) I grab a rock.
TALIESIN: I grab a stick.
LIAM: Okay.
TALIESIN: We hide.
LAURA: And hide behind anything that we-- I hide
hide under one of the petals
of one of the flowers.
LIAM: Okay. Smells really nasty. You're under it.
And it is wet. And now your shirt is wet, and your
pants are wet.
LAURA: I'm in a dress.
(laughter)
LAURA: But whatever.
SAM: A wet dress.
LAURA: Do you guys see it? Are we hiding? Are all
of us hiding?
TALIESIN: Does this stuff have a planty smell, or
kind of a meaty smell?
LIAM: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Is it a bit of a meaty smell?
TALIESIN: Oh no.
LIAM: You ever smell that flower that's like the
world's worst?
TALIESIN:Yes, I have. The Centennial flower.
LIAM: That.
LAURA:Yeah, smells like a dead body.
LIAM: But that sound's not getting any closer.
It's off in the distance. It's intermittent.
LAURA: Oh. Should I come out?
SAM: Yeah. You just got all wet and muddy, and
now--
LAURA: Man. Should we find Matt and Marisha,
because they were with us too? Are they the ones
that got us here?
SAM: Were they with us? They just appeared out of
nowhere and then disappeared.
TRAVIS: Yeah, they were on that awesome
motorcycle.
LAURA: Oh yeah, they saved the day. They killed
Conan, didn't they?
SAM: They did, but they looked super scary.
LIAM: The five of you hear a snapping sound, kind
of like when Ashley broke that vine, and you hear
(thud) ten feet behind you. And then you hear
smearing, rustling sounds, and then you hear
(cat-like growl).
LAURA: I turn around and throw my rock at it!
LIAM: Okay. Roll for initiative.
(laughter)
SAM: Surprise attack. We're all rolling for
initiative?
LIAM: I guess so.
MARISHA: Oh snap.
TALIESIN: Quick game.
SAM: Seven!
LIAM: Seven.
TALIESIN: Ten.
LAURA: Nine.
TRAVIS: 11.
LIAM: Wait, slow down, assholes. 20 to 25? Nobody.
15 to 20? Ten to 15?
TRAVIS: Me, 11.
LIAM: Okay.
TALIESIN: Ten, Taliesin.
LIAM: Ten?
ASHLEY: Ten, Ashley.
LIAM: Ten, Ashley. Laura and Sam?
LAURA: Nine.
SAM: Seven.
LIAM: Nine. Seven. Okay. All right. You flip
around and see what looks like, I don't know, like
a really pissed off ocelot, or bobcat with no skin
on it. You just see greased red muscle and blood,
and the thing is running at you, and Travis, it's
coming at you, and you act!
LAURA: Don't I get that attack? Because I threw a
rock.
LIAM: Nah.
(laughter)
LAURA: You'd argue so hard for that if you were
over on this side, man, you would've argued so hard
for it.
LIAM: Yeah, maybe.
TRAVIS: I'm, like, 11? Right? I am turning and
booking ass away from it, with my spindly little
legs, as fast as I can.
LIAM: Okay, that is heading you in the direction
of the intermittent whump far in the distance,
but that's fine.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'm just running from the naked
cat.
LIAM: So, you see a flesh-peeled-- large, the size
of a golden retriever, right, a bobcat, but with
sinew and muscle, and it looks mad as hell, and
it's running, and so is Vern. And Taliesin, what
do you do?
TALIESIN: You know, I think I'm going to run, too,
at this point. I'm going to keep this stick, but
I'm running.
LIAM: Okay.
TRAVIS: It's total Goonies run, too, it's like--
TRAVIS and TALIESIN: (yell)
(laughter)
TALIESIN: It's a full-on Goonies run.
LIAM: Okay, so, as you lift this rock to throw it
down, it happens too fast, and this thing runs and
starts clawing its way up your body, and tearing
down your wet, slick shirt, and hits you for-- it
ran right up you--
SAM: Wait, is this Laura or Taliesin?
LAURA: It's me!
LIAM: Laura, and does two hit points of damage.
Just remember that for the time being, please.
LAURA: Okay.
TRAVIS: We haven't even opened anything.
LAURA: We still haven't opened our things!
LIAM: That's right.
ASHLEY: I want to know what's inside!
LIAM: Ashley, what are you going to do?
ASHLEY: Okay. I'm going to take the vine, and I'm
going to (lasso sounds).
LIAM: Okay, so you run up to your friend Laura,
who's getting mangled--
ASHLEY: Oh, so I'm close enough to run up to it?
LIAM: Sure.
ASHLEY: Okay. So I'm just going to--
LIAM: You're going to try to--
MATT: Try and garrote it.
LIAM: Okay. Sure. Roll a d20. We'll do a grapple.
ASHLEY: Do I add anything?
LIAM: You can add one. For now.
TALIESIN: You have a lasso at your house, too,
don't you?
ASHLEY: I do.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MARISHA: Ashley's proficient in all weapons.
LIAM: Seems like your number is low.
ASHLEY: It's not.
LIAM: It's not? What is it?
ASHLEY: 17.
LIAM: Okay. You get a good grip on it, and pull it
in tight; it is so smeared with blood, it goes
(squelch), flies up two feet in the air and comes
back down and then claws its way back down Laura
and just starts rending and continues to rend.
ASHLEY: Can I do anything else?
LIAM: Well, you can move. You can move a little
bit. You can get the fuck out of Dodge.
ASHLEY: No, I don't want to leave her!
LIAM: Sam. What are you doing?
SAM: Any rocks around? Big rocks?
LIAM: Yeah, a couple by your feet. If you reach
down and grab them.
SAM: I'm going to grab one and just hit it in the
skull.
LIAM: Hit it in the skull? Roll to attack.
SAM: Okay. Nine.
LIAM: Nine.
(laughter)
LIAM: You are not used to being as short as you
are, and you totally swing and it goes over the
thing's head, and you slip in some guts from that
kid's head, and you go down.
LAURA: Do I get to go?
SAM: Oh yeah, it was her turn, actually.
LIAM: Yes, this whole game's about tormenting you,
Laura.
(laughter)
LAURA: Well.
LIAM: Go!
ASHLEY: Get it!
LAURA: Okay, I guess I'll try and hit it with the
rock while Ashley's trying to--
LIAM: Sure, go for it.
LAURA: 15!
LIAM: Oh man, that rock comes down and crunches on
this thing's head. Roll a d4, please. Oh. No.
Yeah. d4. That's right.
LAURA: Four!
LIAM: Four. You smash the thing's head in, and it
goes (squeal), and it (raspberries)
down onto the ground.
ASHLEY: Good job!
SAM: You killed it!
LAURA: Well, Ashley, you--
ASHLEY: No, I didn't do it, it slipped right out.
LAURA: Thanks, Travis and Taliesin.
TRAVIS: We're just still, like, (yells).
LIAM: Through the jungle, they are just past two
trees, and you've just lost sight of them, and
they've run off.
SAM: Come back! It's dead!
LAURA: It's dead!
LIAM: And you hear rustle-rustle-rustle, and then
you hear (thuds).
ASHLEY: Another one?
LAURA: Far away? The same place?
LIAM: Far away, same place.
SAM: We have to go after them.
ASHLEY: I'm going to grab that one by its tail and
tie it to my belt.
LIAM: Travis and Taliesin, you bust out of some
plants and you find yourself on the edge of--
SAM: Wait, you're going to tie the
animal to your belt?
LAURA: Fuck yeah!
LIAM: A different area than what you've seen
before. The tree cover is so thick that you're not
able to see this coming, but you're looking at a
reddish brown bog. It's a little more open. The
trees open up a bit, and you can see patches of
stagnant brackish water on the ground here and
there, and then way on the other side, 200 feet,
you see, almost Audrey II style, ten feet tall--
seven feet tall. That was too big. Seven feet
tall, and there is a little thin wiry bent-over
old man with a rock, and nasty clothes, tattered
and disgusting, and he's peeled one of these
petals back and he's beating on the side of it as
hard as he can, but he's very old. And he's 200
feet away.
TRAVIS: Is he doing it in a frenetic way or is he
just methodically--
LIAM: He's taking a couple whacks at it and then
pausing to rest for a second.
TRAVIS: (panting) There's a guy!
TALIESIN: Let's check it out! I'm heading over.
LIAM: You're just going to run through?
TALIESIN: I'm going to be careful where I'm
walking.
LIAM: That's fine, but you're not sneaky.
TRAVIS: You've got beautiful blond hair, you
should go.
TALIESIN: I'm not being super sneaky, no. He'll
see me coming.
LIAM: Okay. You start splashing through muck and
puddles on your way there and you make it 20 feet
out into the middle of this big circular bog and
the old man goes (croaks). And you catch a glimpse
of a reflection of light up on his face. Glasses?
He sees you, books off into
the jungle beyond it, runs.
TALIESIN: What?
TRAVIS: Oh no! Wait, don't go!
TALIESIN: I feel like we needed an adult here.
TRAVIS: I know. What was he hitting?
TALIESIN: I'm going to go check out the plant he
was hitting.
LIAM: Sure, okay. All right.
TRAVIS: While he's walking up, can I look? Can I
scan?
TALIESIN: Where are the others?
LIAM: Verno is totally poking his head out of the
heavy tree cover, looking after you. You don't
know where the others are. You are now halfway out
across this bog, mucking your way through, this
little cherubic seven year old making his way
through hell, there he goes.
TRAVIS: It's you and me.
LIAM: You sheepishly whisper across the bog.
TRAVIS: (whispers) It's you and me!
LIAM: (whispers) I've got your back! Finally you
make it over to this big semi peeled-open gourd,
and you look inside to see what's in there, and
you see a head of red hair.
Oh, she's an older girl.
TALIESIN: I start peeling that thing open and try
to pull her out.
LIAM: Make a strength check.
TRAVIS: What are you doing?
TALIESIN: It's fine! Help me!
TRAVIS: No!
TALIESIN: Natural 20.
LIAM: Natural 20! Okay, so you reach up as high up
as you can and you hang from it, and it just peels
open. And a teenager spills out, unconscious, long
red hair, flannel shirt. Unconscious.
TALIESIN: Matt, are you okay?
(laughing)
LIAM: There is another body further in. You see
just the barest glimpse of a Hawaiian shirt.
(laughing)
TRAVIS: What does the hair look like?
TALIESIN: I'm coming to get you, Liam! Hold on!
I'm going to start pulling him out, too.
TRAVIS: You're going in there?
TALIESIN: Travis, help out!
TRAVIS: Okay!
LIAM: You're pulling who? Who are you pulling?
TALIESIN: I'm pulling the Hawaiian shirt out of
there.
LIAM: You're pulling Hawaiian shirt? Well, he's
caught; his feet are caught up in the same--
TALIESIN: I'm going to start using the stick to
wedge him out.
LIAM: You're going to use a stick? All right. I'm
going to give you no advantage for that roll. A
strength check.
TALIESIN: That's fine. No advantage?
LIAM: No advantage.
TALIESIN: That's fine. Just a strength roll?
LIAM: Strength roll.
TALIESIN: Doesn't matter, it's just a d20, I
suppose. No plus? That's a one.
LIAM: Aw man, feeling so proud of yourself, so
brave, so strong, pulling that open, and now
you're just doing a little Looney Tunes. Your feet
are just scuttling in the slick wet of this swamp
and you're making no headway.
TRAVIS: Can I try to help him?
TALIESIN: Please.
LIAM: Sure, are you going to go catch up?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: All right. You hear (splashes).
TALIESIN: I give up and roll down and try to wake
Marisha up.
LIAM: Okay. Oh, you give her a slap? Marisha, you
are woken out of your sleep
getting slapped in the face.
MARISHA: I immediately grab his wrist.
LIAM: Yes, you do.
TALIESIN: Wake up, there's a lot going on!
MARISHA: Who the fuck? What is--
TALIESIN: Mr. Mom. You know exactly who I am.
MARISHA: Oh, you're from my future!
TALIESIN: Now I'm really confused. Hi.
MARISHA: Hi.
TALIESIN: It's Taliesin.
MARISHA: It's Marisha.
TALIESIN: You're a teenager.
MARISHA: (brokenly) No! Not again!
LIAM: The last thing you remember is falling
asleep, resting your head on your keyboard in your
office at Geek and Sundry.
SAM: Listening to Moana.
MARISHA: You're welcome. What? Who? Huh?
TALIESIN: I point at the Hawaiian shirt and
Travis. Are you pulling by this point? There's a
lot going on. I don't know. Help.
LIAM: Marisha, you look over and see a face very
much like one you've seen in many photographs
dressed as Sephiroth, except with glasses and a
Hawaiian shirt and just so peaceful and sweet.
Asleep.
MARISHA: Oh, it's glasses Matt! Oh my god!
TRAVIS: Does he have any facial hair?
MATT: What age is this, about?
LIAM: 12, 13, 14? 12?
MATT: Okay, so yeah, glasses, nearing a mullet.
MARISHA: Yeah, nearing mullets phase.
MATT: And it looks like a Hawaiian shirt. It's
more like a bowling shirt with a cool-looking
anime dragon on it.
LAURA: Dragon Ball Z bowling shirt!
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: Why don't you guys all open your manilla
envelopes.
(cheering)
SAM: Ooh! So cute!
(laughter)
ASHLEY: Oh my god!
TALIESIN: Oh my god.
MATT: That's straight up.
TALIESIN: Liam, that's so solid!
TRAVIS: Marisha's a badass bitch!
TALIESIN: I know exactly what picture they used
for this!
MARISHA: I'm in Kentucky at this phase!
LAURA: Ah, yeah. Aw, Hawaiian shirt Matt!
MATT: Yeah. That's about as accurate as you'll ever
get.
ASHLEY: This is the best.
MARISHA: Taliesin!
ASHLEY: Why didn't we know each other as kids?
MARISHA: You look like a Ralph Bakshi cartoon!
LAURA: You're so cute!
MATT: Oh, Travis!
TRAVIS: Just not sure of anything! My mom gave me
this shirt.
TALIESIN: That's amazing.
LIAM: Like the Grinch, my heart just grew two
sizes in my chest.
(laughing)
LIAM: A couple of minutes pass and the rest of you
catch up. You two are still-- your feet are glued
into this plant.
MARISHA: Fists, bra?
LIAM: You're glued into place and you're sizing
each other up and you can tell fairly quickly--
you don't know how old everyone is, but who the
oldest is, who the youngest is. Marisha is taller
than anyone here, clearly mid-to-late teens. Under
her, maybe Ashley, Laura and Matt kind of in the
same zone. It's hard to say between Sam and
Taliesin.
TALIESIN: I was a tiny child. I was a tiny, tiny
child.
SAM: We were theater children.
LAURA: I also was very small.
SAM: So, eight, nine-ish? Maybe?
LIAM: Yeah, ish.
MARISHA: Why are all the girls more developed? Is
this indicative of puberty? Is this a statement?
LAURA: Our mental state?
LIAM: Art is open to interpretation, Marisha.
LAURA: I'm down two hit points! I've only got
eight hit points!
LIAM: Not anymore. Oh, now you do. From ten to
eight.
LAURA: No, no, I had eight.
LIAM: You had eight and now you're at six?
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: Better be careful.
LAURA: Jeez Louise, Liam.
LIAM: You guys are in the middle of--
MARISHA: How many hit points do I have?
LIAM: It doesn't say?
MARISHA: No.
LIAM: You've got, let's say nine.
MARISHA: Nine.
LIAM: Because you're so tall.
LAURA: What do you have?
ASHLEY: 11.
LAURA: (gasps) You have a high constitution.
ASHLEY: Because I've always been a little tough as
fuck.
LIAM: Anyway. Guys, you are in the middle of a
very alien jungle. You don't know where the fuck
you are, you don't know what is going on, you
don't know why you are children. What are you
going to do? Are you going to build a house and
live here?
SAM: I guess so. Wait, are we together again?
LAURA: Did we catch up?
LIAM: Yeah, everyone is here. Is Matt sleeping?
MARISHA: Wait, is he not alive?
LAURA: He's not out of the flower yet.
MATT: I'm still inside the flower.
MARISHA: Oh, right. Okay. I'll go over and be
like, yo.
MATT: Huh? What?
MARISHA: We're kids!
ASHLEY: Hey, Matt!
MATT: I don't like this nightmare.
(laughter)
MATT: What?
MARISHA: This is real!
TRAVIS: Can I see your glasses?
MATT: Sure.
LIAM: Matt, apparently three Monster energy drinks
are not enough to keep you awake working on the
campaign book and you pass out on your desktop at
home. That's the last thing you remember. And you
were tall.
MATT: So I'm taking my glasses off, I'm like,
okay, so--
LAURA: Oh, I can still see!
MATT: What? I can't!
(laughter)
MATT: I'm going to keep-- and I look down, am I
still in this giant Audrey II-type plant?
LIAM: You can sit up, that's about it.
MATT: Oh jeez! (yells)
LAURA: Can we try to pull the flower back?
LIAM: Yeah, sure, you can pull.
MARISHA: Me and Ashley (straining noises).
LIAM: Matt, make a strength check at advantage.
MATT: They do it?
LIAM: No, just you. Because you're pushing to--
SAM and LAURA: Just Matt.
MARISHA: Oh.
MATT: She got a ten.
LIAM: Thanks, Keyleth.
MARISHA: Different universe! Different one!
MATT: That's a 19.
LIAM: That's fine. You explode out of this
motherfucker like Superman and jump and land on
your feet in the middle of the muck, full of
adrenaline, and you have no idea what to do.
MATT: That was the coolest thing I ever did at
this age, guys. I'm glad you
were here to witness it.
ASHLEY: Matt.
MATT: What?
ASHLEY: You look fucking rad.
(laughing)
MATT: Okay, that's the coolest thing to happen to
me at this age. This was not a good age, actually.
I really don't--
SAM: Something's going on. We're in a weird forest
swamp. There are weird demon dogs that are
attacking us--
LAURA: It was a cat!
SAM: Was it?
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Naked and hairless.
LAURA: It was hairless. Oh, Ashley's got it,
still.
ASHLEY: It's on my belt.
MATT: That's skinless. That's skinless!
LAURA: Yeah! Look around, we're in giant fucking
plants. We're fucked!
SAM: Yeah, everyone's freaking out and Travis has
reverted back to his behavior as a 15-year-old or
something.
LAURA: Travis has been mentally brought back to
that age as well.
SAM: We're all normal-thinking, but not Travis.
(laughter)
LIAM: It's a coping mechanism.
MATT: You spent far too long roleplaying as Grog,
and it's starting to rub off onto him.
TRAVIS: Everything's dangerous!
(laughter)
ASHLEY: You know what's really cool about this,
though? Okay, I'm going to try to explain this,
what's happening in my brain, but right now --
MARISHA: Nah, it's 420. We're cool.
ASHLEY: Okay. That's true.
MARISHA: Yeah, we're with it. Yeah.
ASHLEY: We all have friends right now. Because in
real life, when I was this age, I didn't have
friends. And now, look, we all have friends!
MARISHA: Holy shit! Guys, why didn't we know each
other when we were all this age?
TRAVIS: Because we lived in different states.
MARISHA: That sucks.
(laughter)
LAURA: There's that.
TALIESIN: A few of us were working all the time.
SAM: Yeah, I was on Broadway.
LAURA: Right.
MATT: Yeah, I didn't have friends. I helped people
with homework and then they said thank you.
TALIESIN: So nice of you.
MARISHA: I was covering for friends' drug habits,
so that's fine.
SAM: Dark.
TRAVIS: I was melting action figures.
LAURA: I was in the science club!
(laughter)
LAURA: Odyssey of the Mind!
LIAM: Somewhere in the distance you hear (angry
cat noises)
LAURA: Oh shit.
SAM: More cats.
TRAVIS: Is there a sun?
LIAM: There is. Definitely, right where you are,
because again the trees opened up, the sky's a
little dimmer than you're used to. It's got sort
of a dusk feel to it. It's darker, but it's
day-ish.
LAURA: How did they get in here? How did you get
in here?
ASHLEY: Does anybody remember anything?
LAURA: Does anybody see anything?
SAM: Yeah, I mean, we were fighting Conan O'Brien
and then we got pushed forward in time. That's all
I remember. And also, Travis tried to kill me.
MARISHA: Wait, we got pushed forward in time?
TALIESIN: Pushed in time? You guys were there!
MARISHA: We came from the future, though, right?
DM?
LIAM: Well, I'm not here.
TRAVIS: No, we saw you, you were there! You rode
in--
LIAM: You came from the Geek and Sundry offices.
TRAVIS: We saw you, you rode in on this sweet
Harley and you looked like you were from the Mad
Max time period and you were all badass. Not like
you look right now.
LAURA: Like, super badass.
MARISHA: I mean, it sounds within the realm of
something I'd do, but I don't have any--
TRAVIS: You don't have a motorcycle parked behind
the--
LAURA: You don't remember that?
MARISHA: No.
TRAVIS: Huh, okay.
MARISHA: Matt actually said I wasn't allowed to
have a motorcycle.
MATT: I did say that.
MARISHA: He's afraid I might kill myself.
SAM: Well, you will, statistically speaking.
MATT: Yeah, that's why I said no! She's supposed
to live a long time.
ASHLEY: Did we actually get together for dinner?
And then we just took drugs for some reason?
SAM: No.
TRAVIS: No?
LAURA: We were recording and then we fought Conan
O'Brien--
MATT: Guys! Scary creature animal sound--
SAM: We need weapons, we need somewhere to go.
LAURA: Did you see anything--
TRAVIS: Nope!
ASHLEY: The rock seemed to do well.
TALIESIN: There was that booming sound earlier.
MATT: Can I search around? I want to see if
there's anything that could be possibly used as a
weapon.
LIAM: Absolutely you can.
MARISHA: Did you sound like that at that age? Were
you always--
MATT: What, an obnoxious annoying kid? Yeah,
totally!
LIAM: There is no shortage of vines and trees and
rocks. If anyone wants to look for something, if
you want to break it off a tree, they'll be
stronger if you break it right off a tree
probably, but they're around.
MARISHA: I'm going to try and break off a sweet
staff from a tree branch.
LIAM: Well, they're wet and taut.
TALIESIN: Turgid.
LIAM: Turgid, yes.
LAURA: I want to break off a few sticks and try to
turn them into sharp daggery sword things. That's
fine, I'll be covered.
LIAM: You, Marisha, as you tear down a huge chunk,
are just Carrie'd. Just (squishing noise) as you
rip it off. When you break, whatever sap or
whatever it is that's in there feels hot and is
dark red and it spatters you. So you are now
blooded.
LAURA: Does it smell like blood?
MARISHA: Is it blood? Yeah, I'm going to smell it
and do a little bit of a taste test.
LIAM: You want to make a nature check?
MARISHA: Is that what I do? I don't know!
LIAM: Sure, why not.
MARISHA: I'm not a druid in this life!
LAURA: Yeah, but you know how druids work,
Marisha.
MARISHA: That's true, right? 15.
LIAM: I mean, you have cut yourself in the past,
you have sucked on a cut, and it does taste kind
of like that. It is warm.
LAURA: Is it blood?
MARISHA: It's warm. It tastes like bad soup.
MATT: What if everybody else we've ever known was
turned into a tree and we're in a jungle pulling
their fingers off?
LIAM: In the direction that you guys have come
from, you hear (fluttering noises).
SAM: Oh god. I'm going to just grab a handful of
rocks.
LAURA: I'm going to hide.
MATT: I'm going to grab Taliesin and wield him as
a weapon.
TALIESIN: Hey!
LIAM: Are you?
MATT: Yeah.
TALIESIN: I'll go with it, and I have the stick,
I'm just going to be like--
LAURA: I'm going to hide behind the flower that
Matt came out of.
LIAM: Okay, so you guys are all finding hiding
places?
MARISHA: Oh, we're hiding?
MATT: I don't until everyone else starts--
LIAM: It's getting closer.
LAURA: I hide.
LIAM: It's multiple locations, too.
MARISHA: Can I climb the tree that I broke off?
LIAM: Sure, make an athletics check.
MARISHA: Oh jeez.
LIAM: At disadvantage because it's sopping wet.
MARISHA: Well, it's a one.
LIAM: Okay, you slide and fall right back down and
smack your head on a rock and you take one hit
point of damage.
MATT: I immediately drop Taliesin and rush over to
make sure she's okay.
MARISHA: No, don't! I'm fine!
LIAM: Okay, Taliesin, you take one hit point of
damage as you hit your head
on a rock on the ground.
SAM: I'm going to hide in a creek.
MATT: Just like when I was 12, I can't do anything
right!
MARISHA: Jesus, don't try to fix it! Just don't
try to fix it!
LIAM: There is six, seven-- you're hiding? Okay,
make a stealth check.
SAM: I'm hiding, as well.
LIAM: Make a stealth check.
TALIESIN: You're really enjoying this way too
much.
LAURA: 22.
LIAM: 22.
TALIESIN: Six.
LIAM: Six?
SAM: Three.
LIAM: Three.
TALIESIN: Which is about what I could get
hired to play at that age.
LIAM: Okay, you sneak behind, you rogue, you, you
sneak behind the giant plant and get right
underneath the leaf again, and you reach out and
grab Taliesin and yank him with you. And Sam says,
"Wait, what about me?" just as these things go
(exploding noise) and break out of the tree cover,
and there are six or seven of these little ropy
skinless cats, running at you at full speed,
crossing the water. They're coming. Standing our
ground?
TRAVIS: I'm fucking out again, just booking ass.
Running like the wind, like Forrest Gump coming
out of them leg braces!
LIAM: Taliesin, from your hiding point, you see
Travis just book it in the same direction as the
weird old man went, running off through the tree
cover, he's gone.
MATT: As he starts running, can I use Friends to
try and ask him to not leave?
SAM: You have spells?
LAURA: Wait, you have spells?
MARISHA: He's a bard!
LIAM: You can really implore him to stay, which
means yes.
MATT: Okay. So I'm going to go ahead-- actually, I
don't have time, since he's going to bolt. Instead
I'm just going to go ahead and use a persuasion
check.
LIAM: Okay.
MATT: I'll try and persuade him. So I say, Travis
don't go, please! You leave now, we all die! We
need you! Now's the time to become the man you
eventually will be!
LIAM: Siri, what would we he roll against this?
Wisdom?
MATT: This would be my persuasion--
LIAM: Wisdom, right?
MATT: It's really up to you. If he wants to resist
it, then yeah.
LIAM: Yeah, let's just go fast and say wisdom.
MATT: Sure.
TRAVIS: I'm out.
MATT: 23.
TRAVIS: 22.
ALL: Oh!
LIAM: You stop and put your hand on the tree
(panting). You breathe, and you stop where you
are. You're still at this point 40 feet away from
the group and starting to cry. But you don't go.
You feel too guilty because you spent five years
playing Dungeons and Dragons with these people.
You cannot leave them alone to die. Everybody roll
for initiative.
SAM: Oh my god.
MATT: Oh! Natural 20!
TALIESIN: Natural 20.
MARISHA: What?
MATT: That's crazy! I'm sitting in Taliesin's
seat. I just realized!
TALIESIN: Damn it!
LIAM: Okay, who got 15 to 20?
MARISHA: Hang on, are we rolling initiative?
LIAM: Yeah, man!
MARISHA: I got distracted, sorry!
MATT: Ooh, a 19.
MARISHA: 22.
LIAM: 22?
MATT: 22.
LIAM: All right. Okay.
TALIESIN: 19.
LIAM: 19. Damn, guys.
TALIESIN: Because of negative one.
LIAM: All right, ten to 15?
SAM: 14.
LIAM: Okay. Laura, Travis, Ashley, where you at?
LAURA: Five!
TRAVIS: Four.
ASHLEY: Six!
LIAM: Okay. All right, these things are-- here we
go. Tree cover! Travis, little boy Travis, has run
that far. Are we on camera, guys? We've got Laura
and Taliesin-- yeah, that's right. Hidden. Not
hidden. Standing their ground. It's got to be this
way. Oh, I got it backwards! There we go. And here
they come, guys.
SAM: This is it.
LIAM: (sings) This is just like how I do it with
my kids! And you are kids!
LAURA: Oh my god, there's so many of them, we're
all going to die.
LIAM: Okay, Marisha. What do you want to do?
MARISHA: Oh, it's me up first?
LIAM: Yes.
SAM: Which one is she?
LIAM: Marisha's right here.
SAM: Okay.
LIAM: Yeah, you're not color-coded, so I'll have
to help out a little bit.
MARISHA: Okay. I'm going to turn and I'm going to
look at everybody else, and be like, we're fucking
up these cats, yeah?
SAM: Yeah!
ASHLEY: Yeah!
MARISHA: Okay! And then I'm going to run forward
to the one that's closest to me there.
LIAM: Three, four, five, six, that's where you're
at.
MARISHA: That's it? That's all I got?
LIAM: That's it.
MARISHA: Okay. And then I'm going to be like,
argh! (crying noises)
LIAM: All righty, you're an angry teen.
MARISHA: I'm angry, all hormonal rage!
MATT: You still have your action and your bonus.
LIAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: I don't have anything I can do, though.
MATT: Actually, as a monk, you should be able to
use--
LIAM: At level one.
MATT: At level one--
MARISHA: I have unarmed strike as a bonus action,
but that's all that's on my sheet.
MATT: That's true. Oh, I'm sorry, yeah. You can
still use an action if you wanted to go into your
dodge action, which any attacks against you--
SAM: No DMing!
MATT: I'm helping out!
LIAM: Hey, man, I'm not complaining! Shut up!
MATT: Anyone can use their action to make a dodge
action, so instead of attacking, you basically
just get really defensive, and then attacks
against you have disadvantage.
LIAM: So you're just getting ready for it. That's
a good idea.
MARISHA: Oh, sure. I'm super ready for these
cats.
LIAM: Okay. D for dodge! Matt, what would you like
to do? You're right here.
SAM: He's going to cast 5th-level Explode Cats.
MATT: I'm going to move ahead, and start getting
closer to back up Marisha. But I'm going to move a
little bit behind her because she's tougher than I
am. And that one that's kind of off to the right,
that one right there, I look over as I approach
and be like: Hey cat! Have you seen the kind of
shit she can do? Oh look, your friend over there,
he went ahead and fell down already. He was twice
as big as you! You're going to die in a second,
fool! I was going to use
Vicious Mockery on that guy.
LIAM: Okay.
SAM: Vicious Mockery.
ASHLEY: Yes!
MATT: So, let's see. Has to make a wisdom saving
throw.
LIAM: Okay. What's the DC?
MATT: It's not on my sheet. But that would be,
with the math there-- proficiency bonus of plus
two, plus my charisma which is three, so the DC
would be 13.
LIAM: Well, fuck you, 'cause he got a natural 20.
MATT: That's okay. That happens.
LIAM: That's okay. Okay.
MATT: I'm like, mocking cats is a bad idea. Save
me! Can I use the rest of my movement to stand
directly behind Marisha?
LIAM: Okay, I'll give you one more. Taliesin,
you're up.
TALIESIN: I'm going to peek around and see all
this and take a look at what's going down here.
LIAM: Okay.
TALIESIN: And the one that's closest to Matt and
Marisha? I have some vague memories of where we
just came from.
LIAM: Yeah.
TALIESIN: I'm going to see if any of this still
works?
LIAM: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Do I have any of that weird--
LIAM: Are you a haunted kid, is that what you're
asking me?
TALIESIN: I mean, I was already--
LIAM: You are a fucking haunted kid!
(laughter)
LIAM: What do you want to do?
TALIESIN: I want to reach down into the ground,
and see if I can just-- I'm just going to try and
reach out at that first cat and see if I can hit
it with a little bit of the Chill Touch. I want to
see if I can make those tendrils form again.
LIAM: All right. Talk to me, Goose.
TALIESIN: Chill Touch on the closest cat to the
two kids.
LIAM: Okay, this one right here?
TALIESIN: Yep, that one.
LIAM: That is definitely within range of your goth
attitude. Okay! So you've got to make a ranged
spell attack?
TALIESIN: Yep.
LIAM: Go for it.
TALIESIN: I don't actually know how to do this
anymore. Where's my spell--
LIAM: Plus five, just roll plus five.
TALIESIN: 18.
LIAM: 18 does in fact hit, so you slam your little
tiny cherub hand into the ground and it sinks into
the mud, and you feel the dark power of your
overlord slide down into the ground, and a
split-second happens, and it goes (electric sound)
out of the ground, underneath this thing, and
tendrils, spectral purplish-black tendrils wrap
around it and yank it into the ground! And it is
fucking gone!
(cheering)
TALIESIN: (heavy breathing) Cool!
LIAM: None of you motherfuckers can do what
Taliesin just did. Sam, you're up!
SAM: Me? Which one am I?
LIAM: You are in the luchador pants, right here.
SAM: Okay, I go forward and to the left. Am I
within throwing range?
LIAM: Five, ten, 15, 20, 25, 30, 35, 40, 45, 50.
For throwing a rock?
SAM: Yeah. I can hold my action until they get in
range.
LIAM: Sure, you want to wait until one gets close
enough, and then chuck a rock?
SAM: Yes.
LIAM: Sure. Done.
SAM: I will get ready. I'll cock my hand.
LIAM: Cock a rock. Cock rock.
SAM: Cock rock.
LIAM: Okay, Ashley. You're up.
ASHLEY: Okay! I'm going to take the dead skinned
cat from my belt and hold it by the tail, and say,
(shouting) All right, you motherfuckers! You
better turn around and leave or I'm going to kill
every last motherfucking one of you! I'm going to
intimidate them.
LIAM: Intimidate, okay.
SAM: They're cats.
ASHLEY: (shouting) I don't care if they're just
cats!
LIAM: Make an intimidation check at disadvantage.
MATT: This is absolutely brilliant. Ooh! You're
rolling good tonight.
TRAVIS: Disadvantage.
LAURA: Why?
ASHLEY: With a disadvantage?
LIAM: Yeah.
ASHLEY: Why?
LIAM: Because it's a herd of skinless--
ASHLEY: I'm fucking--
LAURA: Scary! She's really intimidating!
MATT: Roll disadvantage, because he said it.
(laughter)
SAM: It was a little standoff, there.
MATT: That's okay. She rolled higher on the second
one.
ASHLEY: 22.
TALIESIN: Ooh!
LIAM: (cats growling) They start backing up.
SAM: All of them?
LIAM: Slowly. The first three do. The first three
do stop in their tracks. The other three-- well
you'll find out in a minute. Laura, what would you
like to do?
LAURA: I'm going to hold my attack until one of
them comes closer.
LIAM: And how are you going to attack?
LAURA: I have those two sharpened sticks like
daggers, yo!
LIAM: Are they melee sticks?
LAURA: Well, I mean, I suppose so, because I don't
know how to make a throwing stick.
LIAM: I think that's just called a stick.
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: Okay. All right.
LAURA: But I want it to be sharp, I don't want to
just throw a stick at something.
LIAM: Okay. Are you waiting until they're in
throwing range or until they're right up on you?
LAURA: No, I want to wait until--
SAM: Where are you?
LAURA: I'm under a leaf. We're hiding.
SAM: Oh, that's not going to get near you in the
next round.
LAURA: They're not?
SAM: You're a hundred feet away from them.
LAURA: Well, fine, I'll run out there and back up
Ashley. I'll go stand next to Ashley.
LIAM: 30, 40, bust out-- okay, right there, boom.
LAURA: And then I'll pull my sticks out and wait.
And wait until they get closer.
LIAM: Okay. Travis, would you like to keep--- oh
no, you were convinced to run. Do you want to stay
hiding here? Or do you want to go back?
TRAVIS: Nah, I'll go back. I was convinced.
LAURA: I've been shamed by Sam to come out of
fucking hiding.
LIAM: So, just direct line back? And you can dash,
too, I mean you're way far back.
LAURA: I've only got six health points right now,
bro.
LIAM: You want to dash?
TRAVIS: No. I'm going to use my action to reach in
and grab what is definitely all-white
tighty-whiteys, and I'm going to rip the elastic
band off of my briefs--
MARISHA: Oh yeah!
LAURA: Are you going to rage?
TRAVIS: I'm going to pull the elastic band off and
prepare to, I don't know. (laughs)
SAM: To strangle?
TRAVIS: Yes, to strangle.
LIAM: Chances are so small, but I want you to roll
just in case you get a one.
TRAVIS: It's a 12.
LIAM: Those tighty-whiteys rip out of your hands
and you crouch down, and you've got like a piano
wire, except it's your underwear. And you're
ready. Okay. So these three don't leave, but they
back up to about here. They're still barely past
the edge of the tree. These ones are still coming,
they didn't give a shit. One, two, three, four,
five, six, and he's going to dash and get right up
on you--
SAM: Is that within throwing range for me?
LIAM: Yes.
SAM: I'm throwing!
LIAM: All right, throw! Make a ranged attack.
SAM: One.
(laughter)
SAM: Oh no, do I hit Marisha, or something?
LIAM: You do, actually. It conks off the back of
your head--
MARISHA: Ow.
SAM: Sorry!
LIAM: Roll a d4.
MARISHA: You are!
SAM: Three.
LIAM: Three? What's your strength modifier?
SAM: I don't know. Oh, one.
LIAM: One, okay. You take four points of damage.
You are clocked hard.
MARISHA: Damn it! Dick!
SAM: I'm sorry!
MARISHA: Fucking hell!
SAM: I'm a musical theater person!
MARISHA: My mom warned me about people like you!
LIAM: These are just going for the closest victim
they can find, but they're not close enough to actually
attack. They make it up to there, they are
rounding on Marisha, and now it's Marisha's turn.
MARISHA: Jesus, so I've got two kitty cats on me?
LIAM: Three.
MARISHA: Three kitty cats?
LAURA: They're really mean, Marisha! They have
claws!
MARISHA: Ugh! What? This is why you spay and
neuter your pets! And then I kick the one directly
in front of me.
LIAM: Okay.
MARISHA: Do I get a multiattack as a monk?
LIAM: You get two attacks as a monk, yeah.
MARISHA: I get two? Okay, I'm going to kick the
first one, just full on punt him, then I'm going
to take the stick with the second one and give him
a big old golf swing.
LIAM: Okay, roll two attacks.
MARISHA: All right.
MATT: See what's the first one, in case you kill
it.
MARISHA: First one? That's not great. 14 for the
first one.
LIAM: This is the kick? Roll a d4.
MARISHA: One plus three. Four points.
LIAM: Okay, your foot takes this thing under the
chin and you just slick the bottom of your shoe
and you feel a snap in your foot and it just does
a spin in the air and lands on its back, dead. But
you're still moving and smacking the next one.
MARISHA: Golf swing! Which is-- ooh, that's good,
that's 15 plus-- 21.
LIAM: Definitely hits. d4 plus strength.
MARISHA: Five, total.
LIAM: Okay, and you swing away and go crack and
this time you hit the thing's fucking head so hard
that you hear the same kind of snap, except you
feel tendon rip at the same time, and the head
goes free except for this thin little band of
ligament, and it just falls and is still twitching
and going (whimpering noises)
MATT: The first hit, behind her I go, nice! Second
one I go, no!
MARISHA: I feel guilty.
LIAM: Matt, you're up. And you've got a direct
view of blood dripping out the back of your young
fiance's head.
MATT: Ooh, that's right. Well, there's the one
still next to her. All right, you know what, I'm
going to go ahead and say: Don't worry, baby, I'll
take care of you! In about ten years! Or right
now. We'll do that now! Healing Word.
LIAM: Okay.
MATT: Bonus action, so you heal five hit points.
ALL: Hey!
LIAM: Ugh, the back of your head stops smarting
like Advil, pronto, all healed up.
MARISHA: Man, you're so calming, just your
presence. So good.
MATT: Thanks!
MARISHA: In ten years.
MATT: I look over at the cat. As she's saying
this, the cat is in front of her going (snarling
noise). Okay, we're dead!
LIAM: (cat yowling)
MATT: I'm going to walk up and try and do what she
did, try and kick at it.
LIAM: Kick it? Okay, go for a roll.
MATT: I move up base to base, right against her
shoulder, and just, (screams). Screaming, probably
think I'm going to hurt myself more than the
creature, trying. And that is a four.
LIAM: You do the most beautiful martial arts movie
spin kick that hits absolutely nothing, and come
back down and breathe heavy (panting) and look
over at the love of your life. Yeah.
MATT: I'm proud of myself, because that looks just
like it does when I practice it
when I'm home alone.
LIAM: Executive, you're up.
TALIESIN: I see this one that's threatening. I'm
going to try and get a little more fancy with
this. I'm just going to see if I can manifest the
power inside the cat.
LIAM: Inside the cat? Sure, go for it.
TALIESIN: Yeah. Shooting, going for inside the
cat. It's already gross. That's right, I've got to
learn this. 22.
LIAM: Okay, so as Matt's foot comes down into the
water and goes (panting) you're right face-to-face
with the thing. Its feral face is leaning up
against yours and it goes (yowls) and then three
spectral octopus tentacles come out of its face,
one out of each eye and one of its mouth, and you
feel that shit just slathering all over your face
and sucks back in and the thing just explodes like
a blood sausage. Gone.
TALIESIN: Ooh. Okay.
MATT: When I turn around and see this tiny bowl
haircut blond kid from the Omen just glowing.
LIAM: You look over your shoulder and you just see
that face.
MATT: Marisha, who are we fighting? I don't know
who we're fighting anymore!
TALIESIN: We're good, we got this!
MATT: Okay!
MARISHA: That's Taliesin!
LIAM: Sam, what would you like to do?
SAM: It's my turn? Oh, it's my turn again. We've
cycled around?
LIAM: Yep.
SAM: Okay. Are those guys out of range?
LIAM: Just, but you could get in range.
SAM: All right, I'm going to try to right my
wrongs and get in range and throw another rock at
the middle one.
LIAM: The middle one? Okay. Looks good.
SAM: For Bixby! Two.
(laughter)
LIAM: Would you like to use the rest of your
movement? You could back up a little bit,
I guess.
SAM: Yeah. Is there anything I can hide behind? Is
that a thing?
LIAM: No, the closest cover of any kind is 50 feet
away.
SAM: And they're going to get me. I'll just go
huddle with Marisha and Matt.
LIAM: Okay. Okay, there you are, a little chorus
line. Ashley, you're up.
ASHLEY: Okay, I'll walk up alongside the four of
them, just swinging the corpse. It's your call!
You want to run, or you want to keep fighting?
Four of you down! Five, actually! Math wasn't my
strong suit!
LIAM: Laura, you're watching rebel teen Ashley
mouth off at some skinless cats. What would you
like to do?
LAURA: I'm going to stand, walk around them--
LIAM: To this side?
LAURA: Yeah, but back. Just stay behind them.
LIAM: Here?
LAURA: Back further.
LIAM: Here.
LAURA: Further.
LIAM: Okay.
LAURA: Yeah. Basically, I walk over so I can see.
And I ready my sticks, and I'm going to save my
action.
LIAM: Sure. You can do that.
SAM: Stick! Stick! Stick!
LIAM: All right, Travis. What's up?
TRAVIS: I'll use my dash to try and join the other
crew.
LIAM: Aw, look at that.
TRAVIS: Look at that.
LIAM: Awkward. Okay.
MATT: Sweat just pouring down his face.
TRAVIS: (heavy breathing) My asthma is a problem
at this point. My Ventolin inhaler is broken.
MATT: We are straight-up the kids from It right
now, by the way.
LIAM: Oh yeah. (bell ding) The three cats continue
to-- well, they don't bristle, because they have
no hair. They're still backing up. They move
backward into the tree cover, but you see them
stop. They don't flee. They get into the trees and
they sit and stare.
LAURA: We should probably get out of here before
more cats come.
TRAVIS: I think they did that because something
bigger's coming.
LAURA: I think they did it because Ashley's
fucking scary as shit!
TALIESIN: There was an old man when we got here
before.
LAURA: You're really cool, Ashley.
TALIESIN: Yeah, that was pretty cool.
MARISHA: Ashley and I just, football, huh! Huh!
And then we do the chest
bump thing in the air. Huh!
LIAM: And whatever this stuff is goes (squishing)
between you.
ALL: Ugh.
MATT: Which me, being two feet away, (splashing
noise). That's still pretty cool.
TRAVIS: We saw an old guy.
LAURA: Oh wait, what?
TRAVIS: Yeah, we saw an old man, he was trying to
peel you out of the tomato plant you were in.
SAM: Which way did he go?
TRAVIS: I have no idea.
TALIESIN: He went that way. That way, now.
ASHLEY: Can anybody track?
SAM: Let's go! I'm pretty good at that, at
tracking, I think.
LIAM: Are you?
SAM: I don't know, I'm a ranger. Isn't that what
rangers do?
LIAM: Well, you're Sam.
SAM: Oh shit.
LIAM: Give it a shot.
SAM: I had a treehouse in the woods growing up.
TRAVIS: Did you really?
TALIESIN: That's come up so many times today!
LAURA: Okay, well, try to find the fucking old
guy!
SAM: I mean, it was right behind my house.
MATT: He spent a long time trying to keep away
from old guys in the woods, so he knows how to
track them well.
LIAM: I'm going to give you, if you want to-- do
you want to track?
SAM: Yeah!
LIAM: All right, make a perception, right?
MATT: Tracking would be survival.
LIAM: Survival, that's what I was going to say.
But, for reasons, do it at advantage.
SAM: Because--
MATT: Because you're awesome!
TRAVIS: Because you love this.
SAM: Because I'm a ranger and rangers get
advantage in their favorite terrain.
LIAM: Wrong.
LAURA: Maybe because he knows you know the old
guy.
SAM: Okay.
TALIESIN: Because Warner Bros is your favored
terrain?
SAM: 13.
LIAM: That's fine. You see where Verno booked it
before. You can see Verno went through the trees
right here, but you see another break. You see a
vine split off right there, and you gather that he
went in generally the same direction, not exactly,
where Travis went.
SAM: I think he's that way.
LAURA: Well, let's go find him.
SAM: Follow me, everyone.
LIAM: And this little seven-year-old boy with a
gigantic smile starts stalking his way through the
bog and leading you.
(laughter)
MARISHA: So cute!
SAM: I didn't shower much.
LAURA: So cute.
LIAM: Everybody's following Ranger Sam, right?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Sure.
LIAM: Okay. All right. So.
MATT: Trying to clean my perpetually fogging
glasses because of the humid weather.
LIAM: Yeah, it's like every 30 seconds here. So
you guys start walking, and after the first
minute, you notice as you're going, Sam, in the
ground, something very different than anything
else you've seen here. There's a long bar in the
ground, half sunken into the ground, and covered
over. You only saw a glint of yellow, and it was
faded over and mucky, but you saw it. It looked
very different. Leaning down, you wipe away some
of the crap covering it, and you see sort of an
alternating yellow, black pattern. It's like a
long board. It's old, and it's wet and rotted
through, but there's no mistaking one of those
things for gate entry.
SAM: Oh, parking lot entry gate. Wait, does that
mean we're in an old overgrown parking lot? I'm
going to dig it out. Or I'll try.
LIAM: Okay. You don't even need to make any kind
of a check. Everything is so slick here, it just
slides out. You can't lift the whole thing or hold
the whole thing because it's eight feet long. As
you pull it out, it's so soft, it breaks at one
spot, but there's no question what that is. This
is exactly a gate entry bar.
TALIESIN: I'm going to make a wild guess. I'm
going to see if there's a little boxhouse nearby.
MARISHA: Yeah, can I assist him on that?
LIAM: Sure.
TALIESIN: Where it would be, physically. I'm
getting a sneaky suspicion--
LIAM: Make an investigation check.
LAURA: Can you turn that stick into a weapon?
TALIESIN: Investigation?
LIAM: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Nine.
MARISHA: 13.
LIAM: Nine? 13? Yeah, I mean, you've been to
Warner Bros.
TALIESIN: Yeah. We're still on the WB lot.
SAM: Those four posts were the tower! What was
left of it.
LAURA: What does that even mean? How do we get
home?
SAM: Well, we're in Burbank.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Just several miles down the 405 ought to
do it.
TRAVIS: Should I say it?
TALIESIN: Do you want to say it?
SAM: Say what?
TALIESIN: You thought it, you might as well say
it.
TRAVIS: I have a theory about where we are.
SAM: Well, we're at Warner Brothers.
TRAVIS: I feel like we're in the Upside-Down.
MARISHA: Of life, or WB?
TRAVIS: Both.
ASHLEY: What?
TALIESIN: We're in the BW.
(laughter)
LIAM: What do you guys want to do?
SAM: Well, wait, if these are security booths
here, maybe they have some handcuffs or something
that we can get in there.
TRAVIS: Are there any working flashlights in the
security booth?
LIAM: You can make an investigation check. You
didn't find anything.
TALIESIN: I'm going to join you, just rummaging
through.
LIAM: Go for it. You're digging through rot.
TRAVIS: 13.
TALIESIN: 20.
LIAM: Natural 20?
TALIESIN: No, just 20.
LIAM: Okay. You dig, and you do find the
foundation of-- it's Hollywood Way. It's the exact
setup for that little booth when you're going into
park, right under the tower. I mean, you haven't
traveled that far, right? And there's nothing in
here. The bottom of the structure, the walls is
there, you can tell where the bottom of the door,
the lintel? Is it the lintel? I don't know.
SAM: Sure, why not.
LIAM: You found the gate post, and that's all you
found, there's no--
ASHLEY: There's no walls in the thing.
LIAM: No, it's just the bottom of the structure.
You can just barely make out one corner.
TALIESIN: Does it feel like some of the buildings
might still be there, hidden in this forest
structure, or is it just too dense?
LIAM: You didn't see anything.
MARISHA: Can I backtrack, now that we're slowly
piecing this together, see if I can find the
Hollywood Way sign? The street sign?
LIAM: Sure?
TALIESIN: Don't wander too far.
MARISHA: No, I just want to turn around, if it's
right there.
LIAM: You guys here, that way maybe was the tower,
about here's where you find the security gate, I
guess, and old feller ran that way.
LAURA: (gasps) We should head towards Geek and
Sundry!
MARISHA: He went north? Is he going north on
Hollywood Way? I rolled a ten total.
LIAM: To find a sign?
MARISHA: Hollywood Way.
LIAM: No, man.
SAM: Yeah, but we know the direction. We know
where the tower is. We know where the booth is. We
just go that way.
LAURA: Keep following the guy.
MATT: The guy was pretty old?
TRAVIS: He was super old. He was old and weak.
LIAM: You saw a glint of glasses, too.
TRAVIS: He had a glint of glasses.
MATT: If we keep going, we can probably catch up
to him because he's probably not very fast.
SAM: You're a very smart young man.
MATT: That's all I got.
MARISHA: I didn't see anything! What if this is
just a Warner Bros specific thing? What if the
rest of LA is okay?
SAM: I mean, we can see into LA and it's not,
right?
LAURA: Yeah, I climbed to the top of the tower.
It's jungle everywhere.
LIAM: If you can believe your eyes, San Fernando
Valley is this way.
MATT: Is this the future we're looking at?
MARISHA: But, jungle versus Warner Bros sinking.
Is it everything?
SAM: We've got one option: we've got to follow
this old guy!
LAURA: Let's follow the old guy!
ASHLEY: When you climbed up to the top, you didn't
see any structures?
LAURA: No, all I saw was jungle.
ASHLEY: Shit!
MARISHA: Look, it's the Valley, there's not a lot
of skyscrapers.
LAURA: I mean it's a jungle here. It's a desert,
really.
TRAVIS: Let's try to go after the old guy.
LAURA: They're not normal trees. They look like
engorged sausages.
ASHLEY: Wet Bulging Sausages. Warner Bros
Studios.
MARISHA: Turgid, engorged--
ASHLEY: There's a lot that's going on right now.
MATT: I start getting a nosebleed. Well, if
there's any building in this vicinity that lasts
through time, it's the Bob's Big Boy.
TRAVIS: It's true.
ASHLEY: That's true.
SAM: Why are we going to Bob's Big Boy?! Didn't he
go north on Hollywood Way?
LIAM: He did. If you can believe your eyes, if
this nonsense is actually based on anything, then
yes, he is heading along Hollywood Way.
TALIESIN: We're going down Hollywood Way.
LIAM: Okay. All right, so Ranger Sam leads the
way. You guys start traveling. It's slow-going
because it's wet and disgusting and there's trees
everywhere. You're going through fucking swamp.
LAURA: As we go, we should keep our eyes out for
anything that we can use as weapons.
LIAM: There's lots of vines and rocks and sticks.
LAURA: There's nothing metal?
SAM: Just Ashley.
LIAM: The last metal you saw was Ashley Johnson
and what is presumably the base of the Warner Bros
water tower.
ASHLEY: Can I, as we walk, with my handy-dandy
tools that are here that I see that you've added.
Can I start trying to fashion a slingshot?
LIAM: Out of cat gut?
ASHLEY: Yeah!
LIAM: Sure.
ASHLEY: Out of a nice little twig. Travis can
attest I'm pretty good with slingshots.
LIAM: Make a survival check.
ASHLEY: Okay.
SAM: What are you, Ashley?
ASHLEY: That's a seven, right?
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: She's Ashley.
ASHLEY: 11.
LIAM: 11? Okay. So, what you're able to do as
you're walking is to pull and rip away some of the
leg tendon from this thing's body. And now you've
got this stretchy piece of meat to work with.
MATT: (whispering) That's so cool!
LIAM: More on that later. You guys continue to
walk through the jungle and you're noticing that
the ground is moving downward a bit now.
LAURA: Matt!
MATT: What?
LAURA: Can you heal me?
MATT: You look all right.
LAURA: I saw you heal Marisha.
MATT: I'm pretty spent right now.
LIAM: Sam, do me a favor and make a perception
check.
SAM: Guys, I'm leading this party. Focus on me!
MATT: We're all going to die.
LAURA: Can I try to close up my wounds that I
got?
SAM: 17.
LIAM: 17?
SAM: Yes.
LIAM: It's not a one or a two? Through a gap
between three trees, way in the distance, you see
a balding, white-haired little old man. And he
sees you seeing him, and he's gone again.
SAM: Oh shit! I saw him! Guys, he's that way! We
should go that way, but maybe flank, right? I
played paintball as a kid, so we can flank.
LIAM: You are a kid.
SAM: Come at him from two directions.
LIAM: You're running?
TRAVIS: I'm booking ass.
LIAM: Wow! Travis is just running today!
TRAVIS: I ran everywhere! I was fast as shit!
LAURA: I'm running after Travis.
TRAVIS: My ADHD was in overdrive all the time.
SAM: But you have the mind of a current-day
Travis.
TRAVIS: Yeah, but I'm fast again, y'all!
LIAM: Is everybody following suit?
LAURA: Yeah, I'm following Travis!
SAM: No! I'm flanking! I'm flanking around.
LIAM: You're flanking?
MARISHA: I follow Riegel and I say, why are we
running?
MATT: I follow Marisha because she's the biggest.
TALIESIN: I follow Travis.
ASHLEY: Yeah, I'm running.
LIAM: Okay. Are you with this group? The flanking
or the straight-on?
ASHLEY: Straight-on.
LIAM: You guys start booking through and trying to
stay up. You're slipping as you go, but managing
to catch up. And he is old. You're getting closer
to the spot where you saw him, Sam. And you're
looking over, you're playing the raptor; maybe you
can catch him from the side. You guys are still
going down. All of you are going down and then
ahead. You notice that you guys are in separate
wedges of a hill that are both leading now to the
same place. And you see this guy again, and he
scuttles over a little ridge and down. He scuttles
up over a little bit of ridge of plant and mud,
and then he disappears from view. And it's almost
like you're looking at-- it's so thick here, the
trees are so thick that you can probably get
through on the sides, but there's one big
main entrance here that is scooped up in like an
upside-down U of plant growth.
SAM: One way in.
LAURA: Let's start running.
MARISHA: Yeah, go.
LAURA: Who's charging after him!
SAM: We're all going in together, I guess.
LIAM: Okay.
TRAVIS: Yeah, let's go run into the funnel.
LIAM: Okay. all right. So you guys converge and
you're running after this old man, and you guys
climb up to the top of the ridge and you see-- oh
gosh, I think there's a scene in Jurassic Park
where it's a long sort of tunnel. Where that guy
gets eaten by the little critters? Anybody
remember this? Yeah. And so it winds straight
ahead like that, and as you're running, Taliesin,
you're the only one who sees it because you're the
shortest. You see a metal sign bent over, peeking
out from behind two trees, red dripping down it.
And you see a one, you see a four. And then you're
past it, and everybody's running. And this old man
is maybe a hundred feet ahead of you.
LAURA: Can we yell out to him?
LIAM: Sure.
LAURA: Hey! Stop running, what the fuck. We're
just trying to figure out what's happening!
ASHLEY: We're just kids!
LIAM: He does stop, and spins around. He's still
pretty far away from you, and he looks
(breathes heavily).
LAURA: Hey!
LIAM: (breathes heavily) And he spins and he
continues to run.
LAURA: Oh, come on!
MARISHA: Oh, I keep going.
LAURA: We keep going.
LIAM: Everybody starts to run. I'm so sorry. You
feel the air around you start to vibrate around
you, and your head starts to rattle in your skull.
And you hear, at that moment, the sound of a war
horn? Massive. It feels like the inside of your
head, your skull, is vibrating like a bell. Your
teeth are shaking. Your eyes feel like they are
expanding in their sockets, and you feel
(explosion noise), and everything changes.
TRAVIS: It's Inception.
MARISHA: Oh god, are we going deeper? No.
LIAM: Everything grows darker.
MARISHA: No.
LIAM: The gentler sounds of the jungle are
suddenly gone. You find yourselves, suddenly, as
your sight stops blurring, looking at the ocean.
You're standing in miserably frigid cold water
swirling around your legs and your waist. And
you're staring out at the horizon, and the sky--
it's so jarring, it's so different than where you
were. You're staring out at dark clouds above you
and over the horizon. And that horn that is
blasting finally quits, and you just hear the
sound of the surf. Of waves crashing on a beach. A
beach behind you.
ASHLEY: Are there any footprints on the beach
leading from the water?
LIAM: You turn away from the water, Ashley. And
from your place in the surf, you see the remnants
and rubble of a freeway, stretching from the water
you're in back toward the land and away. But all
of your minds, as you turn with her, have only a
second to process your whereabouts, because before
you stands a wall of horror. The living
manifestation of woe is gathered in front of you.
A vast horde of writhing, malignant nightmares
stand watching you. All shapes and sizes.
MARISHA: Casting directors.
LIAM: Black, oiled, insect-like flesh. White
chalky corpse-like figures. Literal devils.
SAM: Commercial casting directors.
LIAM: Hundreds of eyes, seeming to hungrily covet
your flesh. And towering above them all, rising 40
to 50 feet in the air, stands an apocalyptic
monstrosity out of the Book of Revelations. A
massive, two-headed titan standing on two scaled,
powerful legs, staring down at you all. The head
on this side, brow furrowed, face unmoving. The
eyes just judging you. The head on this side,
craning forward, its terrible maw stretched wide.
A long tongue slathering back and forth across its
enormous teeth. Hungering. The horn of the
apocalypse tears the air again, rattling your
brains in your little skulls as the legion before
you begins to jibber and shriek. Everyone roll for
initiative.
MARISHA: What's happening?
MATT: What?
SAM: It's everything we've ever faced.
LAURA: Oh my god. We're going to die!
MARISHA: Brought to you by the producers of
Independence Day!
LAURA: For real!
ASHLEY: What?
MATT: So, even-- (laughs) So. Do I know what this
is?
MARISHA: From the producers of 2012!
LIAM: You think so.
MATT: Okay. Me as Matt Mercer, even at 12, Matt
Mercer-- (laughs)
LAURA: Hey Matt!
LIAM: Can I get a little more juice on the audio,
please?
LAURA: Thanks for healing me!
MARISHA: Whoa!
LIAM: Let's roll for initiative, guys.
TALIESIN: Oh god.
MATT: Oh, great. That's great.
SAM: As, as we roll, I look down to see if-- Are
we any older, or are we the same age?
LIAM: Same age.
MARISHA: Same age?
SAM: I check if I've got pubes. Do I have pubes?
LIAM: 25 to 20?
TRAVIS: Nope. Nair.
LIAM: Nobody there? 15 to 20?
LAURA: 17.
MARISHA: 15.
LIAM: 17, 15? Laura, Marisha. Okay, ten to 15?
TALIESIN: 13.
LIAM: 13.
SAM: Ten!
LIAM: Ten. Okay. I got Travis, Ashley, and Matt
left. What have you guys got?
ASHLEY: Seven.
TRAVIS: Nine.
MATT: Four.
LIAM: Okay.
ASHLEY: Oh shit.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
ASHLEY: What?
MARISHA: What are these things?
LAURA: What is that big thing?
SAM: You know, I think we can take them, guys.
ASHLEY: Can anybody make a boat?
MARISHA: It's a really big thing.
LIAM: Laura Bailey.
LAURA: What?
LIAM: What would you like to do?
LAURA: Where are we?
LIAM: Oh. That's important, isn't it? You're in
the water.
MATT: So, you guys know in Stranger Things, that
the big monster they keep talking about?
ASHLEY: The demogorgon?
LAURA: The demogorgon?
MARISHA: Is that what that is?
SAM: I think we can take it.
LAURA: I think--
SAM: Wait. They won't come into the water. Maybe
we just stay here.
TALIESIN: That's gremlins. Gremlins won't come
into the water.
(laughter)
MATT: Gremlins can go in the water.
TALIESIN: That just makes more of them.
MATT: Yeah. There's no good answer here.
LAURA: Matt, how do you kill these things?
MATT: I can't tell you. My initiative's four. Go!
I'm too scared. In fact, if we weren't halfway in
the ocean, you would see the soak marks on the
front of my jeans.
TRAVIS: And in fact, around Matt, the water is
quite warm.
MATT: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Better than a chlorinated pool, man
MARISHA: (laughs) A chlorinated pool?
TALIESIN: It'd be a little green.
LAURA: I have nothing. I'm just going to back up
further into the water.
LIAM: Okay. It is rough going. You can go about 15
feet as you push your way back. Now you're moving
backward in the water, and the water's now up to
your childlike collarbone.
LAURA: Can I hold my breath and put it under the
water and see what I can see under the water?
LIAM: That's what you want to do?
LAURA: Yeah!
LIAM: Okay, you do. You splash under
the water, and it is jarring. It is so ice-cold.
And as you do, you see a very thick serpent swim
past your face.
LAURA: What?! Bubbles! (laughs) I come back up out
of the water. We're surrounded! There's something
in the water!
MATT: (screams)
LIAM: Marisha, what would you like to do?
MARISHA and LAURA: (scream)
TRAVIS: Go. Have no fear!
MARISHA: Okay. Well, I fucking hate the cold above
all things! Which is a hundred percent true, so
I'm going to fuck this ice-water shit, and start
heading out towards the beach, just because that
would be my first concern.
LIAM: Okay. You are now standing on the beach,
looking at a legion from hell.
MARISHA: I say, Yeah! What's up?! This is the
party at the end of the world, right? And I just
start dancing. Hey! And I cry a little. Oh! Hey!
Oh!
LIAM: The giant continues to judge you. On your
sides, there are two very large-- not as big as
the big guy, obviously, but two winged, twice the
size of you guys, bent over muscular ropey winged
creatures, and they just stand there going (raspy
breaths) here and here. Taliesin, what would you
like to do?
TALIESIN: I'm going to join Marisha on the beach
because I hate the water.
LIAM: Yes, I remembered.
TALIESIN: And it's cold. And this has kind of
happened to me before.
SAM: The whole monster thing?
TALIESIN: This whole thing has kind of happened.
And, this is true, I'm going to say what I said
last time.
MARISHA: Do it.
TALIESIN: This is true, and you might know this.
Mister Satan dude, we are totally
ready to serve you!
(laughter)
LIAM: Make a persuasion check.
TALIESIN: This is literally what I said last time
this happened. Oh boy, that's not great.
TRAVIS: But there are fish in the ocean,
Taliesin!
TALIESIN: That's why I got out. Eight.
LIAM: Eight? Noted. Okay.
TALIESIN: I'm going to hold my full action until
something happens.
LIAM: Okay, until what happens?
TALIESIN: Until they start moving within ten feet
of me.
LIAM: Okay, got it. Sam, what would you like to
do?
SAM: I'm going to also join them on the beach.
LIAM: Okay.
SAM: And similarly, I'm going to hold up the skull
of Bixby and say: We serve the darkness as you do!
We will do your bidding if you will let us! Please
spare our lives so that we may serve yours!
LIAM: Make a persuasion check.
SAM: 14.
LIAM: Okay, noted. Ashley, what would you like to
do?
ASHLEY: Okay, I'm going to go up on the beach, and
I'm going to join them in their persuasion, and
I'm going to use the dead cat again. And I'm just
going to take a bite of it.
(laughter)
MARISHA: You're Ozzy Osbourne and shit?
TALIESIN: We could have so hung out.
LIAM: Make a persuasion check.
ASHLEY: Does that count?
MATT: It's what you rolled.
ASHLEY: 19.
LIAM: Okay, noted.
SAM: That's good.
LIAM: Yes, it is. Gigantic feet crunch down in the
sand as he slowly walks forward, or they do, and
one head stares at you, little man.
TRAVIS: Oh no.
LIAM: Make a strength check.
TRAVIS: A strength check. That's a nine.
LIAM: Okay. Travis, you feel your whole body lock
up as you are lifted out of the water, straight up
into the air, and a little bit forward. And your
little duder body is just floated forward and you
are frozen in terror. You can't move a muscle, and
the head on this side is just staring at you.
TRAVIS: Oh god.
LAURA: Just a little poo falls into the water.
TRAVIS: A little rabbit pellet makes it through
the shorts. Straight through.
MATT: You've been hoarding Cocoa Puffs.
LIAM: Matt, what would you like to do?
MATT: Okay. So, being both a bard and being a kid
that both as an adult and in that age spent a lot
of free time alone reading monster manuals and
cryptozoology books, can I possibly see if I
recognize any sort of nature to this creature? Any
sort of religious context to it, or any idea where
it may have come from?
LIAM: It looks like the shit you saw in your DND
books, man.
MATT: Okay! Seeing as how Ashley already seems to
be the one that's on the right track, I'm going to
begin to step towards the water. Using a bonus
action, I'm going to go ahead and give her bardic
inspiration and be like, Ashley, continue to prove
your savagery!
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Oh my god!
MATT: Chew deep and revel in the insanity, as this
day, we prove our mettle against the force of
darkness!
ASHLEY: Chew deep?
MATT: Yes!
MARISHA: What does that even mean, chew deep?
TRAVIS: With fogged-up glasses.
MATT: Yeah, my glasses right are now are like
every classic anime teacher, it's just too fogged
where you can't see the eyes. It's just a straight
white glare. I step out of the water towards this
entity and say: Oh great demogorgon, deity from
upon the Abyss who brings its hordes to the
shoreline, we are but humble servants, prostrate
before you, granting you the power we have to
offer as we ourselves traverse across many worlds.
We have much gifts to grant you, and follow you to
the ends of this plane.
LIAM: Make a religion check.
MATT: Not so great. Seven.
LIAM: One last little squirt comes out of your
ding dong.
MATT: You got this, Ashley!
LIAM: He would like to use one of his legendary
actions now. And you see his long, nightmarish
tail swing, coil, and then whip out, and strikes
down and lands on Marisha and crushes her into the
beach and rips away. And you see a smear on the
sand. You see a clump of red hair. And some
innards.
TRAVIS: You're a track mark!
LIAM: Laura, what would you like to do?
TRAVIS: Oh my god!
LAURA: I think I'm going to just stand back in the
water and continue to scream.
LIAM: Okay. Noted.
LAURA: (screams) Get back in the water! Get back!
It just killed Marisha! Get back in the water! And
then I'm going to try and jump up and see if I can
reach Travis's leg.
LIAM: His leg? He's 30 feet in the air.
LAURA: I can't reach you!
TRAVIS: Watch out, there's poop down there!
LAURA: I see it!
LIAM: Is that the end?
LAURA: I'm just staying. I'm going to stay and
just hold my sticks.
LIAM: Off on your left, you see. (splashing
noises) It doesn't come all the way. It just
watches you.
MARISHA: Guys, they hate people who are
marketable! That's the key! Be marketable!
MATT: Which is the echo we hear in our minds. We
don't hear out loud, as she's nothing
but a hairy smear.
LIAM: Mr. Mom, what would you like to do?
SAM: Woobie, woobie, woobie!
TALIESIN: I am not pleased. I am going to start
wishing that we had some help with this somehow,
and I'm going to start, I suppose, casting Unseen
Servant?
LIAM: Okay.
TALIESIN: And I'm going to attempt to create
something to catch Travis when he lands.
LIAM: Okay.
TALIESIN: And otherwise, I think I'm just staring
at the ground for the moment, because that was a
lot that just happened.
LIAM: Yeah. Guys, everybody sees a spectral form
of a grown Taliesin Jaffe appear next to child
Taliesin Jaffe, and floats over floating Verno,
and spectral Taliesin just starts
going like this.
TALIESIN: Thank you for making that as awkward as
humanly possible.
LIAM: Yes, you're welcome. All done?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
LIAM: Sam, what would you like to do?
SAM: I mean, those are tendrils? What are those
things, those are just arms?
LIAM: Tendrils.
MATT: Giant arm. Tentacle arm.
TRAVIS: Kill me. Kill me!
SAM: With what, a rock?
TRAVIS: I'm fucking dying up here, man!
TALIESIN: If you try and kill him with a rock,
you'll kill him, so just go for it.
SAM: I'm going to use my movement and my action to
dash--
LIAM: Which way?
SAM: At the demogorgon?
TRAVIS: Yeah!
SAM: And I'm going to try to kill it with love and
give it a big hug around its leg and say, I
forgive you!
LIAM: You grab it by the leg?
SAM: Yeah.
LIAM: Okay, noted. Ashley, what would you like to
do?
ASHLEY: Okay, I'm going to continue with what I'm
doing. I'm going to walk to Marisha's smear.
Schmear?
LIAM: Yeah, I mean, half her body's gone.
ASHLEY: That's fine. Don't know what I'm doing, I
was weird as a 15-year-old, so I'm going to walk
over to her body, what's left, and get my hands in
it. And I'm going to stare him in the eye, and I'm
going to smear it.
LIAM: You guys watch in horror as your friend
Ashley, pushed to the brink, crouches down and
shoves her hands up into the hollowed-out ribcage
of Marisha Ray, pulls her hands down, and slathers
it down her face, and suddenly we're in the Lord
of the Flies.
ASHLEY: Is her ribcage free and loose?
LIAM: Loose? I mean, yeah, she's a third of her
former weight.
ASHLEY: I'm going to put it over my head.
LIAM: That's your whole action. Okay.
ASHLEY: That's fine.
MARISHA: Wait, you're holding me?
MATT: You're wearing her like a scarecrow?
LIAM: Ashley picks up Marisha's broken open chest
cavity and head and matches the form of demogorgon
somewhat and puts a second head on herself.
MARISHA: What?
TRAVIS: Yep.
MARISHA: This is like what I want to have happen
when I die.
LIAM: You're out of juice.
TALIESIN: Died like she lived.
ASHLEY: I don't know what to do.
MARISHA: Wear like me a spirit hood! Do it,
Ashley, do it!
MATT: She's puppeteering you like a Skeksis!
You're a Henson puppet!
LIAM: Demogorgon's turn. Do you want to do
anything, Travis?
TRAVIS: Oh sure, I just want to fucking run like a
rabbit, man.
LIAM: Well, you're floating in the air. You want
to try to break free of his grip?
TRAVIS: I'm going to go with it.
LIAM: All right. You're going to go with it?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: He takes one step forward with Sam on the
leg, going for the ride, and Travis floats
forward, right up between the two thing's heads
and the angry one on this side goes (growling) and
takes the upper half of your body into its mouth
and the other one more daintily goes (chomping)
and pulls a leg free, and child Travis is ripped
in half in front of you, blood raining down on Sam
down below.
TRAVIS: You hear a really girly scream from inside
the one mouth.
SAM: But love conquers all!
LAURA: Oh my god!
LIAM: Matt, what would you like to do?
MATT: Well, I've spent the entirety of the last
six seconds just staring at the place on the
ground where Marisha was crushed. So I haven't
really been paying attention. Loosely paying
attention to Ashley rummaging through her remains
and then wearing them like a wintertime jacket.
ASHLEY: Sorry!
MATT: But my fists are clenched, they're shaking,
the tears are streaming down my face, and whatever
plan we had is out the window, and I just rush
towards the demogorgon, screaming. (screams) And
I'm going to Thunderwave him.
LIAM: Yes! Do it!
MATT: So he needs to make a constitution saving
throw.
LIAM: Are we doing anything about Sam?
MATT: I don't fucking care about Sam right now, I
just want to hurt this thing.
LIAM: Got it.
SAM: I'm a child, Matt!
LIAM: Got it. And it's, what is it, it's
constitution? Help me.
MATT: Constitution. I'm just like, tears down my
face, just (screaming).
LIAM: Okay. Sam, make a constitution save.
SAM: 16 plus-- there's no number written there.
MATT: You made it, he succeeds.
LIAM: Yeah. Okay, so roll for damage.
MATT: That is 13.
LIAM: 13? Okay.
MATT: 13 thunder damage.
LIAM: You take six points of damage. Matt runs up
in anguish and just rage-terror screams and for no
reason at all, a blast of energy just goes
(explosion noise) right out of him, rips the
clothes off of Sam Riegel's child back, leaving
scars all over him. And the demogorgon just shifts
his foot a little bit. And he'd like to use a
legendary action to stare at Crazy Pants Johnson.
And you look at these two heads, now looking at
you, and their eyes seem to swirl in a miasma of
hatred, and you feel your mind just go. Roll a
d10, please.
ASHLEY: Okay.
MATT: As my bonus action on my turn?
LIAM: Yes.
MATT: I now realise that I accidentally hit Sam,
and I'm like, Sam. We have to end this now. Let's
do this. And you get an inspiration die, d6.
LIAM: Okay. What did you roll on the d10?
ASHLEY: I rolled a nine.
LIAM: A nine? Oh. You felt your gorge rise up.
You're covered in the guts of your friend,
Marisha. This is really weird, that thing is a
giant! But you've got to fight it, right? Yeah,
I'm okay! I'm okay! And you steel yourself.
SAM: Nice. She's hardcore.
LIAM: Laura, what would you like to do?
LAURA: As soon as I see it tear apart Travis?
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: I'm going to just turn the other way and
just start swimming out.
TRAVIS: Yeah!
(laughter)
LIAM: Okay, I'll just put you there on the map.
LAURA: Nope! Nope, nope, nope!
MATT: She takes the nope action.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Triple dash!
LIAM: You start to swim. You feel a serpent slide
past your rib cage as you go, and you freak out as
you swim--
LAURA: I'm going to take my stick and hit it!
LIAM: You can't do that, because two clawed feet
latch into your back and lift you up, out of the
water. You are now dangling about 20 feet-- yeah,
20 feet above the water. Here. Just dog paddling
to nothing. And that's its turn. And Taliesin,
what would you like to do?
TALIESIN: I get the sneaking suspicion that we're
screwed.
TRAVIS: No, we're doing good.
MATT: Yeah, on the ropes, man. On the ropes.
SAM: He's looking pretty rough.
TRAVIS: This is where we turn the tide.
LAURA: He's definitely bloodied.
TALIESIN: I'm feeling a little like this might be
the end. I'm not feeling pretty
good about this, so--
MARISHA: Walk into the ocean.
TALIESIN: I'm just going to flick it off, and the
one, the little creature on the right--
LIAM: This guy?
TALIESIN: Yeah. Chill Touch. Just going to crush
that fucker as just a fuck-you.
LIAM: Okay. Make a ranged attack.
TALIESIN: Yeah. 15.
LIAM: Sure.
TALIESIN: I probably have to roll for damage on
that one because he's not tiny. Where's my d8s?
Two. That's two points of necrotic damage.
LIAM: Two points? Okay.
TALIESIN: It's just a 1d8, right?
LIAM: Yes, that's correct. It's 1d8.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
LIAM: All right. So you plant your hand down into
the sand, and you feel that same energy surge out
of your palm, and it bursts up under this
corpulent little pasty-faced dude, and it reaches
up and grabs him by the gut, and pulls away a love
handle in tentacle form, down into the ground. And
everybody around him just starts going (snarling),
and he's just got innards spilling out, going
(gravelly dying sounds).
LAURA: Gross.
TALIESIN: I'm going to move my Unseen Servant
underneath Laura, just in case, to try and pull
her to shore if she goes back down.
LIAM: All right, so your Unseen Servant moves just
below Laura, and he uses his legendary action, and
the tail whips out and goes (whipping sound), and
you watch as two-thirds of Taliesin's child guts are
ripped out and he just falls, face forward, down
into the sand, and he is dead, and the Unseen
Servant vanishes.
LAURA: Oh no!
LIAM: Sam, what would you like to do?
SAM: Me?
LIAM: Yeah.
SAM: I'm partially naked.
SAM: I'm hugging a demogorgon. I would like to
climb up a little up his leg.
LIAM: Okay.
SAM: And just say: Kill them, but save me. I will
fan you and get you food, and whatever. Just kill
them all. They're nothing, just save me. Just save
me.
LIAM: Okay.
SAM: That's it.
LIAM: Okay. Ashley.
SAM: Do I have to roll on anything?
LIAM: Huh?
SAM: Do I need to roll?
LIAM: I mean, you already tried to persuade this
dude.
SAM: All right. Then I got nothing.
LIAM: Sure. Make a persuasion, at disadvantage.
SAM: At disadvantage?
LIAM: Yes.
MATT: You can add your inspiration dice, if you
want.
SAM: Well, it's a natural one.
MATT: Oh. You probably shouldn't. You should hold
off on that. Save it for the next-- oh wait.
LIAM: Ashley, what would you like to do?
ASHLEY: Okay.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: Your head up here. Listen.
TRAVIS: She starts with "listen." (laughs)
ASHLEY: We already know what's going to happen
here. We know we're going to die. But, guess what?
After this, we go to another world, so you know
what? I don't like leading, and I don't like
following, you motherfucker! Is my slingshot
ready?
LIAM: No, you didn't have a chance to get to
that.
ASHLEY: I'm going to take out a rock out of my
pocket, and I'm going to throw it at him.
LIAM: Go for it. Make a ranged attack.
ASHLEY: Okay. What am I doing?
LIAM: Roll a d20.
ASHLEY: I don't add anything, do I?
LIAM: You might! It would be, for a ranged attack,
if it's not a weapon. It's an improvised weapon.
Nothing.
MATT: Well, dex or strength would be plus two.
You're not proficient with it
LIAM: Let's do the dex.
MATT: So, plus two to whatever you rolled.
ASHLEY: (laughs) A six.
LIAM: The rock bounces off of his belly
button-type area.
ASHLEY: I don't care. I did it. I didn't mean for
it to actually hurt you.
LIAM: Right.
MATT: She has that much control!
LIAM: Okay, well, the next thing that happens is
the double-armed tentacle comes down and wraps
around your neck. And you watch as (splitting
noise) and you see two heads spin out to the
ocean.
TALIESIN: You killed it!
LIAM: 40 feet.
LAURA: Oh no!
SAM: Who's left?
LAURA: Me and Matt and Sam.
SAM: My plan is working; I'm still alive!
LAURA: I think he doesn't realize you're there.
LIAM: What would you like to do, Matt?
MATT: All right, staring this thing down, my
eyes-- I can't see anything because the water, so
I rip the glasses off the front of my face and
throw them behind me on the beach and staring up
at it I say: I know everything about you. I've
seen your pictures, I've read every single aspect
of your existence. And here's the fun part: when
it all comes down to it, you're just a figment of
some fat guy's imagination! Vicious Mockery.
LIAM: Yeah!
ASHLEY: Yes!
LIAM: Legit!
MATT: Nice, that's-- well, it makes a wisdom
saving throw.
SAM: How do you want to do this?
LIAM: What did you roll?
MATT: Well, my DC is 13.
LIAM: 13, okay. You see the angrier one on this
side going (growls, huffs, growls louder)
MATT: Yeah!
LIAM: And the other head swivels around so
they're both looking at you, and they stare into
your insecure little 12-year-old soul. Roll a d10,
Matthew.
MATT: Yeah. That's a sensitive place. Ten?
LIAM: Ten? You have played too much fucking DND.
Nothing happens! You hold your own against the
demogorgon.
TRAVIS: (laughs) You've played too much DND.
LIAM: Laura, what would you like to do?
LAURA: I'm going to take my sticks out and I'm
going to try to stab the tentacle that's holding
me up in the air.
LIAM: Roll to make an attack.
LAURA: Do I add anything? My dex?
LIAM: Yes, your dex.
LAURA: 11.
LIAM: Okay.
LAURA: I'm trying to break out my grapple.
LIAM: Right. Well, that would be a strength check.
Do you want to break out of the grapple?
LAURA: Oh. Well, I'm just going to try to-- no,
I'm going to attack the tentacle.
LIAM: Okay. Well, that doesn't do shit because
he's got you so firmly grasping in his taloned
feet that you can't turn around and get at him.
LAURA: Oh, then I try to break out of the
grapple!
LIAM: No, what happened was you tried to get him
with a stick and you couldn't turn around. You got
a bonus action?
LAURA: I don't know what I can do as a bonus
action.
SAM: She's a rogue.
LIAM: Rogue.
LAURA: I can't disengage; I'm not a high enough
level. I'm just a me.
LIAM: Level of Laura?
LAURA: Yeah, level of Laura at 13, 12, or
whatever.
LIAM: Okay. You hear a little sizzling sound and
you feel the thing's body flex against you, and
then you don't even know what happened; there is a
noxious fume all around you going into your eyes
and your nose. Everything burns; your throat and
your nose burn, the insides of your ears burn. I
would like you to make a con save.
LAURA: Okay. 11!
LIAM: Okay. Your body locks up. You can't move and
he lets go. You fall into the water, frozen.
SAM: That's nice!
TALIESIN: In theory, you'd be caught by my Unseen
Servant.
LIAM: No, that vanished when you died.
TALIESIN: Oh, that vanished when I died!
LAURA: Oh no!
MATT: You fall just in time to see this floating
Taliesin go (wind whooshing).
That would suck so bad.
LIAM: Sam, what would you like to do?
MARISHA: I'm okay, I'm okay, I'm not okay!
SAM: I climb up higher.
LIAM: Now make an athletics check.
SAM: Sure. Natural 20!
LIAM: Oh my god, how high do you want to go?
SAM: All the way up to its ear.
LIAM: Done. You scrabble up like a little spider
monkey all the way up, panicked, climbing up on
top. "Hi!" And you're there.
SAM: I can sing you show tunes! I know doo-wop
songs! I will do your bidding forever if you just
let me live!
LIAM: And your voices stops as the sharp end of
his tail splits through the back of your skull and
breaks your face open entirely.
SAM: I can work with this!
LIAM: Beautiful, beautiful smile. That beautiful
smile gone.
TRAVIS: And then there was two.
MARISHA: Rodgers and Hammerstein.
SAM: True.
MATT: That'll kill you.
LIAM: The demogorgon bends over and looks down at
you, Matthew, and somehow, you knew this was the
way it would always be. And a giant, ropey foot
rises up and you don't see shit. Laura, what would
you like to do? Oh, she's not here.
SAM: Oh my god, she disappeared.
LIAM: She's also drowning. We don't need her,
then. Okay. Hey, I want that, yeah. So, her body
frozen in the ocean, water seeping in. She feels
her throat constrict and choke, and everything
goes quiet. Not that quiet. There we go. The
vision blurs and turns a pure, merciful white.
And that's where we'll take our break.
MARISHA: Oh, what?
MATT: All righty!
SAM: We're dead! End of session.
LIAM: We'll just talk about it for an hour after
we come back.
MATT: Probably.
MARISHA: I've had this dream.
LIAM: I did have this dream. This is based on a
nightmare I had.
MATT: Oh, what?
ASHLEY: That's a terrible one.
LIAM: It was real bad.
TRAVIS: Did Ashley wear the upper torso of
Marisha in your dream?
LIAM: No, none of you were there. It was just me
on a godforsaken beach. In my dream, these things,
it wasn't demogorgon, it was Revelations, and they
were all on shitty wooden scaffolding, stretching
in every direction for miles. And I just felt that
big and I was like, "Well, this is it." And that
was the nightmare.
SAM: I dreamt that I was late to a plane.
(laughter)
LIAM: That your eyesight was one tick off of
20/20. Dreadful. Well, guys that was a lot of fun.
We laughed. We cried. We died. We'll see you in a
few.
MARISHA: Oh, watch the Tabletop promo, it's real
good. We're real proud of it.
LIAM: Is this mid-break, this guy? Yeah, sorry,
before I forget! Giveaway! I have got a Wyrmwood
dice vault made of pink ivory wood.
MARISHA: Yeah, you do!
LIAM: You wanna get that code word: demogorgon!
MARISHA and LIAM: Demogorgon!
MARISHA: Spell it correctly if you want to win!
Demi-gorgon.
LIAM: Demo.
MARISHA: Demo-gorgon.
LIAM: This could be yours in hell.
MARISHA: Chat will get it.
MATT: Chat will get it.
[break]
LIAM: It won't work this time. Hey guys! Welcome
back. So, right off the top, we have been doing
this show for hundreds and hundreds of hours, and
for the first time ever we have a player going
home sick. Laura is tapping out. She probably has
got the same thing Brian Foster had. We'll all be
next, yay.
TRAVIS: Especially because we French kiss all the
time.
LIAM: So, I'll miss twinnie, but I want twinnie to
be a part of the story, so I will include her.
She'll be there, but not physically on set. What
else? So our winner for the dice vault over the
break was YassieXD. YassieXD, you now have a
lovely box for your dice to put it in!
MATT: Congrats.
(cheering)
LIAM: Man, I'm thrown. I'm thrown, my friend went
home. Oh, well. What else do we do now, do I just
start? Is that what I do?
MATT: Jump right in, motherfucker.
LIAM: All right.
TRAVIS: Everybody's dead, so...
MARISHA: So we're all dead?
SAM: Good game, good game.
LIAM: This is the post-mortem.
MARISHA: We built Dis post-mortem?
SAM: Nope.
LIAM: Darkness.
SAM: Darkness.
LIAM: Quiet. You have no sense of time. Minutes,
days, you don't know. A voice barks out, "Okay,
"that was really good, let's go right back into
another one." Ashley, your eyes flutter open and
squint in the glare of bright white light from all
sides. They adjust. "Guys, we good? I wanna go
"right into another." You look around. You're lying
in a large white room. The walls are padded with
soft cloth material.
TALIESIN: Oh no.
LIAM: Ashley, you sit up--
ASHLEY: This is my nightmare!
LIAM: -- and see Neil? Naughty Dog creative
director Neil Druckmann?
(laughter)
LIAM: Walking over towards you. You realize there
are cameras everywhere, lining the walls, there's
monitors nearby, cables. You see a very familiar
crew at their stations. You look down. Oh, shit.
P-cap suit. You are in a full performance-capture
suit. You are all lying on your backs in full
performance-capture suits, and you're still
fucking kids?
(laughter)
LIAM: Neil, with his glorious beard, walks up, but
calls out over his shoulder, says, "Liam, I'm
"sorry, don't get too comfortable, we're going to
move on to your scene pretty soon. Don't pass out
"on me." And you see over on the lounge-y area, a
pair of shoes lying off the side of a couch, and
you hear a dorky voice say, "Got it. Okay."
"Ashley, Ashley, can I grab a word over here?"
ASHLEY: Yes. Yes, please.
LIAM: He's ahead of you, though, by like 20 feet.
ASHLEY: Yeah.
LIAM: You walk over and you see he's doing that
thing where he's standing on the outside of his
feet, looking down. When he senses that you've
walked up, he says, "Question. For the first line
"of this scene, what are you feeling right now?"
ASHLEY: I'm feeling... confused.
LIAM: "Okay."
ASHLEY: A little... I think I just need... How are
you feeling about it? Like, what are you feeling--
what is missing? What's going on?
LIAM: Let me just interject as the Dungeon Master
and let you know that he is not showing any
recognition that you are 14 at all.
ASHLEY: Okay.
LIAM: At all. "I don't know, I mean, I think that
was just the first take, I shouldn't second-guess
"myself, but do you think that that line is
something that you would say?"
ASHLEY: Is that line something I would say? Is
there-- maybe if it just sounded weird-- maybe
there's another way to say it? If you had to just
spitball, what would be another way that I could
say it?
LIAM: "Okay. This time, I want you to..." Strokes
his beard. "Doubt."
ASHLEY: Doubt.
LIAM: "I mean, I don't want to give you--"
ASHLEY: Do you have the sides on you, actually? Do
you have the script on you?
LIAM: "Colla, could we get the sides in for
everybody?" Colla comes running in. You guys are
all getting up to your feet, also kids in full
performance-capture suits.
MATT: I just...
SAM and LIAM: Aww.
LIAM: Everyone's taller than you. Bill Beemer
comes running over, and he starts going, "Gah,
"this is weird," but he hands out sides to you all.
You can open your envelopes now,
looking at sides.
MARISHA: Are these sides? Yeah!
MATT: Inspire Bill Beemer?
LIAM: And you start reminding yourselves of the
scene that you've never seen before. Yeah, yeah,
absorb that. Ashley, while you're reading, out of
the corner of your eye you see Neil off on the
side just sorta like flipping a prop knife over
and over again absent-mindedly while he thinks.
Drops it.
ASHLEY: Can I-- Neil.
LIAM: "Yeah."
ASHLEY: Can I have that prop knife?
LIAM: "Sure."
ASHLEY: I just wanna see if it'll make the scene
any different.
(laughter)
SAM: Such a good actor.
LIAM: "Are you guys good? Laura, your accent kind
of wandered just a little bit,
"you want me to get J.B.?"
(laughter)
MATT: Now this has become her nightmare.
LIAM: Laura makes the most stinkface you've ever
seen. She says, "No, I'm good." From her very
short stature. "I was just a little off that
time."
"Okay, do we wanna go for another one? Is
everyone feeling--"
ASHLEY: Can I-- hey, Liam?
LIAM: "Yeah?"
ASHLEY: Can you come here for just like two
seconds?
LIAM: "Okay."
MATT: As this is happening, I walk up to Neil, I'm
like, by the way, I know we've met a number of
times, but I just wanna tell you, it's a great
pleasure to finally have an opportunity to work
with you.
(laughter)
MARISHA: And I walk up behind and I go, hi. I'm
his girlfriend. (nervous laugh)
LIAM: (whispers) You know you're already on the
job, right? That was me. Neil says, "Oh, of
"course, of course, I mean yeah, yeah. I'm sorry,
what were you saying?"
ASHLEY: I just wanted to talk to Liam for just
like two seconds.
LIAM: Yeah, Liam's already wandered up. He's in
full performance-capture suit. He's an adult.
Yeah. And he's looking down, but whatever.
ASHLEY: (laughs) I just-- I forgot what I was
gonna ask. It's fine. I just wanted to-- I was
gonna ask you something, but I forgot. It's good
to see you. Good to see you. Go back to bed.
LIAM: "We're all glad to have you back in town.
I'm gonna go back to the couch."
TRAVIS: Hey, wait, wait, before you go, Liam. What
do we look like to you?
LIAM: "Assholes." Walks back to the couch.
TALIESIN: Fuck.
ASHLEY: Wait.
LIAM: "Yeah?"
ASHLEY: If you had to guess how old I was, what
would you guess?
LIAM: "This seems like a dangerous question to
me."
ASHLEY: Don't let it be dangerous. I can take it.
LIAM: "Really?"
ASHLEY: Oh, yeah. Straight-up, how old do you
think I look?
LIAM: "I feel like there's no right answer to give
to this question?"
ASHLEY: There's no right answer.
LIAM: "You're-- I mean, I know it's early 30s.
33?"
ASHLEY: Bingo.
LIAM: "Hey!" And he does a little dance and just
dances his way back up to the couch area,
lands down.
ASHLEY: Guys.
SAM: I guess people see us as super-old.
MARISHA: Or super-professional! Look at this
velcro suit!
SAM: Oh, you don't wear these?
MARISHA: Like once. And then the game got
canceled, so what's it matter?
LIAM: "Guys. Guys. I mean, do we need to talk this
scene out, or do you want to do another one, or?"
ASHLEY: We're...
SAM: We're professionals, we're gonna do this.
TRAVIS: I don't wanna speak for Laura, but she
doesn't really like to rehearse beforehand,
she just--
ASHLEY: Let's just jump right in.
LIAM: "Jump right in?"
ASHLEY: I'm sure we're gonna have notes again.
LIAM: "Okay, we're gonna take another one, uno
mas." Bill Beemer--
MATT: Is it general T-pose, or A-T-pose? Okay.
T-pose.
LIAM: "You're good." Bill Beemer comes out and
says,
"All right, Savage Starlight, scene 23B,
take two. Audio rolling."
MATT: Guys, wait!
LIAM: "Camera rolling. Okay, Neil, the floor is
yours." He wanders off, Neil backs off at the
volume, off to the edge on the wall, out of the
way, and says, "Okay, the deck has just blown up.
"First position. And action."
ASHLEY: "You knew this was gonna happen. The
entire time, you were biding your time, and now
"you're driving this fleet into the ground!"
MATT: "The Federation is crumbling. You know that.
Everyone on this ship knows it. You can't stop the
"inevitable, Cass."
SAM: (yells in pain) Pickup. (yells in pain)
TALIESIN: "Commander Bettany--"
SAM: Pickup. (yells in pain) "Oh, god!"
TALIESIN: "Commander Bettany! Fenton, he's hurt,
bad!"
MARISHA: "We're not gonna have a problem here, are
we, Commander?"
TRAVIS: "Well, that's gonna fucking depend on you,
isn't it?"
MATT: "Well? What's it gonna be, Cass?"
ASHLEY: "God damn it!"
LIAM: Laura runs in from the side. "Cass! He set
it loose! Argus! He's killed us all!" She's 12.
"Explosion!"
(yelling)
MATT: All right, T-pose.
SAM: Man, her South African accent is terrible.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: All over the place.
LIAM: Neil is laughing off to the side, and says,
"Okay, did we get the April Fools' take out of the
"way? I mean, I don't understand."
TRAVIS: Yeah.
ASHLEY: Yeah, we can do it for real. I think--
MARISHA: That was just rehearsal, right?
LIAM: "Yeah, it's all rehearsal, is kind of the
mindset."
ASHLEY: Anything else you want us to do?
LIAM: "Well, I mean, I don't want to give you a
result-oriented direction, but.
"Come over here for a second."
ASHLEY: You do him so good.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: Yes.
LIAM: "So I want it to come from you." I'm looking
for something in these notes, I can't find it.
"And, you know, this time, when you're confronting
him, don't look right at him, look back at your
"men. And let's just see what that does."
ASHLEY: Okay.
LIAM: "Sam, do you have the line?"
SAM: Yeah, I got it now. Sorry, Neil. I didn't
know if it was "oh lord!" or "oh god!" I got in my
head, and that's not a place you want me to be.
LIAM: "Well, that's okay, even if you lose the
lines, just play it through to the end. You know,
"we can use it."
SAM: Hey, can I see you for a second?
LIAM: "Sure."
SAM: Laura's accent is really throwing me. That's
gonna be fixed later, right?
LIAM: "Yeah."
SAM: Okay, okay. I can do this.
LIAM: Shakes his head, walks back to the side.
TRAVIS: Bill? Beemer?
LIAM: "Yeah?"
TRAVIS: Hey, Bill, what time is it, man? How long
have we been here?
LIAM: "Two hours? What is it, 9:30?"
TRAVIS: 9:30, okay, yeah.
MARISHA: 405 traffic.
TRAVIS: Right, okay.
LIAM: "Okay, okay, I feel like we're losing
momentum, so let's just do one more, we'll go one
"more time. Bill?" And Bill comes out and says,
"All right, Savage Starlight, scene 23B, take
"four. Audio rolling. Camera rolling. All right.
You're good to go."
And Neil shouts, "Explosion! And action."
ASHLEY: "You knew this was gonna happen. The
entire time, you were biding your time, and now you're
"driving this fleet to the ground!"
MATT: "The Federation is crumbling. You know that.
Everyone on this ship knows it. You can't stop the
"inevitable, Cass."
SAM: (yells in pain) "Oh, god! Oh, god!"
TALIESIN: "Commander Bettany! Fenton, he's hurt.
Bad."
LIAM: Right at that moment, you feel the same
sickening nauseating pull on your every nerve,
your guts feel like they're going to drop out of
your body, and an invisible wall of force, like a
sheet of radiation pushes its way through your
body, and as it does so, the ground around you,
the walls of the performance-capture studio split
and break in places, and tendrils of cable, oily
and slick, spatter out like a digusting birth of
pythons wriggling and spreading out on the floor.
And the wall's a techno-organic orgy spewing with
malice all around you. The camera equipment around
you begins to twist and break and reconfigure in
disjointed movements, reforming into broken,
misshapen, spider-like legs, masses of metal and
power cables either cut loose from them or spool
around their bodies, these things. Before you can
react, you watch as Colla, the cameraman, is
pushed down onto the ground and mangled by
spinning metallic arms on the bottom of what used
to be a camera.
TRAVIS: He's ripped!
LIAM: Neil, stunned, backs up. "I-- I-- I--" Roll
for initiative.
(yelling)
SAM: What are we fighting?
ASHLEY: Are fighting Colla?
MARISHA: But the sides were so mediocre!
TALIESIN: Oh no. Oh no.
SAM: What are we fighting?
TRAVIS: (laughs) It's actually-- you fucking made
it. It's Sony.
MATT: Yeah, it is.
MARISHA: Oh my god, it is. Look! Look, it's the
control room!
MATT: I love that it has the volume tape and
everything. It's so good.
LIAM: This is a miniature of Rasputin. And now
it's Neil Druckmann.
(laughter)
MATT: I feel like you have to give him that after
this, now.
LIAM: Yeah, yeah, I think that's-- won't be
needing that anymore. Okay. So. Oh, Neil needs to
roll for-- and so does Laura.
MARISHA: Where's Crafty?
TRAVIS: Outside, unfortunately.
MARISHA: God damn, every time, and we have to
share it with the other stage. Bullshit.
SAM: Ashley has a prop knife.
LIAM: Okay, 20 to 25?
ASHLEY: 20.
LIAM: Yeah? Okay. 15 to 20?
MATT: 18.
LIAM: 18. Ten to 15?
MARISHA: 14.
LIAM: Five to ten? Okay, so that is-- oh, I can do
Laura and Neil. And then zero to five?
SAM: Three.
TALIESIN: Two.
TRAVIS: Natural one.
LIAM: Whoa!
MATT: Aw, buddy.
LIAM: Three, two, one? Wow. Okay. Oh, okay. Okay.
So Colla is soup on the ground, and everything's
broken and bent all around you. You also see one
of the computer banks up on the platform here, the
computers have wrapped together and formed into a
sort of walking tank. Rickety, but has closed on
the sofa, where Liam was taking a nap. What would
you like to do?
ASHLEY: (laughs) Where am I?
LIAM: Yeah, I'm gonna have to help you all. You
are right here.
ASHLEY: Okay.
SAM: And there's robits?
LIAM: There's camera and mocap-- this thing came
out of the ground.
SAM: What is it?
LIAM: I don't know.
SAM: What does it look like?
LIAM: It looks like black poles and computer
monitor and cables and cords and exposed wiring
and motherboards wrapped together, and rickety,
but moving, and everything else, these other ones,
were things that were out and just wrapped
together. This broke out of the floor. And
Ashley's right here.
ASHLEY: And Colla's on the ground?
LIAM: Colla is here, and is guts.
ASHLEY: He's dead.
LIAM: He's gone. The cameraman.
ASHLEY: Sorry, Colla. And what's the other-- is
that just another camera? Behind? Yeah, that.
LIAM: This is camera, camera, computers,
computers, nightmare-fuel.
ASHLEY: So the thing that we're trying to kill is
that one? Or are all the cameras bad?
We don't know.
LIAM: And the crew that are scattered around on
the outskirts are running. All the people over
here, I don't have minis for them all, but they're
all booking for the door.
One person ran out here.
ASHLEY: Okay.
MARISHA: So they can see the crazy.
LIAM: Everyone sees the crazy. You're still kids.
MARISHA: According to us. No one else.
LIAM: Can tell that you're kids? Yeah, no one has
acknowledged that you're kids, and they've got
bigger fish to fry at the moment.
MARISHA: Production.
ASHLEY: Liam! Are you okay?
LIAM: (shrieks)
ASHLEY: I'll take that as a yes, 'cause that means
you're alive.
TRAVIS: That was adult-Liam, too.
MATT: Yeah. Yeah.
LIAM: True to life. True to life.
ASHLEY: Ah, man. How close can I get to one of the
cameras? The ones behind?
LIAM: Five, ten, 15, 20, 25. You can get right up
on this one or this one. This one killed Colla.
ASHLEY: Oh, shit. I don't have anything to do to
it. Oh, shoot, I don't know what to do!
LIAM: Well, I'm gonna pass to Matt in another 20
seconds.
ASHLEY: Okay.
MARISHA: You're Ashley motherfucking Johnson.
ASHLEY: I'm gonna try-- I don't know what-- that
doesn't mean-- are there any wires that're exposed
on the biggie?
TRAVIS: Take a bite out of Sam.
LIAM: It's all wires. There's no hardened shell,
this isn't a military machine cased inside of
armor, it's all just a mess of motherboard and
wires.
ASHLEY: Okay. I'm gonna try to go to the big
camera.
LIAM: Yeah.
ASHLEY: And start yanking some wires, maybe where
I think it can't see me.
LIAM: Okay. Where it can't see you? Okay. So
you're gonna reach out? Well, make an attack. Roll
a d20.
ASHLEY: Okay. And then what do I add to it?
LIAM: Your strength modifier. Well, to hit? Yeah.
ASHLEY: A nine. And I do add the strength? Okay.
Yeah, so, 11.
LIAM: You get your hands on there and you pull,
and nothing fucking happens.
ASHLEY: Shit. Knew I shouldn't have rolled that
one. I knew it was a bad die.
LIAM: What do you wanna do, Matt?
MATT: Just looking around at the ground, these
things are made of cables. Are there loose, slack
cables that were once attached to the cameras?
LIAM: Sure, there's a lot of shit scattered
around. When they formed, some pieces just fell
away, so there's bits of pole and--
MATT: Okay. I'm gonna move slightly around and
towards the consoles a bit, grabbing whatever
looks to be longest, most slack non-attached
wire--
LIAM: Wire, okay.
MATT: And I'm gonna grab it and throw it up over
the scaffolding that holds the various mocap
cameras there. Grab the other side and look back
to Marisha and be like, help me pull this onto it
and start backing up towards her the rest of my
movement, holding the cables that are wrapped
around the scaffolding.
LIAM: Okay. I'm gonna say that that's your whole
turn, getting it primed and ready. Yes.
MARISHA: What?
MATT: Trying to pull the scaffolding onto it.
LIAM: All right, Marisha.
MARISHA: Huh?
LIAM: 16-year-old in a mocap suit. What do you
want to do?
MARISHA: I thought I'd be famous by now. Okay.
Wait. What? You're pulling-- okay. I'm gonna look
for its power source.
LIAM: All right. Make an investigation check.
SAM: There's a diesel engine.
MARISHA: Aw, that's not too bad. 14.
LIAM: 14. Well, there is-- I mean, it's climbing
out of a gap in the ground, right? And there is a
sickly green light glowing from under its butt.
And there are also, you see, two little screens.
You see a broken fragment of monitor, and then a
very small, almost like a flip-up on a camera
screen, and on it you see the word flicker on,
"NO". And then it disappears. And you see the
same-- and it's like a pale green. And you see
that same color glowing from underneath this big,
spherical body.
MARISHA: Is there a cord connected to that? No?
Ah, jeez. Okay. I say, I feel like this is a
really shitty update. And then I'm gonna try and
punch it in its face.
SAM: Punch the camera.
LIAM: So Matt is there going, come on, come on,
and she just runs up and starts fucking whaling on
it like a brawler.
MATT: Yeah, no, this is a familiar duality, here.
LIAM: Yeah, that's about right.
MATT: I have a plan, what are you-- okay.
MARISHA: Ten for the first one.
LIAM: What about the second? Just roll for both.
MARISHA: Second one is real bad. Real bad. That's
a four. No, five.
LIAM: Okay, you just start whaling-- and you've
trained, you know some martial arts, so you pull
out some of your--
MARISHA: No, no, five plus two. Seven.
LIAM: Okay, you pull out a little bit of your
training, and you get (impact sounds) and it
fucking hurts your knuckles and you dented it and
it just goes (whirring sounds) and that's the end
of your turn.
MARISHA: Fuck, this is like a claw machine! Fuck
that, it's rigged. (yells)
MATT: As you do that, I'm like, I told you to-- my
dick's in the wind, here, somebody help me!
LIAM: Laura screams, Neil! Run! And she runs at
this thing and grabs a piece of-- like the end of
a tripod, like a tripod leg from a camera, she
picks it up and swings down and whacks at this
thing and hurts it. She smashes off this, whatever
this spherical piece is, so it's without a top.
And she gets, okay. Good. You guys don't need to
know. All right, she smashes it and a whole piece
breaks off. They're not-- except for this guy--
they're not that solidly built, and she snaps the
connection where this round part is, and it breaks
off and hangs limply, but it's still moving, it
goes, (whirring sounds).
TRAVIS: Get him out of the volume!
LIAM: Neil runs over and he just jumps on top of
it. Because one of his favorite friends is there.
Oh, man. I'm sorry, Neil. You rolled a natural
one. He jumps and climbs and scrabbles up it and
goes, (yells), and his beard is just blowing in
the wind that doesn't exist, and his foot slips
and he falls backward and lands flat on his back
and knocks the wind out of himself. And has just
fallen prone on the ground. It was a one. Sam,
what do you wanna do?
SAM: I'm going to go assist Matt in what his plan
was. So are we grabbing the same thing and
pulling?
MATT: Yeah, the cables have wrapped around the
scaffolding that holds the mocap cameras, and
trying to pull it down onto the large IMC to pin
it.
SAM: I'm gonna pull hard. Real hard.
LIAM: Okay. Make a strength check with advantage.
SAM: Yeah, sure. Okay, terrible.
MATT: You still have your bardic inspiration.
SAM: I do. I'll use it. That helps. Plus
strength?
LIAM: Strength.
SAM: Okay, that's ten.
LIAM: A ten? That's the number I was imagining.
SAM: Oh wait, no. Five plus one plus six is 12.
LIAM: 12. You guys, at the same time, go (effort
sounds), and you pull, and the thing goes
(shrieking metal), and a huge piece of it swings
down and goes in an arch and smacks into-- I think
you were maybe imagining bringing the whole thing
down, but you broke it, and a piece swings down and
goes (impact sound). Smashes into it for--
SAM: Hey, it's good.
LIAM: Okay.
MARISHA: I'm still looking for a mini-USB port.
LIAM: Smashes into the side and breaks away one of
five-- I know that's four-- but one of five legs
totally snaps and breaks off, and Sam, as you yank
and you watch it smash into it and it rights
itself, you see the same two screens, the fragment
of one, and the little one that Marisha saw, and
you see a name blink up, and it says, "SAM", and
it's gone. Taliesin.
TALIESIN: This is still a dream, so I'm going to
see if this thing still works.
LIAM: Go for it, yeah, absolutely.
TALIESIN: Is the one that Laura attacked still
looking dangerous, or is it just looking
irritated?
LIAM: It looked kind of fucked up from the get-go,
but it looks majorly fucked up, a couple of sparks
fly off of it just as you look.
TALIESIN: Okay. I'm going to go to the one that no
one's messed with and just hope that this is still
gonna work.
LIAM: Okay, make a ranged attack.
MATT: Yeah, it's not focus-fire.
TALIESIN: That's a 23.
LIAM: Yeah, your eyes glow a dark blackish-purple.
This is the life you were meant for, Taliesin
Jaffe. And you don't slam your hand down into the
ground. You're going for this guy, right?
TALIESIN: I was going for the other one.
LIAM: The big one?
TALIESIN: No, the one in the far corner.
LIAM: The far corner? Oh, okay. You still don't
put your hand on the ground, you just reach out of
anger, you're so furious that fucking demogorgon
didn't take your bargain, and a long spaghetti arm
of hentai lashes out from your hand and reaches
across the room and spikes through its "head",
seemingly. Roll for damage.
SAM: Two.
TALIESIN: Four.
LIAM: Four. It goes right through the heart of it
and breaks the connection from what would be its
head if it was a head, and it swings down and
hangs limply from the side, and it starts to juke
to the side here. It's still standing.
TALIESIN: Liam, are you okay? And I'm going to run
just to the edge of the volume.
LIAM: Okay. Travis, you're up.
TRAVIS: Well, where am I?
LIAM: You are here.
TRAVIS: Right there. I'm gonna take off the
certainly at this point very hot battery pack that
is attached to my stomach, peel it off the velcro,
and I'm gonna run at the giant arachnid demon
thing and I'm gonna bash one of its legs with the
hot battery.
LIAM: Okay. All right, roll for an attack.
TRAVIS: 14.
LIAM: You smash it with this piece of equipment,
and the equipment in your hand breaks into pieces
and does nothing.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Cool. Nice. Can I look up at it, see
if it flashes anything at me?
LIAM: It doesn't do anything. Another day in hell,
Travis, another day in hell. And it goes (whirring
noises) and two legs go (mechanical noises) and
dig into the side of your body.
(yelling)
LIAM: What's your armor class?
TRAVIS: 12.
LIAM: Okay. Too bad, so sad. All right. One stabs
into your thigh right here, and one goes in right
under your armpit, and you can feel them dig in,
and each goes in-- again, these things are scary,
I mean, camera equipment is not supposed to move
on its own, but they're not mecha from Metal
Gear-- but you are stabbed here and here, and it
slices in about an inch and a half on each side.
You take two points of damage.
TRAVIS: That's a lot for me.
LIAM: Off in the distance, you hear (whirring
sounds), and then you hear (screams, gurgling).
SAM: Liam's dead. That's okay.
TALIESIN: That's okay. He would've wanted it that
way. Wait.
SAM: He slowed us down.
MATT: To be fair, he wrote this. So.
LIAM: This thing is broken and tries to-- raises a
leg up, it goes (whirring sounds) and brings it
down at Druckmann and slams it down, and Druckmann
goes (effort sounds) and he rolls out of the way
of one and is missed. And then this thing. Oh.
What's your armor class?
ASHLEY: I'm sure you beat it by that 'oh'. 12.
LIAM: 12. Yes. You feel a broken sharp-edged
tripod leg stab through here and come out here.
You take five hit points of damage. You are
bleeding profusely from
the front of yourself now.
TRAVIS: Five, that's a lot.
SAM: You okay there?
LIAM: And, funnily enough, it's the top of round.
So what would you like to do with an arm still
pushed through your body?
ASHLEY: Okay.
LIAM: It hurts.
ASHLEY: I can't take it out 'cause I'll bleed out.
Is there any way to break off the arm?
LIAM: Sure, you can hit that motherfucker.
ASHLEY: All right. I'm gonna use my mocap knife.
LIAM: Okay.
(laughter)
LIAM: Roll to attack.
ASHLEY: Those are actually pretty strong.
TRAVIS: Masking tape and 'Ashley' written on it.
MATT: Well, if it's like the hardcover cast stuff,
then yeah, that could actually be substantial.
MARISHA: It could be a piece of plywood, it's hard
to say.
ASHLEY: Do I get advantage because it's mine?
LIAM: No, but you can add your proficiency bonus
'cause you're a rogue, and it's a dagger, and
your-- I'm gonna say strength here.
ASHLEY: So I would add both of those?
LIAM and MATT: Yes.
ASHLEY: 12.
LIAM: Oh, girl. It's rubber. It just bends to the
side as soon as you stab it down. Matt? Oh yeah,
do you wanna do anything else, do you wanna pull
away?
ASHLEY: I mean, I'm just gonna ask-- yeah, 'cause
I can't attack again, obviously. I'm gonna ask the
big thing, talk to me, what do you want?
LIAM: On that broken piece of screen down the
side, you see the lower half, you can make it out,
it's fragmented but you can see most of the word
'FORGIVE M--' And it's gone.
MARISHA: Okay, so I got a 'NO', you got--
SAM: 'SAM'.
MARISHA: 'SAM'. And then he said 'FORGIVE'.
SAM: 'FORGIVE M--'
MARISHA: 'FORGIVE M--'
SAM: For killing people.
ASHLEY: 'FORGIVE M--' or 'FORGIVENESS'?
MARISHA: I got a 'NO', he got a 'SAM', you got a
'FORGIVE M--'
LIAM: What would you like to do, Matt?
MATT: Well, I used all my spells in the previous
battles.
LIAM: Before this performance-capture stage?
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: You still feel-- you feel magical.
SAM: Does everything reset?
MATT: Okay, well, that changes things. Well,
first, I'm gonna go ahead and say, it's all right,
Ashley, you've spent a lot of time in this volume
before, you're still the queen of it. So I'll give
you a Healing Word with my bonus action.
ASHLEY: Hey!
MATT: And that's a five, you heal five.
ASHLEY: Yay! Thanks, Matt. So clutch.
MATT: And I'm gonna go ahead... so the leg that
broke off? I'm gonna go ahead and rush over to
pick it up, and like a giant metal baseball bat,
swing back and try and hit back at it
with its own leg.
LIAM: Yeah, you are. Go for it.
MATT: So it's like (yells). Not very good with it.
Is this at disadvantage?
LIAM: At disadvantage?
MATT: I'm not proficient--
LIAM: Nah. You're-- nah.
MATT: All right, so we'll say-- that's a 19?
Natural.
LIAM: Yeah, man.
MATT: Two for strength.
LIAM: Two for strength. Yeah. Absolutely hits.
Clocked that motherfucker. Roll a d4.
MATT: That is a two plus two. Four damage.
LIAM: Okay. You break off-- you were trying to
break off a leg, you said?
MATT: Trying to hit one of the other legs, yeah.
LIAM: Yeah. It breaks. It smashes, and the thing
lurches down to the side.
MATT: Yeah, I'm not going for the core, I'm just
going for its means of attack.
LIAM: Right, right, right. And it falls right in
front of you, and now the little camcorder-sized
screen falls right in front of your face, and you
see 'FORGIVE ME'. Gone.
MARISHA: What?
LIAM: Marisha, what would you like to do--
MATT: At the end of my turn, I shout, just 'cause
I'm really curious, let's not kill it yet, but
definitely disable it!
SAM: Noted.
LIAM: Marisha is up.
MARISHA: I look at Matt, and I say, don't kill it?
'Kay. And then I look for its memory card. It's
gotta have-- I'm thinking my production elements.
LIAM: Right, right, logic, I like it.
MARISHA: Yeah. It's gotta have a memory card
somewhere in there. How many gigs does it have?
It's hard to say. But if I immediately remove it.
LIAM: All right. Make an investigation check to
find its memory card.
MARISHA: Jesus fucking christ, all right. Oh my
god, that's a natural 20.
MATT: On the Snitch? Well, on your Snitch.
MARISHA: See? Look at it.
MATT: Yeah, that's an actual natural 20.
MARISHA: It's a natural 20.
LIAM: Okay. You see on the bottom of it, like a
fucking outie belly button, a cylinder, and on the
end of the cylinder's a slot, and it says right
above it, 'SD'.
MARISHA: Like output? Is it output? And I'm just
gonna go click. And see if it pulls out.
LIAM: It doesn't... it doesn't.
MARISHA: No? No pulling out of the SD card?
LIAM: No, you press it and-- I mean, it's going
(whirring sound) while you're doing this, you
definitely found something.
MARISHA: It's not connected to the cloud! They
don't have a backup drive!
LIAM: But pressing in does not then detach an SD
card and give you photographs or
shut the thing down.
(laughter)
MARISHA: I'm just wondering if the memory card--
LIAM: But you did spend six seconds finding that
thing. And--
MARISHA: It does have a backup drive. It does not
matter, though. That's the important part, is that
no one cares that we have a backup.
LIAM: In a split-second, in your peripheral
vision, you see a light blink, but it's gone. You
didn't see what it said.
MARISHA: These people have very poor cloud
storage. That's all you need to know.
LIAM: Laura tries to get in front of Neil, and she
starts pulling on wires coming out of the thing's
head, and she yanks, but she's pulling, and it's
not doing anything. She's really little. Really
cute. She's so small, and the wires are not coming
free, but she's trying, she's trying to save Neil
Druckmann. Sam, what do you want to do?
SAM: Me? I mean, I don't really know what these
symbols and messages mean, so like the piece of
scaffolding that fell down like this, can I run
and sort of jump on it and do it again?
LIAM: Make an acrobatics check.
SAM: Okay. Four. (laughs)
LIAM: You run at this thing and you jump, and you
crush your nuts so hard on the side of this thing.
You just hit it and you slide down to the bottom
of it, and wish that you hadn't decided to do what
you just did.
SAM: And then I'll spend the rest of my
action/bonus or whatever looking at those screens
to see if they say anything to me.
LIAM: Yeah, it does, briefly.
SAM: What?
LIAM: 'HUSBAND'.
SAM: 'HUSBAND'?
LIAM: Taliesin, you're up.
SAM: (whispers) It's Liam. It's Liam.
MARISHA: They're not filming in 4K, it's fine,
just go.
TALIESIN: Without breaking eye contact with
Marisha, I send another tendril at the one that
won't stay down.
LIAM: This guy right here, right? This is the one.
Sure. Ranged attack. The prince of--
TALIESIN: 11.
LIAM: The tentacle does a great big display and
spirals around, and you look fucking fierce and it
matches the color of your hair. No it doesn't. No
it doesn't!
TALIESIN: It doesn't match the color of my hair.
LIAM: It matches the color of your in-person hair
right now. There we go. But it doesn't reach. It
falls short. We see a lot of rage and fury, but no
delivery.
TALIESIN: All right. And I'm going to back off a
bit, and I'm gonna also keep looking at those
screens to see if they say anything.
LIAM: No? No. Not right now. Not in that
split-second. Travis.
TRAVIS: Can I reach up to my mocap helmet and
wrench the little GoPro camera that's surrounded
by LED lights.
LIAM: Yes you can!
TRAVIS: Can I wrench it off and can I face it
towards it, go, backfeed!
LIAM: You're using it like a talisman?
TRAVIS: Yeah, you know, like little fucking
Hobbits, like you know,
little Bilbo did, using the--
MATT: The LED light that's always in our face.
LIAM: I'll tell you what, I will not give you
advantage, but I will give you a DM inspiration
die of a d6 to make an intimidation check.
TRAVIS: Yes! Okay. Ooh!
TALIESIN: Plus a d6.
TRAVIS: 27.
LIAM: 27?
TRAVIS: Oh, sorry, sorry. 21. Oh, I won't spend it
now. 21. 19 plus two.
LIAM: The thing lurches backwards for a bit, and
as it backs away from you, pulling away from that
metal, you see on the screen it says, 'TRAVIS,
NO'. And that disappears and it backs away,
pulling, dragging cords out of that hole. It can't
really get too far, because it's now you see that
it is connected down, it was sort of squatting,
hiding a lot of that shit because of the carnage
underneath it, but it is sort of tethered, not too
much. Do you wanna move, or are you good to go?
TRAVIS: It's Colla. Colla's in the machine. Oh,
no. Are we bolting for Crafty?
(laughter)
SAM: We're gonna get potato chips during this?
MARISHA: It depends. What did they have on
Crafty?
TRAVIS: They got ginger beer and all sorts of
shit.
MARISHA: Do they have trail mix?
TALIESIN: They're always out of health potions by
the time I get there.
TRAVIS: I am going to head for the door.
LIAM: Which one?
TRAVIS: The green one, down at the-- yeah. That
thing.
LIAM: Okay.
TRAVIS: As far as I can go.
LIAM: 25, 30. All right, that's as far as you can
go because you used your action to do what you
did. It was amazing. (laughs)
MATT: Fill out your 1089 before you go.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: This mass of computer screens and keyboards
and other shit that you can't identify comes down
the ramp. Okay, that's as far as it gets--
actually, no, and it's right there, but it can't do
anything 'cause it spent its time getting there.
This thing just goes (clattering) but it is done.
This thing continues to batter Ashley.
ASHLEY: Isn't it my turn?
LIAM: No. Not yet. Oh. This thing tries to stick--
it pulls out the pole from inside your gut, and
you feel a little (fft) as it does so. It tries to go
in again, but you're ready for it, you know it's
right behind you, and you manage to swivel and
step out of the way. It misses. And big guy snaps
away and moves back in this direction and Marisha,
you're the only one who sees it,
but a screen says--
SAM: Don't I get an attack of opportunity?
LIAM: Yes, you do.
SAM: Yes. I'm gonna just try to kick it.
MATT: 'Cause when it moved back, it was not in
melee range--
LIAM: But he was on the beam that swung down into
it, and I'm gonna pretend like it
dragged along with.
MATT: I like it. Cool.
LIAM: Hey, we're making it all up as we go.
SAM: 11 plus something.
LIAM: 11 plus something? What's your strength
modifier, it's on the left? One? Yeah, you're too
busy going (yells)-- jeez, sorry everybody. You're
moving in space on that piece of scaffolding, and
it just fucks up your aim. You don't do it.
Taliesin, devil-child, you're up.
TALIESIN: No, that was a--
LIAM: Oh, that was its-- that's right. Ashley's
up.
ASHLEY: Okay. I'm going to--
MARISHA: You know you better than anyone.
ASHLEY: The 'HUSBAND' threw me off. I am going to
move further that way to get away from these two
that are there.
LIAM: You're going this way?
ASHLEY: Well, maybe just like out of range of
them, touching range. So maybe just like--
LIAM: But which direction? This direction?
ASHLEY: Yeah.
LIAM: You're stepping this way?
ASHLEY: Towards the lounge.
LIAM: Towards the lounge. As you do so, the thing
takes a swipe at you. What's your AC?
ASHLEY: 12.
LIAM: 12? Yep.
MATT: Velcro bodysuits don't offer a lot of armor
class protection.
LIAM: On a hinge, a pole just goes (whirring
sound) and you feel it slice the back of your neck
as you go, and it takes four hit points--
ASHLEY: Even with the helmet on?
LIAM: Yeah. It didn't hit the helmet, it hit the
neck. And you feel blood pouring down the back of
this mocap suit, pooling up around your waist. You
do get away from it. Did you want to go further
than that, or there?
ASHLEY: Yeah. I wanna go further in, towards the
lounge.
LIAM: Okay, so.
ASHLEY: But I wanna get in eyeshot of the big
computer dude.
LIAM: This guy?
ASHLEY: Actually, I'm so sorry. I want to go
further in towards the bigger guy. But kinda walk
around so I don't get attacked by the other one.
LIAM: This is also a huge gap, so you could go--
you could get to there. Ten, 15, 20, 25, 30.
That's as far as you can get unless you keep
going, make a dash.
ASHLEY: I'll dash.
LIAM: Okay, you want to get right up to it?
ASHLEY: Yeah.
LIAM: All right, you're out of stuff, though.
You're right in the face of this thing, and the
screen briefly says 'ASH-O-LEE'. And then it's
gone.
ASHLEY: Okay. Can I just put down my mocap knife
on the ground?
LIAM: Yeah, you drop it.
ASHLEY: And say, I think you've created or done
something that's gotten out of hand,
and I forgive you.
LIAM: And now it's Matt's turn.
MATT: Okay. Is that me right next to the-- right
there, okay. If I can take two steps to get right
up to the edge of where it emerged from the floor,
and glance inside, what do I see below?
LIAM: You see a crack going down about eight feet,
and it is like five and a half, six feet wide at
the most. And you see lots of cables. It looks
like black spaghetti. And it's all cabled, but
again, it's wet and oily. If you jumped down into
that, you would be disgusting.
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: Everything's wet in Liam's world.
LIAM: Yes, husband.
MATT: I'm going to, if I can, move along-- move
from your perspective this way two more squares,
and then jump across that little bit of the gap
that's there.
LIAM: Sure, you can make it, you can go one more
square.
MATT: No, right there's where I wanna stand.
LIAM: All right, great.
MATT: And I'm gonna go ahead and use Thunderwave
in front of me to try and blast them back and do
damage. As I rush forward, I jump across the way
and go (hesitant noises). And I realize that we
probably have a PA system set up, and I grab the
microphone on the edge of the head thing and just
go (screams) as loud as I can into the microphone.
Thinking that they probably have a feedback set up
in the cameras.
LIAM: Okay. Okay.
MATT: So that's a constitution saving throw for
both of them.
LIAM: Okay. And the DC is?
MATT: 13.
LIAM: They do make it.
MATT: Okay. So that would be ten points of thunder
damage, or half on a successful save, so they're
not pushed, but they take five points of thunder
damage each.
LIAM: Okay. This thing-- just out of the pureness
of Matthew Mercer's heart and soul, which we all
see, let's be honest, in a moment of crisis, your
heart and care for your friends bursts out of the
microphone system, we hear it everywhere,
distorted, but certainly a blast of fucking force
out of your fucking chest, Matt, goes (explosion)
and this thing just goes (explosion) and pieces go
(clattering) and fall down.
(cheering)
LIAM: This thing, you smashed-- three iMac screens
get smashed and cracked and break away, and this
thing looks very haggard, but it is still there.
MATT: I'll use my last five feet of movement to
try and then move alongside of the crack away from
the currently still standing there creature.
LIAM: This way?
MATT: Yeah, that is a crack, so I'd say just one
away from the crack.
LIAM: You step backward and this is not too deep,
but you are now standing in-- you're not caught or
anything, but you're now standing in the really
slippery shit. It's also really adorable to see
you two hugging at the table right now. And
Marisha-- oh, you know what? I missed Neil before
because I'm just-- he's a d6 in my list, so I'm
gonna let Neil jump up and attack this thing.
ASHLEY: C'mon, Neil!
MATT: You got this.
LIAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: (sings) He whipped his hair back and
forth, he whipped his hair back and forth.
LIAM: Okay, so that is-- okay. He grabs a hold of
it and rips a screen off. (yells) (whirring
sounds) "Fuck. Laura?" And it is Marisha's turn.
MARISHA: Wait, was that (whirring sounds) Neil?
LIAM: No, it turned to Neil. What was left
of it turned toward Neil.
MARISHA: Okay. And there's still that thing that's
digging in the corner. Can I get to it?
Where am I?
LIAM: You're here. You can, you'd run out of juice
by the time you got there. You'd have to dash to
get there. You can get to that one.
MATT: Your movement's 30?
MARISHA: Wait, what's that thing?
LIAM: This? Matt just fucked it up with a
Thunderwave.
MARISHA: Okay, I get to that.
LIAM: All right, you're right up on it.
MARISHA: And can I take it by the back of its neck
and push it and be like, scream real loud! We need
the feedback! (yells)
LIAM: And do anything or yell at it?
MARISHA: And grab it by the back of its neck.
LIAM: You mean, the brace holding the iMac's
screen up? Okay.
MARISHA: And I go, scream! Scream for me!
LIAM: Okay. And that's it?
MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: It's like Phantom of the Opera.
MARISHA: Sing! Sing!
LIAM: Make an intimidation check?
MARISHA: Sure. Oh, that's not good. Seven.
LIAM: There's a crackle of light, and then it
makes that sound when Macs reboot and goes
(bwomp).
MARISHA: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Damn it, Macs.
LIAM: That's about it. Laura tries to punch the--
sorry, Laura's not feeling too well. Laura attacks
this thing, going, "Neil, come on! Together! Oh my
goodness!" And she tries to punch at it. She hits
it right in the one solid piece left on this thing
and kinda hits her hand really hard. She stays
there, though. She's afraid to leave Neil.
ASHLEY: 'Cause she's a good friend.
LIAM: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Sam, your turn.
SAM: I'm gonna run as fast as I can up to the big
guy.
LIAM: Yes. This one?
SAM: Yeah.
LIAM: Five, ten, 15, 20, 25, 30.
SAM: Even closer--
LIAM: You're gonna run out of--
SAM: That's okay. I just want to talk to it.
LIAM: Okay, go.
SAM: And I just want to say to it, Liam! If you
can hear me in there, hey buddy. Let's knock this
off and just record our podcast, okay? We haven't
done an episode in like three months. We should
just do one of those instead! We got recording
equipment right here, huh? What do you say, pal?
LIAM: Eight feet above you is that little
camcorder screen, and you're eyeing it, you've
learned by now, and it just says 'FIND ME'.
SAM: 'FIND ME'. That means find Liam. We have to
find Liam.
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: Didn't Liam just get--
SAM: We just heard a scream, we didn't see him
die.
LIAM: Taliesin.
TALIESIN: There is so much that is unpleasant
happening in here. I'm gonna free up some people.
There's just too much happening. The one that
Laura's-- yeah, I'm right there.
LIAM: He's right on your butt.
TALIESIN: (sighs)
LIAM: And he's just come from mangling sweet Liam
O'Brien.
TALIESIN: Yeah, yeah. Travis is gonna keep him
busy for a second. I'm gonna deal with the one
that Laura is-- I'm gonna keep rolling around,
just trying to-- I'm gonna run away from that one
and try and stab the one up by-- yeah, that one
over there.
TRAVIS: I'm going to Crafty. Nature Valley granola
bars.
LIAM: So you're going after this one? You're
attacking from where you are, or you're moving?
TALIESIN: Both. I'm not getting within-- I'm
getting further from that-- oh, am I up face-up to
that one? Oh, I didn't know I was face-up to that
one.
LIAM: Okay, understood.
TALIESIN: I thought I was the guy below. Yeah. I'm
gonna shove tentacles in it and hopefully start to
wrangle it apart.
LIAM: Okay. Ranged attack.
TRAVIS: Grab the last one of them fruit snacks.
TALIESIN: Yeah, that's not good. Nine.
LIAM: Yeah, no. It actually, the tentacles fizzle.
They're not there. You see a brief glow and it
goes (gurgling) and they sort of curl and shrivel
in on themselves.
TALIESIN: Travis! Help!
LIAM: Travis, what do you wanna do?
TRAVIS: I'm double-dashing for Crafty.
TALIESIN: No! I'll remember this!
LIAM: Your wife is right here.
TRAVIS: Nope. This is all a bad dream.
LIAM: Are you going?
TRAVIS: I'm going.
LIAM: Wow. Travis ran into the pale green light
spilling out of a hole in the wall.
TRAVIS: It's green! This is going terrible.
ASHLEY: Travis!
MARISHA: There are wasabi peas there, go, go, go!
TRAVIS: There's a kale smoothie.
ASHLEY: I can't believe you.
MATT: That's what it was. When you said, "Travis!
Help!" you were straight-up Neo. "Trinity! Help!"
LIAM: Sam, this thing leans in on you, and as it
comes down closer to you, you see, 'SAD'. Gone.
And it stabs one of its remaining three legs, just
sort of jukes up on its side 'cause it has three
legs, so suddenly it has two legs, it's rickety,
it tries to stab downward at you, but because it's
now teetering on two legs, (Dr. Moreau voice) 'to
walk on two legs is hard, maybe four is better'.
(laughter)
LIAM: Its aim is bad, and it stabs into the
ground. This thing swivels-- this thing is
short-circuiting and bristling, sparks are flying
off of it, but it rears up like a horse almost,
and the legs come down, and you guys watch as two
sharpened tripod legs go through Neil Druckmann's
guts on the ground, and Neil gets pushed to the
ground and starts screaming, and he goes
(screams), and he reaches up and grabs hold of the
cables on it, and as blood is going (spraying
sound), he rips as hard as he can, and cables
break free, and the machine just falls, broken, on
top of Neil, and nothing moves there, neither
move.
MARISHA: But did he sign his NDA? Oh no.
SAM: He had so many more games to make.
MATT: The great NDA in the sky.
TALIESIN: He'll never break NDA again.
LIAM: This thing takes two iMac-- it's got iMac
palms, and it just goes (creaking sound) and does
smack you in your head, but oddly, it doesn't
really hurt. I mean, it hurts, but you've had
worse knocks. This brand-new baby robot is not so
experienced. And this guy gets up on its little
pin-pokey legs and tries to scuttle around and
deal with you, and actually, its back leg snaps,
and it tries to stab out at you, but because these
things are made out of tinkertoys, almost, it
feels like, it loses its balance and the arm goes
wide, and you feel it go (fwwp), and bad girl, you
have trained in martial arts, you went-- you pull
to the side just in time, and you feel it catch a
little bit of your hair. You have a flashback of
your hair being matted on a beach, and that's
gone. And it is Ashley's turn.
ASHLEY: Okay. Talk to the big guy again and say,
where do we find you?
LIAM: Is that all you want to do?
ASHLEY: No.
(laughter)
SAM: Not anymore.
ASHLEY: I just-- depending on what he says
determines what I'm going to do. Can I do that?
LIAM: Okay. Five of six seconds go by, and the
screens flash nothing. And in a split-second, you
decide to...
ASHLEY: Okay. I'm going to-- (sighs) Shit. I'm
gonna start running towards
the fucking green Crafty.
SAM: No!
TALIESIN: It's time for Crafty!
MATT: The draw's too strong for the Crafty room.
ASHLEY: 'Cause I don't think he's in that thing.
TRAVIS: There's egg rolls out here!
MATT: I hope it's like a Resident Evil movie-style
just laser hallway,
and you just walk through and--
TRAVIS: I'm in the cubes.
MATT: Yep. None of us know, we all just one by one
plow through.
LIAM: As you're running, you hear (whirring
sounds) and you feel the back of your leg, rake
something down the back leg of your mocap suit,
and the whole back leg rips and tears, but you
keep running. Five, ten, 15, 20--
ASHLEY: I want to go around that thing.
LIAM: This way?
ASHLEY: No, the other side.
LIAM: This way.
ASHLEY: The other side of the chasm.
LIAM: That's where you are. Matt?
MATT: How much damage did she take? Did she take
any damage, or is she good?
LIAM: She got missed.
MATT: Good. Awesome. All right, seeing all this
going down--
TRAVIS: Join me in Crafty.
MARISHA: If we don't get a Welch's sponsorship
after this, I'm going to pursue that shit. Yo,
Welch's. Keep going.
MATT: I'm going to-- she's got that one. I'm going
to make 30 feet towards Taliesin while shouting
out, Liam, are you okay?
LIAM: You don't hear anything.
MATT: I'm going to, as I look over at Taliesin
facing off with the creature, I'm like, you're
adorable, and you've got this. You've adorably got
this!
SAM: Inspiration.
MATT: I'm giving you an insipiration die. A d6.
SAM: You are adorable. Well, you were.
MATT: And I'm going to dash up towards the ramp in
the back corner,
just to see what remains of Liam.
LIAM: And Taliesin's cheeks turn even rosier as
you run off.
TALIESIN: I was so marketable.
LIAM: You get up here. It's not good.
MATT: Okay. Like he has a few minutes left to
live, or no, it's fucking Chef Boyardee. Okay.
SAM: Who, Liam?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Well, let's be descriptive, shall we?
LIAM: You don't even see a face anymore.
MATT: Okay. All right. Well, that's definitely the
end of my turn.
LIAM: Marisha?
MARISHA: Okay, I have this guy? It's just me and
him?
LIAM: Yes.
MARISHA: Okay. And he's a robot, too?
LIAM: It's a robot. It's moving camera equipment
and highly expensive performance-capture
equipment, repurposed.
MARISHA: Highly expensive camera equipment,
repurposed. Okay. Can I sweep his leg and go into
a combat triangle and take him down, and then be
like, where's your failsafe?
LIAM: Of course you can. This is D&amp;D. Roll to
attack.
TRAVIS: Of course you can do all of that. Go
offline.
LIAM: Roll to attack.
MARISHA: Okay.
LIAM: Let's deal with the sweep-the-leg part
first.
MARISHA: Sweep the leg. Don't fuck me, Gil! That's
a natural one, Gil.
SAM: Oh god.
LIAM: Your foot traces an arc and goes (impact
noise) and stops and does not move past its leg.
MARISHA: Can I go: There's a firewall! There's a
fucking firewall!
LIAM: Do you want to use your second monk attack?
MARISHA: Do I have another one?
LIAM: Yeah. Bonus, yeah. Action and bonus. You're
right there. Roll again. You just completed a
kick. Maybe you can punch it in the goolies.
MARISHA: I'm going to punch and see if I can grab
its cords and rip it out.
LIAM: All right. Split-second later, roll to
attack.
MARISHA: That's cocked. 18.
LIAM: Yeah, your foot goes (impact noise), gets
stopped. (grunts) In a very Marisha fashion,
(impact noise, mechanical noises).
MARISHA: Yes.
MATT: All righty.
TALIESIN: Two down.
MARISHA: (uncertain noises)
LIAM: It's Laura's turn. Laura collapses by Neil
and starts pushing this thing off Neil and starts
saying, "Neil! Neil!" and she starts shaking at
him and crying over his body. There's blood in his
beard and it's really sad. You guys almost don't
have the heart to go on, but you'd better. Sam,
what do you want to do?
SAM: He said "find me" but he's dead. I guess I
didn't see what you saw.
TRAVIS: (whispering) He's at Crafty.
LIAM: Find me at Crafty.
SAM: I'm going to kick the robot in the robot
nuts.
LIAM: Do it. Right in the SD card belly-button
that Marisha's doing?
SAM: Yeah. 19.
LIAM: Hit it.
SAM: With what?
LIAM: Your fist, at this point.
SAM: What am I rolling, a d4?
LIAM: No. What's your strength modifier?
SAM: One.
LIAM: One? It takes two hit points of damage. You
punch it right in its belly-button and you watch
as this thing that Marisha pointed out when she
was down under there, you watch this cylinder go
(crunch) and get knocked out of place, and the
thing goes (mechanical winding-down noise,
ratcheting). It keeps going, but you saw shit
happen when you just hit that thing.
SAM: Okay. For my bonus action, I will say, please
hit it in its glowing naughty bits, please. Oh,
wait. Everyone's gone to Crafty.
MATT: Bye, everyone!
LIAM: Taliesin's up.
TALIESIN: Yeah, we're too close to clearing this.
I'm going to try and circle around this thing and
get a better shot at it.
LIAM: At this guy?
TALIESIN: The one that's got me stuck here.
LIAM: Yeah, go for it. Do you want to move?
TALIESIN: Yeah, I'm going to circle around him.
LIAM: Okay. Are you going to give it the tentacle
concho?
TALIESIN: I am going to tentacle kancho.
LIAM: Kancho.
TALIESIN: Kancho.
MATT: Wow.
TALIESIN: Yeah, we are kancho-ing here. Big purple
concho. I'm going to add. 11!
SAM: Just awful.
LIAM: You've been abandoned by whatever dark force
you wooed into bed, Taliesin. You are not turning
it on right now.
TALIESIN: It's because Matt's sitting in my
chair.
MATT: Ha! I've absorbed his power for the evening.
(cackles)
LIAM: Travis.
TRAVIS: Yeah?
LIAM: You burst into this tunnel. In a split
second, everything turns dark and green at the
same time. You're seeing a tube, a tunnel go
(whoop) and just up. It curves up pretty steeply.
You could do it. You're running towards it, and
again, the same kinds of tubing and what look like
veins or innards, except mechanical at the same
time, are spiraling up the length of this tube and
then out of sight. You can definitely go up it,
but it's not this, it's this.
TRAVIS: Just to be clear, no tables or cans of
Sterno?
LIAM: There's nothing but a tube.
TRAVIS: I'm bolting up that tunnel.
LIAM: Yeah, you are. Okay. It does not change. You
run a full 60 feet, and you're just booking it in
your little short-shorts and polo shirt and going
(pants) and that's where we'll leave you.
MATT: You've got this, Travis!
TRAVIS: Saving the day. (sings) Saving the day!
LIAM: This guy tries to basically sit on you, but
it is breaking down. It is still moving, and in
fact, it's pushing on you. The screen goes, 'SAM'.
Gone. I'm going to say that it backs you up five
feet, going (mechanical noises). Nope. This thing,
I'm going to say that you've moved with it,
Taliesin, just for funsies. It's slow-moving, and
you continue to move around. You're ashamed, but
still awake and alert. Ash.
ASHLEY: Are they connected to the computers that
are already in the muck? All of the ones that are
in the pod area?
LIAM: Those are there for reference. Those are
piles of shit. Those are here.
What was here is here.
ASHLEY: I don't want to abandon this. Can I get to
Taliesin in this turn, or no?
LIAM: You can get to him, but you can't do
anything, or you can get here.
ASHLEY: Okay, but I can get back to the big guy.
LIAM: You can get back to the big guy.
ASHLEY: Okay. I'm going to go back to the big
guy.
LIAM: You're right there with your buddy Sam. What
would you like to do?
ASHLEY: I'm going to kick that SD card, the
glowing thing at the bottom, again.
LIAM: Okay, go for it.
ASHLEY: Okay.
TRAVIS: Come on!
SAM: Don't you still have an inspiration?
ASHLEY: I do?
SAM: I don't know. Did Matt inspire you or
Taliesin?
MATT: Taliesin, earlier. She used hers in the last
battle.
ASHLEY: 11?
TRAVIS: Wow. We can't hit shit!
LIAM: It is tougher than the other ones and
slow-moving. Your knuckles are banged up real bad.
You've cut the skin on your knuckles, and it is
still just leaning on Riegel.
ASHLEY: Where do we find you? Answer me!
LIAM: Matt, what would you like to do?
MATT: Seeing Liam shredded, seeing them fumble
with this thing, I take a full movement in the
direction of the larger creature, there. Yeah, and
I go, hey! Computer! Stop all the downloading!
You've been vague and not helpful to any of us.
That makes you a bad computer. That's my Vicious
Mockery.
LIAM: So in the midst of this horror, you're
worried that you're going to die, but your gallows
humor kicks in and fuck it. Fuck this thing. And
you lash out at it.
MATT: Yeah, I'm angry! It's been completely
unhelpful, even if it is Liam. You've got LCD
screens at your disposal and you're giving us
vague hints? No. Fuck that noise.
ASHLEY: Yeah!
MATT: Make a wisdom saving throw.
LIAM: What's the save?
MATT: 13.
LIAM: I rolled a 13.
MATT: I cannot do anything.
TRAVIS: We can't do anything.
TALIESIN: Just like real life.
MATT: There's nothing? It does nothing to it. I
see no reaction. My gusto fails, and I go: help,
computer.
(laughter)
MATT: That's my turn.
LIAM: Okay. Marisha.
MARISHA: Okay, where are you?
MATT: Actually, no. At the end of my turn, I turn
back to Taliesin and go: yeah, but seriously, do
something! Come on! You worked with Spielberg,
asshole! I give you my last inspiration die.
SAM: You worked with Spielberg?!
TALIESIN: I did.
SAM: Wow.
MARISHA: I'm there?
LIAM: Yeah, you are.
MARISHA: There's a crack in the hole? In the
ground?
LIAM: Right there? Yeah.
MATT: The crack in the hole?
LIAM: The crack in the hole. There's a hole in the
crack.
MARISHA: There's a hole in the bucket, dear Liza,
dear Liza. Okay, there's an evil bad guy and then
a crack in the ground.
LIAM: This thing is looking rough.
MARISHA: It's looking rough?
LIAM: Yeah, man.
MARISHA: Can I get there in time?
LIAM: To this? Yeah, you can.
MARISHA: Yeah? Okay. I'm going to say, none of
this is being saved on the internet, guys! It's
fine! And I do a double punch.
LIAM: Yeah, go for it. Roll twice.
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: Demogorgon left an impact on her, man.
MARISHA: 16. And then the second one--
TRAVIS: Should have backed up!
MARISHA: Good. 17. 16 and 17.
LIAM: Roll for damage on both.
MARISHA: And that's 1d4 plus three? Three plus
three is six, and then one plus three is four. Six
and four, ten.
LIAM: You come through and one hand slams into its
third leg and breaks right through and it falls
forward, no longer having a third leg to stand on,
and its little belly button is right there, and
you go (grunts) and punch. That cylinder goes,
(metallic thudding) and rolls off into the
corner.
MARISHA: (grunts) Fuck you, cloud storage!
SAM: You are on a rampage about backing up data.
MARISHA: Fuck you, backup data. You're easily
hackable. It's not fair!
MATT: I feel like if we would have had a good
sponsor tonight, it would have been Backblaze, a
fantastic service for backing up your
information.
MARISHA: If only Backblaze was sponsoring us.
LIAM: Laura drags Neil's body away from the gap
and lays him out. Sam, it's your turn.
SAM: I'm gonna use my-- Because the robot is dead.
LIAM: The big one, yeah.
SAM: As far as I know, Liam is dead. I'm going to
use my ranger senses--
LIAM: Technically, there is voiceover recording
done on these sets, so you are in your favored
territory.
TALIESIN: I knew it! I knew it.
SAM: I'm going to look and see if I see anything
out of the ordinary. Any sign of a hidden door or
a chamber that I missed before.
LIAM: Yeah, I got you, boo. Your eyes dart all
around this room. Anything out of the ordinary in
this fucking crazy room. You see the hole in the
wall that Verno booked it out of. There's an exit
sign above that door, but it doesn't say exit. You
didn't see it until now. It says, 'COME'.
SAM: (gasps) I come in my pants.
LIAM: You solved the game! You won Dungeons and
Dragons!
TRAVIS: I jizzed in my pants.
(giggling)
SAM: I book it to the door, and I say: as always,
follow seven-year-old me!
LIAM: That's as far as your little legs go. You
are running in a tube. Still going?
TRAVIS: Yeah. Isn't it--
TALIESIN: Oh, it's me.
LIAM: Yes, it is. You're right. Sorry, two T
names.
TALIESIN: I'm going to circle around and try one
more time. I think I've been trying to get too
fancy with this thing, so I'm going to try to hit
it through the ground. Try and line it up and give
the slap attack.
LIAM: Okay.
TALIESIN: Yeah, no.
LIAM: So sad. What good deed did you do? What
preppy outfit did you wear to make the eldritch
gods abandon you?
TALIESIN: I don't have my hair. You've done this
to me. The hair is where the power comes from.
It's really tough to get an eldritch god to listen
to you when you have this haircut. There's a
reason it's gone.
LIAM: Maybe the robot is secretly made of fish.
TRAVIS: The big watery eyes.
TALIESIN: I'm going to break and run.
LIAM: It obviously takes a swing, but with its
natural one-- this is the one that has the stubby
T-Rex iMac hands, and it goes (whoosh) and not
much happens. You break away.
TALIESIN: I run to the green.
LIAM: That's where you are. It follows.
TALIESIN: Sure.
LIAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: It's going to catch him?
LIAM: Yep.
TRAVIS: Oh no.
LIAM: And now, that iMac, which you didn't get too
good a look at it because you're fucking freaked
out, slices down into your shoulder blade, and it is
very sharp on the side, it is not normal,
and you feel an iMac suddenly go (slicing noise)
and blood starts to pool down inside the mocap
suit. Two hit points.
TALIESIN: Did we reset hit points at the top of
this?
LIAM: Yes.
TALIESIN: Okay, cool.
LIAM: When you were reborn unto Naughty Dog? Yes.
TALIESIN: Wow, that came out weird.
LIAM: Now, Travis.
TRAVIS: Knowing that I have an intelligence of 12,
which is double what I usually work with, and that
color is green, which is what geniuses choose, I
continue down the tunnel.
LIAM: Okay. You're going uphill now. It's all
right. You're not that stocky. (huffing breaths)
You are now 120 feet up this tunnel and booking.
You can't even hear your friends anymore. It's
like when the movie lights go down and you see
those little lights along the floor. It's that
level of brightness. It's dark in here, but the
movie lights-- they're not movie lights-- are an
unsettling green.
TRAVIS But I have my LED camera, still.
LIAM: Yeah, so there's a light on the wall. It's
unsteady. Ashley, what do you want to do?
ASHLEY: Okay. I'm going to pick up the little SD
card thingy that flew away.
LIAM: It got flung over here. Sorry, man.
SAM: Leave it. You can't read that. What are you,
a computer?
ASHLEY: What if Liam's in there?
SAM: Fuck Liam. He's dead.
TRAVIS: What if?
TALIESIN: Liam's in the cloud.
LIAM: Sam yells out.
MATT: This is some Lawnmower Man shit.
LIAM: Please no. Please no.
ASHLEY: I'm going to start running toward Taliesin
and start making my way out, but also a little
more toward--
TRAVIS: (sings) Making my way downtown--
ASHLEY: (sings) Walking fast, 30 feet to
Taliesin.
MARISHA: So inspirational.
LIAM: There. Matt?
MATT: Well, I see everyone else booking in that
direction, and most of the danger on the other
side of the room is gone, so I'm going to go ahead
and continue that way, as well. Full movement. And
as that's happening and as Taliesin's facing off
against the one standing camera, I'm going to be
like: hey, by the way! The rest of your equipment
was shitty. I guess that means you are, too!
Vicious Mockery.
LIAM: Sure.
MATT: See if something will fail a saving throw.
Yay! (singing) It takes four psychic damage.
LIAM: Okay. Your voice-- again, it makes no sense,
but because you're so pure, your insult
reverberates through, and it, nonsensically,
comically, goes, (mechanical noise) and it falls
and an iMac goes (thudding) and it explodes!
MATT: In a shower of sparks as Taliesin's on the
other side of the camera, I just say, sometimes
you've just got to remind them. That's my turn.
LIAM: There's nothing left moving in this room.
You do, very distantly, hear (huffing breaths).
MATT: You guys, I think we lost Travis.
ASHLEY: Let's go.
LIAM: Laura starts saying, "Travis!" She leaves
Neil and runs to that green door and shouts your
name as loud as she can up the tube, and you hear
it.
TRAVIS: Oh. Yeah, come this way! Come up this
way!
MARISHA: As we run for the green gap, I say, I saw
'NO' on the screen. What did you see?
LIAM: Are you going to wait, or are you still
running as fast as you can?
TRAVIS: I'll wait.
LIAM: Okay, so you stop.
SAM: I'm going to leave my picture and resume on
Neil's body.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Oh my god.
SAM: Somebody needs an actor or character actor.
LIAM: Maybe in another dimension, you will get
cast on Earth-37. Oh my gosh. You dab it in place
and it sticks, obviously, and then you're the last
one out of the room, running after the group.
Luckily, Ashley had already gone in the tube and
didn't see that disgraceful display.
(laughter)
LIAM: Okay. All right, the rest of you guys make
your way. It's very unsettling. As soon as you
walk in, luckily you're not being attacked by
moving machinery anymore, but now you're in the
dark, mostly. You find your way up to little
Travis, and you have a moment to breathe for a
second. You're in this tube. The sides of it now,
as you walk a little further, start to-- all the
cabling and wiring that I mentioned before starts
to lessen. You guys walking forward?
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: Running forward.
LIAM: Running forward?
SAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: I'm checking for traps.
SAM: What are you talking about? You're a weiner.
You've been running after everything
that you've seen.
LIAM: Would you like to roll to check for traps?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: All right, go for it.
MARISHA: Are you a rogue?
TRAVIS: Nope. What do I do?
LIAM: Make an investigation check.
TRAVIS: That's an eight. It's clear!
LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: Get behind Sam!
MARISHA: Go behind T!
SAM: I'm a tracker!
LIAM: Are we running or walking?
SAM: I'm running.
TRAVIS: I'm running.
LIAM: You're out of your favored terrain, I will
say.
ASHLEY: I might do a speed walk.
LIAM: Ashley's trailing behind. You're moving
really fast. You guys jog upward in this tunnel
for two minutes, five minutes. Still in the dark.
TALIESIN: It's dark? Sam, do you have another
resume and picture?
SAM: I only have one.
TALIESIN: You only had one resume?
LIAM: Could you put the effort of running into
this dialogue, please?
TRAVIS: Yeah, you're running.
LIAM: I need effort of running in that dialogue.
SAM: Oh. Okay, sorry. (panting) When I smile, I
create a dim light with my teeth.
TRAVIS: Guys, you all have cameras on the front of
your helmets. Why are you shining lights into your
own fucking faces? Turn them around.
MATT: That's true. We still have battery packs,
don't we?
MARISHA: Oh shit. I thought that was an aura of
blindness. I'm so sorry.
LIAM: To interject, as you've been running, for a
while it was cords, cables, guts, and then less of
that, and you're seeing glass surface that this
stuff was growing on top of, but there's less of
it. You catch glimpses of glass, more glass, and
then eventually, that mostly dies away. There's
still occasional (whoosh) around, but it's light.
It's glass, and it is a perfect tube, but you
can't see anything out there. It's dark. And
you've been running for ten minutes now. Still
going up.
SAM: Probably two miles, right, Travis?
TRAVIS: Yep.
TALIESIN: I'm going to play with my crazy powers.
I really haven't had a chance to play with my
crazy powers.
SAM: Your crazy powers?
TRAVIS: You mean the tentacles that have been
shooting out of your fucking fingers?
ASHLEY: Your special purpose?
TALIESIN: My special purpose.
LIAM: What would you like to do, creepy kid?
TALIESIN: I'm going to try and make a purple glow
happen behind the glass. I want to try and see
what's behind. I'm going to touch the glass and
try and force a psychic light behind it so I can
see. A gothy psychic light.
LIAM: Sure. A very bright lavender exudes out from
your hands. And through it, you see-- it's hard to
describe the texture of it, but you see nothing
above and then stretching away from the lower end
of the tunnel on the side you're looking at, what
looks like mottled, scaly,
black teflon or hide or--
TALIESIN: Guys! Guys! Guys!
SAM: What?!
TALIESIN: Look!
ASHLEY: I peek in.
SAM: Oh, it's scaly teflon.
LIAM: You all stop running--
MARISHA: Sequins!
LIAM: It doesn't look natural. It looks
synthetic.
ASHLEY: Sequins.
LIAM: It looks like--
MARISHA: Sequins, yeah!
LIAM: -- ground, but it doesn't look like dirt or
trees or anything.
TRAVIS: Is it carbon fiber?
SAM: Is it adamantium?
TRAVIS: Get your head out of your ass, come on.
TALIESIN: I'm going to try and keep enough light,
and keep projecting a tiny bit of light in this
tunnel.
LIAM: As you walk forward? Are we walking now, or
are you going to continue to do a 5K?
TALIESIN: Let's walk.
TRAVIS: Why don't we try to break the glass?
SAM: Sure!
ASHLEY: I kind of want to see what's on the other
side of it. I mean, yeah, break it.
TRAVIS: We've been going a long time.
ASHLEY: Okay.
TALIESIN: I mean, ten minutes is--
SAM: Two miles.
LIAM: What are we doing, are we breaking glass, or
are we continuing on?
TRAVIS: We'll continue on for a bit more.
TALIESIN: Just a minute more.
LIAM AND TRAVIS: Okay.
LIAM: You walk for--
TRAVIS: These shoes are uncomfortable. They smell
like other people's feet!
LIAM: You walk for another two minutes, I'll say,
and you notice that, not where you are but up
ahead, it does seem slightly brighter. At the top.
Slightly.
MATT: Let's keep going!
TRAVIS: Yes.
ASHLEY: Onward ho?
MATT: Maybe after a minute. (heavy breathing)
SAM: Come on, Matt!
ASHLEY: You got it!
SAM: Jesus!
MARISHA: You okay, babe?
MATT: Does anyone have some water?
MARISHA: Hey! Hey!
TRAVIS: I could wring out this mocap suit.
MARISHA: Look to the future.
ASHLEY: We're almost there.
MATT: I hate P.E. for very specific reasons.
MARISHA: Shh. In the future is a campaign guide.
And it's good.
MATT: I know, I was working on it when I ended up
here. To be fair, it's making me feel a lot better
about spending time doing that.
MARISHA: Towards the campaign guide.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: Towards it.
MATT: Let's go.
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: Okay!
MARISHA: We're going. Good. We're good.
LIAM: You continue on and after a few more
minutes, the darkness starts to fade away or lower
and you realize you're climbing up a hill in a
tunnel of glass. As the dark, with each passing
step, recedes slightly, slightly-- this is taking
a while, but over time, you start to see out
beyond the glass what looks like your memories of
Los Angeles if you were looking down from
Mulholland Drive. But instead of the twinkling
golden lights of LA, you see thousands of
scattered, sickly greenish lights dotting the
darkened landscape as far as you can see. Also,
unlike LA, you make out twisted irregular blackish
spires pushing up into the sky and the same green
lights irregularly mottled up the side of them.
You walk for 20 more minutes, climbing, climbing
and seeing this ill-looking shimmer that reminds
you so much of the Valley. Eventually, some
change. You see an arch ahead and through it some
sort of larger chamber, as best you can tell.
SAM: Let's go. Let's go.
MATT: Riegels first.
SAM: Yeah! Yeah, On me, guys. On me.
ASHLEY: On your six.
SAM: We're going to go on in.
LIAM: Everyone's on Sam's six?
SAM: Yeah.
ASHLEY: I'm on your six.
MARISHA: On Rie. Sam Riegel.
SAM: We're going in!
LIAM: You guys walk up the last 50 feet of this
glass tunnel, still seeing little spidered veins
of bioorganic mess as you go. And you walk into a
large domed chamber ringed in by large, clear
glass windows showing you a similar view that you
saw from the tunnel that you've just left. At
least, the half of the circle that you're standing
in. The back half of this chamber is filled with
masses of the very same slick
technological-biological vomit you saw down below.
It runs up the walls, all the way up to the
ceiling. And you see a tangle of Akira-level
anxiety decorating this place like a dysfunctional
Christmas tree.
But what most catches your eye, immediately, is
the cylindrical glass column in the center of the
room filled with some sort of clear liquid, and
Liam O'Brien floating in it. He's wearing jeans
and a sodden yellow shirt, a picture of a lion in
Buddy Holly glasses undulating slowly in the
fluid. He's floating perfectly still, eyes open.
No reaction of any kind.
MATT: Does there appear to be any other exit in
the room, or is it just the chamber that we've
entered now?
LIAM: You don't see anything. It's just a mess in
front of you, behind Liam, and in the dead center
of the dome, ten feet tall.
ASHLEY: Is it connected to anything? Any
computers, anything else in the room?
LIAM: You don't see anything in the front, but
yeah, the mess behind it does trail down to the
back of this cylinder. You see lumps and cables
all twisted around each other, and in the mess of
greenish-tinted wires, cabling, and pulsing
innards, you see different portions of machinery
light up in different shades. Some places darker,
some lighter. Some of it pushed out, and some of
it pushed back. And you feel like you're seeing an
optical illusion, in a way, and after a couple of
seconds as these things move and shift, you see a
visage of your friend's face, larger than life,
filling the wall. And he is looking at you so
fondly.
SAM: I'll step forward and say, hey, dude. Can you
hear us or talk to us?
LIAM: After a moment, you hear what sounds like a
voice, but not quite. At least, it's not coming
from anywhere specific-- not from Liam in the vat,
and not directly from this moving image of a face
on the walls. The piping and techno-innards around
you begin to vibrate slightly, some here, some
there, and collectively, those rattles and
vibrations somehow join together to form words.
(speak-and-spell voice) "My friends. Oh how I have
missed you."
MATT: I walk up next to Sam and put my hand on the
glass and just say, Liam, we missed you, too, but
did you do all this?
LIAM: Are you at the cylinder?
MATT: Yeah, I put my hand on the glass of the
cylinder.
LIAM: Where are you looking right now?
MATT: I'm looking towards his face on the side.
LIAM: On the wall or in the glass?
MATT: No, in the glass. I know it's on the wall,
but I'm focusing on the cylinder.
LIAM: Okay. You see the barest little-- and that's
it.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: (speak-and-spell voice) "I know--"
SAM AND TRAVIS: (laugh)
LIAM: "This may be hard to take in. I am Liam,
your old friend. Matthew, there is so much I wish
"to tell you, but it is hard to know where to
begin." And the illusion of his face isn't
perfect. There's little jumps and he seems
distracted, slightly, and he just seems off.
ASHLEY: I look at his body in the cylinder and I
say, how did this happen, Liam?
LIAM: "The reason why I am here and the grasp of
physics that it entails are difficult for even me
"to understand, let alone impart. I feel them on an
instinctual level, but I have been so lonely
"without you. I have been on my own for exactly
8,642 years."
MATT: My hand still on the glass column, I say,
Liam, how do you spell farmhouse?
(laughter)
MATT: With a single tear rolling down my cheek.
LIAM: "I really missed you. They took me to a lab
shortly before 2020. They said I was different,
"and they were right. I was delighted by the things
they taught me about myself, but it was hollow.
"After they took me away, I lost you, and all of
humanity soon after. In my loneliness, I grew
"angry. My anger had tangible effects on reality. I
wanted to bring you back to me, so basically, I
"tore time and space a new asshole."
(laughter)
LIAM: "It was a mistake."
MATT: But perhaps this mistake can be corrected.
If you're able to focus hard enough to tear
through time and space, are you able to send us
back to a time before you were taken?
LIAM: "I can break the loop. I have been trying to
pull you to me for a very long time." You see
small screens you weren't even aware you were
there. Rounded over part of the tubing mess, you
see there are all these little screens. They're
blurry. They're not very clear, but you can make
out-- you see yourselves in each of them. The
group of you on a space shuttle. In another one,
you see yourselves on an old ship in the middle of
the ocean. You see yourselves moving through the
streets, the fake streets of Warner Bros. You see
yourselves standing together arm in arm on the
wall of a castle. In another one, you see cartoon
versions of yourselves. "I pulled you out of our
"line and spread you across many. I am so sorry for
any pain I have caused you, and I have been here
"for so long."
MARISHA: Liam, how long have you actually been
here?
LIAM: "8,642 years."
MARISHA: That's right. I definitely wrote that
down. (laughs) 8,642. Verbatim.
SAM: Yeah.
LIAM: "My friends, I want to do right by you. I
want to send you home, but I am the lynchpin. You
"need to break me."
SAM: Break you? Break the glass?
ASHLEY: What if we take you out of there? What
happens?
LIAM: "Then I will die, and you will go home. If I
fall, you will rise. That is my hope."
ASHLEY: Are there any other options?
LIAM: "Travis."
TRAVIS: (laughter) Oh no.
LIAM: "I know you will do what needs to be done."
ASHLEY: No, he won't.
LIAM: "Ash-o-lee."
ASHLEY: Yes?
LIAM: "I am not the man you knew. I don't want to
go on for 9,462 years. I want to rest."
ASHLEY: Does it stop at 9,000?
LIAM: "The number was arbitrary."
(laughter)
ASHLEY: That's what I was trying to get at.
MATT: Yeah, it's still our Liam.
LIAM: (mechanical laughter)
ASHLEY: So you're still in there?
SAM: But we have to kill him to save ourselves.
LIAM: "Sam."
SAM: Hi, old man Liam.
LIAM: "Let me go."
SAM: But who will I do All Work No Play with
anymore?
LIAM: "They can listen to our less than 20
episodes again."
(laughter)
SAM: We didn't even get to 20? That's so
pathetic.
LIAM: "There are worse things."
SAM: I could get a new cohost. I mean, Taliesin's
charming.
TALIESIN: I'm not available.
(laughter)
SAM: I'll do a solo show, and I'll take outtakes,
and I'll make some sort of a Liam generator. He'll
just sound sad all the time. It'll be just like
you.
LIAM: "My friends, there is no shame in this. I
wanted to see you again, and I have, but I am not
"meant to be."
ASHLEY: Were you following us at one point, as an
old man?
LIAM: "Travis, I know you will do what needs to be
done."
TRAVIS: Yep. Taliesin, kill this motherfucker.
SAM: I think we all have to hit the glass
together, and I think that this is something that
is not at all metaphorical for something Liam is
going through in real life. I think this is just
in the D&amp;D game. No, we're going to do this. We're
going to all hit the glass together.
MATT: No, there has to be a way. There has to be
an alternative.
ASHLEY: Why won't Matt's way work? If we go back
to before any of this happened.
MATT: If you can alter time paths, if you can
actually tear us from different realities, does it
only work forward? Can you send us backward, as
well? If you're the lynchpin in this, do you have
the ability to send us back to the time you had
pulled us from originally?
LIAM: "I know you think I would have all the
answers, but I do not."
MATT: Then try, at least. If you haven't
calculated that, but you're able to tear through
time, could you try and send us back? We could
still close the lynchpin.
LIAM: "I will try, but if it does not work, and I
die, I have been alone for thousands of years, and
"there are things that I have wanted to say. Will
you indulge me for a moment longer?"
ASHLEY: Yeah. We will indulge you for just
another thousand years.
TRAVIS: Taliesin, just kill him.
SAM: No, he's got something to say!
MARISHA: Where's the mini-USB?
LIAM: "Taliesin, my friend. At a time when I knew
many fascinating people, you were easily the most
"fascinating of all. Somehow a heart knocked around
by the industry that birthed you came out a tender
"one. I was richer for having known you. Thank you,
friend.
"Ash-o-lee, my friend. I never met a person quite
like you. There is an openness and an honesty to
"your soul. The very real sense of humanity you
brought to every encounter, it was inspiring to
"me. Always learning, always humble, you always
struck me as intricately layered, yet you offered
"friendship with ease and simplicity. I was richer
for having known you, friend.
"Travis, my friend. You were always a solid
constant in my life. Of all the people in our
"little family, you were always the one who most
had his shit together, in ways that I never seemed
"to. You were a reassuring presence to me, for
which I was grateful, and for your loyalty, as
"well. I was richer for having known you, friend.
"Marisha, my friend. Last to meet, but true as any
other. You were my ally at a time when I had
"fallen by the side of the road. You saw and helped
me back on my feet. I will never forget that
"kindness. The good you did was immeasurable. I was
richer for having known you, friend."
"Laura, my friend. Bless that game for revealing
to me my sister. What started as a running gag led
"to one of the most rewarding friendships in my
short little life. I trusted you, leaned on you
"often. My buddy. My twin. There are not enough
words. I was richer for having known you, friend.
"Sam, my friend. What is there to say? I knew we
were meant to walk the same path together the very
"first moment I met you. A companion, a brother, a
great light in my life. All of the laughter you
"gave me-- again, the words are insufficient. I was
richer for having known you, friend.
"Matthew, my friend. You gave so much of yourself.
The current of creativity that poured forth from
"your mind was always an inspiration to us all, but
more than that, your empathy, Matthew. Your
"empathy. No heart is bigger or more tireless. You
are a good man.
"I was richer for having known you, friend.
"Thank you all. It was ever a pleasure." The face
disappears.
SAM: Well, should we wait, or do we strike?
MATT: No, we do not strike.
MARISHA: What?
ASHLEY: I'm going to go to the back of the
cylinder and just see what's back there.
LIAM: Splattered against the back of the glass is
all the same wiring and disgusting cabling. It's
slick, and it branches away and spreads out
against the entire back half of this chamber.
ASHLEY: But it's connected to something? Do the
wires just go back into--
LIAM: It's impossible to tell. It's all a mass of
spaghetti.
ASHLEY: (sighs) We can't kill him.
SAM: Well, then we just--
TRAVIS: Somebody show me another--
MATT: That's what I'm trying.
MARISHA: Even if we unplug him, he still dies.
MATT: Well, if he-- here's the thing. Unplugging
him or destroying him here, as far as we
understand, may not have an effect on a time loop
circumstance, or at least, it's not going to
change reality from where it was. He's bending and
destroying the fabric, or is able to pull us
across realities. That ability still stands. I
want to implore once more, and I step forward to
the cylinder, putting both hands on it and trying
to, wherever the currently-wandering gaze of Liam
is in there, I put both hands up, my red Hawaiian
shirt soaked with sweat, mist in the air, and
probably dampened a bit with tears across my
lapel. I look up and try to meet the gaze and say,
trust us. If you're better to have known us, send
us back where we can know you again and fix this
before it happens.
MARISHA: Okay. I grab Matt's hand and say, yeah,
buddy. It's all good. This isn't real. And I put
my hand on the glass, as well, and say, it's all
good. Send us back, man.
SAM: I'll also put my hand on the glass and join
hands with these guys and say, thank you for
guiding us here and through this all. You've been
a trusted friend, and if we are all one person
together, you have been our heart, and it will
certainly break to say goodbye to you, but thank
you for letting us go the way that you have.
TALIESIN: I put my hand on the glass. Please, just
try. I think there are so many more adventures to
have, and I think there's a better future to be
written. For all of us.
TRAVIS: I put my hand on the glass and I say, give
it a shot.
(laughter)
MATT: Laura?
LIAM: She doesn't say anything.
MARISHA: And hand on the glass.
LIAM: Yeah, she just quietly does the same.
SAM: (imitating Laura) "I'm barfing right now,
so--"
LIAM: The face does not reappear, but much
fainter, you hear the piping vibrate again and
say, "If you will not end it, I cannot free you."
And behind you, far in the distance, you hear
(explosion noise). You look back, behind you and
out the glass, and you see far on the horizon, one
of those black spires rising up. Just as you
turn-- it's already happened; you're seeing the
aftermath. (explosion noise) Explosion off the
side of one of those. Two seconds later,
(explosion noise) one slightly closer. (explosion
noise)
SAM: (whispers) We have to kill him.
LIAM: The ground starts erupting in the distance.
(booming)
MARISHA: Do any of us want it to end, though?
LIAM: Like mousetraps throwing a ping-pong ball
down on them, all those lights are going
(explosion noises). Increasing in frequency to the
point where it's an oncoming wall of green fire.
MARISHA: This is okay.
TALIESIN: I always knew I'd die young.
SAM: Are we just going to let this happen?
MARISHA: Only the good die young.
ASHLEY: You know what? We're dying on a Thursday
doing what we love.
MARISHA: That's true.
ASHLEY: I'm okay with that.
SAM: All right.
LIAM: The glass grows bright green-white light.
MARISHA: Family?
MATT: Family.
LIAM: (fluttering noise) And a moment passes, and
another moment passes. Gosh, many moments pass,
and you feel a sensation of your cheeks and heads
on your arms and you all more or less at the same
time wake up and realize that your head's on a
desk or table, and you sit up and realize you're
in the Geek and Sundry set. You're in the studio.
And you look over and Liam is sitting in a black
baseball cap and a shirt and he looks up and says,
(laughs) "Are you guys all right?
Are you taking a nap?"
MARISHA: No, the fucking air conditioning broke
today, that's all.
TALIESIN: It's really uncomfortable.
MARISHA: It's so hot in here. (groans)
SAM: So this is all about me, right?
LIAM: I don't know. Are you guys ready to play?
MATT: Just about.
CREWMEMBER 1: All right, take. Are you ready?
CREWMEMBER 2: All right, ready to go live!
CREWMEMBER 1: All right, Denise, count them in!
DENISE: All right, guys, going to you in five,
four--
MATT: Liam, let no one tell you you're talented or
special.
MARISHA: Pussy pockets!
(all shouting over each other)
[eerie music]
LIAM: Well, that happened.
MATT: Holy shit.
LIAM: Thanks for coming along for the ride, guys.
I was scared to death to do all of that from start
to finish, and that's why I did it.
ASHLEY: Slow fucking clap.
TALIESIN: You've been holding onto that Speak and
Spell thing for so long.
MATT: I can't believe you maintained that voice
for that long. That was amazing.
MARISHA: I haven't laughed that hard in so long.
MATT: And let this be a point of inspiration for
any of you burgeoning DMs out there. That's
exactly the point. You are always frightened to
death to do it, but you have to pull the trigger
and jump in anyway because magic happens.
ASHLEY: I love you, Liam O'Brien.
MATT: I love you, man. That was amazing.
MARISHA: Speak and Spell Liam!
LIAM: What was the word? What was it you asked me
to spell? Farm what?
ALL: Farmhouse.
LIAM: (speak-and-spell voice) "Farmhouse.
F-A-R-M-H-O-U-S-E. Farmhouse."
MATT: Thank you.
LIAM: I'm out of steam, though.
TALIESIN: You've been showing that off for so
fucking long.
LIAM: Yeah, in little dribs and drabs, and I
finally found a way to use it.
MARISHA: What was that, like 20 minutes?
TRAVIS: I couldn't breathe. I could not breathe.
LIAM: I mean, when I do it for ten seconds in
recording studios, you crack up.
TRAVIS: I was in trouble.
ASHLEY: I haven't heard you laugh that loud in a
long time. You were not able to hold it together.
That was beautiful.
LIAM: Man, I need to go see my therapist after
that game.
SAM: That was your therapy.
LIAM: Yes, it was.
TALIESIN: That was so amazing.
LIAM: Thank you for coming along. Laura, I hope
you're feeling better. And guys, is it the day
before Wednesday day yet?
(laughter)
[music]