SAM: Hey, everybody! It's me, Sam Riegel! Welcome
to Not Critical Role! I will be your host for the
evening and Dungeon Master. This is the first time
I've ever done this, so treat me nicely and
gently. I will be guiding our players tonight
through some sort of convoluted story that I've
come up with. My guests for this evening are
ferociously handsome and attractive people.
Perhaps I can introduce them to you now. Over here
is cabbage-smelling Brian Foster. Next to him is
the fabulously talented and sultry Mary Elizabeth
McGlynn. Next to her is cute-as-a-button Ashly
Burch. Then my wife and yours, Liam O'Brien. Next
to him, playing his first ever game of Dungeons
and Dragons--
ERIC: I just got off my Uber shift, and I am
terrified right now.
SAM: This is Eric Bauza, man of a thousand voices.
He really doesn't know how to play at all, and
didn't really practice.
LIAM: He knows six percent less than you!
SAM: Yeah, that's right! I will be asking for a
lot of help tonight from Liam O'Brien, as will Eric.
LIAM: And I'll turn to the right and ask Matt--
he's not here.
SAM: Matt and Marisha and the rest of the Critical
Role gang are on the playa in Burning Man right
now, so they can't be here. Naked. Humping each
other. So they can't be here tonight, but we're
going to carry on without them and have a one-shot
deal. We have some announcements before we go,
right, Liam?
LIAM: Yeah, I got some, you got some.
SAM: I'll start. First, new merch, guys! New merch
available in the store right now. This awesome
shirt that says Dalen's Closet in Shamal Bay. It's
a little throwback to that little fun beach
adventure we had with pranks and stuff. Ooh, it's
so soft.
LIAM: If you think that sleeves are bullshit, we
have this one, as well.
SAM: Wow, that's such a beachy shirt!
ERIC: You get a great tan with that shirt.
SAM: Wow, I love it! And it's available in the
store already? Now? Go purchase it! Go purchase
the shirts.
BRIAN: I want to see Travis wear that when he
works out.
LIAM: There's more stuff, though. Well, the Dagger
Dagger Dagger shirt is back. I know that's not
brand new, but it's new-ish. The Scanlan shirt is
even less new-ish, but it's an amazing shirt, and
it's still there. We have the aprons still, we
have pencils, we have Tarot cards. I feel like
going: ooh. She's in the desert; she can't touch
me right now. That's it.
SAM: So that's our merch update. Liam and I will
be tomorrow morning flying to Sacramento to do
SacAnime. Are you doing it, Mary?
MARY: No, I have to do a red-eye on Friday night
to Dragon Con. Yes, very exciting, to meet Mr.
Steve Blum there. I haven't met, I'm looking
forward to it.
SAM: So we'll be in Sacramento for the weekend, me
and Liam, doing stuff. Come see us. Come say hi if
you're in the northern central California
vicinity. Sure. Any other announcements, Liam?
LIAM: Yeah, we've got that art book coming out. If
you want to get updates you can go over to
geekandsundry.com/artbook and sign up for updates,
and you'll get the latest. And then also,
Taliesin's not here; he's also naked in the
desert, but on Wednesday he'll be back for
Wednesday Club. In addition to everything they're
going to be talking about, there will be a little
scuttlebutt about the Critical Role comic book. We
might show you the cover of the damn thing. Other
things to announce about it, so tune in if you're
curious.
BRIAN: There's Talks Machina Tuesday night.
SAM: Oh Jesus, Brian, come on.
BRIAN: It's shameless self promotion at this
point. But no, it's great, actually, to be a part
of the show that I have been riding the coattails
of this past year. It's great to finally be a part
of the actual show. Tuesday nights, Talks Machina.
I'll talk to you guys afterward about who's going
to be on, and then we'll announce. So that's it,
7:00 on these very channels.
SAM: Eric, anything to plug?
ERIC: DuckTales. That's how we do our thing. We're
on DuckTales together.
LIAM: Yeah, he plays many characters.
ERIC: Yes, actually, I think the 23rd may be the
introduction of the many characters.
SAM: Oh is that true? September 23rd, tune in to
DuckTales. He played 30 characters in one episode?
Something like that. It's a lot.
ERIC: I had to sing Happy Birthday 47 times. 47
different accents.
SAM: Ash-boo, anything?
ASHLY: I think you're great and you're going to do
a great job. Oh, OK K.O.!, which Mary's also on,
is out now on Cartoon Network. Are you on it,
Bauza?
ERIC: No.
(laughter)
ERIC: I'm just trying to learn how to play
tonight. This is my guy. It's almost like it's the
same person.
SAM: All right, so with all that out of the way,
let's dive into another episode of Critical Role!
[dramatic music]
SAM: Hi guys! Welcome back!
BRIAN: He got in just under the wire.
LIAM: Safe. Totally safe.
ERIC: How many drinks do you have going there?
SAM: I have two drinks, one alcoholic--
BRIAN: And one if that one breaks down.
SAM: Okay. So needless to say, I'm super nervous
because I've never done this before, but it's
going to be fun, and if it sucks then who cares,
right? So let's just dive in, right? I'm going to
play music from my iPad.
BRIAN: Thank you for telling us everything you're
doing as you do it.
SAM: I'm now turning to my notes. All right. I'm
about to begin the show.
BRIAN: This is great.
SAM: Here we go. Black and white, as far as the
eye can see. The black of a cold night sky, the
white of ice capping every tree and dusting the
roads below. It is a frigid, monochromatic night
in Jorenn Village, at the foot of the Umber
Hills-- until! A flash of yellow hair, hoofbeats,
a fast-moving horse, a young human woman riding at
top speed through the windy night. She barrels
down the street, muttering to herself, "Shit,
shit, shit, I'm late again!"
Then suddenly, a thunk. The horse whinnies. Did
she just hit something or someone? Oh no. The
young woman stops, dismounts, walks back, and sees
an awful sight. An old woman in a simple grey
robe, cane in a mangled hand, face bloody, arm
broken. She's motionless, ashen. "Oh fuck," says
the girl. "Oh my fuck. I think I-- is that a-- I
just killed someone. Oh gods, what am I going to
"do? I am so dead." The young woman looks around.
No one to call for a doctor. No fire-lit homes to
knock on for help.
Wait. No lights. No prying eyes. No witnesses.
The rider takes a breath, kicks a little snow over
the body of the old woman, checks the streets one
more time, and then mounts the horse and gets the
hell out of there, no one the wiser. She rides on,
feeling guilty, but also relieved. No one saw,
right? Right?
In a few minutes she arrives at her destination,
shivering with cold. She ties her horse to the
lion statue across the street, just in time for
her shift at the second crappiest tavern in town:
The Ass Sailor. The sign above the door once said
"The Crass Sailor," but months ago, vandals pried
off the shitty letters C-R, so now it just reads,
"The Ass Sailor." The name seems to have resonated
with its low-life patrons and they seem to prefer
it.
The poorly built tavern sits on the foundation of
an old chapel, and some time in the last hundred
years was expanded to two stories: a pub on the
bottom and rooms above. Despite its thin walls, it
has one feature that regulars love on nights like
this: it is notoriously warm.
The woman pushes open the door, jogs past the Ass
Sailor's source of heat: a large hearth, blurred
with red coals. It's a small fireplace, but no
matter where you sit in The Ass Sailor, you always
stay weirdly warm. So toasty, in fact, that
there's a massive pile of jackets and scarves and
weapons to the left of the door. Everyone inside
has stripped down to the bare minimum of dress.
With the lack of clothing comes an oversupply of
skin, skin of all shades and body parts. The ruddy
belly of a human salesman stuffing himself on
rotten mutton. The dark blue-tinted shoulder of a
tiefling whore, enticing a gray, bearded, older
man upstairs. The gray forearm of a half-orc
merchant, drawing a mug of Greep from the keg on
the bar. Greep, by the way, is a homemade house
liqueur. It's so potent, its nickname is "kindling"
because it is also extremely flammable. Hint,
hint, hint!
LIAM: Red barrels, everywhere!
SAM: "You're late!" calls the bar manager, Xavier,
wiping his hands on his grubby chef's apron.
"I hit some unexpected traffic on the road!"
replies your late-shift bartender, Valerie, as she
puts on her apron and ducks behind the bar. There
are a dozen tables, most populated with drunken
assholes, half-witted con artists, and infectious
laughter. Val gets right to work on a night that
will prove to be unlike any other.
At the bar, a noble half-elf woman with fiery
eyes, dark skin, and spectacular blonde hair
nervously fidgets with her necklace. She glances
about, looking for someone. In an elegant blue
and white gown and golden jewelry, she is
definitely out of place among the riffraff. This,
we will learn, is Gryffin.
Val, the bartender, approaches. "Hi. So what can I
get you?"
MARY: What is your name?
SAM: "Valerie, hi."
MARy: Hello. Do you have any scotch?
SAM: "Well, no." I have a menu.
MARY: You do?
SAM: I'm over-prepared. Oh god, I've lost the
menu. Oh god, everything's gone wrong one minute
into the show. Oh god. "We have ale."
MARY: Any Fireball?
SAM: "We have Greep, which is the house liqueur. We
have some whiskey, and we have some wine. The wine
"is not very good."
MARY: I'll have the whiskey. Actually, you know
what? Can I have whiskey with a Greep chaser, please?
SAM: "Oh, sure. That'll be seven copper."
MARY: All right, here.
SAM: "There you go. What brings you around here?
Haven't seen you before."
MARY: Oh, well, mostly to get out of the cold.
Actually, maybe you can help me. I'm so sorry.
I've been looking for a girl, and there was a man
who told me of this place.
SAM: "Well, we have two ladies of the night over
there. One is named Zarvah; she's the tiefling,
"and she's a crowd pleaser. Yes. The other is Kay,
and she's over there as well."
MARY: Thank you, thank you. Actually, I was
looking for someone a bit younger than both of
them. She has red hair. I'm wondering if you've
seen anyone quite like that?
SAM: "I'm no one to judge but whatever sort of
thing floats your boat. I don't know any young
"whores, if that's what you're asking for."
MARY: No, just a young girl. All right. Frankfurt,
have you heard of a man named Frankfurt?
SAM: "Sure, yes. Frankfurt. He's a dwarven man. He
comes in here from time to time. I think he's on a
"run. I haven't seen him tonight."
MARY: All right. Well, he told me to come here, so
I did. So I'll just have a drink for now, if
that's all right.
SAM: "All right, I'll let you know if he
arrives."
MARY: Thank you so much, I do appreciate that,
Val.
SAM: Just then, a tall female humanoid with
rippling biceps and long whiskers takes the next
stool over. She's covered with tan and orange fur,
which is unsurprising because she is tabaxi, a
cat-woman. Her feline face is bandaged from recent
battles, and she snarls with an imposing posture
that says, "Don't fuck with me." This is
Clothesline. Val approaches. "Oh, hey,
"Clothesline. The usual, I assume?"
ASHLY: Do you have the milk that I ordered?
SAM: "Yes." Val takes out a saucer of warm milk
and puts it on the bar. "Oh, and here's some
"spice, too." She places a box of crimson powder on
the bar. It is catnip.
ASHLY: Thanks, Val.
SAM: "What happened to your face?"
ASHLY: Oh, you know. It's a funny story. I
clotheslined some people.
SAM: "Oh, that's--"
ASHLY: Yeah. And their nails were not cut.
Generally when you clothesline someone you (clicks
tongue) go, but they caught on for a little bit,
went for a little bit of a ride, and then I killed
them. So that's that.
SAM: "Wow. That sounds like a lovely evening?"
AHSLY: Oh yeah, it was great! I could've done
without all the cleanup after. There was a lot of
blood. It's hard to get out of the old fur.
SAM: "Sure. Clothesline, this is-- What was your
name again?"
MARY: Gryffin. Gryffin Erendel.
ASHLY: Hi.
MARY: Hello, how are you?
ASHLY: You got weird eyes. What's the deal with
her eyes?
MARY: They're gold. There's nothing wrong with
them.
ASHLY: They're gold, like currency gold?
MARY: No, they're not karated gold, they're just
gold. I'm a sunny Eladrin half-elf, all right?
ASHLY: What does that mean?
SAM: "I don't know. I don't really know."
MARY: It doesn't matter. Why do you have fur? Why
does anybody have anything? It's just who I am.
It's who you are. So cheers to us.
ASHLY: I don't cheers ladies with weird eyes.
MARY: All right. You've got a little blood on you
there, dear.
SAM: As they speak, over at a small table, a young
human girl sits alone, peering out of her hooded
cloak. She has almost translucent skin, and snowy
wisps of white hair fall over her face. Her cool
blue eyes reveal a quiet confidence, but she seems
guarded and keeping her back to the wall, not
touching her glass of water. This is Jayne.
Strolling over to the table, with a wobbly gait,
is a short elven man with gray skin, gray hair,
and a black leather choker. He wears a sour
expression and projects abject apathy. He reeks of
booze and appears to be wearing dark red eye
makeup. This is Kingston, and it looks like
Kingston is approaching Jayne.
BRIAN: Evening.
LIAM: Oh, hello.
BRIAN: Do you come here a lot?
LIAM: No. I am traveling, actually.
BRIAN: Alone?
LIAM: Yes.
BRIAN: By what mode of transportation are you
traveling?
LIAM: Well, have a seat, I'll tell you everything.
Let's start with my childhood.
BRIAN: Great! Do you want a drink?
LIAM: No, and that was irony. I could have
something to eat. Do you want to get us something
to eat?
BRIAN: Yeah. Any dietary restrictions? I don't
want to walk over and then have to come back.
LIAM: Just a little something.
BRIAN: Okay. I'll walk over to Val. Unless there's
table service?
SAM: Hell no. "Hi, Kingston. What can I get for
you?"
BRIAN: Me and the child over there need food.
SAM: "The child?"
BRIAN: She's a bit young for me. I like them old.
SAM: "You're going to buy this person food?"
BRIAN: Yes.
SAM: "With what money?"
BRIAN: You can put it on my fucking tab, for
starters. She looks famished. She's traveled by
some unknown mode of transportation. She looks
famished. She doesn't want a drink. She wants to
eat. Put it on my tab. Consider it a humanitarian
gift.
SAM: "All right, I'll give you some bread. All
right?"
BRIAN: And also some Greep for me.
SAM: "Fine." Takes a glass of Greep for you. "And
here's two loaves of bread. On your tab. Again."
BRIAN: Thank you. I walk over and hand her the
loaves. Here you go.
LIAM: That's nice.
BRIAN: I get stuff free around here.
LIAM: You're from here?
BRIAN: Yeah. Nearby.
LIAM: Is it always this cold?
BRIAN: Well, not in here. But outside? Yeah, it's
pretty cold.
LIAM: I'm sorry, what was your name?
BRIAN: Kingston LaForge.
LIAM: Strong name.
BRIAN: Thank you. I come from a long line of
LaForges.
LIAM: Tell me about yourself. And as he goes, she
starts inspecting the room, kind of listening.
SAM: All right, you see a bunch of rowdy people
all about you. No one out of the ordinary that you
can see so far. Let's see here, what interesting
things? You know what? Make a perception check.
LIAM: It was almost good. Ten.
SAM: You see lots of festive people eating lots of
food and drinking lots of wine. That's about it.
LIAM: Does anybody look dangerous?
SAM: Dangerous? Well, most of the people in here
are weaponless. Some do have weapons. The tabaxi
over there is packing some biceps and some sharp
claws. There's a couple of guards. There's one
guard over near the door who's watching people's
cloaks and whatever weapons have been checked.
There's another city guard who's drinking, but
he's got his sword. He's near the wall over there.
He's got his sword sheathed, and he looks like he
could do some damage, maybe. That's about it. The
prostitutes look really feisty, and one of them is
having an argument, still,
with this man, about payment.
LIAM: So you were going to tell me your story?
BRIAN: Did you see that cat lady over there?
LIAM: Yes, I did.
BRIAN: She is something else. I'm not saying I
have a type, but my preferred terrain is a litter box.
LIAM: You know, I'm happy to share the loaves of
bread with you, but my feelings won't be hurt if
you want to change over.
BRIAN: Thank you, but I'll tell you a little bit
about myself first. What would you like to know?
LIAM: Oh, start from the beginning. You grew up
here? Tell me all about it.
BRIAN: I was born Kingston LaForge. Still am. To a
long line of LaForges.
MARY: Did you hear him say Kingston LaForge?
BRIAN: My family was acrobats.
ASHLY: Why is she talking to me, Val?
BRIAN: Carnies. 24/7 locksmiths. I, however, was
afraid of heights, so I had to learn how to sing
for my supper. However, nature took over around
the age of teen. I lost my beautiful singing
voice. It was a falsetto, a very lovely falsetto.
LIAM: When you were young, you lost it? That must
have been a long time ago.
BRIAN: Oh yes, over 100 years. So I left my family
and the traveling circus, and I found myself a
wife, Cloris. We wed, and together, I wrote some
of the best books the land has ever seen.
LIAM: Jayne is quietly digging her fingernails
into her leg to stop from screaming.
MARY: I quietly start pounding on the bar.
BRIAN: Together, we bore a child, and it was one
of the most incredible things that ever happened
to me. The child was precious.
ASHLY: Oh my god, Kingston, give it a rest!
BRIAN: Hi!
ASHLY: Hi.
BRIAN: I was just talking to this child--
ASHLY: Yeah, I get it. It's creepy. Could you stop
creeping us all out? You re-hash your goddamn life
story every time you come in here.
BRIAN: She asked! I simply brought her free food.
She asked me a question. I have an interesting story.
ASHLY: You don't have an interesting-- No! Your
beautiful falsetto? No! No one cares!
BRIAN: You say that because you never got to hear
it.
MARY: Hello, I'm sorry, my name is Gryffin Erendel
and I'm the biggest fan. I can't begin to tell you
how much I love your work. Your book of poetry,
Black and White, was one of the most amazing
things I've ever read in my entire life and I
happen to have a copy with me. Would you please
sign it? Do you mind? I don't want to intrude. I
would pay for it.
BRIAN: Have you read some of my other books?
MARY: Yes, I have!
BRIAN: Two Witches, One Broom?
MARY: Yes, yes! The Wicked Grouse?
BRIAN: Yes, Doors: The Idiot's Enemy?
ASHLY: Val, another milk, please!
BRIAN: Here you go. Here's your book.
SAM: "I made it a double."
ASHLY: Thank you.
MARY: You have no idea. Would you read from it?
BRIAN: I will, after. May I talk to you for a
minute? I know, may I just-- (sighs) I know we
don't get along very often. However, I find you to
be very attractive.
ASHLY: Oh, what the hell, Kingston!
BRIAN: I've struggled on how to say this to you,
but--
ASHLY: You are this close from a claw in your
goddamn eye, Kingston. So choose the next few
words carefully.
BRIAN: Catnip and chill?
ASHLY: Can I attack Kingston?
SAM: Sure! Whatever you want to do.
MARY: I step back.
ASHLY: I try to punch Kingston in the mouth.
SAM: All right, roll for an attack.
ASHLY: Okay, let's see. I don't want to use my
claws. I guess I'm going to clothesline him.
SAM: Great. Clothesline attack.
ASHLY: 1d4.
SAM: Roll a d20, add, what is it, five?
ASHLY: 13.
SAM: Okay, what's your armor class there,
Kingston?
BRIAN: My armor? 13.
SAM: That's a hit, right, Liam? 13 and 13, that's
a hit? All right, roll for damage. 1d4 plus something.
ASHLY: Eight!
SAM: Wow! Did you roll a four? Okay, so you don't
have to roll for anything.
BRIAN: Hold on, I'm buried in my notes.
SAM: So Clothesline has a special clothesline
attack. If she rolls a four, it's eight points of
damage to you, sir, and you are knocked prone.
BRIAN: Shit, that's amazing!
SAM: That's a big fucking hit.
ASHLY: It is! I deliberately didn't use my claws
because I didn't want to hurt you too much!
SAM: So Kingston slams down onto the floor, taking
a couple of drinks with him. He's dazed. He's
woozy. He looks around. He didn't even see it
coming.
BRIAN: Did my drink go with me?
SAM: Sure, yeah. Greep all over the floor. All
over you. You now have a flammable alcohol all
over you. It's probably stinging your eyes. You
hardly know who hit you or why.
BRIAN: I'm blinded!
MARY: He will write of this day, and I will know
that I was here!
BRIAN: You're going to have to write this down. I
can't see!
MARY: It's all in my mind!
SAM: Xavier, the manager, comes over. "All right,
enough of that! No fights tonight, all right?"
ASHLY: Sorry, Xave, sorry.
BRIAN: It was just foreplay. We have a big night
planned, and I'm sorry we started it in your
establishment.
ASHLY: No fights? What about a murder? One
murder?
SAM: "Nothing like that tonight, please."
MARY: I use Prestidigitation to cleanse him off.
ASHLY: What did you just do?
SAM: Some magical energy comes out of her and
magically cleans up the stains off of his shirt.
Everyone in the bar turns to see and goes like
this to you when you do it. You are no longer
flammable.
ASHLY: What the hell was that? What you just did?
Creepy guy? He's no longer whatever?
MARY: What, you've never heard of magic?
ASHLY: I know about magic.
MARY: Oh, you do? Well then, why are you asking me
such a silly question?
ASHLY: Val, I'm going to move to a table.
SAM: "Sure."
MARY: I meant no offense.
SAM: As the tabaxi glides across the room, finding
another table, let's move you over here. I just
knocked over a stool.
BRIAN: I'm going to walk back over to Jayne. Yeah,
because things didn't go as well as I was hoping.
SAM: So you're alone by the bar now? Yes. And just
then, the wind whips into the bar again as the
door opens. Valerie, the bartender, gasps, scared
it might be the dead old lady. But instead, it is
not. Two stout male dwarves walk in. Behind them,
a young girl with fire-red hair and elven ears.
They walk in, and let's put them here for now. One dwarf
is sullen, with thick muttonchops and a stumpy
axe. He says, "I tire of the road. We eat here and
rest. Frankfurt, this is your job. You pay. Obby
"the Rat is done for the day."
ASHLY and LIAM: Yes!
SAM: The other dwarf is a younger, stronger man
with a braided beard, piercing eyes, and a heavy
maul in his hand. He scans the room and picks a
table. Unlike some of the patrons, these two do
not check their weapons. Instead, they park them
under the table. This is Frankfurt and his friend,
Obby the Rat. They pull up a chair for the young,
fair-skinned ginger girl, who joins them. Her eyes
sparkle with innocence and a touch of fear. Her
name, we will learn, is Holly. "You have been to
"this place before?"
ERIC: Yep, many times. Known for their Greep.
SAM: "What is that?"
ERIC: Delicious, is what it is. You should try
some.
SAM: "Obby the Rat drinks ale."
ERIC: Careful, there's a cat-woman in here. You
might want to be careful of that. Val!
Two Greeps, please!
SAM: "Yes, right away, Frankfurt! That's him."
MARY: Thank you so much.
SAM: "Certainly. Tips would be appreciated."
MARY: Oh, of course! What was I thinking? Here. I
give her a piece of gold.
SAM: "Oh, wow. Thank you very much."
MARY: You're welcome.
ERIC: I start taking off my clothes.
SAM: "All of your clothes?"
ERIC: Almost all. It's hot. It's boiling in here.
SAM: "It is very hot. Are you sure you want to
strip down? There are unsavory types in here."
ERIC: I'm a regular. They've seen the merchandise
before.
SAM: "Yes."
ERIC: But don't attract too much attention to us.
We've got some cargo here that people might be
interested in.
SAM: "What cargo? We are not transporting any
cargo tonight."
ERIC: Well, not anything in particular that anyone
would be looking for, but have
you seen Garello around?
SAM: "I do not know this Garello. You have spoken
of him, but I don't know that I would recognize him."
ERIC: Well, keep your eyes peeled.
SAM: "Perhaps ask someone else."
ERIC: Hey, Cat-Woman?
ASHLY: Oh, for fuck's sake, what?
ERIC: How are you?
ASHLY: How do I look?
ERIC: Bloody! And your glass is half empty. Val!
More milk, please!
SAM: "Right away. Whole or skim this time?"
ASHLY: Give me the raw shit.
SAM: "Okay."
ERIC: So! How's your night been?
ASHLY: I've had better.
ERIC: Okay. Any scraps you've been into?
ASHLY: What do you want, man?
ERIC: Okay, look. I'm going to get down to
business here. I've got this girl, and we're
looking for a guy named Garello. Maybe you've
heard of him?
ASHLY: Garello?
ERIC: G-A-R-E-L-L-O. I got to make a delivery, and
I want to get it over with.
ASHLY: Is this the type of thing that I can roll
to see if I have information of?
SAM: Sure, yeah. Why don't you make an
intelligence check?
ASHLY: That's not going to go well. What does that
stand for? That's a natural 20? Never mind. I
haven't used these dice before.
SAM: So you don't personally know Garello, but you
are a woman about town who hears things, hears
whispers, talks with unsavory sorts. You have
heard there is a man in town, not from here, named
Garello, who has been poking his nose around The
Ass Sailor, waiting for something. But you haven't
met him yet.
ASHLY: So I don't know what he looks like or
anything like that?
SAM: No, just that he's been asking around. He's
been here before.
LIAM: He's way up in The Ass Sailor.
BRIAN: He's ass-deep in the sailor.
ERIC: Well, good to know.
BRIAN: Jayne? Picking up quickly where we left
off, I apologize for how that went. I had a wife,
Cloris, I mentioned. A child. We named our child
Denise. She was beautiful, yet expensive.
MARY: I slowly make my way over to Frankfurt.
BRIAN: One day, I came home and found my wife in
bed with another man. And not even a real man, a
half a man. A dwarf.
ERIC: Oh! I spilled something on my pants.
BRIAN: The last time I saw that dwarf, I told him
I was going to fucking kill him if I saw him
again, and he just walked into the fucking bar.
That's him over there.
SAM: "What is wrong with you?"
ERIC: Hey, hey, hey.
SAM: "What?"
ERIC: Obby, there's a dude over there. He's
staring right at us. Don't make any moves.
SAM: "Which dude?"
ERIC: That guy, arms crossed.
LIAM: So you're telling me this man has impugned
your honor.
BRIAN: My family's honor.
ERIC: I may have fucked up. Well, not me, but I
fucked someone--
BRIAN: I came home and she was sitting on his
frankfurter.
ERIC: Oh shit. You know, the T in my name stands
for "The." Frankfurt The Dwarf. I have to tell you
a secret.
SAM: "Do you have a beef with this gentleman?"
BRIAN: Oh, there's beef involved, all right.
ERIC: Yeah, you could say that. There was beef.
BRIAN: Yeah, there was a little too much beef, if
you ask me.
SAM: "Do you want me to go kill him?"
ERIC: You could try? Do your old pal a favor?
BRIAN: I cast Message to Gryffin.
SAM: Okay, sure.
BRIAN: Can I send her a secret thing? Can I tell
her a message?
SAM: Yes, Message will make a whisper appear in
her ear.
MARY: And I can whisper back.
SAM: Once.
BRIAN: Gryffin, that dwarf fucked my wife.
(laughter)
SAM: So Gryffin, you're sitting at the bar looking
around. You don't know who just talked to you. All
of a sudden, you hear this voice in your ear that
says, "That dwarf fucked my wife." You vaguely
have heard the voice before, but it's loud in
here. You have no idea what the fuck just
happened.
BRIAN: Am I allowed to add to it?
SAM: Sure.
BRIAN: By the way, it's me, Kingston LaForge, from
earlier. I signed the book that I wrote.
MARY: Is that the title of your new book?
SAM: And the spell fades.
(laughter)
SAM: Expert use of Message.
MARY: So I continue to work my way slowly, slyly,
away from the bar.
SAM: Okay, as you travel across the room, Liam
opens a book of some sort. As you are walking
across the room, Jayne, our young girl played by
Liam O'Brien, starts eyeing Clothesline and trying
to get her eye contact. She raises an index finger
to her eyebrow and winks. I think? Oh. Yes. There
is some sort of a wink or a nod exchanged. Yes?
Okay. At which point Clothesline looks around her,
having received some sort of a signal. To her left
is one human guard. Where the fuck did you go?
MARY: Is that the guy you threw away?
SAM: No, where's the tabaxi? Where is the cat
lady?
BRIAN: Oh, she went to a table.
SAM: (laughing) Where is she? There's too many
people in here. Oh, there she is. Okay, so to her
left is one human guard ordering a drink. To her
right, one half-orc merchant. Behind her has
wandered Zarvah the whore. And she turns.
BRIAN: How old would you say she is?
SAM: Who?
BRIAN: Zarvah the whore.
SAM: Zarvah the whore is a tiefling. I don't know
how tiefling ageing works, so I'm going to say 30.
(laughter)
BRIAN: Do you know how old the other one is?
SAM: The other whore?
BRIAN: Yeah.
SAM: Is older, much older.
BRIAN: Like old?
SAM: Yeah. Her name is Kay, I think.
BRIAN: Kay is the elderly one?
SAM: Yes. Clothesline looks around. Human guard,
half-orc, Zarvah the whore. Would you like to do
anything, Clothesline?
LIAM: Actually, quickly I whisper over to the
weird one and I pull out my holy symbol of the
Lawbearer and say: there is a time and a place for
law and civilization, but your experience sounds
trying, and I know what I would do. And I tuck the
medallion away.
BRIAN: Look, you seem like a sweet chick, but what
the fuck were you grabbing onto? What was this?
What is that? What is the necklace? What is that?
LIAM: Are you not familiar with the gods?
BRIAN: Fuck the gods! The gods?! Sarenrae's a
bitch! Kord couldn't lift a dead sparrow! The
Chained Oblivion took your mom to second base and
never called her again. Fuck the gods!
SAM: Yes. Gryffin has arrived over at the table,
yes.
ASHLY: Where's my movement? My speed, right?
SAM: All right. You're fast, 30, I think?
ASHLY: 30, yeah. Can I reach Gryffin?
SAM: Yeah, sure. Let's see here. Five, ten. Yes,
sure. You're going to have to dodge around some
dudes, but yeah, you can reach Gryffin. Sure.
Would you like to move there? All right. With
cat-like grace, she leaps up onto the table, back
to there, back up on the bar, back down, back on
the table, all the way over to Gryffin right
there.
LIAM: Assassin's Creed.
MARY: With Gilbert and Sullivan playing in the
background.
SAM: And no one even hears you move, you're so
dexterous and awesome.
MARY: I'm pulling out a small bag of gold.
ASHLY: And to immediately ruin my stealth, I go:
Sorry, Xavier! Bar fight! And I hit Gryffin.
SAM: What did you roll?
ASHLY: 14.
MARY: Yeah, that hits.
SAM: Okay. What are you attacking with? Your
claws, or--
ASHLY: Oh yeah, what should I attack with? I'll
attack with my claws.
SAM: Claws. So plus, what is it? Five?
ASHLY: Five. Yeah.
SAM: So it's a 19, right? Okay. That hits. Okay.
This is it. So the words "bar fight" ring out,
everyone turns, looks to the source of the action
over there at the table, and with razor-like
claws-- right? You did a claw attack? Digging into
the back of your head, Gryffin, you feel intense
pain, and roll for damage.
ASHLY: That is a five.
SAM: Five. Take five hit points off there, Gryff.
You feel these claws dig into the back of your
head, you feel blood trickling down your neck. It
sucks. What would you like to do, Gryffin?
MARY: I turn and I cast Reduce.
SAM: Reduce? Not familiar with that one. Oh,
Reduce Size!
MARY: Reduce Size!
SAM: Yes! I am familiar with that one. Okay, as
you do that, I need everyone to roll initiative.
It is a bar fight.
ASHLY: 14.
MARY: Natural 20! Thanks for not fucking me, Gil!
SAM: Oh god! Okay. Everyone get your numbers in
your head. I'm going to roll for about seven other
people. Okay. Sure. Uh-huh. Oh yeah. Yep. Uh-huh.
Oh, not good. Not good. Uh-huh.
BRIAN: Guys, don't forget to get the Tal'Dorei
Campaign Guide book, available from Green Ronin
Publishers, Inc.
LIAM: And a special shout-out to Dwarven Forge for
sending me all this shit two days ago!
BRIAN: Thank you, Dwarven Forge, for the awesome
mappage.
SAM: All right. Give me your numbers. Anyone from
20 to 25?
MARY: 20. Natural 20.
SAM: Ooh, okay. Where are you? You're down here.
Great. Who's next? Anyone from 20 to 25, anyone
from 15 to 20?
LIAM: 16.
SAM: 16. Okay. Good. Yes. Anyone else 15 to 20?
No? Ten to 15?
ASHLY: 14. Sorry.
ERIC: Go for it.
ASHLY: 14, yeah.
ERIC: 13.
SAM: 13. Frankfurt, what do you got?
BRIAN: That'd be a three. That would be a big old
three.
SAM: Gnarly!
BRIAN: (singing) Roll a little three in Kingston
town! Down, down, down to Kingston town.
SAM: Let me do the order here. (singing) There are
so many people in this bar! Why would I do this to
myself? (speaking) Yep. This was a bad idea. Okay.
Nine.
BRIAN: This is your Liam's beach, Sam.
SAM: Yep! Okay, good. We got 13 people to keep
track of. Great. All right, here we go! Wait, I
got some battle music playing. Is it playing?
Sure. I don't know. I don't know what any of this
shit is. (giggles) Okay. You cast Reduce. Your
spell DC is what?
MARY: Exactly! (mumbling) But where's the spell
DC?
BRIAN: Right here.
MARY: 14.
SAM: Okay. Oh, you have to save. Is it a
constitution save? Do you know? I can look.
BRIAN: It's on the card, too. Oh yeah, you got it
here.
MARY: Yeah, it's a concentration.
SAM: Concentration?
BRIAN: Yeah, constitution saving throw.
SAM: So roll 20, add your constitution save
modifier.
ASHLY: 19.
SAM: A blast of sorcerous energy comes out of
Gryffin's hands? What do you use to cast things?
MARY: My hands!
SAM: Your hands. And the magical energy passes
right through you, it's a burst of strange
tingling sensation that bursts right past your
face, but you shake off the effects and nothing
happens.
MARY: So I didn't need to roll to attack?
SAM: That's a spell, yes? So you don't roll on
spells, I don't believe. Unless I'm wrong about
these things?
LIAM: Which is the spell?
SAM: It's not a ranged attack, Reduce, right? It's
just a spell. Does it say ranged attack or
anything?
BRIAN: Yeah, no. It's 30 feet.
SAM: I don't know how to play, and I don't know
how to DM. I would appreciate that we hold all
questions to the end of the session.
LIAM: Don't worry, there are people tweeting
advice right now that you can see
three hours later.
MARY: Because I thought I always would roll for
attack, whether it's a spell or not? I don't know.
SAM: Not tonight, Mary.
MARY: So everything is going to be 15 all night,
with all the spells?
SAM: No, that's your spell save DC, right? You
have a spell save DC, it's on page two of your thing.
LIAM: The target makes a constitution save for
this one.
SAM: For spells like Chromatic Orb or other
things, those are ranged attacks that you roll for
your attack. Reduce is just a thing that happens.
You don't have to target anyone.
LIAM: Are you shrinking yourself or someone else?
MARY: No, someone else.
LIAM: So you have to make a constitution save.
ASHLY: I did, and I cannot be shrunk! I'm
unshrinkable.
SAM: Okay. So nothing happened. But it is your
round, Gryffin. That was a surprise attack. No, it
wasn't a surprise attack, you fucking attacked
first. So you still get a bonus action and a move
if you would like.
MARY: Yes! But it has to be a specific bonus
action.
SAM: If you have a spell that you can cast as a
bonus action.
MARY: I don't think I do. And I can't do any
cantrips as a bonus action, can I?
SAM: You do have one bonus action spell.
MARY: Which is?
SAM: Misty Step.
MARY: Yes, but I don't want to use that now.
LIAM: And in Matt's world and homebrew, bonus
action, you can use a cantrip on, right? Since I
don't do spells a lot.
SAM: No. But if you really want to, I'll let you,
because I don't care.
(laughter)
SAM: Sure, why not.
MARY: Then I cast Firebolt!
SAM: Firebolt. At whom?
MARY: At this lovely cat!
SAM: All right. This is a ranged spell. You roll
for your attack.
BRIAN: You're doing great, Sam.
SAM: I am doing.
MARY: I'm going to use Tides of Chaos.
SAM: Tides of Chaos? Yeah, I hear you. Tides of
Chaos is a sorcerer feature.
MARY: Do I add anything to that?
SAM: Yeah, plus six. That's your spell attack
bonus.
MARY: Yes. So 18.
SAM: 18. This is versus an armor class, I
believe.
MARY: Which is 19, so I miss again.
ASHLY: Eat it, magic!
MARY: But I did roll Tides of the Chaos.
SAM: You did. Which gives you advantage.
MARY: I did, and that was it.
SAM: Fuck! This tabaxi is tough. So you take a
deep breath, Mary, Gryffin, and you say, "Oh, I'm
"going to get you this time!" And you cast another
spell, which, again-- a tingling sensation passes
over your face, as the tabaxi shakes it off.
Nothing happened.
ASHLY: That was a nice tickle. Thanks, Gryffin!
SAM: You still have movement, if you'd like to
make it.
MARY: Yes, I'd like to move behind the bar.
SAM: Okay.
BRIAN: Did you need a tickle? Did I hear you
wanted to be tickled?
ASHLY: Kingston, not now!
SAM: You're going to move over here?
MARY: Can I go behind the bar?
SAM: Oh! Sure. Oh, let's see, what's your
movement?
MARY: 30.
SAM: Okay, yeah. Then you can make it right there.
And as you go, Clothesline gets an attack of
opportunity. Not a clothesline attack, because
that takes movement, but other things you can do.
ASHLY: Okay. I can claw her again?
SAM: You can claw her again. Roll for an attack.
ASHLY: I forgot how to play DND. It is a nine.
BRIAN: Can I inspire her? On her attack?
SAM: No, you have to do that before. Inspire, you
can't use a reaction. What did you say?
ASHLY: I got a four on my d20. Don't work.
SAM: Yes, no, absolutely not. Clothesline takes a
swipe and only just gets a little shock of blonde
hair in her claws.
MARY: Sorry, kitty-kitty-kitty!
SAM: Ooh. They're already so feisty against each
other! I love it! And you get away safely. Next
up, everyone in the bar turns to see that there is
some fighting going on. Many patrons of the bar
who are regulars just sort of say: "Shit!" and
don't really react very much. There're some
newbies in the bar who are on edge, they start
moving around; there's a hustle and bustle, they
start going across the bar to get their weapons.
Let's say that this fine young cannibal over here
starts moving to get her weapons.
BRIAN: Is that where they are?
SAM: The weapons are over here near the front
door. And let's say that this gentleman moves over
to the front door to grab his weapon. Let's see
here, that takes care of... so she's done. Who's
three? No one goes third. What the fuck? There's
no three. All right, so we go straight to four.
She doesn't do anything, she's just moving. Okay.
Jayne-- No, that's not true. Yes, it is! Jayne,
you are up. It is your turn to act and strike.
LIAM: Okay. So I cast the spell Command, which has
a range of 60 feet, on the little red-haired girl.
And I will say: Approach. And she has to make a
wisdom saving throw.
SAM: Oh snap! On the little girl? On Holly, the
little girl? Who hasn't said a thing or done a
thing to you yet?
BRIAN: That's the one that came in with you?
ERIC: Damn it! Yes.
SAM: Yes, the two dwarves.
LIAM: She has to beat a 14. Wisdom.
SAM: Let me find her. On a what save?
LIAM: Wisdom.
SAM: What did you say she has to beat?
LIAM: 14.
SAM: She does not beat 14. So what are the effects
of this spell?
LIAM: Approach means she has to come toward me on
her turn.
SAM: On her next move?
LIAM: On her every turn, until the spell gets
interrupted. And then I would like to use my
movement to start moving toward the door as far as
I can get.
SAM: All right. How fast can you move?
LIAM: 30 feet. So five, ten. It's crowded. You
could probably slow it down a little bit.
SAM: Yeah, you had to get up, you had to walk over
there. Let's say you get about this far, near the
dog. And the little girl is right here. She hasn't
moved yet, but on her turn she will.
LIAM: And before all that happened and people were
running to what? To grab their weapons to be part
of this bloodbath?
SAM: To defend themselves if needed.
LIAM: Yes. Does anyone have a hand on a weapon
yet?
SAM: Absolutely. The guard right here has drawn
his sword.
LIAM: Yes. What about by the door?
SAM: By the door? This guy has been guarding the
weapons, and he holds a longsword, and he had it
already readied before the fighting even started.
He's a paid hired hand to guard the door.
LIAM: Then I'm just going to use my bonus action
to yank the belt off of me, which is actually a
white whip, and crack it on the floor, and that's
the end of my turn.
SAM: Does that do something?
LIAM: Just flair, baby.
(laughter)
SAM: Oh snap! Okay, that ends your turn, Jayne.
Okay, who is next? Okay. Valerie, the bartender,
does not like this, and she does not like someone
coming behind her bar. So she is going to move
over and attack Gryffin. Let's see what she's got.
She's not armed, currently, so she is going to
roll a punch attack. That's an 18. Does that hit?
MARY: It does.
SAM: Okay. She's not a martial weapon person; I
think that's one point of damage. She smacks you
in the face and says: "Don't come back here! This
is the bar!"
MARY: Gryffin's eye starts to twitch a little bit
as she feels things welling up inside of her.
SAM: Oh boy. It's not going great for you. Let's
see here, who is next? Five, that's six, seven.
Seven, who is seven? Why did I write two sixes?
Clothesline! It is your turn.
ASHLY: What's up? Okay. Where am I?
SAM: You're right over here. You just made a swipe
attack on Gryffin as she left. You're near
Kingston, and you saw Jayne get up and walk away
after she gave you the signal.
ASHLY: Okay. And Frankfurt is adjacent to me as
well, right?
SAM: Frankfurt is pretty close to you, yeah. He's
instinctively put his hand on his weapon, and his
other hand is starting to clutch the girl's arm,
the girl Holly.
ERIC: That's my cargo.
BRIAN: What is his weapon?
SAM: What is your weapon?
ERIC: Hot dog buns.
BRIAN: That could be brought down with some
water.
ERIC: My buns!
ASHLY: Okay. I'm going to attack this guard with
his sword drawn.
SAM: Okay. So you're going to move over here,
yeah? 15 feet of movement or something. And you
attack with what?
ASHLY: I want to clothesline him.
SAM: Sure. Yeah. So you've used ten feet of
movement.
ASHLY: 18. The lesson there is I should only try
to clothesline people.
SAM: That is a definite hit. So the tabaxi runs,
full sprint, ten feet across, holding her arm out
in a clothesline motion and makes a huge impact
with the guy's neck. Roll for damage.
ASHLY: That's a five.
SAM: Five damage, okay.
BRIAN: Well done!
ASHLY: You're next, man!
BRIAN: Bring it to me, hard and fast!
SAM: So the guard is a regular, and he looks up at
you and says, "What the hell, Clothesline?"
ASHLY: I'm sorry, man!
SAM: Would you like to do anything on your bonus
action? Is there anything?
ASHLY: Who else has swords drawn? This other guy,
right?
SAM: Which guy? This orc guy? Yeah, this half-orc
guy, let's say he's got something. What does he
have? Nope, nope, he doesn't have any weapons. I
wrote it down that way, so that's how it is.
ASHLY: I'm going to jump on the table and go
(snarls) to make things feel crazier.
SAM: Okay. So you do a catlike roar on the table.
(hisses) The four or five people near you look up
at you, totally baffled at what the fuck is going
on right now. One guy, who is a regular, grabs his
drink and sips it; he doesn't give a shit. Okay.
Next up. That was Clothesline. Next is Kingston's
turn! Kingston. What would you like to do. Oh,
Kingston! Kingston is over here, sorry.
BRIAN: Actually, he rolled higher than me. For
initiative? I'm three.
SAM: Oh, I wrote down 13 for Kingston and three
for Frankfurt, but it's the opposite? So 13 for
Frankfurt, three for Kingston. Sorry about that.
ERIC: It's okay.
LIAM: How many shows are you directing right now?
72?
SAM: All of them. Okay, sorry. Sorry. I get you
guys confused because of your stupid names. So
Frankfurt, it is your turn. There is chaos all
around you, the girl is sitting there harmlessly.
She's a little frightened, but there's a lot of
action; lot of movement.
ERIC: I mean, I have a feeling that Kingston knows
what I did to his wife. With his wife.
SAM: On his wife.
ERIC: Last summer. I feel like I might try to
start some shit with Kingston.
SAM: Okay. So seeing his opportunity, Frankfurt
leaves the side of the little girl and runs across
the room, using your awesome dwarf speed. How fast
can you move?
ERIC: 25.
SAM: 25. This is you, the gold guy, by the way,
Eric.
ERIC: But is Obby still protecting her?
SAM: Obby is still protecting her. I will say she
was sitting in between you two. Obby is calm. So
you go over, and you attack. Are you doing a
weapon attack?
ERIC: I'm going to use my maul.
SAM: So roll a d20 and add your plus something to
it.
ERIC: Okay. I'm rolling. 18.
SAM: 18? I'm sure that hits you, right, dude?
Wait, you rolled an 18?
ERIC: I rolled an 18.
BRIAN: Wait, is that a melee attack?
SAM: Yeah, he hits you. Yeah. So roll for damage.
ERIC: Oh! And that's this one?
SAM: What does it say? Hold on. Your maul is 2d6
plus six! This is a big, fat weapon. Two-handed
strike comes down right on the top of your head.
Full force. This guy is a bruiser. So roll 2d6. Or
1d6 twice.
LIAM: Is this the maul? That's six two times.
ERIC: Okay. So this one?
LIAM: The square. Traditional die. And one more
time. A six!
SAM: Oh my god! You're fucking dead, dude.
LIAM: Two, that's eight, plus six.
SAM: 14 points of damage. Kingston, still reeling
from getting dissed by several ladies tonight,
didn't really even look, and all of a sudden a
maul cracks down on his skull, sending him to his
knees. Are you okay? Kingston is not doing great.
ERIC: No hard feelings.
BRIAN: Just you wait. When I get up from this
ground!
SAM: Because I don't know what the fuck I'm doing:
on your knees, Kingston-- by the way, sorry. Would
you like to use any bonus actions, Mr. Frankfurt?
You don't have to.
LIAM: Your Hunter's Mark is a bonus action, I seem
to recall.
SAM: You could have used before, or you could
put it on somebody else. Also, forgive me.
Hunter's Mark, he has something similar that is a
paladin feature, I think, that doesn't use a spell
slot. Vow of Enmity, is that a thing?
LIAM: That's big time. Yeah, that gives him
advantage on every attack against one target. So
if you really want to fuck that guy up, do Vow of
Enmity. But I think that's an action.
SAM: I don't know.
ERIC: It sounds a bit too complicated. I'm a
little satisfied with what I did just now.
BRIAN: Yeah.
SAM: You're satisfied?
ERIC: Yeah.
BRIAN: My wife wasn't satisfied!
SAM: Oh shit!
ERIC: I've got video. Do I stay in that area?
SAM: You can move a little bit. I think you have
five or ten more feet of movement.
ERIC: Head back towards Holly.
LIAM: Vow of Enmity, bonus action. If you want to
destroy Kingston. It gives you advantage. Vow of
Enmity. One time tonight you can say, that person,
and then you can roll with burning hatred.
Religious hatred. You know, the religious hatred.
SAM: So keep that in your back pocket. Frankfurt
goes back towards the girl, keeping her protected
from badness. That was Frankfurt. At this point,
the old bald man who was arguing with the whore
uses this as an opportunity to flee, and starts
running for the door. He's moving this way. Zarvah
the whore sees this happening and starts bolting
to catch him.
BRIAN: Don't leave!
MARY: All the plants will die!
BRIAN: I'm going to be done with this so soon.
SAM: This guy over here, who was eating mutton
before. He's got his weapon now and he turns to
anyone who's available to him, which is the
easiest target in the area, which is Jayne, a
small girl. Mutton Man has--
LIAM: Do you know the Mutton Man?
SAM: He sees you running for the door; he thinks
this is fun. This is his favorite thing, is bar
room brawls. He is going to roll a 14 plus five,
19 versus strength. No, he's trying to grapple you.
LIAM: Versus strength. Oh, that does it.
SAM: You are grappled by the Mutton Man. He grabs you
and says, "Not so fast, dear, we're going to have
"some fun tonight." You are restrained for right
now. You cannot move.
BRIAN: Do you know that Muffin Man?
MARY and ASHLY: (singing) Do you know the muffin
man?
SAM: So you are grappled. Ooh! I have a thing! You
are grappled!
(cheering)
LIAM: It matches my albino, even!
SAM: That's the Mutton Man. Now we go to Kingston.
Kingston, before your roll, you have dropped to
your knees. You are feeling like shit. You open
your eyes; roll a perception check.
BRIAN: Don't fuck me, Gil. I can't tell what it
is. 12?
SAM: 12, okay. You see the table in front of you;
you've fallen facing the table. Under the table in
front of you is a small vial of something
underneath it.
BRIAN: I grab the fuck out of it.
SAM: That is going to take some of your movement.
You could grab it; that's fine. You grab it. I got
stuff. I got presents. Let's do this, because I'm
a kind god. (laughing) You recognize one of these;
you've seen them before: it's a potion of healing.
Someone must have dropped it in the scrum, so it's
there for you if you need it. What would you like
to do on your action?
BRIAN: Is standing up going to take my movement?
Half my movement? Okay. I'll stand up and then
where is Frankfurt?
SAM: Frankfurt is pretty close to you.
BRIAN: Okay, I'm going to cast Blindness on
Frankfurt.
SAM: Blindness? Okay, what is your spell save DC?
BRIAN: That way he thinks he's going home with
someone's wife, but he's going home with someone's
mule. My spell save DC is a 14.
SAM: 14. Is Blindness a constitution or wisdom
save?
BRIAN: It is a constitution save.
SAM: So Eric, you need to roll a d20 and add your
constitution save modifier, which Liam will point
out to you right now. Constitution save.
LIAM: Constitution save is right here. Plus four
to whatever you roll.
SAM: So roll something.
ERIC: Now hold on a minute. I love vision.
LIAM: Oh yeah, 20.
SAM: 20. A prickling in your neck, Frankfurt, as
you feel some sort of magical effect starting to
take hold but you burp and shake it off like
nothing happened.
ERIC: (burps, laughs) I've never played before.
BRIAN: You're doing great.
SAM: Kingston, you still have a bonus action.
BRIAN: I'll take this potion as my bonus action.
SAM: Okay. It's a 2d4 plus what?
BRIAN: 4d4 plus four.
MARY: It's a greater healing.
SAM: Yeah. Well, I don't want him to die already.
BRIAN: Getting pretty close there for a second.
All right. 4d4. 14. Yeah, not bad. 11 plus four so 15.
SAM: All right. Lucky. All right, so that takes
care of all you guys, I think. The half-orc who
you did not attack sees you on the bar, sees that
it's going to be fun, and is going to try to pull
you down off the bar. He will roll a 14 plus
something. I don't know what. Just a 14. I'm going
to say straight 14. No, this would be a strength
check. He's pretty strong so I'm going to add four
to that? 18 versus strength. Strength save. 20
plus your strength.
ASHLY: (singing) Critical roll symbol, so natural
20.
SAM: Holy shit! So the half-orc grabs for your
catlike ankles and you see the grab coming, and
you kick your half-drunk saucer of milk right in
his face. He's distracted and gets a whiff of air;
doesn't grab any fur or anything. That ends his
turn. Anybody else? Okay. There's one other person
who moves, and she's picking up a weapon. That is
the top of the round-- Oh no! Obby the dwarf. Obby
the Rat. Okay, Obby is going to go across to the
girl, take a couple steps closer to the girl
because that's what he's being paid here for. Grab
her by the arm and hold his action until someone
tries to attack the girl.
ASHLY: Does Holly move?
SAM: Holly can move. Shit, I never rolled for
initiative for Holly! Okay, so she should have
gone a while ago. Fuck! Let's just say she was so
confused she's only going now.
BRIAN: Can you describe to me what she's wearing
and if she's carrying anything?
SAM: Holly is wearing a simple gray raw silk tunic
with a belt around it. She is-- let me see,
where's her fucking stats? She is not holding
anything at all except for, let's say for dramatic
effect, she has a tiny something in her hand that
looks like a charm bracelet or something that a
young girl might have, like a hair tie with some
charms dangling from it or something. That's it.
And she starts to move, right? That's what happens
with this thing, right? She comes towards you and
her movement is fast. So she comes right over
and stops at your feet, looks up at you with puppy
dog eyes as if to say: who are you and where are
we going? And that concludes her turn.
LIAM: I barely notice because someone from the
Jersey Shore is lifting me into the air.
SAM: That's the top of the round. Holy shit, I'm
running a game of Dungeons and Dragons!
(cheering)
ASHLY: You're doing a hell of a job!
BRIAN: You're doing great.
SAM: As the fight continues, time freezes. Our
vision dims. Flashes to another time, another
place. It's blurry at first. Then, coming slowly
into focus is a dimly lit room, a simple table and
chair in the center. From this perspective, only
the person in the chair can be seen. There is an
off-stage voice: that of a gruff man, asking
questions, but we never see him. It is, by all
appearances, an interrogation. In the chair sits
Gryffin. The gruff voice says: "Uh-huh. And why
"were you there? At the bar?"
MARY: Well, I'd come to speak to Frankfurt.
Frankfurt had told me to meet him there because he
was transporting someone that I needed to speak to
very badly--
SAM: "This girl that you keep talking about,
right?"
MARY: Yes, Holly, the girl. I needed to speak with
her.
SAM: "Why? What could a little fucking girl have
that you needed?"
MARY: I'm not supposed to be here!
SAM: "Well, you're not going anywhere, honey."
MARY: No, I mean, not here, in this chair. I mean
here! I come from Illyria, and the solar eclipse
a week and a half ago placed us in this
wherever-the-hell we are, Jorell, I'm not sure
where we are, right? And my city appears during
the solar eclipse, during the period of totality.
So out I come. I was pushed out of my city, and I
woke up here. My city was gone. This girl, Holly,
potentially could be from Illyria. I need to find
her so that I can find the location of where
Illyria will reappear next. That's why I'm here! I
certainly didn't mean to start a fight with the
cat, nor did I certainly mean to declaw her!
SAM: "Are you some sort of royalty or something?
You talk real funny."
MARY: Well. Yes, my mother was a queen and I was a
princess, yes.
SAM: "Are you shitting me?"
MARY: I have Prestidigitation. If you do shit
yourself I could clean you up?
SAM: "Don't even think about it, honey."
MARY: I never would. But yes, my queen, my
mother-- but she's no longer alive.
SAM: Time shifts again. Same room, different time.
Now in the hot seat is Kingston, looking very
confused. Eyes red, hungover, woozy, dazey. "So
this guy, he slept with your wife?"
BRIAN: I mean, I'm pretty sure they fucked first.
(laughter)
SAM: "And that's all the beef there was between
you two?"
BRIAN: That's all the beef there was in my house
that night, and there wasn't any beef in there for
a long time after.
SAM: "What were you even doing in this bar?"
BRIAN: I live above the bar. I have an extensive
tab.
SAM: "But they let you live there?"
BRIAN: I perform certain services in exchange for
drinks and board.
SAM: "What does that mean? You sweep up after the
night is over?"
BRIAN: If you mean I'm a male prostitute, then
yeah. I sweep up all of the elderly women at the
end of the night. I take them upstairs, and I show
them a good time, and in exchange I get all the
Greep and ale I want. Even the elderly of this
great land deserve to capture the flag every once
in a while.
MARY: (laughing) Why did you look at me?
BRIAN: I was hoping you would tell me the rest of
what I was going to say.
SAM: "So you, freaky-looking guy, are a male
prostitute?"
BRIAN: Look, some of these elderly ladies, they
like their men with their make-up runny. But yes,
in exchange for room and board, I will often
pleasure these women deep into the night.
SAM: "I don't need the details, buddy."
BRIAN: Oh, you haven't even scratched the surface
of the details.
SAM: "Please, spare me."
BRIAN: Okay. When the wigs come off--
SAM: Time shifts again. Now Clothesline, looking
surly and pissy, is in the hot seat.
"What's with your face?"
ASHLY: What's with yours, bastard?
SAM: "Fair enough. The white-haired girl: what's
her deal? Did you know her?"
ASHLY: Maybe.
SAM: "Maybe what?"
ASHLY: What are you going to do if I don't answer
you?
SAM: "Put you in jail."
ASHLY: (growls) Yeah, I know her.
SAM: "How?"
ASHLY: She saved me once, all right? I was dying.
I don't know. I have almost died like 20 times, I
don't keep track, okay? But this one time I was
almost going to really die, and she saved me.
She helped me. Only person that's ever really done
that.
SAM: "You would do anything for her?"
ASHLY: Not anything. But I'd help her out, yeah.
Someone does you a good turn, you do it back.
SAM: "Were you helping her this night?"
ASHLY: (sighs) She wanted me to make a
distraction. I don't know why, so don't ask. So I
took a little skin off the creepy girl. There were
a couple creepy girls: the one with the weird eyes.
SAM: "I just want to get this down: you are
admitting that you started the fight in the tavern?"
ASHLY: Yeah.
SAM: "All right. Thank you for your honesty."
ASHLY: You're welcome.
SAM: "Hey, where did you get that name, anyway?
Clothesline? Do you have another alias, anything else?"
ASHLY: Where I'm from, they give you a nickname
for the thing you like to do the most. I love to
clothesline. There were a lot of "Porns" in the
town; it was kind of confusing.
SAM: "A lot of 'Porns?'"
ASHLY: Yeah. A lot of people's favorite thing is
porn. You talk to many people?
SAM: "Yeah, no. That tracks. That definitely
tracks."
LIAM: Etchings.
MARY: Lots of etchings. Brass penis and balls with
wings pointing in certain directions.
SAM: I don't know how to change music, people. I
don't know. Sorry about this. Time shifts again.
Now in the hot seat we see Frankfurt, the dwarf.
"All right, this girl that you claim you were
"there to deliver. Who gave her to you? Where did
you find her? Where did she come from?"
ERIC: I was told I could have one courier pigeon.
I need to contact my lawyer. Why am I here?
(laughter)
SAM: "You'll get your courier pigeon."
ERIC: Where's Obby? Obby! You've separated me from
my Obby.
SAM: "Listen."
ERIC: What?
SAM: "We're trying to round up Obby right now.
We're aware of where he lives in town."
ERIC: Where's the girl?
SAM: "What do you mean, where's the girl?"
ERIC: Where did you put the girl? I have one thing
to do and that's talk to Garello.
SAM: "I will be asking the questions here, thank
you very much."
ERIC: Ugh, I've never played.
(laughter)
SAM: "Fine. If you had your courier pigeon, who
would you send it to?"
ERIC: I would send it to (coos, wings
fluttering).
SAM: "While that is extremely impressive, it
leaves way more questions than answers."
ERIC: What does a dwarf got to do to get some
Greep around here?
SAM: "I don't feel like you're taking this
interrogation seriously."
ERIC: I am. Okay, look. I was only told that I
had to transport this girl, Holly.
SAM: "And what would you get in exchange?"
ERIC: A couple bucks. 100 gold coins.
SAM: "100 gold?!"
ERIC: 100 of them, yes.
SAM: "For just taking a girl from point A to point
B?"
ERIC: Look, I do a lot of missions and I don't ask
many questions. I was told to bring her there, and
I'm told to find the guy or a girl named Garello.
That's all I know. Hey, you seem to know a lot
about me. Can I ask you something?
SAM: "Go ahead."
ERIC: What do you know about this Chained
Oblivion?
SAM: "I know absolutely nothing about this Chained
Oblivion. It's some sort of fucking religious thing."
ERIC: Well, I am going to take them down!
SAM: "Oh."
ERIC: So if you see anyone from them.
SAM: "I don't see anyone from them. I've heard
rumors that they exist. Wait, why am I answering
"any questions?" Time shifts again. Now, we have a
white-haired girl child in the hot seat. "All
"right, tell me your story. Why were you there?
What's a sweet, innocent little sweetheart like
"you doing in a place like The Ass Sailor?"
ASHLY: (laughing) I forgot it was called that.
LIAM: (soft giggling)
SAM: "Go on. I'm listening."
LIAM: Sorry. I was just imagining you burned to a
crisp.
SAM: "Excuse me?"
LIAM: Am I bound?
SAM: Yeah, your hands are tied behind your back.
LIAM: Hands are tied behind my back. Are they
movable?
SAM: They're movable.
LIAM: They are? Then I cast Sacred Flame on the
guy.
SAM: I don't know what that is.
LIAM: Oh, it's holy fire for 1d8 damage.
SAM: Do you roll something?
LIAM: Yeah. The target must succeed on a dexterity
saving throw.
BRIAN: Talk about fuck the police.
LIAM: You make a dex save.
SAM: What was the number?
LIAM: 14.
SAM: Okay. So as we see a burst of flame, right,
you said flames? We see from your eyes, they start
to glow and burn with a holy light and fire starts
to emanate from your eyes straight towards our
point of view. We hear a gruff man say: "Ugh. Hey!
What the fuck are you--" and time shifts again.
(laughter)
SAM: And we are back in the bar, and it's the top
of the round. Gryffin, it is your roll.
MARY: I turn to Valerie and I pull out the bag of
gold that I was going to give Frankfurt and I say
to her: Valerie, I have no intention of doing you
any harm whatsoever. I'm so sorry to invade your
space back here, but I really need to get out of
this place alive. I don't need your help. All I
need are four bottles of Greep. So here is a bag
of gold. May I have four bottles of Greep, please?
SAM: "There's a keg right there." It's right here.
It's full of Greep.
MARY: Okay. Is that something that I could
potentially carry?
SAM: It's heavy, but you can pick it up. It's a
pony keg.
MARY: Are there any bottles in my vicinity?
SAM: There are a bunch of cups over here. Greep is
a pour thing. So you either have a big bottle of
it or you can use your turn to start filling up
cups of it.
(laughter)
MARY: So there are no whiskey bottles or
anything?
SAM: There are whiskey bottles all over the place
in the back of the bar. They're not filled with
Greep, though; they've got different other
spirits: whiskey--
MARY: And there are no empty bottles whatsoever?
SAM: Empty bottles? Sure, yeah. They've taken
the used bottles and put them sort of behind the bar.
MARY: Great. I start filling bottles with Greep.
SAM: Bottles with Greep? You're going to use your
action to do this? All right. So Valerie, who
still doesn't really love you behind the bar is
watching you fill up bottles, but she's okay
because she got a bunch of gold out of it. So
she's allowing it with a sneer. The man right
behind you, Xavier, really doesn't like this, but
he is a ninny, so he's just like (grumbling).
MARY: For my bonus action, I toss him ten gold, as
well.
SAM: Oh, wow! Bonus action gold toss. That's nice.
While you're down there getting these bottles, why
don't you roll a perception check? (whispering) I
made these and I'm going to use them, fuckers!
MARY: I haven't used my Tides of Chaos this time.
Perception, though. 13.
SAM: 13. Yeah, sure. So you see a small box that
has intricate gold leafing around it. Looks out of
place behind there. It's small, the size of a deck
of cards or something. Oh god! You'll never see
it. Okay. That's a thing that exists. Okay, next
up. One, two, okay. This whore--
LIAM: Hey! You've known me for so long!
SAM: She wants to help out her hooker friend and
catch the old guy who's leaving, so she runs over
and attacks him. Yep, that hits. I'll roll for
damage. Great, where's he? Okay, so she lunges at
him and hits him in the back of the head and grabs
onto his pants, which pull them down. He's now
naked from the waist down. And slightly injured
and he says: "I'm being attacked! I'm being
"attacked!" Next. Remember, there is no three,
because I never assigned that number. Four. Okay.
The ranger has found her shit. This is the ranger
right here. She has found her bow and arrow,
nocked an arrow and she's going to shoot, she
needs some range, so she's going to shoot at the
most prominent target in the room: the cat thing
on the bar, and she rolled a one. The arrow
whizzes by your head (arrow impact) right into the
thing behind you. No damage, no nothing. That's
four, five, next. Jayne, your turn. You are
currently restrained. I think you can do a
strength check to try to get out of it.
LIAM: I can attack normally, I just can't move
anywhere. I would like to do a melee spell attack
on him. So first I'm going to see if it hits then
I'll tell you what it is. That is an 18.
SAM: An 18? On whom?
LIAM: On the guy grappling me.
SAM: Oh yes, for sure. He was the Mutton Man,
right? His AC is 12. You hit.
LIAM: So I would like to cast Inflict Wounds at
level two and rot this fucking asshole from the
inside out.
SAM: Oh my god. I don't know what that is but it
sounds horrifying.
LIAM: Yeah, it is.
SAM: "Now, we're going to have some fun-- what the
fuck are you doing?"
LIAM: 18. Good. That is a 25 total.
SAM: Okay, so with his snarling, disgusting yellow
teeth, he's smiling at you as his whole head from
top to bottom disintegrates into ash and falls to
the floor in a pile of disgustingness. He's dead
and gone. You are no longer restrained and can
move at will.
LIAM: I would like to use my bonus action to break
the fucking Lawbearer chain off my neck and throw
it over my shoulder and walk towards the door.
BRIAN: Yeah, fuck that thing!
SAM: Okay. No longer restrained. You're calmly
walking out like you own the place. No one takes a
strike against you because you're not involved in
combat with them. Oh, this guy is gone! Splash
one. Okay, that ends your turn. Let's see.
(counting) So after Frankfurt, Holly goes. Okay,
that's you, Jayne. Next is the guard who failed on
his attack against you, tabaxi, the last time. So
instead, he's frustrated by that, so he will
attack again. Why not? He rolls a natural 20 with
his longsword. d8. This is not going to be good
for you. Eight. So 16 points of damage as you take
a sword right in your left shin. Your leg buckles.
You fall to one knee and blood starts pouring out
of your furry knee. And he says, "I've got you
that time!" That's his turn. We go to Clothesline,
it's your turn.
ASHLY: You fucking asshole! What's the worst that
I can do to him on sword, please? I'm going to
slash at him with my longsword.
SAM: Sure, go for it.
ASHLY: So that is a ten.
SAM: Ooh. Because your knee is buckled, you're
wobbly. Your sword strike goes errant and strikes
the side of the bar, digging into it. He looks up
at you and laughs again. This is an epic battle
between a very lowly guard and you.
ASHLY: Can I still do a bonus action?
SAM: Oh, yeah, you do have a bonus action! You
have, I believe, an action surge if you wanted to
attack again.
LIAM: You could get an extra one-time attack right
now.
SAM: You can just attack again. I gave her two
because I like her.
ASHLY: I'm going to try to do the same thing:
attack with my longsword. Okay. 14?
SAM: That hits. He has AC 13.
ASHLY: 1d8. Is this a d8? I'm so bad at this.
This, right? Okay. Eight.
SAM: Okay. Yeah, he's dead. Your sword digs into
his neck, getting about halfway in. He looks
surprised and he falls over, limp on the ground.
He's gone and dead.
LIAM: I'll never learn the violin!
SAM: End of him.
BRIAN: You're getting hotter as this night goes
on.
SAM: Jesus. Frankfurt, you are up.
ERIC: How can I get in contact with Gryffin? Is
she gone?
SAM: In contact with her?
MARY: I'm fucking filling up bottles with Greep.
SAM: Yeah, she's behind the bar. You can yell at
her.
ERIC: Hey!
MARY: Frankfurt!
ERIC: Yes. Apparently, I have a thing for a
fine-looking noble blondes. That'd be you.
SAM: You're flirting during this fight?
ERIC: Yeah.
MARY: Thirsty?
ERIC: Yes. Greep, please.
SAM: People are running around half-naked. Somehow
all the sound dims. They make eye contact. It's
beautiful.
ERIC: I've been looking all over for you.
MARY: I've been looking for you, too.
ERIC: I have Holly.
MARY: I know. I need her.
ERIC: Okay.
SAM: As you talk, Holly is walking towards the
door.
MARY: She's walking away from you.
ERIC: How can I stop Holly?
SAM: You can move. You can attack. You can grab.
You can do all sorts of things.
ERIC: What has her possessed to move away?
SAM: You don't know. All you saw was she stood up,
walked away from the table, and started walking
towards the door. She paused briefly to look up at
Jayne, this white-haired person. Jayne kept
walking to the door, and Holly's eyes followed
followed Jayne. It looks like she's watching
Jayne's every move with rapt attention.
LIAM: I am rather attractive.
ERIC: Well, I got to do something about Jayne,
then.
MARY: Get Holly.
ERIC: I will get Holly.
SAM: You're right here, and I forget your
movement, but you can at least move to Holly. 25.
You can get to Holly if you'd like to. Okay, you
jump over this dog, you get to Holly. A courier
pigeon flies by.
ERIC: I got shit in my eye! Fucking pigeon! How is
there a pigeon inside of a tavern?
SAM: You can grab her. You can attack someone. You
can do whatever you would like to do.
ERIC: Well, I will secure her. I will grab her.
SAM: Okay, so roll a strength check.
BRIAN: Roll a d20, Eric, and add your strength
modifier.
ERIC: Okay, d20? Ten.
SAM: Okay. What's your strength modifier? It's
four, for you, so 14. So she's going to roll. She
rolls an eight plus zero. She is grappled!
ERIC: You're not going anywhere! I've got a job to
do.
SAM: Still, her eyes seem distant, and pupils
dilated, but she is unable to move any further.
BRIAN: Put the ring around her, Sam. You brought
it all the way here.
SAM: I got multiple rings! Holly's not moving. You
have a bonus action if you want to use it. You
have bonus actions if you'd like. I don't know
what spells you've chosen, but you do have a few
spells that you can use as a bonus action. Or you
can do nothing, yell to Obby.
LIAM: Oh! Command only lasts one round.
SAM: Well, it hasn't come back to Holly yet.
LIAM: Well, I'm letting you know, that it's not
going to last forever.
SAM: That's good to know.
BRIAN: That's bringing her towards you?
LIAM: At the moment.
SAM: It was your "and I walk away" that did it.
ERIC: Can I Smite anyone?
MARY: Does he have any more movement?
SAM: It took most of his movement to get over
there. It's a cramped bar; he's dodging dogs and
stuff. Smite, I don't know how it works. Liam, how
does Smite work?
LIAM: He attacks. If he hits, he does regular
damage and adds Smite damage.
SAM: Oh, but this is Divine Smite you're talking
about. That is after a melee hit. We're looking at
a bonus action. He's used his action to grapple
Holly.
LIAM: Right, so he can't attack.
SAM: He can't attack. If you have a bonus action
spell?
LIAM: He could cast Hunter's Mark. Did you cast
that already? You could cast Hunter's Mark on
Jayne, or anybody.
SAM: Or you don't have to do anything. You can
hold your spells for later, whatever you want to do.
ERIC: I'm happy with grappling.
SAM: Okay, good. I love your voice.
ERIC: What voice? I'm just being myself.
SAM: The old man who was trying to flee, he's
going to attack one of the whores. He does not hit.
MARY: Whores are tough.
BRIAN: You leave those whores alone.
SAM: It is Holly's turn. She is restrained. She
doesn't know what the fuck's going on. She's still
under her spell. I guess the spell is fading off
now. So she shakes it off, doesn't know how she
got over here. Now she's being held by a strong
dwarf man. She doesn't do anything to fight that.
Kingston? It's your turn.
BRIAN: Am I still over by that table over there?
SAM: You are still over by the table.
BRIAN: And where is Frankfurt, at the moment?
SAM: Frankfurt's closer to the door. He's this guy
in gold right here.
BRIAN: Okay, cool. I'm going to cast Hold Person
on Frankfurt.
SAM: Oh, shit. Wait, you're going to hold a guy
who's holding a girl. This is amazing. Okay,
Kingston, your spell DC is 14. Hold Person, I
believe, is wisdom? So roll a d20 and add your
wisdom save modifier. It's in a little box that
Liam will point to you right now.
LIAM: Wisdom save is this, so plus three. Natural
20!
SAM: Spells are not working tonight.
LIAM: Actually: thanks, Keyleth. Because those are
her dice.
SAM: Kingston has been drinking a lot tonight, so
all of his spells when uttered come out a little
bit slurry. And they don't seem to have as much
power. Again, there's a little prickling in the
back of your neck but nothing happens. Kingston's
very frustrated. You have a bonus action and
movement if you'd like it, Kingston.
BRIAN: I'm going to move over where I was by the
bar at the beginning. At the end of the bar.
SAM: I think you can move, what, 30 feet? No one's
engaging you, so you walk over and you get all the
way there.
BRIAN: Then that's probably good. I don't know
what to do for a bonus action.
SAM: You don't have to do anything. You can
inspire. You can heal.
BRIAN: I can't use a cantrip for a bonus action,
can I?
SAM: I let Mary do it. Yeah, go for it, because
your spells have been sucking tonight.
BRIAN: I was going to do Vicious Mockery on
Frankfurt.
SAM: Okay, before you move, while you're still in
range of him, because I think it's 30 feet--
BRIAN: 60.
SAM: 60? Then by the bar, you got to yell loud
because you're across this loud bar.
BRIAN: (singing) I'm so excited! And I just can't
hide it! I know, I know, I know, I know I'm going
to kill you!
SAM: The sung words from Kingston's somewhat-drunk
voice enter your ear and affect you in a way that
you've never felt before. You feel bad about
yourself. You feel demeaned, and you feel unsure
of yourself as a dwarf in general. You take actual
physical damage.
BRIAN: It's 1d4 psychic damage, and you have
disadvantage on the next attack roll you make
before the end of your turn.
SAM: So roll a d4 and add something.
BRIAN: Do I add my spell--
SAM: No, just a d4. This is a damage roll we're
doing.
BRIAN: That's a four.
SAM: Four plus what does it say on the spell? 1d4
plus something?
BRIAN: Psychic damage. Yeah, 1d4 psychic damage
and you take disadvantage on the next attack roll.
SAM: So you take four points of damage, so you are
less powerful than you were before, and you can't
get the song out of your head, and it will affect
your next turn. You will have to do your next turn
at disadvantage, which means you will be thrown
off. So take your little number there and reduce
it by some points.
ERIC: So 34, right?
SAM: Yep, sure. Okay, that is Kingston. The
half-orc is going to run over to Kingston and hit
him. He heard your dulcet tones. He doesn't like
them. It is an unarmed strike. He does not hit
you. He whiffs. The sound confuses him, and he's
too tall for you, anyway. Just goes right over
your head clean.
LIAM: "I have auditory issues."
SAM: That's the top of the round. What do I do
next?
BRIAN: This is fun, Sam. Even though the spells
aren't working.
MARY: There's no magic working at all tonight.
BRIAN: You guys can't see, but behind Sam, his
hair is starting to fall out.
SAM: The heat of the room and the movement of
everyone around is really making the place fucking
hot. So hot, in fact, that you all get the sense
that if you don't remove an article of clothing
soon, you may become exhausted. So there's a brief
pause in the action where everyone says, "Oh my
"god. It's fucking hot in here!" I would need you
all to either remove an article of clothing or suffer
one point of exhaustion.
LIAM: Oh man, the room has turned into (singing)
turn down for what!
ASHLY: I'm going to rip everything clean off.
SAM: Everything? Well, you're a furry. You've got
nothing on. So you're ripping your fur off?
ASHLY: Wait, I don't have anything on?
SAM: Where's your picture? Okay, you have armor.
You want to take off your armor? You're going to
lose AC.
ASHLY: Can I take off just the pants? Can I go
Donald Duck?
SAM: Sure. I'm going to give you a negative one to
AC. So you're down to 18. And we can see your cat
lady bits.
ASHLY: Are they articulated?
SAM: Yeah, they're nice.
BRIAN: They are some of the best in the land.
MARY: #CriticalRoleFanart.
SAM: Kingston, anything?
BRIAN: I'll take the point of exhaustion.
SAM: Oh shit! So you have disadvantage--
BRIAN: Wait, I thought it was minus one point.
SAM: No, I think exhaustion is disadvantage on all
ability checks.
BRIAN: Well, fuck that! I'll take off my corset.
What am I wearing? I'll take off my Spanx.
SAM: You're going to take off your shirt, so you
are now shirtless.
BRIAN: Yeah, behold! This is what happens when you
give up!
SAM: He rips open his shirt. The buttons fly
everywhere exposing a really out of shape guy.
Little man boobies, love handles.
BRIAN: So I'm Dan Harmon, basically.
SAM: Yeah, really lopsided, too. It's not good. A
writer's body. Gryffin, anything
you'd like to remove?
MARY: I'm ripping off my sleeves. I've got this
white gown underneath the light studded armor. I
rip off some sleeves.
SAM: All right, so you're sleeveless now. This is
strange for you, because it's an elegant gown. You
rip off the sleeves and it's frayed and tattered
there. You feel a little uncomfortable. Jayne?
LIAM: Yeah, I rip off the cloak that I'm wearing
to reveal the white porcelain doll dress and
straps of white leather around the biceps and
around the thighs. Yeah, I look like Courtney Love
a little bit.
SAM: Anything else we should know about that we
see?
LIAM: There are very light chain tattoos along the
collarbones, disappearing down the dress.
SAM: You look so good. Frankfurt, what you got?
ERIC: My chainmail shirt.
SAM: You're going to take it off?
LIAM: Wow.
ERIC: Wait.
BRIAN: That's how DND works. You take off the
stuff that's really heavy and metallic.
ERIC: What if I shaved?
SAM: You cannot shave.
ERIC: It looks like I've got a--
SAM: Some sort of a tunic thing. Your options are
pants or armor, we'll say.
ASHLY and MARY: (chanting) Pants! Pants!
ERIC: Pants!
(laughter)
ASHLY: You and me, Frankfurt!
ERIC: I'm going to go with pants.
SAM: Seeing Frankfurt's exposed wang drives
Kingston into a fit of rage. He knows that was the
wang that was in his wife. And he wants to hit
that wang so hard. I don't know what's going on.
BRIAN: Put those pants back on, you foul creature,
before I come over there and do no more damage to you!
SAM: Obby the Rat, who has been saving his turn
for a while now and forgotten about, does not like
where this is going. And so he strikes out at the
first person he can get to. What's his movement?
Not very much. Shoot, he can't get to anybody.
LIAM: "I kick the dog."
SAM: Sure, he's going to kick the dog. No, why
would he kick a dog? He's going to attack
someone who's in a fight.
ASHLY: What about the old guy and the lady
prostitutes?
SAM: Yeah, he's got to get there, though. He's
going to push past the prostitute and defend Holly
and hit the first person he can, which is this
woman right here, this fighter. 15. Oh yeah, he
takes her.
BRIAN: Just a quick question. No one has attacked
the prostitutes yet, right?
SAM: The old man has tried, but I think he failed.
Okay, she's gone, he knocks her out. She's dead.
All right, top of the round? Oh my god, this is so
hard.
LIAM: How does Matt do it, right? Every week.
SAM: Okay. Gryffin, what would you like to do?
MARY: So I take my sleeves, and I rip off a piece
and shove one into a bottle. Are there any candles
lit near me?
SAM: There are candles lit near you. There are
torches on the wall and a couple candles on the
bar for light.
MARY: So I light one of the bottles of Greep on
fire, and I throw it at the kitty-kitty-kitty.
SAM: She's right next to you. You wouldn't have to
throw it far, you would just smash it on the bar.
MARY: Smash it on the bar. Is that considered
movement at that point?
SAM: I would say that you would want to move back
a little bit so you don't get splashed or hit.
MARY: Well, I'd like to throw it at her and then
run.
SAM: It's an area of effect, so I'm going to treat
this as like a very modified Fireball. What's your
spell attack bonus? It's plus six. So roll a d20,
add six.
ASHLY: I really want to do the Terminator thing
where I walk through the fire.
MARY: 16. I'd like to use my Tides of Chaos again
but I can't.
SAM: Oh, you have advantage! No, you used that the
last time. Let's see here, this would be a dex
save. Do a dex save, catty.
ASHLY: 18.
SAM: So you still get burned, but you take half
damage. Let's see, it's a modified thing, so I'm
going to roll. That's cocked. So take five points
of fire damage as the fire spreads across the bar.
Let's say that it's green fire, because I have a
rubber band. That guy gets hit, too. He takes one
point of damage. Kingston, you take--
BRIAN: Wait, I'm at the other end.
SAM: I thought you were here?
BRIAN: At the start of the game I was at that end
of the bar. That's okay. I might still get hit,
but that's fine. I just wanted to be on that
corner.
LIAM: You created a combat scenario for yourself
with 33 enemies.
SAM: I don't know what the fuck I was thinking.
Okay, good. The bar's on fire. People are running
away from it, "I don't know who I am! I don't have
a fully fleshed-out character!" This cat is on
fire, makes your heart weep. And your fur is on
fire, as well. This is bad. That was great.
Anything bonus, anything other?
MARY: No. I'd love to reset that Tides of Chaos. I
have to roll on the table.
SAM: You have to cast a spell for that, right?
MARY: Once I do Tides of Chaos, you can do it--
SAM: No, I mean you have to cast something to roll
on the table. Spells don't just come out of you,
you have to try to cast a spell, right? I don't
know how your fucking wild sorcery works.
MARY: So was that my action, to drop all of that?
SAM: Yes, but if you have a bonus action or
something you can use?
MARY: Yes, I would like to bonus action a
Firebolt at kitty-kitty-kitty.
SAM: Oh my god, fire is the thing today. So you
automatically roll on the table. So get out your
100-sided die. This young lady is a wild sorcerer,
she--
MARY: (New Jersey accent) Hey, don't fucking tell
me what the fuck I am, motherfucker! All right?
Hold on a second! How you people doing? You good?
Look at you, little girl with your white hair.
Where the fuck did that come from? Ooh,
kitty-kitty-kitty, fucking pussy. How you doing?
You and I need to talk later, apparently, from
what I hear. I'm not sure. You got man boobs;
that's kind of hot. Okay, what did I roll? I
rolled an 80-fucking-six. How you doing? Hold on,
just wait!
SAM: She starts acting very strangely, talking in
a different accent. Her whole personality shifts
and magic seems to overtake her body.
MARY: (New Jersey accent) What the
bing-ba-da-bing-bo-boom? This is bad. I can feel
it, oh! Oh! Ba-da-bing!
SAM: The Diceman over there feels a sudden pain
inside her belly as part of her magic has
disappeared. She tried to cast a Firebolt spell on
you, but instead of any fire coming out of her,
nothing happens. Instead she feels slightly less
magical than she was a moment ago. She has lost
her highest spell slot.
MARY: (New Jersey accent) I got maybe one left. I
don't know. I love you people! I'll talk to you
soon. Go to the Clam Broth House. They need
service over there. Ba-da-bing, love you, Jersey!
That's my name, too!
LIAM: (New Jersey accent) Did you just make a
Hoboken reference in the middle of our DND game?
MARY: (New Jersey accent) It don't exist no more,
bitches.
LIAM: (New Jersey accent) The Clam Broth House is
a huge part of my childhood, and she's right. It's
not there any more. It's been gentrified.
MARY: (New Jersey accent) Every fucking Mother's
Day we used to go to the-- Father's Day.
BRIAN: Now it's a Momofuku or whatever it was.
LIAM: (New Jersey accent) Sure, yeah. When I was a
kid, it was a place where drunks stumbled out of.
MARY: (New Jersey accent) It was a place where
freaking Sinatra used to go.
SAM: The guy the no pants, the old man is dead.
One of the whores just killed him with a
crossbow.
BRIAN: What was her name? Was it Kay?
SAM: That was Kay.
BRIAN: Good job, Kay. You get extra applesauce.
SAM: We go to four. This other ranger now sees
that the dwarves are on the move. She shoots a
shot at you, Frankfurt. What's your AC?
LIAM: It is 15.
SAM: She does not hit you. A crossbow bolt whizzes
by your body and hits this person behind you.
"Hey, I wasn't even doing anything!" Let's see
here. Jayne, you're up.
LIAM: Oh, am I? There's still a dwarf holding the
girl, right? The dwarf is holding her?
SAM: The dwarf? No, Frankfurt is still holding
her. She is grappled.
LIAM: Frankfurt is?
SAM: Yeah, Obby is standing in front of her in a
defensive position.
LIAM: I would like to hit that fucking dwarf's
bare ass with my whip, so I'm going to make an
attack. Oh, that's a natural one!
(groaning)
SAM: The whip crack knocks a bowl of Greep off the
table. It explodes! There is fire on the floor
over there. Right there. She's on fire. "I
literally haven't done anything!"
LIAM: Fucking fuck a duck. As a bonus action, I
would like to cast Sanctuary on myself.
SAM: Okay. An invisible shield comes up around
Jayne, who is still right next to the door, unless
you want to move.
LIAM: No, I have to stay right here. Next.
SAM: Okay. Val, the human bartender, will pick up
her greataxe from behind the bar, and she wants
you off the bar. She's going to swing. She's
trying to protect her bar. Ten. What's your AC?
ASHLY: An 18.
SAM: You're fine. The fire confuses her. She
swings wide. Clothesline, you're up.
ASHLY: I'm going to fucking pounce on this
motherfucker. Okay.
SAM: On the bartender?
ASHLY: No, on this one. This cat's claws thing.
What is that? What's the deal with that? Climbing
speed of 20?
SAM: Oh, you can climb very well and fast. That's
all. You can also slash with them.
ASHLY: As part of my movement toward her, could I
slash during my movement? Like a pounce?
SAM: You mean to get two strikes out of it?
ASHLY: Yeah.
SAM: I would say that upon reaching her, you could
make a slash attack, but you'd have to get to her
and then past her to even touch her.
ASHLY: Okay, I'm just going to move toward her,
then. Hop off the bar.
SAM: Okay. So you jump off the bar. You're no
longer on fire or in the fire. You get right next
to her.
ASHLY: And I'm going to clothesline her.
SAM: Sure. That's what you do.
MARY: You're so repetitive!
ASHLY: Hey Gryffin, are you freshly laundered
clothing? Because you're about to get
clotheslined!
(laughter)
ASHLY: That's a 21.
SAM: Oh, that'll hit.
BRIAN: Hey, guys, we do not guarantee that all the
Critical Role dice roll this well. Because before
you buy them, she's rolled three 20s on it.
ASHLY: Five. And then she is knocked prone,
right?
SAM: Oh wait, if you rolled a four, she is knocked
prone.
MARY: Can I react to any of this?
SAM: Sure. Do you have a reaction? Is that a thing
that you have?
LIAM: There's no reaction to getting hit in the
face.
SAM: No, unless by your class, can cast a reaction
spell, but I don't think you can, so you're okay.
ASHLY: Okay, so I do four damage. No, five damage
because I rolled a one. And then, for a bonus
action, oh! I should probably heal. Second wind.
Regains 1d10 plus four HP.
SAM: Oh, nice. Roll that d10.
BRIAN: Roll that beautiful bean footage.
SAM: After she clotheslines you, we see the tabaxi
take a deep breath of air and now, out of the
fire, suddenly she feels better than ever before.
ASHLY: It says clothesline attack takes ten feet
of movement. Could I have moved away?
SAM: How fast is your movement total?
ASHLY: 30.
SAM: So it took you 20 feet to get there. You have
another ten feet if you'd like to go somewhere else.
ASHLY: Okay. I'll move toward Jayne and Frankfurt,
that whole situation.
SAM: Okay, go this way. Excuse me, pardon me,
excuse me.
MARY: Do I get an attack of--
SAM: No, because I think it was a part of her-- I
think that's how it works. She does not get an
attack of opportunity, right?
LIAM: It's if somebody is running away from you.
SAM: Yeah, but this is during the move, right?
You ran by, clotheslined her, and keep running. So
I don't think you get an attack of opportunity.
LIAM: That's hazy; that's up to you.
SAM: I'm going to say no. Because I got to keep it
moving; there's more shit to do! Who's next? That
was Jayne, Clothesline. Frankfurt, you're up.
ERIC: Yes.
SAM: What would you like to do, Frankie?
ERIC: Is it possible to move Holly?
SAM: Yeah, you're holding her. You can do whatever
you want.
ERIC: I want to pull her towards Gryffin.
SAM: Okay. Gryffin's way across the room. Sure.
What's your movement?
ERIC: 25.
SAM: She is not resisting. I'll say that you get
full halfway there, right around where kitty-cat
is. That's your movement. You can still act. Can
still do something, or you could have attacked
before you moved. Up to you.
ERIC: I just need to talk to Gryffin. That's the
point.
SAM: Just talking!
ERIC: How you doing?
MARY: I've been better!
ERIC: I'd like to heal her. Is that a
possibility?
SAM: Sure, yeah! Do you have a healing spell of some
sort or a potion of some sort?
ERIC: I believe so.
SAM: Lay on Hands. You can use Lay on Hands. You
have a healing pool of 20 hit points you can give
in any denomination to anyone. So you can give her
20, you can give her one, you can give her four.
You can do whatever you want.
ERIC: What's it going to take to make you feel
better? We can strike a deal. Ten.
SAM: So from your 20, you now have ten left in
your reserve. Gryffin heals ten. If you want to do
a bonus action, or anything else?
LIAM: Hunter's Mark or nothing.
ERIC: Nothing.
SAM: Good. That's Frankfurt. Who's left? Holly's
not going to do anything. That guy is dead. We're
going to go to Kingston.
BRIAN: I am going to move closer to the action.
Can you put me on your left side of that table
with the weird onion garlic clove looking nutsack
on it? Is that a candle?
SAM: Yes.
BRIAN: Put me there, bro. Then I'm going to cast
Sleep onto Frankfurt.
SAM: Shit. You guys are turning really mean. Go
for it. Sleep is not a ranged attack; it's a spell
save DC of 14 against what save?
BRIAN: Can I target one person with it, or does it
get everybody? I've never used this spell.
SAM: Learn your spells! I can look it up.
BRIAN: Roll 5d8. The total is how many points of
creatures this spell can affect. Does that mean I
get everybody with that?
SAM: Roll 5d8 first.
BRIAN: All eights. Just kidding.
SAM: Oh, there's no save on Sleep. It just
happens.
LIAM: You count it up.
BRIAN: 25.
SAM: 25. Okay. I don't how this works because
you've got more than 25 hit points.
LIAM: The one with the lowest hit points gets hit
first within the area of effect.
MARY: How many does Holly have?
SAM: The lowest hit points?
LIAM: Creatures within 20 feet of a point you
choose within range. Did you pick a point?
SAM: He picked Frankfurt.
LIAM: Are affected in ascending order of their
current hit points, starting with the creature
that has the lowest current hit points. Each
creature affected by this spell falls unconscious
until the spell ends.
BRIAN: Fuck, Sam, this one's complicated.
MARY: How many does Holly have?
SAM: More than that, and so does Frankfurt.
LIAM: So whoever's at their lowest gets hit first.
Hit the dog with one hit point.
SAM: Yeah, so the dog's asleep.
LIAM: That's the first hit point.
SAM: Tabaxi, how many hit points do you have?
She's okay.
MARY: What about Zarvah?
BRIAN: I don't want to hit tabaxi, I want to hit
Dr. Frankfurt!
LIAM: Frankfurt's in the center. Viking woman.
Barmaid?
SAM: Yeah, so she's down. She's asleep on fire.
Barmaid's asleep, for sure. And then there's not
enough hit points left for him. You make all these
randoms fall asleep. This guy, too. Four people
pass out around Frankfurt. They are peacefully
asleep.
BRIAN: All right, so then for my bonus non-action,
can I inspire my beautiful cat friend with a
bardic inspiration?
SAM: Of course you can.
ASHLY: This relationship is so confusing!
BRIAN: Not to me. I'm going to cast this on you,
and you can add 1d6 to an attack, save. Okay.
(sings) Pour me some Greep, boys, and fuck my tab.
I want to go home with this sexy cat, and maybe Jayne.
ASHLY: (singing) Jayne's a minor.
MARY: (singing) Those rules don't apply in this
world.
LIAM: She's not a minor, but she is not
interested.
BRIAN: Yet. Wait until I put my shirt back on.
SAM: That's an inspiration to you. Hearing his
words of compliment inspires you. What is your
inspiration die?
BRIAN: You know what, man? As a bard, tell me
where that is.
(laughter)
SAM: We'll look it up. I don't remember. It's your
charisma modifier. It's probably a d8. I'm going
to say a d8, because I don't know, man. You get
one extra d8 on your next roll.
BRIAN: Oh, wait, no. It says here that it's a d6.
Yeah, cast this on another creature. That player
can add 1d6 to an attack, save, or skill check.
LIAM: Players are in charge of knowing their shit,
except for Eric.
SAM: Okay! Suddenly, without warning, without
making a sound, a new mysterious figure emerges
from the back room. Pushing Xavier away, he moves
quickly and silently across the Ass Sailor with a
speed none of you have ever witnessed. It's like
the figure runs without moving his body. He floats
in a beautiful sprint. As he passes by you,
Gryffin, you suddenly feel even hotter than
before. For an instant, he strikes fear into your
heart. Roll a perception check.
MARY: (gasps) Perception. That would be a 20.
SAM: Oh fuck. Okay. I could whisper, but that
takes too much time. You see first, as he glides
past you, he is wearing pants. He looks like a
normal human man except his eyes are different.
They seem to glow red. It's disconcerting. Also,
as you watch him run, his gait is weird. There's
no this movement of his shoulder, it's just
straight like he's floating, like he has no legs.
And as he whizzes by you, past these sleeping
people, you see the faintest flick of a tail. He
runs across. Does not say a word. Does not make an
attack towards you, Frankfurt. Does not even
regard you. But simply removes Holly from your
grasp. Roll a strength save.
ERIC: With which dice?
SAM: d20 plus your strength. Ability check.
ERIC: Is that Garello? Excuse me!
LIAM: You don't know. That's the mystery, Eric.
Plus five, that's right. 23!
SAM: 23? Let me look. Oh, wait. Didn't you have
some sort of disadvantage?
MARY: No, he tried to cast Sleep on him, but it
didn't work.
BRIAN: No, he got Vicious Mockery. Which means he
has disadvantage on his next attack roll.
SAM: We're going to put it on this. Roll again. It
was a while ago; we never did it. We're doing it here.
BRIAN: That wasn't his last turn.
SAM: No, I know, but we haven't incorporated it.
LIAM: So why are we doing it again?
SAM: Did he roll with disadvantage on his last
turn?
BRIAN: I did it after his last turn because I roll
after him in the initiative.
LIAM: Jesus, it was almost the same! Oh no, that's
a 12. 17.
SAM: 17. Where's the Guide? Shit. 17. Nope, that's
not it. Shit, too many pages! All right, I'm going
to just make something up. I'm going to say that
there's a brief tug-of-war. He does wrest Holly
from your grasp, but you slow him down
considerably and he only gets five more feet away
from you. He's going this way.
BRIAN: He's taking Holly with him.
SAM: He's taking Holly with him, and he's making a
beeline this way.
BRIAN: What's that way? The door's that way.
SAM: I don't know. You don't know. Gryffin, you
saw this weird thing just happen. What are you
going to do?
MARY: Are we back up to the top of the round?
SAM: Why not? Sure.
MARY: All right. Oh my god. I rush over to
Frankfurt.
SAM: You rush over to Frankfurt? Sure. What are
you doing?
MARY: What the fuck is going on?
ERIC: I don't know.
MARY: Where's the girl?
ERIC: Who was that guy?
MARY: I don't know. There was a tail. He had some
sort of tail.
ERIC: Where are my pants?
MARY: Well, it got really hot in here. And you're
fine. Do you still have the hotdog buns? Because
that could help keep you-- Are you all right? No?
Okay, don't worry about it. Who's the girl? Tell
me about her.
ERIC: Look, I don't know. Her name is Holly. She
lost her mother.
MARY: Is she from Illyria?
SAM: I love how they are having conversations
through this whole fight. I love it!
MARY: That's all right, we're just going. How can
I help you? Is he prone, is he anything-- Is he all right?
SAM: No, he's fine. Nothing happened.
LIAM: This has got to be Gilmore Girls dialogue.
SAM: He is naked from the waist down.
ASHLY: He's feeling ashamed.
MARY: I don't know what to do.
SAM: Did you move over to Frankfurt? You see this
dude carrying a girl running across the room.
MARY: All right. So I am going-- viciously mocked.
Okay! I am going to cast a cantrip of Ray of Frost
on him. It's a ranged attack against a target.
SAM: Roll a d20 and add six.
MARY: 16.
SAM: That hits. Go ahead.
MARY: He gets 1d8 cold damage and his speed is
reduced by ten feet until the start of my next turn.
SAM: That's very useful.
MARY: Yes, so 1d6. Six! 1d8, motherfucker. Five!
Five damage, and he's reduced to ten feet.
SAM: The cold blast hits him in the back squarely,
and even though it's a minor spell, you see him
react way worse than you thought it would be. He
cries out with an inhuman shriek (shrieks) and
seems to take even more damage than that. But he
continues on, slowly now. Because his non-feet
feel slower. All right, go on. He is where he is.
That is Gryffin's turn. Next is-- I don't care
about them. Jayne. Oh, sorry. There is a ranger
who's going to shoot somebody. I don't care. I'm
rolling to see who she fires at, and I rolled
Jayne. Sorry, I rolled randomly. It's a plus-five,
so that's eight plus five, 13.
LIAM: I am 13, but until the spell ends, any
creature who targets the warded creature must make
a wisdom save versus 14.
SAM: Okay, versus 14. She fails that. She goes to
draw her bow on you.
LIAM: Choose a new target or lose the attack.
SAM: She chooses a new target. She chooses
Clothesline. She fires, and it's a one. She's so
discombobulated that she hasn't hit anything
today. She sucks. Okay, now it's Jayne.
LIAM: Okay, so I know that I can get within ten
feet. I'm going to take my fucking white whip and
whip this guy in the fucking face.
BRIAN: Violence is Jayne's addiction.
LIAM: Ugh, no. It's bullshit. It's eight. It's
just an eight. That does not hit.
SAM: The whip makes a wonderful crack, and nothing
else happens.
LIAM: Fuck it! Then, for a bonus action, I'm going
to cast Chill Touch on both whoever this person is
and Clothesline because I'm a death cleric and
part of my perks is that I can cast Chill Touch on
two people next to each other instead of just one.
Two ghostly spectral hands fly out and latch onto
both of their fucking faces. The targets must both
succeed on a dexterity saving throw versus 14.
ASHLY: 14.
LIAM: Fuck you, Ashly Burch!
ASHLY: Fuck you! You betrayed me, you piece of
shit!
SAM: You did it on the bad guy?
LIAM: Yeah, both of them.
SAM: 17.
LIAM: Oh, then neither worked.
ASHLY: Do I notice that this motherfucker did that
to me, though?
SAM: Yeah, you see a blue spectral hand reach out
towards your face. It's super freaky. There's
fingernails on it, and then it suddenly (gasp)
faces away. It's super weird, and it emerges from
Jayne. While she cast the spell, it seems that her
lips go to the back a little bit, then become
thinner. Her eyes narrow, and she has this
skeleton look for half a second as she casts the
spell and then goes back to normal.
LIAM: Oh, BFFs K-I-T!
BRIAN: I'm terrified.
SAM: Okay, that's Jayne. Next is-- oh, you've got
more?
LIAM: Well, I can move back one space. That's it.
SAM: Clothesline, what you got? Clothesline, what
you got?
ASHLY: Hey, idiots. You want this little girl?
Talking to you. I'm talking to you. I'll help you.
Fuck you, Jayne! I'm going to attack Jayne.
SAM: Okay, go.
LIAM: Sanctuary is still up.
ASHLY: What does that mean?
LIAM: I don't know. You don't know.
SAM: Just do your attack first.
ASHLY: Okay. I'm going to use my longsword, even
though I'm tempted to clothesline you. So that's 18.
SAM: Okay, first make a wisdom saving throw, yeah.
So roll your d20. Add wisdom save.
ASHLY: Seven.
SAM: That's not great. So you feel the urge to
maybe hit somebody else.
ASHLY: I'll hit the guy taking Holly.
SAM: Okay, go for it. Roll again for your attack.
ASHLY: That's a 14.
SAM: Again, you are so distracted by what just
happened that your sword knocks over a bottle of
Greep, which explodes, and this dude's now on
fire.
ASHLY: Okay, as long as I'm not.
SAM: "I don't have a name!" Okay, that's
Clothesline. Frankfurt, you're next.
ERIC: I would like to attack the guy that's taking
Holly.
SAM: So you're going to move towards him? All
right. With the speed of a Frankfurt, you move
towards him, and you do something.
ERIC: A pantsless Frankfurt. I would like to hit
him with the maul.
SAM: Go for it.
ERIC: 20-sided die?
SAM: Yes, please.
ERIC: 18.
SAM: That hits. Go ahead and roll for damage. Your
maul does 2d6 plus six.
LIAM: Yep, the square. The cube. Six! Plus. Roll
it again. Six!
SAM: 18 points of damage. Oh shit.
ERIC: Take that.
SAM: Whoa. My god. The man with the girl is super
surprised. Oh wait. Even though you hit him with
this insanely hard hit-- you connected real hard--
somehow, he shrugs it off and turns to you and
sneers at you. He does take some damage, but it
doesn't seem like it's as much as you thought it would be.
LIAM: But you got maximum damage on that attack,
which is rare.
SAM: Okay. That was Frankfurt. Kingston, you're
up. While this is all happening, Obby says, "Obby
"the Rat does not like this." And he leaves.
MARY: Bye, Obby!
BRIAN: Obby, goddamn.
ERIC: Where you going?
ASHLY: Love you, Obby. Nice to see you.
BRIAN: Hey, does kidnapper guy seem hostile
towards anyone else?
SAM: He has not even looked at anyone else.
Singularly focused on Holly, has not uttered a
word, except he did turn around to look at
Frankfurt when he hit him,
just because he was pissed.
BRIAN: Can I try Blindness on Frankfurt again?
SAM: Glad you've got your priorities right. Go for
it.
BRIAN: Well, no one's attacking me. I don't give a
shit about this kid. I don't care about the guy
taking the kid, but this guy fucked my wife.
MARY: You fuck my wife?
BRIAN: Did you shampoo my wife? Blindness.
SAM: Go ahead. So your spell DC is 14, I think.
Eric, roll a d20. What's Blindness? Constitution?
Or is it wisdom?
BRIAN: It's going to be (singing) blinded by the
light, wrapped up a like a-- constitution.
SAM: Constitution. Roll a d20, add your
constitution saving modifier.
LIAM: Constitution. You've been rolling real well
tonight, Eric. And you still are. It's a 23 total.
SAM: This tickle on the back of your neck again.
Nothing happens. You are blue-balling so hard for
your spells. I hope you're marking these off. You
don't get infinite spells.
BRIAN: I am marking them off, Samuel. (whispering)
Which ones have I used? I'm kidding.
SAM: Any bonus actions? Anything else? Any
healing? You good, Brian?
BRIAN: Oh, am I still on the other side of the
garlic nutsack? I would like to move to where that
torch is over by the woman that's prone.
SAM: You're moving away from the action.
BRIAN: I would like to move away from the action
to the torch and face back towards the crowd. And
as my bonus action, can I cast a cantrip as my
bonus action? Actually, you know what? I'm good.
SAM: Great. Okay. Kidnapper guy with Holly makes
his way all the way to this trapdoor--
MARY: Remember, he's only ten feet. He can only
move ten feet because I Ray of Frosted him.
SAM: That's if his movement is 20, which it is
not.
MARY: I thought it's move to ten.
SAM: I thought you said it moves in half.
MARY: Oh, it's reduced to ten.
SAM: To ten? Shit. Well, then you are correct. So
let's say five, ten, uses his action to dash,
five, ten.
MARY: Oh, I'm sorry. You are right. It was reduced
by ten feet until the start of my next turn.
SAM: Then he's fine. He makes it there in one
clean dash, uses his bonus to flip open the
trapdoor. Just for good measure, he touches this
guy, who hasn't done anything wrong and he takes--
he's dead. Yeah. He dies.
BRIAN: By what method did he kill him?
SAM: He just touched him. The trapdoor is open,
and he is gone, and that's where we'll take our break.
LIAM: Fuck that guy!
SAM: Thank you so much for playing so far, guys.
We'll have more when we come back.
(cheering and applause)
LIAM: Just for the record, when I sat in the
chair, I'd at least directed-- DMed to
eight-year-olds once or twice. Sam came in blind,
hot. So hot.
BRIAN: Can I just say I now fully understand the
Travis knee shaking feverishly under the table? I
now get it.
SAM: Okay. So we're going to (voice breaking) give
away--
(laughter)
SAM: We're going to give away this-- our good
friends at CritRole. Not Wyrmwood. Our good
friends at Wyrmwood have this beautiful dice
thing. I don't know what it's called. It's English
wych wood. It is a elm burl hero vault, and we
will be giving this away to one lucky fan in the
chatroom. The code word for winning this fine
thing is meow, M-E-O-W, meow. Please enter. We'll
announce the winner after the break. Let's keep it
a quick break, guys. This is fun.
(cheering)
BRIAN: Eric Meowza.
SAM: Yes. (sighs) Oh god.
(laughter)
MARY: Yay, Sam!
SAM: Are we out? Come on.
[break]
LIAM: Clit-rota.
SAM: I'm pretty sure that was on.
ERIC: And we're back.
SAM: And we're back! Congratulations to the winner
in chat of this fantabulous Critical Role English
wych elm burl hero vault from Wyrmwood Gaming.
CholieAmenthys is the winner. Danoba will contact
you shortly for your shipping information.
Congratulations and meow.
LIAM: CholieAmenthys?
SAM: Yeah, CholieAmenthys.
LIAM: Punchy. Pithy.
SAM: So guys, when last we left, a mysterious
figure, who emanated heat, had grabbed Holly, the
little girl, who Frankfurt and Obby-- oh, we need
music-- were transporting, tore across the bar,
and went down into this trapdoor. You are all
confused, looking around; there's still fights
going on. What would you like to do? Go.
LIAM: I'm moving towards the door immediately, the
trapdoor.
MARY: Instantly. I grab Frankfurt, and off we go.
SAM: Okay, so you're all converging around the
trap door. Kingston, are you with them?
BRIAN: Yes.
ASHLY: If everyone else is going to fucking do it,
then yeah.
LIAM: As I walk, I'm casting Shield of Faith on
myself. It just boosts my AC, that's all.
MARY: And I still have three bottles of Greep.
SAM: Oh shit. Okay, you get to the top of the open
trapdoor, and look down into darkness.
ASHLY: I can see in darkness.
SAM: Sure, yeah. Many of you have darkvision. It's
okay, guys.
ASHLY: I got really excited that I had an ability
to do.
BRIAN: I became Laura for a second. "Actually--"
SAM: Clothesline has no pants. Both of your
genitals are exposed.
ASHLY: Free and clear in the wind.
SAM: So who's going first? Who's going second? Are
you going to talk to each other at all? You're
just going to go? Are you going to hit each other?
What's happening? Anyone want to go in first?
LIAM: I'm going to kick the bard in the ass, and
when I kick him in the ass, I'm going to cast
Light on his ass as he falls down into the hole.
SAM: You can cast Light on an ass?
LIAM: It's anything I touch, and it's a cantrip,
so his ass lights up as he falls down the hole.
SAM: All right, so yes. Kingston, you fall in
first.
BRIAN: Am I like propeller guy in Titanic?
SAM: Sure. Yep. In fact, roll an athletics check.
BRIAN: Okay, thought that'd be great. All right,
let's use Gil.
SAM: Or acrobatics, whatever's higher for you.
BRIAN: Well, you made the print so goddamn small
on my character sheet.
SAM: Sorry. Acrobatics is probably higher for
you.
BRIAN: Don't fuck me, Gil! Oh wow. Acrobatics?
Let's go ahead and call that a 22.
SAM: Whoa, shit. You're familiar with this tavern
and all of its layout because you live here, so
you land like a cat in a three-point landing at
the foot of this darkened ladder/stairs.
BRIAN: If you don't realize, I'm into cats.
SAM: How long does Light last, by the way?
LIAM: Oh, let's see how long that lasts.
BRIAN: Do I feel a sensation on my bum?
LIAM: One hour. So Kingston's ass is lit up.
SAM: Is it concentration or anything?
LIAM: No, it's a really easy spell for many of
us.
BRIAN: My ass is a beam of light for one hour? A
beacon of light for one hour? Can I bend over and
blind an enemy?
SAM: If you shove your ass close to them, it would
probably affect them at some point. So you are a
lightning bug, and your ass is illuminating this
whole space down here. Where did the figures go, Liam?
LIAM: On your other side, Sam.
SAM: Oh, there they are. Let's place you guys
around somewhere, haphazardly. Oh god, this
thing's so far. I can't do it.
LIAM: I'll help. Are they here or are they here?
What's our marching order, DM?
SAM: There's no marching order; it's a room.
LIAM: We shoved the bard down first. I'll go after
him.
SAM: He fell down, so he's over here, you guys
can-- who wants to go next?
ASHLY: Wait. I don't want this fucking thing,
whatever it is, Creepy McCreeperson over here.
Excuse me! You took your little icy tentacles and
tried to put them on the back of my head! We need
to restrain her. Something.
BRIAN: As I'm falling, I sing, (singing) Let my ass lighten
the way.
SAM and BRIAN: (singing) To your heart.
SAM: Okay, is anyone going to follow Clothesline's
suggestion?
ASHLY: Anybody? You want her just roaming around?
MARY: My concern is for other things at the
moment.
ERIC: She hasn't done anything to me.
BRIAN: What happened to your necklace? Wait, I
couldn't talk to him, I'm falling down a tunnel
with my ass made of light.
SAM: You're at the bottom, and Jayne is coming
down the steps right behind you.
MARY: What do you see down there?
LIAM: We have something to do. You can ask me lots
of questions later. Let's just kill the thing and
get the girl, all right?
BRIAN: Do you know what this thing is?
LIAM: I do not.
BRIAN: Do you know who the girl is?
LIAM: Sort of.
BRIAN: Tell me, and I'll give you some of
Gryffin's Greep.
SAM: As you talk, you all make it down there
slowly, filling the room.
LIAM: I walk past the idiot and start walking down
the hallway.
BRIAN: Piece of shit. I cast Talk to Me at Once!
SAM: I could pull it towards me. It's going to
wreck some microphones over there. Okay. I should
tell you, before you start walking, at the foot of
the stairs there's a single lantern casting a dim
glow, although that doesn't matter because you've
got Light coming out of your ass. On the walls are
graffiti, seemingly from patrons who've wandered
down here. One reads, "For a good time, do not
"call Isabelle." Another reads, "Do you know why
they call him Obby the Rat? Because his dick is
"the size of a rodent." And the other one says,
"What do you call a pile of tabaxi? A Meowntain."
BRIAN: Respect.
SAM: Straight on at the bottom of the steps, a
narrow corridor leading out around a slight
bend, obscuring the view. To the other direction,
it's a dead wall, however there is a space
underneath the back of the stairway. It is dank
and cold. Light frost covers the floor, because
you are out of that hot bar, now. So you would like
to continue down this hall?
LIAM: Yeah, I'm looking as carefully as I can into
the next space. I will peer for enemies or the
people we're following or anything.
SAM: Okay. This curves this way and leads to a
door. The corridor proceeds around to the left. As
you proceed through it, Clothesline has to bend a
little to make it through. Frankfurt feels roomy.
It ends with a simple wooden door and a rusty
knob. Are you still in the same marching order?
Kingston first or Kingston second?
LIAM: I call down over my shoulder and say: hey,
ass kicker!
SAM: That's you.
LIAM: No, it's not. Clothesline, get up here.
BRIAN: I'm ass flicker.
ASHLY: Fuck you! I don't follow your orders. You
tried to kill me!
MARY: I want to investigate what's under the
stairs.
ASHLY: I don't even know why I'm still here!
SAM: So nobody is going with you right now, Jayne.
You're in front of a door. Gryffin, can you roll
an investigation check?
LIAM: And I'm going to do my best to see if
there's any kind of trap on the door I'm looking at.
MARY: 18.
SAM: 18. Yes. All right. There is a false wall
here that opens up into another corridor that
leads this way. Let me see how I described it.
Yes. Okay. It empties out into a wider room, and
I'm going to do this. All right, so what would you
like to do?
MARY: Can I check to see if there's any trace of
footprints or anything?
SAM: Sure, roll a perception check.
MARY: (winces) I'm not going to waste that though.
Ten.
SAM: Ten? That's what you needed. So there is
frost everywhere. It's super cold down here,
because we're underground in a cellar area, and
it's winter. Yeah, now you're also getting cold.
BRIAN: I don't have a fucking shirt on!
MARY: Your nipples are rock-hard.
BRIAN: Good thing they're pierced.
SAM: Gryffin, you notice that there's less frost
on the floor under the stairs and through this
hallway than on the rest of the downstairs area.
MARY: Are there any footprints that I can see?
SAM: There are no footprints. If anything it's
just a straight line. You also notice something
else: two things, actually. Would you like the one
on the left or the one on the right?
MARY: Left, please.
SAM: Left? Read that out loud.
MARY: Oh, there's a fucking snake on the left!
Oops, a fucking snake just bit me. I take one
point damage and I make a constitution save
versus ten.
ASHLY: It literally says "a fucking snake" by the
way.
MARY: Constitution, which, okay. Ten.
SAM: That saves. You're fine. Just one point of
damage.
MARY: Goddamn it! And I step on the fucking
snake.
SAM: It's dead. Would you like the thing on the
right?
MARY: Yes. Another fucking snake. Whoa! I will
take that.
SAM: Okay. Do you proceed into this room or do you
hang out?
MARY: I turn around and I say: kitty-kitty, there
seems to be another room down here and it seems to
me that the frost is dissipating a bit on the
floor. What do you think we should do? There's no
sign of footprints, but I don't know that there
were footprints on the other way. Jayne, do you
see footprints? Besides your own, of course.
LIAM: I'm looking at the door in front of me and
seeing if I can see anything hinky with it.
SAM: Sure. Make an investigation check.
LIAM: Natural 20.
SAM: The door is not locked and not trapped.
LIAM: Well, I'm going to go inside.
SAM: You're so freaky. It's a rather long room
with boxes everywhere. Seems to be some sort of
storage area. In the middle is a table with
potions and beakers on it. A closet over here. It
is not lit at all. Let's see what I said about it.
A single lantern glows near the door, casting dark
shadows everywhere. Stacked boxes all around.
Weirdly, the smell of cabbage permeates the air.
In the center of the room, a wooden table
resembling a crude chemistry lab. Beakers and
vials are arranged. A whiff of something strange
hits you. It stings your nose like gasoline. Would
you like to look around?
LIAM: I would first like to cast Light again,
because it's a cantrip, I can do it as many times
as I want, and that means the bard's ass goes out
and I'll say that the grip of my whip lights up
and I hold it upside down.
SAM: That's so cool. So you've got a white whip
that's lit up.
MARY: So it's finally useful, is it?
LIAM: You're not there.
MARY: That was Zahra showing up for a moment.
LIAM: You said there were potions on the table
that I see now.
SAM: You can investigate that, yeah.
ASHLY: Is it possible for me at some point to try
to grapple her?
SAM: To grapple Jayne? If you want to walk down
the hall, you can try.
LIAM: I've entered the room and I want to inspect
the potions you said there were on the table?
SAM: Okay, roll an investigation check.
ASHLY: Can I move toward the room?
SAM: Sure.
ASHLY: And try to grapple Jayne?
LIAM: Ten.
SAM: Okay, ten is what you needed. Upon further
inspection, you use your light to reveal the
labels on the jugs. Someone has been mixing liquor
down here. After a minute of study, you figure out
that the house alcohol, Greep, is made right here,
and the formula is remarkably basic. It is four
parts standard rice wine, one part balsamic
vinegar, one part simple syrup, and one part pure
kerosene. Everyone who has drank it has been
drinking kerosene the whole night.
LIAM: I jot that down on a scrap of paper and put
it away, because I am a businesswoman, as well.
SAM: That's it. That's all you find, currently.
LIAM: Okay. I will start back and find the
catwoman in the doorway.
SAM: Okay. Catwoman, what would you like to do?
ASHLY: Hi, Jayne. And I would like to grapple her
by the neck and hold her aloft.
MARY: Oh hi, Jayne.
SAM: How's Sanctuary going? Still on?
LIAM: It's up to you. If ten minutes have passed
since I cast it?
SAM: It has not been ten minutes. So you'll have
to make a wisdom saving throw against 14.
ASHLY: Shit. Well, she's not very smart so she
would try. Natural 20.
LIAM: That's the third one for Burch!
SAM: So sadly, that does not mean that you
grapple. That means that you have the fortitude to
attempt to grapple.
ASHLY: It'd be really sad if it fails right now. I
got a nine. Is there anything I could apply to it?
SAM: Yeah, strength, and you're pretty strong.
ASHLY: So it's 12.
SAM: Wait, three? Your strength is three? No, it's
not.
ASHLY: Plus three modifier?
SAM: Really? I thought you were stronger than
that.
ASHLY: Wait, or is it this one? Saving throw?
SAM: No, you're right.
LIAM: And I have to roll versus it. So you got a
what total?
SAM: 12.
LIAM: That's a big four.
(laughter)
BRIAN: I'm still so used to Liam rolling and then
going: 196.
LIAM: The big thing tonight is I'm like: luck--
no. Phantom limb syndrome.
SAM: Okay, so you are grappled and restrained. You
both can't move or anything, unless you want to
try to drag her somewhere.
ASHLY: I want to be like: what the fuck, man? You
brought me here. I'm doing you a favor. Why did
you try to fucking kill me?
LIAM: (strained) It was probably a bad idea.
ASHLY: Bad idea, yeah. So? How are you going to
make it up to me?
LIAM: (strained) I think you need to kill me
later. I think we need to survive this basement.
ASHLY: I don't give a fuck about this girl or
anything going on with you, so if you don't want
to die right now, or have me leave and fucking
feed you to these dogs--
LIAM: We're talking a long time. Can I cast a
spell?
SAM: Sure, yeah.
LIAM: I would like to cast Inflict Wounds at
second level. Make a melee spell attack against a
creature you reach. Okay. She's done. That is
a 19 plus six. That is a 25.
SAM: What does this spell do?
LIAM: This is Inflict Wounds. Make a melee spell
attack against a creature you can reach. On a hit,
the target takes 3d10 necrotic damage. Except I'm
doing it at second level, so it's 4d10. And so my
hand just grips her forearm and death filters
through it. Ten. 19. 29.
ASHLY and MARY: (singing) I have three hit points,
just three hit points. I am about to die.
SAM: That was beautiful. And sad.
LIAM: Not even the bard.
ASHLY: You know what?
SAM: All right, so you are released, Jayne, from
her grapple.
ASHLY: Whatever you want to do is fine. That was
fine. Everything is fine. What do you need, buddy?
BRIAN: Can I do something? Since we're all in the
same area. Am I standing next to Frankfurt?
ERIC: Ah, Jesus! It's freezing down here.
ASHLY: I have two hit points left! I'm bad at
math. I have two hit points left. So am I knocked out?
LIAM: No, you're awake, you motherfucker!
SAM: You are feeling really shitty right now.
BRIAN: Wait! Did she do the 1d6 to her attack for
the bardic inspiration that I gave you?
MARY: She hasn't used it yet.
LIAM: That's water under the bridge, Brain.
BRIAN: Fuck the bridge!
MARY: Use it next time for something!
BRIAN: Okay. Can I force myself to throw up Greep
onto him? It says I have a candle, can I then
light that candle and light Frankfurt on fire
because I threw Greep up on to him?
SAM: I mean, you can certainly make an attempt.
MARY: That's 3,000 actions.
LIAM: Gagging your ass and then lighting a candle
seems like possibly three actions.
BRIAN: Have you ever had someone with a gnome
bard-sized penis steal your wife from you?
SAM: So many times. Go ahead and make a
constitution saving throw to see if you can make
yourself throw up.
LIAM: DND is all about negotiation.
BRIAN: Constitution saving. We're going to go with
a 12-- or no, 11.
SAM: You stick your fingers down your throat to
throw up, but it doesn't work. You gag and dry
heave for a while, and nothing comes up,
unfortunately.
BRIAN: So a typical night at the tavern.
MARY: All right, you two, would you stop it for
the moment? Seriously. We have a mission here, or
at least you and I have a mission and I do not
want to-- Look, Kingston, I love your work, I
really do and I realize that you're a fantastic
writer and everything else, but there are other
things to do right now. There is a room underneath
the stairs. Shall we check it out? It gets
increasingly warmer, it seems.
BRIAN: Are the elderly whores in there?
MARY: Yes! They most certainly are.
BRIAN: Let's go.
MARY: (whispering) Frankfurt, come with me and
we'll get to her. Yes.
SAM: Who's going down there? You three?
ERIC: Yeah.
MARY: The others split up and go rogue. Whoa!
SAM: As you walk in, you see that the walls of
this part of the tunnel are rough as if they had
been clawed out of the rocks. It's very cold; you
can see your breath as you enter. It's also pitch
black because light is gone. Those of you with
darkvision can faintly see that this tunnel-- I'm
going to skip that part, in the interest of time.
That this tunnel continues into darkness for a
wide oval anteroom. It's a bit oddly shaped to be
a storage room; it's about 20 feet wide with a 15
foot coved ceiling.
BRIAN: My ass is an hour?
SAM: When he cast Light, it went out.
MARY: Oh. Can I cast Light?
SAM: Sure, if you would like to? Okay. Things look
nice and bright in here. Four evenly spaced
pillars are holding up the ceiling, each with
intricate, beautiful carvings. At the other side
of the room is a single large door. The door seems
to be made of heavy forged iron, with carefully
inlaid bronze details: images of fire and lizard
tongues. Who would like to do anything or walk
around or enter? What do you want to do?
LIAM: While they're thinking about it, can I
talk to the cat?
SAM: Sure, go ahead.
LIAM: I'm not a very nice person.
ASHLY: (strained) I'm gathering that.
LIAM: Yes. I am a servant of the Chained Oblivion,
and I want everything destroyed. And I know that
doesn't sync up with your motivation. That's
rough. But I could kill you now.
ASHLY: Sure, yeah.
LIAM: Or you could come with me and help me get
this girl. And then maybe you'll make your way out
of it. Maybe you'll survive. I'm going to give you
a chance because I think you're worth more to me
alive now than dead. And if you're very nice and
don't argue, I'll even make you feel a little
better. What do you say?
ASHLY: That sounds great. It's cool. I'm good.
We're good. Yeah.
LIAM: Clothesline, I'm not a nice person.
ASHLY: I get it! I got it from the time when you
almost killed me, yeah. I got it. I'm good.
LIAM: I facepalm her and cast Cure Wounds. That
is-- I'll tell you. That is eight hit points back
for you. Hooray, eight, hey!
ASHLY: Hey, ugh. (coughs) I would say thanks, but
I'm not going to argue. What do you need?
LIAM: You can try to kill me later. I want the
little red-haired girl, you understand?
ASHLY: Yeah. Red-haired girl. Got it. Got it,
boss.
LIAM: Come on.
SAM: So you join the others?
LIAM: I'll follow her.
SAM: All right. So who is looking around the room,
doing something?
MARY: Can we check for traps?
SAM: Sure. Make an investigation check. What are
you checking for traps?
MARY and SAM: The floor.
BRIAN: You said there was shit written on the
pillar? Can I see if I recognize any of the
symbols on the pillar?
SAM: Sure. What languages do you speak?
BRIAN: I speak Common, Elven, Halfling, Valley
Girl.
SAM: What was your check, Mary?
MARY: 18. And I speak Elvish, Abysmal and Common.
SAM: Abyssal. You're looking at the floor
specifically? Okay. Brian, can you roll an
investigation check? Okay, so Mary, looking on the
floor you do not see any tiles or anything. It is
smooth, like poured cement. Seemingly no
traps on the floor. Glancing about the room,
though, as you step in and sort of use your light
to look around-- you rolled an 18, you said? You
see cobwebs and grime and dust all over the place.
It's not a very used room. But on the ceiling you
do notice faint symbols covered in years of
cobwebs and grime. Brian, what did you roll?
BRIAN: Was it an investigation? 18.
SAM: Okay. So you cannot read any writing on
these-- you're investigating the pillars? You
can't read any writing on them, but it's okay
because there's not really any.
BRIAN: Do I recognize the symbols?
SAM: There are symbols of serpents carved up and
down on these pillars, way nicer than they need to
be, and you can see from your excellent
investigation skill that the eyes of the serpents
have a faint glow of magic in them. They are
definitely trapped.
BRIAN: We got some weird snake shit going on over
here, guys. I don't want to touch it, but I would
like it if one of you did.
MARY: I was bitten by a snake on the way in, so I
would recommend not touching any of the snakes.
BRIAN: Maybe you're immune now that it bit you and
you could just go touch it and press one of the
eyes and maybe it won't do anything to you. I
recommend trying all the eyes.
MARY: It would make such a good story, though, in
your book if you did it, Kingston.
BRIAN: Oh, I know, but if it goes bad, who will be
around to write the book? Surely a fan such as
yourself would be dedicated enough to--
MARY: Did you always write your books or did you
have a ghostwriter?
BRIAN: Oh, I didn't have a ghostwriter. Are you
kidding me? The pain that I went through. I was
able to pull from so many different places.
ASHLY: Could I also do a perception check? Do I
see the symbols on the ceiling?
SAM: Not yet, not until you roll.
ASHLY: That is a 19.
SAM: You definitely see the symbols on the
ceiling. They're all over the place, many of them.
They appear to be writing in Common. They appear
to be numbers. Lots and lots of numbers. Also,
glancing about the room you've entered now, behind
this pillar back here you find something. Heads or tails?
ASHLY: Oh! Tails. Because I'm a cat!
SAM: Here you go. All right, so that is something
you find.
MARY: How high is the ceiling?
SAM: The ceiling is whatever I said before: 25
foot coved ceiling. 25 feet high. And it's covered
with numbers. They're all hard to make out because
it's dusty.
MARY: Numbers, huh? I have a feeling we're going
to have to touch one of those.
ASHLY: Is anyone good with numbers? I'm not great
with numbers.
BRIAN: And I'm drunk.
SAM: Okay. From the other side of the door you
hear a girl scream.
MARY: At the end?
SAM: Yes.
MARY: Oh balls. All right.
BRIAN: That end? Oh shit.
ASHLY: Hey creepy girl! Are you good with
numbers?
LIAM: No, but I have other skills. I would like to
cast Command on the dwarf. He has to make a wisdom
saving throw. So roll the d20 plus three.
ERIC: Are you allowed to do this? Is he allowed to
do this?
SAM: Sure, he can do whatever he wants. You can
also hit him over the head if you want.
LIAM: Not until after this spell is done.
ERIC: 13!
LIAM: Aw, 13? Plus three is 16. He beat it! Damn!
He beat it! Spell burned!
BRIAN: Now you know how I felt all night, Liam
Oberon.
ERIC: You know, Jayne, I couldn't help but
overhear. You were talking down the hall, and
these caverns echo. Did I not hear you say that
you may or may not be associated with the Chained
Oblivion?
LIAM: Was he anywhere near me when I had that
private conversation?
SAM: The caverns do carry audio. Why don't you
roll a perception check? A retroactive perception
check to see if you could hear that?
ERIC: A straight roll.
LIAM: Roll high. Catch me out, because I'm
terrible. That's a two.
ERIC: Two! Fuck!
SAM: You heard him say, "Jayne's a mailman."
ERIC: Got to clean my ears.
SAM: But something about Jayne has been bugging
you a lot. Me too, really. If we're going to be
honest.
ERIC: I've got my eye on you, Jayne.
SAM: So is this where you guys are standing? Where
are you?
MARY: Yep! That's where you put us.
BRIAN: I might be leaning against something,
because I'm a little tipsy.
MARY: I would like to move towards the door.
BRIAN: Yeah, I'll go with her.
ASHLY: So there is a door there?
SAM: That's a door.
BRIAN: Then there's a girl screaming on the other
side of that door.
LIAM: Jayne places her hand on Clothesline's
shoulder and says: wait. No, I didn't leave that
hallway. Whenever she would have walked forward I
would have said, wait.
SAM: Oh, so she's back here? But she found an
object over there. So she's definitely there?
LIAM: It's up to you if you wanted to.
ASHLY: I will do what you say.
SAM: You can tell her to go back or you can tell
her to wait there, but she's already there.
LIAM: Come.
SAM: Come where?
LIAM: No, I'm at that tunnel entrance. I never
entered.
SAM: Okay, got it. So you're calling her back?
Great. And Frankie?
ERIC: I'm going to stay right there.
SAM: Great. So you take four points of poison
damage as this pillar shoots out a bit of poison.
You're standing near it, unfortunately.
ERIC: Look, I just want to be close to the
action.
SAM: Cool. You guys kind of get the sense that the
longer you stay in here the more shit's going to
start happening. Anyone want to look at the door?
MARY: I would like to look at the door.
SAM: Okay, make an investigation check.
MARY: Oh, Tides of Chaos. That's better. Not
really. 18. 16!
SAM: Great. The door is not trapped. However, it
has a lock on it. A padlock. A curiously made
padlock. Where is it?
MARY: Are there numbers on the padlock?
SAM: There are numbers on the padlock, and you can
definitely sense that the padlock is magically
enchanted. And here it is!
LIAM: Oh shit!
MARY: What are the numbers on the padlock?
SAM: Who wants to look where?
LIAM: I'm looking at the ceiling.
SAM: Okay, you're looking at the ceiling.
LIAM: You said there are a lot of numbers up
there?
SAM: Tons of numbers. 29, seven, 65, 44, ten,
nine, four--
LIAM: And there's nothing different about any of
them?
SAM: Yes there are. They are all in different
colors. Some are red, some are green, some are
yellow, some are gold, some are orange.
MARY: Can you see if there are numbers, like four
numbers on the ceiling that are the same color?
LIAM: What color is the lock?
SAM: The lock is a basic gray. However, the slot
where you line up the correct numbers has a faint
color on it. The first two are orange. The second
two are green.
MARY: Okay, so I'm looking at the padlock. Because
you're up at the ceiling and I'm at the door,
right? Two orange, two green. What do you see up
top?
LIAM: An Irish flag.
MARY: All right. Which numbers are orange, which
numbers are green up on the ceiling?
SAM: Can you make a perception check? It's really
grimy up there.
LIAM: That is a 17 for me.
SAM: You definitely get a bead on the orange
numbers. Grab your pencil. There's many orange
numbers. They're all across the top of the
ceiling. They are six, one, eight, seven, two,
one, eight, two, four, nine, two, seven, one,
zero.
LIAM: You're a terrible person.
ASHLY: Can I use this item about this?
SAM: What is this item? Is it the earring? It can
tell you something about a person or a creature,
but not about a room.
ASHLY: Okay.
LIAM: Were those the orange numbers?
SAM: Those were the orange numbers.
MARY: What are the green numbers?
SAM: Make another perception check.
LIAM: I got a 14.
SAM: You can make out many of them. You get the
sense that if you got closer, somehow, you could
see more.
LIAM: How's the bard doing?
SAM: The bard?
LIAM: The bard!
SAM: I don't know how he's doing.
LIAM: I see him staring up, as well. How are you
doing, darling?
BRIAN: Fine. I'm wondering the endgame. I might go
back upstairs. But I want to see--
LIAM: Can you read the numbers on the ceiling?
BRIAN: Yeah, let me try. Oh wait, I did. Oh,
perception. I did investigation.
ASHLY: I rolled a 16 for perception.
SAM: Okay, so fine. While Kingston is fiddling
with his wingle--
BRIAN: 20.
SAM: 20?! You both see the green numbers very
clearly through the grime, dust, and cobwebs are
one, five, four, nine, eight, one, four, one,
three, two, zero.
LIAM: Keep going.
SAM: Now, I wait.
(laughter)
MARY: There are three less green numbers than
there are orange, and we've got two and two on the
padlock, two orange and two green. First two
numbers add to six and six. Motherfucker. I was
promised no math.
BRIAN: Promised no math.
ASHLY: There's four pillars in the room, but I
assume it's not relevant.
MARY: There's only three, right? Is the one pillar
still standing, or did it explode after hitting us?
LIAM: There's four pillars. One of them poofed out
poison.
ERIC: It was rough.
SAM: Sorry, guys. On the other side of the door,
you hear a low (snarling).
MARY: Oh, fuck. All right.
BRIAN: Did that sound like a cat to anyone else?
MARY: No, that sounded like a lizard or
something.
LIAM: And the lock looks like what over there?
MARY: It's like a big padlock.
BRIAN: Is there anything I can see on the lock?
Tell me about the lock.
SAM: Sure. Make an investigation check.
BRIAN: 18.
SAM: 18. That's great, yeah. It is specifically
designed in a way that-- it's a fragile thing. I
wouldn't try to hit it, because it has a trigger
mechanism that could fire something if struck.
It's got a pressure pad on it.
ASHLY: That's what I was going to do.
MARY: Can we see any of the numbers on the walls?
Is there anything else on the walls?
SAM: No numbers on the walls.
MARY: There's nothing on the floor.
ASHLY: How many snakes are on the pillars?
SAM: Let me do the math.
BRIAN: There's no numbers on the pillars, correct?
Just symbols?
LIAM: Sam's given us a MENSA challenge, and we all
die here.
MARY: We come back four years later. All right, so
the numbers again? Six, one, eight--
LIAM: Seven months without an episode break.
SAM: On one pillar, there's one snake. On the
next, there's three. On the next, there's two. On
the next, there's six.
ERIC: Say that again.
SAM: One, three, two, six.
BRIAN: That's on the pillars? Both, or all four?
SAM: This one has one, this one has three, this
one has two, this one has six.
BRIAN: Does the padlock have four numbers to open
it?
SAM: Four numbers. Two orange, two green.
BRIAN: How do we try them?
LIAM: The numbers on the pillars are not any
color, are they?
SAM: No.
ASHLY: I wonder if there's a penalty for trying
them. You could try it on this if you want to.
BRIAN: Could I try it on this? Okay. I'm just
going to fucking just because I know this fucker.
This is very hard to turn. It needs some WD-40,
Sam.
SAM: Sorry.
BRIAN: It's okay.
LIAM: You're so brave, Kingston. You should try as
many combinations as possible. Even if it burns
you somehow, you should keep trying.
BRIAN: Is it top to bottom or bottom to top to
open this?
SAM: Top to bottom.
BRIAN: Shit. Fuck. Someone do something else while
I do this.
ASHLY: While he's doing that, Sam, I'm going to
use this Earring of Piercing Knowledge and try to
find out if there are any weaknesses that Jayne
has.
SAM: She gets to know one fact about you. What she
has just used is a magical-- what is it called?
ASHLY: Earring of Piercing Knowledge.
SAM: You have to pierce your ear with it. Little
trickle of blood comes down, and now she knows one
fact about you, and she's chosen to know your
weaknesses.
LIAM: My weaknesses? I don't know what those are.
I could tell her many things.
SAM: Well, how about your-- let's see here.
LIAM: I will tell you lots of things in the
interest of not slowing down this episode. You
learn that I'm very weak and easily hit. You learn
that I am almost out of spells. And you have
learned that I am part of four generations of
women that have served the Chained Oblivion, which
is a god that everyone has heard of. And the
Chained Oblivion wants to destroy everything and I
am fucking crazy, just like my mother.
SAM: Make a perception check. Or investigation
check, whatever's higher.
MARY: Investigation. 14.
SAM: Upon looking at the numbers up top,
especially the orange ones, you start to realize
there's spaces between them. It's six, 18, seven,
21, eight, 24, nine, 27, ten. There are spaces in
between.
MARY: Those are the orange numbers.
SAM: Come on, guys, it's basic arithmetic.
ASHLY: We all had a little bit of Greep. I can't
even remember what it's called now.
MARY and ASHLY: Greep.
LIAM: What's after the eight? 24?
SAM: 24.
LIAM: Nine. The fuck is this, Sam?
ASHLY: I'm sure the chat's like, "It's this! It's
this!"
SAM: Oh, they are absolutely.
MARY: The chat's going, "Why can't you figure it
out?!"
BRIAN: Are we in any imminent danger?
SAM: As you say that, one of the pillars explodes.
These guys, Mary and Brian, you each take five
points of poison damage.
LIAM: I see a pattern, but I don't know what it
leads to.
ASHLY: 24, nine.
LIAM: Assholes.
ASHLY: What?
LIAM: Six is one-third of 18. Seven is one-third
of 21. Eight is one-third of 24. Nine is one-third
of 27. Ten. What's the ten? Ten is different than
the rest. I don't know if that means ten is
important, but it's different than the rest. Ten.
SAM: Say that all again, Liam?
LIAM: Six is one-third of 18. Seven is one-third
of 21. Eight is one-third of 24. Nine is one-third
of 27. Ten is one-third of-- there's nothing
there.
BRIAN: What is ten one-third of?
LIAM: 30.
BRIAN: So try-- well, there's four numbers,
though.
SAM: Those numbers that you're looking at are
orange. The first two slots on the lock are
orange.
BRIAN: So we need to find the two numbers that are
green now.
SAM: Make a perception check.
BRIAN: (groans) This isn't going well for me.
MARY: That's a five.
BRAIN: Perception? 18.
SAM: There are also spaces between these numbers.
BRIAN: Nope. 13. Your writing's too small.
SAM: One.
BRIAN: Is that an eight or a three?
LIAM: Why did you have to bring math into it, you
shit?
SAM: Yeah, I know, right? Four. I can't really
write upside down.
LIAM: You're doing it.
MARY and SAM: Nine. Eight.
MARY: 14.
SAM: Correct. 14.
MARY and SAM: 13, 20.
LIAM: Shit, what is that?
BRIAN: Well, there's even and odd numbers mixed up
in there.
MARY: One plus four is five. Four plus five is
nine. Eight plus six is 14? 13 plus seven is 20.
That's all I know. That's all the math I got. So
you got four, five, six, seven-- in a row. I don't
know what that is, Liam.
ASHLY: This is not my forte. I'm just pulling
shit--
MARY: So one plus four is five. Four plus five is
nine. Eight plus six is 14 and three plus seven is
20. I don't know what that means.
SAM: So what's next?
MARY and ASHLY: Oh!
LIAM: There are so many math majors watching right
now who are so mad at us.
MARY: Why are you so stupid, Rose? You're so
stupid.
LIAM: But Eric can sound like Chris Rock so--
SAM: Let's hear it, Eric.
ERIC: What's the deal with math? It wasn't a math
quiz show.
BRIAN: So 30. the first two numbers were the
last--
MARY: 14, 30! 20-- Wait. Okay, so you subtract one
from five, you get four. Subtract one from nine,
you get eight. Subtract one from 13, you get 20.
Subtract--
BRIAN: 19! So 3-0-1-9 or 1-9-3-0? Would be the two
options.
SAM: What you got, Mary?
MARY: 30 was the first and 19 was the second, but
that ain't right.
SAM: Look at the slot. Look at the slot on the
side. That's where the numbers go.
(laughter)
MARY: 30 and 19.
BRIAN: Or 1-9-3-0.
SAM: The lock is broken. The door is open; you are
in. This doesn't work!
BRIAN: You used Sharpie!
LIAM: Can we get a wet rag flown in? You are
getting beat up behind the studio tonight.
SAM: I love it. I'll do it over here; it's fine.
MARY: Does that work? Oh yeah. We just need a wet
rag. We need a wet rag, it's all good.
BRIAN: I got it!
MARY: You got it. You have no idea how difficult
math was. Math! No math, ever. Sam, you have a
brain for it. We don't. We've been drinking since
Tuesday.
SAM: Okay. Who's going in?
MARY: I am. Because I was right there by the
fucking door and in a celebratory moment of
getting the padlock open, I fall to my death.
SAM: Who's going in?
MARY: I'm going in.
SAM: You're going in. Where'd you go? Oh, over
here. Okay. Just you, right?
MARY: Well, Brian might go too because he was
right next to me.
LIAM: I mean, his character's dumb as fuck. I
think he might be going in.
MARY: Okay. Kingston LaForge!
SAM: Mary, this is what you see. The room is
similar in size and shape to the anteroom with a
coved ceiling held up by four spectacular carved
pillars. Two side pathways go to the right and
left of the room. I didn't remember that part, but
whatever.
On the far side of the room is a circular portal
glowing gold and emanating a low hum and even
though you are far from the warmth of the tavern
this room throbs with heat, as if you were walking
through a recently used oven. At the foot of the
portal, you see that man. Jesus, I lost him.
MARY: Where's that man?
SAM: I lost him. There he is. Boom. Holding a
struggling child. She screams in pain. There are
scratch marks above her eye and a steady trickle
of blood is pouring down half her face. The man
sees you enter and says, "It seems we all want
this youngling. I'm sorry, surface creatures, I
"saw her first. She's needed below." And you notice
that behind him a large, glowing portal opens up,
iris is open ever so slightly. It's pulsing, it's not
open enough for a person to walk in, but it's
getting close. What would you like to do?
MARY: I wanted to do a bonus action. I want to use
a couple of sorcery points to get another
1st-level spell because I lost one because of my
wild magic. Hello, everybody, there seems to be
our girl with the guy who's awful and he's-- come
here now! We need to help because otherwise he
will leave. There's a portal that's opening!
SAM: The man dashes to you. He gets right there
and he attacks. He rolled a one. He misses, but he
gets another attack. That's a 20. That hits.
MARY: Yeah.
SAM: Let me roll. Ooh. It's going to be bad.
ASHLY: He's still rolling!
SAM: Roll a dexterity saving throw.
MARY: I have good dexterity. 20.
SAM: Great. As he attacks, his human form drops
away and you see a salamander standing before you.
He's a large, ferocious lizard creature with a body of red
and orange scales, hard to see clearly because the
intense heat they throw off blurs the air around
them. His head and neck are more humanoid, with
smoke seeping out of his eyes and ears. He has a
streak of black that runs from one eye all the way
up and over his scalp. He's so hot, it's as if
he's made of fire. He holds a long black iron
spear in one claw and a ten-foot-long tail snaps behind
him. His slimy black tongue darts out, testing the
air, smelling you. You have just been dealt 15
points of fire damage.
MARY: Fire's my element. Does that mean it's
halved?
SAM: I don't know, man. You know you. Are you
resistant to fire?
MARY: I'm resistant to fire.
SAM: Then you only take seven points of fire
damage. You are not grappled. It is your turn, Mary.
MARY: The Ray of Frost seemed to work so well.
BRIAN: Did we roll initiative?
SAM: You're not in the fucking room.
MARY: It's just me and him.
BRIAN: Oh! I see. Sorry, I was getting you your Wet
Nap.
SAM: You guys are letting Mary take it.
MARY: It seems to be, Mr. Salamander, that you are
fire, fire, fire, so I'm going to come at you with
frost, frost, frost which is the only thing I
bloody have. Oh, wait. I'm going to use Chromatic
Orb of cold against salamander.
SAM: Go to that table.
MARY: I'm going to roll on the fucking table. (New
Jersey accent) Boom! All right, so I did just get
back from the Clam Broth House. They had some
beautiful trout. They had some beautiful fucking
trout that day. You know what I'm saying? They had
trout. It was gorgeous. It was beautiful.
LIAM: (New Jersey accent) You know what you got to
do? You got to fucking attack.
MARY: (New Jersey accent) Oh my god. What is that?
I think that's a fucking nine.
SAM: Nine. Oh shit.
LIAM: (New Jersey accent) I would like to use my
bonus action to drop a deuce.
MARY: (New Jersey accent) Isn't this beautiful?
Hey, motherfucking salamander! How you fucking
doing? You good today? You good? Your tongue
smells like shit, like a bad pastrami that I had
once back at the Millburn Deli. What I'm going to
tell you right now. I rolled a fucking nine.
You, 60 feet, are going to become poisoned.
SAM: Yeah. He is poisoned now. I really don't know
how poison works, but I assume
he takes poison damage.
LIAM: Disadvantage on his shit. I love high
fantasy, by the way.
MARY: (New Jersey accent) Millburn Deli, you're
going to like a sloppy joe. What you want to do is
get it with a little extra mayo, you got to go
extra sloppy with this shit. It'll counteract the
poison. Too bad we're not there right now. You're
going to fucking be poisoned. How you doing?
Boom, bitches!
SAM: He does not like that very much. He also
doesn't like the accent. He thinks it's uncouth.
I'm looking for poison. Bear with me. Okay,
poisoned creature has disadvantages on attack
rolls and ability checks. Holy shit! That's
amazing!
MARY: And he's poisoned for--
SAM: Well, it'll be more than an hour, so it's fine.
That's great. Well, he's about to attack you again--
MARY: For four hours, he's poisoned.
SAM: Great. Anyone else doing anything?
BRIAN: I would like to come into the room.
LIAM: I start pushing the cat, and start moving
towards the room.
MARY: Push the cat towards the room.
ASHLY: Oh great, it's a salamander now. Awesome.
Perfect.
LIAM: And I would like to try to get within ten
feet of the salamander, so behind the sorcerer.
SAM: All right, I'll say they flank them. You're
behind the sorcerer.
LIAM: And I would like to attack, if no one else
is going to jump on it.
SAM: Well, roll for initiative. Let's get an
initiative order.
LIAM: Yeah.
ASHLY: Eight.
SAM: Okay, 20 to 25?
MARY: Do you add anything to initiative?
SAM: Yes, it'll say on your character sheet.
You're plus three to initiative.
MARY: I am? 19.
SAM: Okay. Gryf.
LIAM: 17.
SAM: 17 Jayne, who else, 15 to 20? Anyone 15 to
20? Ten to 15?
BRIAN: 11.
SAM: Who else?
ERIC: Seven.
ASHLY: I'm an eight.
ERIC: Didn't roll high that time.
SAM: Frank is eight? No--
ASHLY: I'm eight.
SAM: Clothesline's eight. Frank's seven. Okay.
Salamander gets to go first. I don't know how to
do this for him.
MARY: It's okay. Just wing it, it's the secret to
adulthood.
LIAM: None of it's real.
SAM: All right, he's going to use his spear to
attack the bard to his right. That is a big old
22.
BRIAN: That hits.
SAM: Yeah, sorry, friend.
15 damage. You get pierced by this super
sharp spear, and it hurts real bad. And also, when
he withdraws it from your body, you suffer another
two points of fire damage, because it's
super-heated; it's almost molten iron, it's so
fucking hot. 15 plus two, and he gets to attack
again. He's going to go to the cat. Ooh, that's a
19 plus a lot. With his tail, he whips it around--
ASHLY: This might be the end of Clothesline.
SAM: That is a ten.
ASHLY: That is how many hit points I have.
SAM: You are unconscious.
ASHLY: See ya!
SAM: I don't know how all that works, but you're
unconscious.
LIAM: On her next turn, she makes a death saving
throw. So she's just unconscious. She could be
brought back, if anybody gives a fuck.
SAM: And on its movement, it will leave. You get
an attack of opportunity on it, both of you.
LIAM: Oh, it's running?
SAM: Yes, it's going (hisses).
LIAM: It's within ten feet of my range with the
whip, so I do, too.
SAM: All right, so make three attacks against this
thing. Kingston, you go first.
BRIAN: I would like to--
SAM: Are you a lore bard? I think you are. I think
you get to cast a spell on retreat.
BRIAN: I am, man. I will cast a--
SAM: If you want. Or you can use a fucking sword
or whatever.
BRIAN: I am going to have to cast Thunderwave at
this bitch.
SAM: Okay, go ahead. That is just a spell, right?
It's not ranged.
BRIAN: On a failed save, a creature takes 2d8
thunder damage.
SAM: Sure, what is the save?
BRIAN: The save is going to be a 14.
SAM: 14. Oh, he makes the save, but he takes half
damage, so instead of 2d8 it's 1d8?
BRIAN: Sure, man.
MARY: He's still poisoned. What does that mean?
LIAM: Disadvantage on everything.
SAM: Oh shit! I didn't roll disadvantage on those
attacks!
ASHLY: It's all right. I'm taking a cat nap; it's
fine.
BRIAN: That's not going to work. That's an eight.
SAM: Great. Actually, roll 2d8, and then take half
of that.
BRIAN: Okay. That's also an eight.
SAM: Great, so it's eight. Did he make his save?
He made his save, so he's not knocked prone, but
he does take eight points of damage. Good job,
guys! That's thunder damage, yeah? Okay. Great.
BRIAN: As a bonus action, can I cast a spell?
SAM: No. You get that on retreat. Mary, it's your
turn.
MARY: I get an attack, yeah? So I'm going to cast
a 1st-level Chromatic Orb.
SAM: You don't get to cast spells, I believe. You
can only do a melee hit if someone is running away
from you.
MARY: All right, then I'm going to pull out my
shortbow, and I'm going to (bowstring pings).
SAM: All right, roll an attack, plus whatever.
MARY: That was terrible. Just a straight attack?
SAM: Nope, it's d20 plus-- what is it? Is this a
finesse weapon? I don't know how bows work. Here,
it says plus three. Plus three.
MARY: Oh, plus three. Eight.
SAM: That goes wide, and it almost hits the girl.
Whip master? What've you got?
LIAM: With how things are going, and where I am
right now, I'm just going to cast Chill Touch,
which has a range of 120 feet.
SAM: Can you cast a spell on retreat?
LIAM: Retreat?
SAM: He's moving away from you; it's not your
turn.
LIAM: Oh, it's not my turn?
SAM: No, this is your attack of opportunity.
LIAM: Oh, if he ran, no, that would be the whip,
as soon as he ran. So that's just an attack. That
hits. That's an 18 plus some stuff. Okay, so
that's just 1d4 plus two, so that is a two plus
two is four, and I'm going to Channel Divinity and
fill that with death. So that will be a total of
more than four. One second, please.
SAM: Less than three?
LIAM: Hold on. That's an 18 damage, as it runs. 18
total, as it runs. It was a four from the whip,
and then 14 necrotic damage because I'm fucking
insane. And the Chained Oblivion's wrath fills
this fucking asshole.
SAM: Ooh, nice. He does not like that. It is now
Gryffin's turn; that was just his turn in retreat.
MARY: All right, I'm going to then cast Chromatic
Orb. Cold.
SAM: Okay, he's hiding behind a pillar; he has
half cover.
LIAM: Half cover, so at disadvantage.
MARY: Half cover.
SAM: You can move to see him.
LIAM: So you can go on a diagonal, and then you
can see him straight on.
MARY: I'm going to go on a diagonal. Diagon Alley.
And I am going to cast Chromatic Orb, with cold.
SAM: All right, spell DC? Right? Or is it a
ranged?
MARY: It's a hurl. I've got to hurl.
SAM: Ranged attack. Okay, so roll a d20 add six?
MARY: 24?
SAM: Yep, that hits, for sure. So now roll 3d8.
MARY: Right. 3d8, because I cast it at 1st-level.
What are d8s? Oh my god. I got you, bro. One, two,
I'll just-- Five and four is nine, plus seven--
16.
SAM: 16 points of damage, doubled to 32, is a big
hit. Great.
MARY: Feel the chill, motherfucker! Oh, another
salamander's coming.
SAM: Just then--
LIAM: Elizabeth Warren runs in!
MARY: What?!
SAM: I don't have her. Fuck it. Just then, an old
lady runs in the room. She has a hoof print on her
face. She's bloody, she is pissed off, her arm is
broken, she runs in and says, "Where's the bitch
"that ran me over with a horse?" Great. Jayne, it's
your turn.
(laughter)
LIAM: Well, it wasn't me. Shit.
MARY: So he's not bloodied, he's not nothing?
SAM: Oh, he's looking rough. Oh yeah, salamander
is looking rough.
LIAM: As a cantrip, I'm going to cast Chill Touch
on the salamander. Ranged spell attack. All right.
I want to use this one. Oh, that's terrible!
That is an eight.
SAM: Yeah, it hits the pillar in front of him.
LIAM: So a ghostly hand grabs the pillar and
nothing happens.
SAM: Absolutely. Ricochets off.
LIAM: That was an action.
SAM: Now you have to solve another lock riddle.
You can move; you can do a bonus action.
LIAM: Yes, I'm going to move. I'll move myself.
Five, ten, 15, 20, 25, 30. I'm just going to be
right there.
SAM: Okay, Kingston, you're up. Do something.
BRIAN: For my action, I will cast Cure Wounds on
myself, because I am so low.
SAM: On yourself. There's a dead person next to
you, it's all good, but sure. Yeah, go ahead.
LIAM: To the home audience: choose the Luck feat.
BRIAN: You know what? Oh yeah, she is unconscious.
Where is she?
SAM: Here.
BRIAN: Oh yeah, okay. You know what?
LIAM: Whoa, she's unconscious?
SAM: Yeah, you can retroactively bonus action,
sure.
LIAM: I can? Oh, good. Instead, while everyone's
focused on the salamander, I'm going to loop the
whip around, and yank, and twist her neck.
SAM: In an instant, you feel the life drain out of
you.
LIAM: That's two death saves, is what that is.
ASHLY: I only clotheslined people so I could feel
human warmth!
SAM: Even though you are unconscious, you still
feel shitty.
BRIAN: Wait, but he does that before I can change
my mind about healing--
LIAM: And on her turn, she has to make a death
save. If she fails it, she's a goner.
SAM: Sure, but now it's Brian's turn, and he gets
to decide what to do.
BRIAN: All right, well now that it's my turn, and
we definitely haven't decided what I'm going to do
with it yet, I'm going to cast Cure Wounds on...
Clothesline. 1d8 plus my spellcasting modifier.
SAM: You're using this as a bonus action?
BRIAN: No, my regular-ass action. Because I'm
fine.
SAM: It is a bonus action. You can also use a real
spell.
BRIAN: Wait, I just asked that earlier, and you
said no!
SAM: What are you talking about?
BRIAN: I asked if I could use a spell on my bonus
action, and you said no.
SAM: You said if you could use a cantrip.
BRIAN: I asked if I could use a cantrip?
SAM: That's a level one spell.
BRIAN: I don't have bonus actions as a wizard,
yet, so I'm confused. Okay, so for my action, I
will-- fuck. I'm going to do Vicious Mockery at
Frank Grillo.
SAM: Okay, go ahead.
LIAM: At who? Frank Grillo?
MARY: Who's Frank Grillo?
ERIC: I'm Frank Grillo.
BRIAN: That's 1d4 of psychic damage.
SAM: Sure, I've got to make a save.
BRIAN: Yeah, you have to make a fucking wisdom
save.
SAM: Wisdom save?
BRIAN: Yes, wisdom save.
SAM: Okay. I do not make it. 2d8. Go ahead.
BRIAN: Oh, yeah? Oh.
SAM: Wait, what is this? This is Vicious Mockery.
BRIAN: It's 1d4. I was gone for a minute, but I'm
back now. Sit the fuck back down. Seem like
everyday nowaday Hollywood-- Three.
SAM: Okay. Of psychic damage? And he has
disadvantage on his next attack, which he already
had. So great.
BRIAN: I'mma show these motherfuckers how to act
now.
SAM: Okay, you also get your bonus action, which
you can use to heal--
BRIAN: My bonus action will be to cure my
beloved.
SAM: How would you like to talk to her to cure
her?
BRIAN: I have to talk to her to cure her?
SAM: It's Healing Word, you have to say a word of
healing.
BRAIN: Oh, Cure Wounds?
SAM: Cure Wounds? Okay, that is a real spell; that
takes an action. It's okay, just do Healing Word, bud.
BRIAN: Oh fuck, yeah. Okay. Healing Word is--
SAM: 1d4 plus something, four, maybe?
BRIAN: (singing) I love Greep. I love cat people.
What the hell am I doing here? That's a two.
SAM: Great, you've got two hit points; you're
alive.
BRIAN: Sorry it's not more, but hopefully it's
enough to get us maybe a date, later?
SAM: Kingston just saved you. Clothesline, you are
alive. It is your turn. She's prone.
ASHLY: I'm prone? What can I do, then?
LIAM: You can get up. It's half your movement, but
you can fuck me up, still.
ASHLY: I can get up? Then I am going to
clothesline that motherfucker there.
SAM: Great. Roll an attack?
LIAM: I haven't lost a hit point this entire
game.
ASHLY: Natural 20!
(cheering)
SAM: That certainly hits. Roll 1d4 plus four?
ASHLY: Come on, baby. Three plus four is seven.
SAM: Double it. 14.
LIAM: No, the dice are doubled.
SAM: It's ten. It's ten. And you're not knocked
prone.
ASHLY: Did I take my second action surge?
SAM: No. Do it.
ASHLY: I'm going to clothesline you again! A
natural 20!
(cheering)
LIAM: What the fuck is that? Get out of this
building!
MARY: Buy this die. You can sell this die for
millions.
SAM: So Clothesline turns around, delivers a
right-armed clothesline to you. It hurts. She
kisses her bicep, uses the other arm. Left-arm
clothesline on you.
ASHLY: Give me a four, baby, give me a four. A
four!
SAM: A four!
ASHLY: And you're prone, motherfucker.
LIAM: Do the Leonidas handshake with me; that was
amazing.
SAM: That's 22 total points of damage, and you are
prone. The double clothesline.
LIAM: In addition to the last attack?
SAM: No, that's total. 22 total.
MARY: So what did you say right before she rolled?
You had taken no hit points? Say it again out loud.
ASHLY: Yeah, say it, please.
LIAM: No hit points, to all the hit points.
ASHLY: All of your hit points?
LIAM: No, not all.
ASHLY: Damn it. Wait, he gave me the 1d6--
SAM: Oh, that wouldn't be useful here, anyway. Do
that on a save. Eric, it is your turn. What do you
want to do?
ERIC: I mean, my knowledge of his association with
Chain of Oblivion.
SAM: Sure. When Jayne falls, you see very clearly
the symbol of the Chained Oblivion, and the
tattoos under her skin, clearly exposed now that
she's lying on the floor, white skin revealed.
She's definitely a servant of the Chained
Oblivion, whom you are sworn to kill.
ERIC: You know, it's my first time playing. But it
clearly states that you raided my village, and I
have sworn an oath to seek revenge on the cult, or
anyone associated with the cult of the Chained
Oblivion, so I would like to continue the attack
on Jayne.
LIAM: Only the best people are in the cult. You'd
be surprised.
ERIC: And I choose to do so with my maul.
SAM: Yes, please. Two-handed strike, go for it.
Roll for an attack.
LIAM: Not great, but hold on. Five plus six is 11.
I'm sorry, that does not hit. I'm so sorry.
ERIC: Man, I just revealed my hand.
SAM: Hold on, let me just look at you, see if you
have any extra things--
BRIAN: My ex-wife said you didn't know how to use
them.
MARY: Apparently, he knew how to use other
things.
SAM: Okay, you know what?
BRIAN: His dwarven hammer, perhaps.
SAM: If you wanted to--
LIAM: This salamander is like, "Look at these
assholes fighting amongst themselves!"
SAM: I'm just going to suggest to you that we're
late in the night; you might have used Vow of
Enmity as a bonus action to give you an advantage
on this attack, so you could roll again.
ERIC: I did write it down and circle it.
LIAM: So you could cast it on me, which you would
do, as a paladin who hates the Chained Oblivion.
So roll again; if you do better, you hit me.
ERIC: I will cast my bowels of Enmity.
SAM: You've shat on the floor. It's an angry
poop.
ERIC: I would like to use my Imodium AD and come
right in. Five again!
MARY: It was meant to be. You convinced him to use
it, is the thing.
SAM: Blinded by your hatred of the Chained
Oblivion, you can't seem to make contact with your
maul, and instead you swipe to the left, hitting
the old lady in the face. Killing her. Again.
ERIC: Problem solved, guys.
MARY: Sorry, random newcomer.
SAM: That's Frank's turn. We're onto the
salamander, who is going to use half his movement
to attack Gryffin. Rolls an eight plus seven. 15?
MARY: Nope.
SAM: Okay. Second attack. That hits, that's a
20-something. Okay. Eight plus four. 12. Oh boy.
Plus seven. Okay, so it's 12 bludgeoning damage
and seven fire damage.
MARY: The fire is halved.
SAM: Okay, so 12 plus two then, right? 14? Roll a
dexterity saving throw to see if you're grappled.
You know what, it doesn't matter; he's not going
to grapple you. He's moving. The portal is fully
open. He grabs Holly, he puts one leg in. That's
as far as he can get.
LIAM: He's got no legs.
SAM: I'm sorry. It's one penis in. He walks on 100
penises. He's like a centipede-- he's like a
centipene. It is Gryffin's turn.
MARY: I take out my Wand of Entanglement, and I
whip it at motherfucking salamander.
SAM: I don't know what that is. What does he do?
MARY: I entangle him.
SAM: Automatically?
MARY: Yeah, I don't know. It's fun, isn't it?
SAM: It's the Entangle spell.
MARY: It's the Entangle spell, and I have a wand
that does it--
SAM: I might have written this on your card. Hold
on, let me look.
MARY: I hope so, because it's going to take me a
second to find it.
SAM: Here it is. 20 foot square versus strength.
14 save. He makes his save.
You still get a bonus action.
MARY: Okay, well my bonus would be-- are you
allowing the cantrips as a bonus?
SAM: Sure, man. Go for it.
MARY: Ray of Frost.
SAM: Yep, do it.
BRIAN: Maybe a little dinner and some laser
pointer?
ASHLY: Okay, don't push it.
MARY: 22.
SAM: He looks back at you and says, "Fuck you, you
can't catch me," and you hit him square in the
face. Roll for damage.
MARY: Yes, I fucking can.
SAM: 1d8 cold.
MARY: 1d8 cold. Five.
SAM: Five. He has ten hit points left, but cold
damage is doubled. How do you want to--
(cheering)
SAM: How do you want to kill this?
MARY: From my hand, comes a spear that hits him
square in the jaw, as he-- what did he say?
SAM: "Fuck you. You can't fucking catch me!"
MARY: And at that moment, it goes (impact). Well,
you figure it out.
SAM: Yeah, not only does it bisect his tongue, it
splits his head open all the way back to the back
of his neck, protruding out the back. When it goes
behind him, your cold spear-- it's a cold spear?
Enters the portal and instantly melts, because
it's so fucking hot in there. His head splits in
half, and he falls to the side, next to a frazzled
and crazed Holly, who is looking at this with open
eyes; she hasn't said a word.
BRIAN: Holly's going to need some therapy after
this.
MARY: Holly! Holly, we're here, don't worry, it's
all right. Move towards me. Get away from that thing.
LIAM: Wait, before we move forward, I know that
I'm after Gryffin. Yes. So because that is so, I
would like to attack the tabaxi with my whip,
now.
MARY: He's just got a thing for your love.
BRIAN: She's not doing anything to her that I
think is worthy of this.
LIAM: That is a 13 to hit?
ASHLY: 18 armor class, my friend.
LIAM: Fuck. Okay, I'm going to start to run. One,
two, three, four, five, six. Okay?
SAM: Okay, good. As the defeated salamander lies
motionless on the floor, there's a brief moment of
calm. You look around the room. Just moments ago,
you were strangers, but at the Ass Sailor,
anything is possible. The girl, Holly, finally
speaks. She steps forward and says, "Thank you,
"kind souls. I know not why you have rescued me,
but my people will be grateful, and you will be
"rewarded handsomely for your goodness. I can sense
that many of you do not trust each other."
ASHLY: Can I run after Liam?
LIAM: Six seconds have passed. One, two, three,
four, five, six.
SAM: "Please, don't leave, Clothesline. I'm not
done with my speech."
MARY: Jayne's running like Tom fucking Cruise.
SAM: She casts Hold Person on you.
ASHLY: Goddamn it.
SAM: On Clothesline. "I ask you, as one caring
creature to another, to put aside your differences
"and marvel in what you have accomplished here
together, as more than strangers, as friends. I
"must leave now, but you will see me again. And as
I leave you, I suggest you remember these words of
"advice: snitches get stitches. If you talk to the
police, try not to tell them too much, for all our sakes."
And with that, she poof, disappears. And suddenly,
in the back of the room, holding Jayne in his
arms, a gruff man constable and ten armed guards
beside him enter the room and say, "Freeze! All of
"you, hold it right there, you fuckwads. We caught
your little albino freak trying to run away. You
"five made quite the fucking mess upstairs, you
know that? Dead hookers, burned up old ladies,
"some guy talking about a fucking rat. It's going
to take days to mop this shit up, and you're going
"to help me figure out what the shit happened.
That's right: you're all under arrest. Boys, bring
"them down to the station; I'm going to interrogate
every single one of them until they talk, and talk
"they will."
As the police take you into custody, marching you
back up through the ruined bar, you notice
Valerie, the bartender, frazzled, removing her
apron, letting out a big sigh, mounting her horse
for the long, cold ride home. The end.
(cheering)
SAM: I'm spent.
LIAM: Takes a lot of concentration, yeah?
SAM: Oh my god.
MARY: Sam, that was amazing!
SAM: That's hard, dudes.
MARY: I loved the interrogation mid-way through.
That was so cool.
LIAM: Ashly, we all lived, so it's like we're all
winners, right?
ASHLY: Is that really what it's like, Liam? Is
that what it's like?
BRIAN: How many did you have left, two? I had
seven.
MARY: I was 12.
LIAM: I kept trying to take away those two hit
points for so long!
MARY: Eric's like, "I got full strength, I got
full power."
ERIC: Play neutral, that's how I play it. In any
game.
SAM: What items did you find and not use? The
Snuff Box of Jump?
MARY: The Snuff Box of Jump was pretty cool.
SAM: Yeah, you snort coke and get Jump. You also
didn't find the super weird porno book or the jug
of nasty grease.
MARY: When would I have used the Scroll of Feather
Fall, though?
SAM: Oh, that was something that you guys didn't
go to.
LIAM: If I could have rolled a critical hit one
time, like you did three times, I could have
one-hit killed any of you. Any of you.
SAM: Yeah, he has this special whip that if people
get weak enough, you die.
MARY: So I thought it was like a Finger of Death,
I wasn't sure; it seemed to be very Fingery of Deathy.
SAM: Sort of. Oh, it was fingery all right.
ERIC: Who was Garello?
SAM: Oh, Garello was a.k.a. Sal the Salamander.
MARY: Yes! I killed Garello!
SAM: You were being paid to transport this girl
here to them, you don't know who was paying him.
ERIC: So it would've been bad if I had found
Garello.
SAM: Yes, it would've been bad if you'd found him.
He would've taken the girl, and taken her back to
his land to do some untold badness to her.
BRIAN: Man, magic did not work well tonight.
MARY: Magic, it didn't work in the first half. It
worked better in the basement than it did
upstairs. Once I'd figured out-- the first thing
that I hit him with was frost, and that was
upstairs, and I was like oh, he totally, English
football (squeals). And I was like, oh, okay.
SAM: Guys, this was so much fun. I hope it was fun
for you. A big silent hand for Brian Foster, Mary
Elizabeth McGlynn, Ashly Burch, Liam O'Brien, and
Eric Bauza.
ASHLY: And to Sam Riegel!
SAM: Thanks, guys. I'm going to go home and sleep,
and then I'll see you in the morning.
LIAM: Thank you to Matthew Mercer, who does this
week after week after week.
MARY: Eric, how do you feel? First time playing.
ERIC: Pretty good, I called so many of my friends
that actually do play for advice, and one of them,
Graham Lunam, who I said I'd call out-- because
he's a huge fan, he's a Canadian, watching
probably right now-- he's been texting me, saying
I've been doing a good job. But I would totally
come back again, but thank you for having me.
SAM: No, thank you for getting dressed up for the
occasion.
ERIC: I kept the AC going in the Uber, but of
course I've got to cover my Olive Garden shift.
BRIAN: I'd like to thank my attorney, Eric Bauza,
for coming tonight to play with us.
SAM: Have a good night, everyone. Check us out on
Tuesday for Talks Machina; we'll be talking about
the game and stuff. Congrats again to
CholieAmenthys for winning the thing, and-- what
do I say now?
MARY: Yay, you say yay, Sam.
SAM: And now, is it Thursday yet? Goodnight,
everyone.
[music]