[electronic music]
MUSIC: I run and hide.
MALE VO: How do you want to do this?
MUSIC: You’re inside. Yeah, you can always
save me. Run and hide. Yeah, you can
always find me.
MALE VO: How do you want to do this?
MUSIC: You my boomerang, boomerang, boomerang!
Yeah, you my boomerang, boomerang.
MALE VO: How do you want to do this?
MUSIC: You my boomerang, boomerang, boomerang.
Yeah, you my boomerang, boomerang.
Doesn't really matter how strong you are today
MALE VO: Smelling like an adventurer isn’t easy.
MARISHA: You can certainly try.
MALE VO: CR. The new perfume from Critical Role.
You cannot buy this, it’s not a real product.
MUSIC: You my boomerang, boomerang.
You’re really real, don’t you never ever go.
Yeah, you’ll never ever know.