MATT: Oh, hi. I didn't see you there. I'm hanging
out this afternoon, apparently reading some
fantastic books, and excited to hang out with a
lot of you fun, interesting elements on the
internet. But I figure, let's go ahead and make it
comfortable. Let's enjoy ourselves a little bit of
personal time together and get to know a little
bit about each other. I've got some fine port here
to keep me company, like you do on a Tuesday
afternoon at 4:00pm. I poured a lot in there, so
this is what's called not being the designated
driver.
Anyway, I'm glad you could join me. We're going to
have a good time, hopefully. This is going to be a
general hang out, get to know each other type
circumstance. As far as the types of questions,
the quality of questions, they can be game
related, they can be Critical Role related, they
can be role-playing game related, they can be
voice-over industry related, they can be just life
related. They can be stuff about my history, or
telling me about your history. Just opening
conversations about that. I want this to be an
open hangout, a whatever you're curious about, and
then I might ask some curious things back. So
yeah, this is just a hangout.
Thank you for the robe recommendation. This is the
finest quality I could find for $20 on Amazon. And
it met my expectations. It is every bit as shitty
as I expected. But anyway, welcome! We'll get a
ways into this Q&amp;A, and then maybe we'll start
creating an NPC and a monster for the campaign a
little ways down the road. So cheers! Oh, that is
nice! That is sweet! Anyway, glad you could join
us. This will be interesting. Let's begin with
some fun questions here, if I can remember how to
get the pad here open. Possibly? Maybe? We'll find
out. If I learn technology, if you've seen the
Periscopes, you know that me and technology
strangely do not mix very well. But that's okay.
First question I see in there is, "Where's
Larkin?" That's a better question for Liam
O'Brien. Larkin resides in the same location that
Raishan does, which is, as far as everyone knows,
very deceased. By the way, for the record, if
you're not caught up on Critical Role, I'm going to
try and avoid spoilers, but something may squeeze
through, and I apologize in advance.
"Did I fix the yard?" Fix is a relative term. I
got the yard mowed, and then the remnants of the
mowing could fill eight or nine of our green bins.
So we've been slowly off-loading it week after
week, and our yard in the meantime looks like a
series of hills. It's terrifying. But we are
getting it taken care of, hopefully.
Let's see what questions we've got here. It is a
Founders Reserve Porto. Sandeman! It looks like it
has Darkman on the cover. I know people say Zorro.
I'm going to go Darkman because that's the person
I am. If you haven't seen Darkman, it's awesome.
The first one. Don't see the rest of them. Leslie
Nielsen, actually. The first thing I really knew
him from.
We'll get to the first question at the top.
"What's your favorite trope in D&amp;D, or just in
"general? What was your favorite storyline besides
the Chroma Conclave?" This is from Nikosia. Good
question. Favorite trope in D&amp;D? Those are fantasy
tropes in general, and I personally really like
political intrigue. The fight-the-monsters is fun,
but I like the idea of trying to balance that with
nations that are warring or crumbling. There
hasn't been a lot of that in this campaign because
I can't fit every theme and every trope in every
campaign. But I wouldn't be surprised if those
elements show up in campaigns down the road.
Personally, I really enjoy challenges that involve
more finesse besides just bursting into doors and
defeating creatures. So that's a big fan of mine.
As far as previous campaigns that I really
enjoyed? I ran the expedition at Castle Ravenloft,
and that was an absolute blast. I adored that
campaign as I ran it. So that one has a special
place in my heart. And had some political
intrigue, which was fun.
What's another fun question? "What's my favorite
class in D&amp;D?" by Lairohi, which I'm probably
butchering that. My apologies. Seriously, I'm
really sorry about that. I've always loved
casters; caster classes were a big thing for me
growing up. I love the options of spellcasting and
the utility factor for a party. You may not be the
most powerful or the most survivable, except the
later levels get powerful. It is nice to be able
to take care of some of those challenges. The rest
of the party is like, "I don't know what to do!
We're kind of fucked!" And you're like, "Wait, I
"got a spell for that!" You're essentially the Clippy
paperclip of D&amp;D, and I love that! That was a lot
of fun.
That chatroom is moving really fast! We're
cultivating questions from the chat, so don't
worry. Even if it goes past, we're keeping an
eye out. "Has the Raishan trophy mount arrived
"yet?" It has arrived. We haven't opened it yet.
We're planning another Critmas. Scheduling has
been a pain in the butt, between completing the
campaign guide, general work, and multiple
projects at once, and everyone else's busy
schedules, organizing another day to do a Critmas
has been very arduous endeavor. But we're zeroing
down on it soon. We will have that soon, and then
we'll have all of them, and we might actually be
adding them to the set over here pretty soon as
one. Once again, you guys are amazing! Thank you
again.
"How surprised was I when Liam killed everyone
mid-last week?" from CritterNation3000. (laughs)
Definitely surprised! I wasn't expecting him to
just throw out, you know, the Abyss against a
bunch of level one us-es that early in. I had an
inkling he was going to do one of those you wake
up and you're still okay in another realm or
you're out of your sleep circumstance, but the
party was like it would also be fitting if he
literally brought me in to be a player for the
first time in a long time in his game and he
fucking throws a demogorgon at me and kills me in
one hit. And that's it, and thanks Matt for
playing! Because as much as that sucks on one
degree, that shit would be funny! That would be
so funny.
I'm going to adjust this real fast because it's
turning off rather quickly on me. If I can find
it. Because I don't know where it's all organized!
Where is the settings on this son of a--! There it
is! I see it. Pardon me, internet. I appreciate
your patience. We're going to head down to the
Control Center. General, display, auto-lock in 15
minutes. That'll work fine. Thank you. Pardon me
for the slight delay there, friends. I appreciate
your patience. If I could pull it up to where I
was. There we go. Thank you. I'm going to have
another sip of port because it's that kind of day.
Glad you can come and join me. "Matt, did you know
that is not a real fireplace behind you?" from
PSkinner.
[off-screen] (laughter) It's a TV!
MATT: I knew that. But I appreciate you looking
out. And it's really sweet of you. And even if I
didn't know, and this was my actual home, and I
totally believed it was a fireplace, would you
want to be the one person to tell me that it
wasn't? Do you want to be that guy that, out of
the sake of the necessity to be right, you would
tear down the illusion I built around me? Because
you are that guy. Think about that. Goddamn
that's good! Good call, Ryan! Ryan Green chose the
drink of choice, and did a fine job.
Good question! Thamgoule-- I'm going to butcher
all these names, sorry-- asks, "What do I think of
"the new mystic class?" I've had a tumultuous
relationship with psionics for a large portion of
their D&amp;D existence. I like the idea of
psychic-based classes, but the psychic points
system always felt like it didn't fit in the rest
of the theme of D&amp;D from previous editions. I
looked at the new mystic class, and it's got a lot
of really cool options. I'm uncertain of it. It
seems like a lot of everything in one class. It
definitely has a few options that are extremely
overpowered, which is why it's in test and why the
Unearthed Arcana is a really good place to try
these things out and give feedback, and they can
tweak it down the road. I feel like it does feel a
bit trying to accomplish everything at once. So
I'd like to see it maybe be a little more fine
tuned into a theme that stood out amongst the
classes, which is hard because the classes-- as a
person who's designed and tried to design unique
things in the game, a lot of bases are already
covered. So you really got to stick to a unique
style, or try your best to, at the very least. I
like the idea of the mystics. I'm not sold on them
yet. I'm curious to see after testing if they ever
release an official document with a final design,
and to see how that turns out. I'd like to take a
look at it as we go and give some feedback of my
own. Maybe I will, Wizards of the Coast. Moving on!
A question from Alesia Shaeffer. "When starting
the campaign, how much did you start with? What
"level did everyone start at?" Everyone started at
level three at the time. I could have gone earlier
level, but I thought it was just a one-shot. And I
wanted it to be enough of a character ability
spread that they had at least a number of options
at their disposal. So it was a level three
one-shot. The characters were originally built in
4th edition for that one-shot because it was the
most button-push, I tell you the three abilities
you have and how often you can use them and then
we play the game. And that's how it came together.
Once it became a campaign, then we converted over
to Pathfinder. We were already at level three, and
it was fine. And it went from there. If you're new
to D&amp;D, I highly recommend starting at level one
for at least a few games because it's enough where
you can learn the rules without feeling overloaded
with options, especially if you're playing a
caster. Once you've played a game or two where you
feel more comfortable, starting a campaign around
level two, or halfway through two, which is what
I'm doing for the next campaign, I think is good
because it doesn't feel like you're having to
trudge through that very first level if you know
the game pretty well and have enough experience.
But also you're not locked into your archetypes
for your class, so based on the choices and
experiences you have in the first few sessions,
that can really inform the direction you want the
character to take. So by the time you level up to
level three, you've had a few games under your
belt, and you can make an informed decision on the
type of variation of that class you want to
pursue. So that's my opinion.
Got some more questions. "What is my favorite
tabletop RPG system?" from Thermavoire.
Thermavoire, that's fun. It sounds like Theramore,
which didn't do so well in the lore of Warcraft, so
I'm glad you changed the pronunciation. I'm
partial to D&amp;D just because it means so much to me
as far as the genre. I'm a big high fantasy
person. It's the first game I ever played. It's
the game that I play most often now. The newer
editions have gotten a lot better about weaving
narrative into actual gameplay. But I don't know.
I really dug the Palladium system. I'm kidding;
that's not true. The Palladium system's
ridiculous. I like the themes of some of the
games, like the ridiculousness of Rifts, but when
you start getting into 1d4 times one million
mega-damage weapons, it gets a little intense.
I like them all for different reasons.
Unique-wise, I really enjoyed the Amber Diceless
roleplaying game. For those who haven't read the
Amber series. It's actually a pretty cool series
of books, and it's an RPG that the system is based
more upon the GM logistically considering what
succeeds versus what fails based on character
creation and ingenuity and how you present the
challenge and your answer to it. I thought that
was a pretty cool way of doing it, though the
randomization of the dice makes things
interesting, too, so I like that. The Traveler
system was fun! The Traveler system is great. One
of the few games you can die in character
creation, liked that in Paranoia. That was a good
one. I'm probably going to have to stick with 5th
edition right now. I think it's a nice blend of
enough rules and numbers and interesting character
options that you can still create and customize a
character, but still be an easy flow from
narrative to combat. It's not perfect. No system
is really perfect, from my standpoint, at least.
But it's closest to the kind of system that I
would want to play. I actually like that a lot.
From Zemedelfos-- which sounds like something you'd
fight in Xenogears. Question! "What do you
"recommend when you have players that it's hard to
get all together, but have no good reason for the
"character to suddenly pop in and out between
sessions? Not many of them are big into jaegering
"another person's character." That's actually a
very good question; I've had this challenge many
times. There are a couple ways you could do it. If
your party is not terribly locked into having to
keep a very realistic narrative, and you can
introduce somewhat silly suspension-of-disbelief
moments in the game, you can introduce elements
like the heroes, as part of this venture, were all
cursed or locked to a specific artifact and at
randomized times it will fold or steal the players
into an alternate reality. And so when the players
can't be there, all of a sudden the orb claims
them and they're not there, and they have to wait
for them to return. Also, having ventures where
the planes can be unstable, and occasionally
individuals fade from one realm to the other
without given warning. And that can be part of the
overall narrative: to stop these planes from
crossing. And thus, different party members can
vanish and come back, and it doesn't really affect
the narrative flow because you've already
established a reason of that being the case. So
you can run it more narrative-level like that, you
can make it like I do where you try and come up
with a creative reason for them to leave. If
you're in the middle of a circumstance, you can
have them kidnapped by a monster, and now part of
the adventure is also trying to save them. It's
the eternal challenge. It's not an easy answer for
it. It's easier if you're playing more of a
tongue-in-cheek game and you all can lean into it
a bit, and there could even be, in the same realm,
like a curse that befit the party and on certain
phases of the moon, you might turn into cardboard.
And players have to fold you and put you in the
bag of holding until you're ready to come out
again in your full form. Those silly ways make it
a lot easier and you can have fun with it that
way. But when you need a narrative, you can try to
find an overarching reason as to why they have to
jump in and out occasionally. It's not easy! I
don't have a great answer for it, but that's the
best I can give you, because that's all I've done
in the past.
Question from PhantomsRuinLives, "Any tips on
dealing with audition nerves waiting to hear back
"on an audition?" Yes! Audition nerves never go
away. And I know you're like, "Oh god!" I mean,
they'll dwindle over time, but those butterflies
never go away. In fact, you learn to harness them,
you learn to use that nervous energy as a positive
thing. Part of that only comes with experience.
Another is coming to terms with the fact that
you're not there to prove that you're right for
the job. They're just seeking whoever is right for
the job, and if it happens to be you, it's you. If
it's not, it's not. So the pressure isn't to be
better than other people. It's to be the best you
can be for yourself. And if you're right for that
particular role that you auditioned for, then
they'll probably book you. And if not, somebody
else was better for it, it doesn't mean they're
better than you, but they were a better fit for
that one character. And trying to keep that
mindset over time. It's not a you versus them
mentality. You're doing your very best, and if you
don't get it, it's not because you're bad,
necessarily. It's because you weren't right for
that particular job. And as a casting director,
you're not just casting people. You're weaving a
tapestry. Where you're reading for one character,
they have a view of the entire cast, all the
characters and archetypes and story elements that
have to weave together. So they might audition you
and other people that sound amazing for the roles,
but you might sound too similar. And so as an
ensemble, it doesn't work to have you both in
these roles that are so close together. So they
might cast somebody else for that. That doesn't
mean that you weren't great for the job, but for
the sake of casting the project as a whole, they
had to go with something else. But they'll still
keep you in mind for stuff down the road. That's
another thing, too. Even if you don't book
something, if you knock it out of the park in the
audition, people will keep you in mind. I can't
tell you how many projects that I've read for and
didn't book anything, and then a year and a half,
two years later, they call me in to read on
something or book me on something because they're
like, "Loved your read for that! Wasn't right for
the character, but something else came up down the
"road that we liked you for. And we wanted to have
you read on that now, too." So it can help you
regardless. Don't be too hard on yourself for not
booking a gig. The auditioning process is part of
the learning and the experience.
Also, I recommend don't wait to hear back on an
audition. A really healthy mindset when it comes
to that process, whether it be voiceover,
on-camera, everything, is to do your best. You're
doing the job in the room. You're doing the best
you can, and then once it's done, let it go and
move on to the next endeavor. Focus on the next
opportunity. Focus on the next class you can take.
Focus on the next character you can explore. And
let that audition go. It may take some time to
learn that type of behavior, but you really have
to release it. That way, if it doesn't happen,
you've already forgotten about it and you're
already focusing on bigger and better things. If
it does happen, that's a fantastic surprise! So
that's my recommendation in that regard, too. This
is delicious. I will try my best not to get
extremely intoxicated. I do not promise anything.
FickedUp asks, "Have I ever LARPed?" I have not
field character costume LARPed yet. I haven't
because I haven't had time or because I'm scared
I'll like it too much. I have a lot of friends
that do it, and it's consumed them. It's become
their biggest hobby. They put all this time and
energy into costumes and stuff, and I know I would
do that. And I just have too much stuff going on.
I have LARPed Vampire once. I was pulled into a
LARP. It was up in Simi Valley in the early
2000's, and it was this huge chapter of a bunch of
theater kids from a theater magnet school that I
met through community theater, and they invited me
to come be part of this. I had no backstory on it,
and I was thrust into a very political figure that
was introduced by the prince of that whole area as
his new right-hand man. So I became this political
intrigue focus for the evening with no
backstory, no idea of how the political dynamics
worked. And I was thrown to the wolves, if you
will. And there were wolves there. Werewolves,
anyway. So it wasn't the best experience. It was
unique, it was different. But I was out of my
element there and got spooked off a bit from that.
I still had a good time, but if I had another
chance I know what to ask for, as far as research
and background to actually fit in. I think it's
awesome! I did run a show for a while called
Adventure, a stage show that my friend, Coleman,
ran. Marisha was part of it, and Bonnie Gordon,
who you've seen here a ton, she was part of it.
Xander came and played a number of times. Our
fantastic Taliesin was in it with us. Courtney,
our fantastic Alpha mistress over there, she came
and was part of it many times. It was a live
roleplay stage show where we pulled members from
the audience as PCs, and we'd pull them through a
storyline where we were the NPCs, changing
costumes behind the scenes and going from sequence
to sequence. It was a lot of fun. I guess that's
the closest thing I've done to LARPing. But once
again, always NPCs, always the DM. It's fine.
Let's start our first poll. Let's start getting
some of our fun character design stuff going here.
Let's begin with the NPC on this one. How it's
going to work is I'm going to start asking for
some suggestions from the chat and keeping an eye
out when I ask for a certain thing. And then I'll
pick a few, we'll throw them into a straw poll.
That straw poll will be up for about a minute,
minute and a half. So you'll rush in when the
link's available in the chat, vote, and then when
that time is up, we'll call it, and that's what
we're going with for that aspect of the NPC. First
and foremost, let's pick a race for the NPC. Type
into the chat here what race you think it should
be. We're talking if it's human, halfling,
tiefling, half-orc, goliath, anything you want,
just type them in there. I'm going to pay
attention for a second to see what seems to be
popping up more often than not. Oh, that's a lot!
I can see forever! Seeing a lot of half-orc; we'll
put half-orc on there. That'll be one of them.
We're passing by a lot of human, and a lot of
drow. That'll be interesting, too. Hmm, you guys
haven't seen much drow in Tal'Dorei. Hmm. They're
there, which you'll see in the campaign guide. And
dragonborn. So that's four, and we'll do one more.
A lot of genasi. Going some unique classes there,
and a little human thrown in just for some
averageness. I believe that is drow, half-orc,
genasi, human, and dragonborn. Cool! So we're
going to go ahead and get that situated for you
guys here in a moment. We'll have the voting start
for that race, we'll have about two minutes, and
then we'll come back with an answer, and that will
set in the race for the NPC. It's fun, communal
construction. I haven't done it like this. This
will be fun. Once that straw poll is done, the
link will be in the chat, and vote. In the
meantime, I'm going answer another question.
George Fletcher asks, "What is your favorite kind
of cheese?" See, I like these questions. I like
these strange, non-game-related-ones peppered
through. Interesting, weird tidbits of things
you've ever wondered about why I'm such a weird
person. Because I'm a very weird person. Favorite
type of cheese? I really like smoked goudas. I've
actually recently gotten really a fan of extra
aged gouda. It has a slight caramel-ish, almost
crunchy crystals in it. That with some pita chips,
and some wine is good. Or some honey. What would I
pair with my current drink? I have no idea! I'm
not a wine and cheese snob. I know so little. I'm
really good at trying to-- actually, no. I'm
really bad at trying to fake like I'm a cultured
person, because I don't know. Have you seen my
dragon socks, okay? I am not at all a cultured
person. For this, honestly, probably s'mores. This
is a very sweet port. So I'd go more of a smores.
It's not cheese, but deal with it! That's my
answer. Anyway. Next question.
From Galastan, question, "Hey, Matt, thanks for
being my lifelong inspiration. I'm planning to
"break into the VO industry and currently taking
voice acting lessons. Is there anything else you
"recommend doing to get an edge in an admittedly
cut-throat industry?" That's an interesting
question. Cold reading training. I've said it
before and I'll say it again. Training in classic
forms of acting and performance is so important.
Being comfortable and experienced enough to where
you can jump into a scene and make confident
choices, not worrying if they're the right choices,
but whatever feels natural. That's the thing, too.
A lot of people get caught up in their head about,
"Am I making the right decisions? Am I making the
right impulses? Am I feeling this out correctly?"
As long as you're making some choice, you're
doing it right because you're going with your
instincts and it's taking you there. And if it's
not the right direction, the director, who it's
their job, will guide you back on track. But they
much prefer to have somebody who's bold in their
choices and commits to the path they take as
opposed to somebody who's unable to decide which
path they want to go with a character choice. So
that's big. But for voice over in particular, read
out loud, whatever. Don't even look at it! Get a
script, or get a book, throw it in front of you,
and start reading out loud as you read it for the
first time, because that's most of the job. You
want to take scripts and learn to cold read. Most
of the job is cold reading. Rarely do you get a
script in advance for a project, and most of the
time, you walk into the booth, and you're around
sound proofing, by yourself, with a glass window
and a director, and multiple other people in the
room looking at you through it going, "Okay, go."
And you have to go! That's the job. Cold reading,
learning to be comfortable to read things
spontaneously as you receive them out loud. Listen
back; record yourself doing it and listen and you
can self-critique and work on your annunciation.
Work on understanding the flow of dialogue. Don't
be afraid to take beats. A lot of people,
especially when they begin, they read everything
through. But characters breathe, they have
thoughts mid-sentence, they stammer. So another
thing, too, is breathing life into a scene as a
character. Consider what action they're taking
during it. If you read a scene where a person's in
a kitchen, you read the dialogue as, "Well, yeah,
of course. But if we're going to go on a vacation,
"least we can do is try and bring the family." Or,
think about them doing the dishes a minute, like,
"Well, of course. (grunts). I mean, if we're going
to go on vacation, we might as well bring the
"family." Suddenly, even though it's just audio,
you imagine that person doing a physical activity.
You immediately envision a part of the kitchen
that wasn't there before. Think of the character,
think of beats, moments, exerts, things that can
breathe life into their physicality, even though
you're just reading their voice out loud. Those
are good things to keep in mind as you're learning
a scene or playing out a character. And if it's
not the right choice, the director, once again,
will correct you. But rather have you make
choices than not.
Do we have an answer on the straw poll? Drow by
60%?! Oh, man! We might be getting some story on
the Ruhn-Shak soon. You don't know what that is.
You will in August. The NPC race is drow; we have
a drow NPC. We are off to the races! Okay, so now
that we have a drow NPC, think of the occupation
that drow has. That can be a character class or it
can be a position, like a politician, or a guild
master, or an artisan, or a cutthroat, or a
mastermind or whatever you think an occupation for
this NPC would be good for. Spy is a good one.
Okay, we'll look at this for a second, we'll see
what comes through. I see a lot of warlock; we'll
put warlock on there. I see a lot of baker!
There's a lot of bakers in there! It's a big
spread. Warlock, baker. I see a lot of prince;
they want some royalty, some sort of royal or
noble blood involved in there. That'll be
interesting. You guys are ridiculous. Bounty
hunter's come up quite a bit. That's a fun one.
Okay, I'm going to go for a last one here. Oh my
god, it's like looking into the Matrix! It's
(whoosh). There's a lot of prostitute, which is
rad, because sex trade's an awesome, legitimate
form of business for a lot of good people. So
prostitute's in there. So what is the listing we
have? Warlock, baker, royalty, bounty hunter,
prostitute. We're going to go ahead and get that
straw poll going here in a minute. Take a minute
or two to vote, and we'll see where this takes us.
This should be very unique.
Okay, then. So back to the next question here.
Arthur Dent asks, "Question: How do you set
"magical item prices?" This is a good question.
There is, in the DMG, in the magical item treasure
section early into it, there is a table that gives
you the general price range for items by rarity.
So you go from common, uncommon, rare, very rare,
and legendary. And it gives you 500 gold to 5,000
gold, 5,000 gold to 50,000 gold. Yeah, it doesn't
really help a lot. So it comes with understanding
power levels in the game. If it's a very rare
item, but it's a pretty damn powerful very rare
item, I'm like, "Damn, that's a good very rare
item with a lot of abilities!" I'll probably set
that a little higher up. It's a 5,000 to 50,000
and that's a really powerful item, I'll set it at
40 to 45,000 gold. And if they want to persuade
whoever's selling it down a little bit, maybe. If
it's an uncommon, which is pretty low, I think
it's 50 to 500, and it's pretty easy and minimal,
like a tanglefoot bag, I'll probably set it about
50, 60 gold tops. Nothing too big. A lot of it is
improvising it based on the range that's in the
GM's guide and the power level how I understand
it. Doesn't mean that it's right or wrong, but as
a GM, you get to set those based on your
experience. It's okay if you mess it up a little
from what you consider; the players won't know any
better. It's your world; you set the prices. I
recommend you writing them down. Prices can change
from person to person. Prices aren't the same
everywhere. An item might be really common in one
town, and really uncommon in another across the
continent. So the prices might be jacked up in
those various places. It's a combination of
improvising based on what I can ascertain of the
item's power level, along with the range they give
in the DMG. I hope that's helpful.
Question from Niche asks, "Are you surprised by
what some of what Vox Machina has decided to do in
"this past year?" Yes, actually, and I'm excited.
We actually got together last night and went
through what everyone wanted to accomplish, did
some rolls. It was a throwback to our early days
playing at home, in some ways. It wasn't a full
session, but for things they wanted to accomplish,
there were rolls to see if the challenge succeeded
or not. And what we're going to do is begin the
session on Thursday going through those lists,
discussing what happened, and possibly playing out
a few scenes that involve what they're hoping to
accomplish. So that's going to be what Thursday
begins with. It's going to be fun. It's going to
be interesting; there's some interesting choices.
Grog has one thing in particular that the players
don't know about that's going to be real
interesting. Grog's such a terrible person. Okay,
are we about good to close that straw poll?
Baker?! Drow baker! We have a drow baker. That's
going to be awesome. I am excited about this.
BuiltTooFast says, "Is bloodhunter being added
into your campaign?" There was a bloodhunter NPC
and the bloodhunter orders are part of the
Exandria lore. They mostly stem from Wildemount.
But yes, there is, called the Claret orders,
within Exandria. They haven't come within
Tal'Dorei. They haven't come prominently into the
story. I don't know if they will. We'll see how
that plays out. But they are part of Tal'Dorei.
So, next question, and then we'll get back to the
next bit for the NPC. SirRays, "Question about
"life. You always try to be positive and
down-to-earth. How do you do it?" (laughs) I don't
always succeed. I don't know. That's interesting;
it's a weird question. I don't know, just be
empathic. Be willing to make mistakes and own up
to them. Learn from them, and no matter how much a
person frustrates you, makes you angry or tries to
hurt you, maintain a point of perspective that you
don't understand what they've gone through to get
them there; what their day was leading them to
that moment. What abuses they've undergone, what
difficulties, challenges, and failures they're
ruminating on at that time, and you've become an
outlet for it.
That's not always the case. There are bad people
in the world, by all means, and I do understand
that. But I think a lot of dissidence stems from
people's inability to imagine what the other side
of this might be. So allowing yourself that
expansion, to be able to give people the benefit
of the doubt and think, "I know what they said is
really terrible, but maybe they're having a really
terrible day, week, month. Maybe they lost a
friend or family member, and they're just lashing
out." You don't know. That perspective makes it a
lot easier to not take things to heart and step
away. And that opens empathy for others.
And that even goes for everyday encounters. When
you stop at a gas station to order gas, make eye
contact with the attendant and ask them how their
day's been. It's amazing how quickly you'll see
people open up and smile when you engage them as a
human being and not as just part of a transaction.
I recommend you try that on a day-to-day basis. It
makes every day that much more lively. It makes
you really appreciate how so many different
backgrounds, how many different people who all
have their own story, their own trials and
tribulations, and they all come together to make
this beautiful world that we all live in. So good
days and bad days. We're all human beings and
we're all trying to be happy. Keep that in mind.
That helps; it's helped me so far.
We're now getting to the next aspect of the NPC's
design here. So they are a drow baker, according
to chat's design. What is their interest in Vox
Machina? Which, if there are any members of Vox
Machina on the sound stage, they should be
leaving right now because we're getting
into narrative elements.
TALIESIN: Bye!
MATT: Taliesin Jaffe!
TALIESIN: Bye. I'm going now. You have pretty
eyes.
MATT: You have pretty eyes. He does have really
pretty eyes. He has really pretty eyes.
(clicks tongue) That got weird...or did it?
The baker's interest in Vox Machina. All right,
well, Grog has been put in a bunch. So there's
an interest in Grog. I can expand upon that if
that should win. So we have Grog as one option.
People here are throwing out wedding. So I'll put
that in there. Vengeance. Vengeance is always a
fun one, and a nice change up from the previous
suggestions you've given. This is a lot here. I
know this is a rough process, guys. We're all
figuring this out as we go, but we're trying the
best we can.
We're getting a lot of repeating ones that
we've already said. Okay, fanboy I've seen
come up quite a few times. We'll go with that. And
the last one will be: bring Tary home. That's
interesting. We got-- what was it again? Grog,
wedding, vengeance, fanboy, bring Tary home. Those
are the five choices. We're going to throw those
up in the chat on the straw poll. Take a minute or
two to get your votes in. We'll see which one of
those comes out on top. This is a very interesting
process. (evil laugh) People saying mic is low? I
don't know if that's the case, or it was just
their screen. But if it's just your computer, too
bad! Turn up your volume!
Next question, "Pineapples on pizza? Yea or nay?"
Eh. I made a third option. I've had it, and it's
all right. Not my preference. I wouldn't go out of
my way to order pineapples on pizza. But if
pineapples show up on pizza, it's the only pizza
there, I'm not going to be like, "I will not eat
you!" I'll go, "All right," and I'll eat it. I'm
in between. Not meant to be a cop out. Literally,
that is my answer. I hope that was helpful? That
was from KidCross, by the way. Thank you, Kid.
RossReynolds asks, "How do you balance your major
part in Critical Role and your career as a voice
actor?" I'm still figuring it out! Oh, thank you,
Ryan.
RYAN: Your popcorn, sir.
MATT: "Wondrous! Oh, look at this delivery system.
It's glorious." The robe made me Gilmore suddenly.
I don't know why. I'm going to have some more of
that port! This isn't a bad way to spend a Tuesday
afternoon with you guys. Thanks for chilling with
me. This is good.
"How do I balance Critical Role with being a voice
actor?" I don't know yet. I'm still working on it.
When you live a career for long enough that could
end tomorrow, and you don't know where you're next
paycheck is coming from, and it's a passion, you
end up doing odd jobs to make rent. Doing temp
work, doing data entry, environmental agencies, or
stocking warehouses. You learn to say yes to
everything. It's the idea that whenever
opportunity arises, you seize it. I feel very
fortunate that, in recent years, because of all
the hard work and because of shows like Critical
Role that have had a lot of more opportunities
arise. I probably said yes to a lot of things I
shouldn't have. And in doing so, it's consumed
most of my free time and it's driving me a little
crazy. But I'm learning that balance. Both me and
Marisha are each other's support in both of our
lives getting a little crazy and trying to make
sure we allow time for self-care and spending time
together and carving out time for the people that
are closest to us. Part of the reason Critical
Role is so important to us, it isn't just the
show, but honestly, it's a chance every week for
us to get to hang out with some of our favorite
people that we don't have the time to most of the
other days of the week. Or month. So it's still
something I'm working on. I have a lot of projects
on my plate right now. Finishing the campaign
guide's going to be a big weight off my chest.
We're in the final throes of it right now. I'm
really excited for you; I hope you guys like it.
But I'm learning that process now. I'm notoriously
work myself to death. I tend to take on too much
and try to get it done, and it's not the
healthiest thing, so I'm working on it. So my
answer is, "I don't know." I'm still trying. I'll
let you know in a year if I figure out the secret.
Otherwise, I don't know.
PertLikeTheFruit asks, "Is there some type of NPC
in particular you've been itching to introduce,
but the moment never presented itself?" Yeah,
there's a few NPCs that I've created that never
had a chance to show up. But I'm not going to tell
you because any NPC that doesn't get a chance--
and any DM or GM will tell you this-- an NPC that
you like that doesn't have the opportunity to
shine or show up goes back in the toolbox for
later. So they'll come back eventually, I'm sure.
They'll come back. They'll come back. Trust me.
TorchBaricane asks, "What's my favorite type of
cookie?" That would be gingersnap. Gingersnaps are
awesome because they're not loaded down with too
much sweetness, but it's got the right amount of
cinnamon spice. I like things that are sweet and
spicy. So gingersnaps are pretty great. Yeah, I'll
go with that.
Let's go with the next NPC choice, since we got
that locked in now. We did a couple questions
there. This is so delightfully chaotic! I
apologize, but thank you for sticking with me on
this. What is the answer? Bring Tary home. Oh,
man. This is going to be fun. Cool! Got that in
there. And the second to last thing I'm going to
ask about this NPC is they have a secret. There's
something that this NPC is keeping a secret that
may or may not unfold in the game. We don't know,
but you'll know. And I'll know. But what is this
NPC's secret? Go ahead and introduce into the chat
room what your ideas are. Keep them concise, if
you can. We'll get that worked out. So put it into
the chat room and we'll pull some out as they go.
(laughs) Okay.
They're a drow! That's not a very good secret.
They're not keeping it very well, unless they're
an illusion. I mean, it's possible. Hmm.
Hmm. There's a lot of interesting here.
Let's try-- Okay, he's a Revenant.
That's an interesting one. I'm trying to pick
things that might work into the next campaign. I
don't want to pick anything that's going to wreck
it, or the storyline that I have worked out in my
head. So I'm having to cherry-pick a little bit
for this one. Secretly a paladin. That's
interesting; can play with that. Put ziggurat
on there. Just ziggurat.
He's a hitman.
Oh, man! This is so nuts! Oh, that's interesting.
He's blind. There we go. Some interesting ones
there. Some fun little things that can be
utilized. Some of these secrets you guys put on
there might roll into other things that were
already mentioned. We'll see how that plays out.
So reading us back, what do we have? Revenant,
secretly a paladin, ziggurat-- what was the other
ones? Hitman. Or he's blind. Okay, so we're going
to throw that up into the chat in a moment, to get
that straw poll going, and we'll see which one of
those wins out to be the NPC's secret. That'll be
interesting. Blind is not exactly a secret, you
say. However, with the right magic, you can keep it
a secret. I have ideas. Don't worry, I can play
with this.
JayRedWine says, "How'd you get into Burning Man?"
About 2008 or so, I was in a bit of a rough patch.
Losing my faith in humanity and the arts in a lot
of ways. I was in a rough period. Self-esteem,
personal stuff. And my acting coach at the time,
who, hilariously, is Taliesin's mom, Kether, she
had been going for many years. She said, "You
would enjoy this, and you should go. This would be
a good thing for you." And I was like, "I don't
know. I'm not into the whole hippie drug culture."
I had my thoughts of what the event was. She's
like, "It's not like that. I mean, it is like
that in some ways, but not really." "All right,
fine, I'll go." I made a lot of excuses. She
didn't let me adhere to them. Eventually, went,
and it was a lot more than I expected. It's
certainly not for everybody. It's a harsh
environment. It's a very open culture of all walks
of life: culture, sexualities, expressions. A lot
of people there just walk nude. A lot of art,
hippie-dippie stuff that a lot of people probably
couldn't even deal with or would hate entirely.
But for me, it was a wonderful environment of
adults at play for a week, and I really enjoyed
it. It became a very important part of my life. So
I go every year. It's my cleansing, my reset
button, my creative need to return to the default
world. I've met a few Critters out there who are
Burners, as well. They've come by. Operator is a
nice guy. If you're watching, Hello, Operator!
Hopefully see you this year. But it's definitely
not for everybody. It's hard to get there, it's
hard to survive out there, it's a harsh desert
made of high-alkali playa powder. Electronics die
out there. It's hot. You have to bring everything
in to survive, and then bring it out. But if
you're ready to make the journey there, and if you
have that artistic mindset, it can be a really
cool experience.
Anyway, do we have an answer on that straw poll?
Ziggurat. Okay, then. I think we have a pretty
solid background on this NPC and where they can
come into play. I'm excited about this prospect.
The last thing we need is a name. You guys throw
out some cool names. I'll pick out things that
reach me and we'll vote on which one we want the
NPC name to be. So go ahead and throw your
suggestions in the chatroom for the name of this
drow baker. (laugh) No! Nope! Nope! I know you
guys want to be funny and cute. I want to try to
make this also work within the story where it can
be taken seriously, because certain names will not
be taken seriously if they're introduced in this
game. And Troy is definitely one of them. We'll
start with Ruberick. That's interesting. Miklos.
M-I-K-L-O-S. Oh, man. There's a good one that
passed by too fast. Zal...oh, man, it went by too
fast! Curse you, chat, for being active! No, you
guys are doing great. Let's do K'ryyn.
K-apostrophe-R-Y-Y-N. Noxtra. N-O-X-T-R-A. Is that
four? That's five? All right! So we'll go ahead
and throw those into the straw poll. And you guys
go ahead and jump in there and vote on the name.
Then from those names, we'll pick those, and from
there, we'll have an NPC pretty much completed
that you guys helped create that will be
introduced probably in this next arc of the game.
So that'll be interesting. I'm excited to see what
comes out of this one. (laugh) With that, I'm
going to go have another sip of my drink. "RIP
Troy." It's cute. It was a really funny idea,
guys. But in the interest of wanting to keep the
narrative realistic, and because Troy's good
friends with a lot of us, that would have made it
a little weird.
Question from ActionGordon. "Bees. Yes or no? If
yes, how many?" Bees, yes! How many? Seven. I
think bees are awesome. Bees are great. They're
necessary. We have a lot of bees in our backyard.
They're cute. They land on me sometimes. People
get freaked out by bees. That's fine. I mean honey
bees. Fuck hornets! And yellow jackets. I hate
them. But bees are cool.
Question from Leddle526, "Have you ever had a
moment where you almost gave up being a DM
entirely?" Giving up DM entirely? Giving up on a
campaign, almost. Actually, the start of the
campaign I did before this one with my buddy, Zach
Hanks, we were both co-DMing this one. And we had
a number of friends in there: Louie, our buddy
Brian, who looked like a dwarf and played a
dwarf, and Chloe Dykstra. Some of you may know
from some of her stuff. She played Saga, the
rogue. And then, Marisha came in, eventually, to
be an assassin.
But in that campaign, the first couple sessions we
had a guy and his wife playing with us who made
twins. He was a paladin and I think she was a
cleric. And our first two sessions, he got really
drunk very quickly and became unruly. He became
belligerent and was interrupting everybody else,
making sexual jokes in the middle of other
people's turns, and turned it into a him show. And
it was not very respectful. He's a nice guy, but
once he got drunk, it was a problem. So after two
games of that happening. And the final one, we
were in the middle of a boss battle sequence, a
very serious moment, and he was yelling and making
stupid jokes and fart noises and talking about how
he was going to attack with his dick, and it
wasn't even his turn. We're like, "Buddy, calm
down." I could see his wife was embarrassed by it,
and I was like, "It's all right." Finally, during
somebody else's turn, he jumped up and shouted
something obscene; I can't even remember. Knocked
his beer over all over the battle map and smeared
all of the crowd. So I said, "The wall begins to
collapse of the ceiling and unfortunately, a
portion of the cavern was in your direction as
both of your characters are crushed as you
escape." And I killed off their characters. I
apologized to her after, but I was like, "I don't
think this is going to fit." And she is like, "I
understand. No worries." So he stopped playing in
the campaign. He felt bad about it, but it was for
the best. He's a great guy now. His name's Andrew.
He's a really nice fellow. But our styles of
gameplay didn't quite match, and that's fine.
That's the thing, too. There's so many different
ways to play D&amp;D. Even Critical Role-- actually I
want to talk about this a little bit. People keep
saying, "Critical Role, it's the best example
there is for D&amp;D." It's not! It's really not. It's
an example of D&amp;D. It's a way to play the
game. It's a way that we play because we're
actors and as actors, we're naturally more focused
on narrative and characterization and the drama of
the element there. Our version of D&amp;D plays more
to the story than it does the rules, per se, as
you can see some of the players haven't locked in
all the rules sometimes. But it's because we're
more focused on other aspects of the game. And
that's fine. We still have a good time. We're an
example of how it can play. There are elements of
our game that you might like and take into your
home campaign, and there are a lot of people that
watch it that, if they were to play in it, would
probably not enjoy it at all. And there are a lot
of people--trust me, I've seen comments! I've been
tweeted! People saying like, "Your game looks like
shit! I would never enjoy it!" And I'm like:
You're probably right! And there are games out
there that people play that I probably wouldn't
enjoy, either. But that's what's cool about it.
There's so many different ways to play it. There's
so many different ways you can run it for the
players and all the styles are enjoyable for
players that are looking for that type of
experience. So yeah, that's an example of-- Andrew
would be great at a table, like a Harmon-town
type, ridiculous, drunkard debauchery table. He'd
do great there. For those of who are paying a
little more respect to the narrative and the
intensity of a sequence, didn't quite match up
very well. And you both respectfully talk and go,
"Guys, this isn't going to work out." And that's
fine. So keep that in mind.
Also, for all you guys who are new to D&amp;D, don't
expect a Critical Role experience at your table.
Partially because, once again, we're professional
actors and we've been playing this for a long time
before we started the stream. When we first
started playing our first few games, it was
nothing like this. It was a lot of fumbling, and
"What do I do?" They were all just learning how to
play. And some games are a little more rules
heavy. The gamers and the DM are more involved in
the actual game aspect of it, and that's rad! I've
had a lot of sessions like that before; they've
been a lot of fun, too. But you want to make sure
you establish those boundaries and adjust your
expectations. Every game table is going to be
different. Every experience you have at the table
is going to be different from what you've seen in
my, or the Roleplay Guys, or Acquisitions, Inc.,
or High Rollers, or any other great show. All of
them are different and unique because that's how
every table experience is playing D&amp;D. That's part
of what makes it so special. So I ask you guys,
don't get angry if your first or second D&amp;D game
isn't like Critical Role because it can't be. Nor
could our game ever be like yours. They're wholly
unique in their own right. So abandon expectation,
which, by the way, is a great term, a great guide
for life, in general. Abandon expectation. Try and
move forward and do your best. And that goes for
your D&amp;D game, as well. So I recommend that.
Anyway, do we have a name? Answer on this one?
K-apostrophe-R-Y-Y-N. So K'ryyn, the drow baker.
K'ryyn, the drow baker whose interest is involving
bringing Tary home, and they have a secret that
involves a ziggurat of some kind. (evil laugh)
Good to know.
StarryBright brings up a question, "What do I
think about the McElroy boys and the show,
Adventure Zone?" They're phenomenal! It's a great
show. If you haven't had a chance to see it, the
podcast, The Adventure Zone, it's great! They run
a D&amp;D game there. I would say it's a less serious
tone than Critical Role, but they have serious
moments, as well. They have a lot of dramatic
moments. It's a podcast form. It's a lot less
rules heavy than ours, which ours is not as rules
heavy as some other games. So like I said, it's a
spectrum. But The Adventure Zone's great. The
McElroys are fantastic. Travis is fantastic. We've
talked a bit online and I'm a big fan of what they
do. So if you haven't had the opportunity, check
it out. I recommend it. They're fantastic. And
they also do a great job of representing the
importance of community and support others in the
community. They're generally rad people. So highly
recommend you check it out, too.
Let's pick another question here. I'd be curious
to see some non-D&amp;D related, non-voice over. I
want to make this part of a conversation of just
random shit, also, because I answer a lot of
questions on panels and stuff. So if you have any
burning questions about silly things or life
things, we can get real. I'm all for that. If you
want to make this almost a hearken back to the
honesty hours days of the early Twitch stream, I'm
totally fine with that. So be okay with going into
that regard.
"Did you talk with any of the Critical Role guests
about how they spent the year time skip?" from
ScottyKnows. Yes, I did. We actually met last
night for about four or five hours going over all
that. So that'll be coming up soon. So look
forward to that.
Oh, wow, it's all exploding! I saw someone ask,
"Triss or Yennefer?" I was a Triss girl until
Witcher 3, and then I began to lean Yennefer a
little bit. But I went back to Triss. I'm a Triss
person through and through now, I think. I mean,
I'm marrying a redhead, so I feel like I'm a
little biased. Yennefer was a love that was built
by magical force that eventually blossomed into an
actual attraction if you play it right. Triss, I
felt, was a genuine attraction that came
naturally. So that, to me, was something very
important. So I think I'm a Triss guy, to answer
that. I once said Yennefer, but that's changed
since then. As some things do.
HughMillerC asks, "How do you want to do this?"
With alcohol. CalRanig asks, "Can we see more
dwarves? Love their accent." I'd love that. I love
the brogue. It's my favorite. The Scots style is
one of my favorite ones to do. I enjoy it
thoroughly across the spectrum of even soft Scots,
which is more of the casual conversational type. I
love that. It's got a nice almost poetic lilt to
it. I love speaking in it, I love hearing it. I
love it; it's my favorite way of doing it. Usually
when you think about dwarf, you think more classic
video game style and World of Warcraft. "Aye, well
bring me to the orcs!" But for me, the softer Scot
is more nice, too. The more refined and more
conversational type. I love it! So I would like to
do that more, but only if dwarves work in the
story. And they are a threat in many
circumstances.
"Favorite animated movie?" I saw that go by real
fast. Aw, man! Does Who Framed Roger Rabbit count?
It's half-animated. I'm going to say it works
because it's one of my favorite movies of all
time. And not only is it a technical achievement
and a narrative achievement, but such an amazing
cast. One of the last big projects that Mel Blanc
got to work on and actually do his Warner Brothers
characters. It's a perfect film in so many ways. I
love Who Framed Roger Rabbit, and it should, and
will, never get remade because it's one of those
films that only worked in that era and could never
be made again. So that's definitely it.
Someone asked about having another person become a
permanent member of Vox Machina or the campaign.
I'm going to say no to that. I mean, seven players
is already a lot. When Ashley's not here, even six
is a lot, so I think we're good. We're solid with
this number. Six to seven players is good, and
that gives us enough room to occasionally have a
guest, but I feel like stretching the attention a
bit. And I do want to have guests on occasionally,
to add their narrative and to mix it up a little
bit, but I don't think we're going to bring
another permanent member on, in my opinion. It's a
lot to concentrate on, and I'm already stretched
thin as it is. Thank you for understanding.
Have I ever been charged with a crime? No. I've
been interrogated by police. This is a funny
story. Back in high school, I was walking to my
friend Todd Hunt's house to go play Rifts. I had
my Rifts character, my binder, my dice and
everything in a bag. He lived not that far from my
girlfriend of the time, Mira. I would, on the way,
walking to his house, I was going to stop by and
say hi, but she wasn't home apparently. I walked
up, rang the doorbell, nobody there. I looked at
the window to see if anybody was home. Went up and
looked at her bedroom window. Wasn't home, so I
continued walking over to my friend Todd's place.
About five, ten minutes later, a bunch of cop cars
pulled up because apparently the cops were really
bored in Agoura Hills. They stopped me and they
were like, hey, so what's going on? What are you
wandering in this neighborhood for? I'm like, I'm
just going to visit my girlfriend, but she wasn't
home, so I'm going to go to my friend Todd. Oh,
really? What's in the bag? I'm like, my Lord Magus
OC, why? So I hand them my character binder and my
dice.
Apparently, I guess, they got a call that there
was a prowler with a bag of tools lurking around
the house. One of the paranoid neighbors. But I
had the experience of them interrogating me over
my character sheet and asking if there were any
drugs on my dice, and like, smelling and licking
them. I was like, come on, guys. Really? Okay,
we're good? We good? He's like, yeah, okay. Go
ahead. Thank you! I grab my bag and I start
walking on to my friend Todd's house. He's like, I
thought you were visiting the girlfriend? It's up
the road, right? I'm like, well, I mean, no one
was home, so-- I'm a terrible, I get nervous
anyway, so he's like, huh. Well, if that's true,
I'll drive you. I'll drive you to go see your
girlfriend. I'm like, uh! And I got really freaked
out because my girlfriend's mom hated me at the
time, because I wasn't a doctor or from the Middle
East. She was Lebanese. So I was like, oh god, the
last thing I want is to have the police show up at
the door with me and her mom's there. It would be
terrible. Thankfully, she wasn't, and the cop
didn't really do it, and everything was fine, but
that was my really nervous run-in with the police
with my Rifts game character. There you go. Little
story for you to take home. Ah, boy.
Question. Am I going to Dragoncon this year? No,
and I don't know if I'll ever be to Dragoncon
again because unfortunately it happens at the same
time as Burning Man every year. I went back in
2004 and 2005, where I cosplayed as Dan Hibiki and
Mugatu from the first Zoolander, because that's
what you do when you're at Dragoncon. Had a great
time, but since Burning Man becomes a little more
of a creative and spiritual retreat for me every
year, that takes precedence. So I don't know if
we'll ever get back unless they change the
weekend. But it's a lot of fun! I have a lot of
friends that go, so have a good time.
What's our little question? Nebuchadnezzar asks,
"What's the story behind each of your bracelets?"
This is interesting. I know people, I've seen
people make fun of the fact that I wear these
leather bracelets, and it's a fashion statement,
and it seems so douchey and rockstar-like to wear
and fair play. This was the first one I got, right
here. This was a magnet-based bracelet and I
received this actually at my first Burning Man.
This, to me, represents personal responsibility
and knowing where I come from. I come from a
bloodline of alcoholics. My father also dealt with
drug addiction. He was a musician in the 70s and
80s, he went to Narcotics Anonymous for a while--
I'm opening up here. Wonderful man, I love him to
death. He was, and is, such a wonderful person.
But he dealt with addiction issues, and so,
knowing I was predisposed to all of this, I
avoided alcohol. I avoided anything. I didn't even
have my first drink until I was 23. I was so
scared that I was predisposed. As I began to know
myself better as a person in my life, I decided, I
felt that I wasn't possibly held by the same
demons that my family before me did.
So I tried alcohol and was like, okay, yeah, this
might be socially a thing, but it's not for me.
And so I'd occasionally have a drink socially, but
it wasn't a big thing. I felt that was a big thing
for me. Then, my first Burning Man, being
surrounded by drug culture and having a lot of my
judgments on various experiences that I had
friends who had and talked about, and I was like,
eh, no no no-- that was my time to actually face
those demons as well. And so I had a number of
experiences at the burn that year with friends, in
a safe environment, where I could try different
things, safe things. But so I could speak with
these, from a basis of understanding, safe
hallucinogens and things like that in a very nice
environment. The end of that week, I realized that
I really firmly understood that I was not bound by
the same demons of addiction that my father did,
and my grandfather before him. I met a random
person on my last day that week and we met at the
edge of the trash fence, far out into the desert.
We talked for two hours and I told him all about
this history, and they gave me this bracelet as a
reminder that I overcame my family's demons, and
as a reminder of the responsibility that I have to
make sure that I stay true to myself and try and
help others to not befall those same traps. So
that was where I got my first bracelet, and I wear
it all the time.
The second one I got because Marisha made it for
me on our first anniversary. She bought the
leather, she dyed it herself, she punched it and
if you see, in there a little bit, you can see
coordinates that she pushed into the leather.
These coordinates are the coordinates on the earth
where we had our first kiss. This was a beach on
PCH, under the moonlight, because we've got to be
cheesy and romantic and shit. But she gave that to
me as a reminder of that night, and so this
bracelet, to me, is a reminder of her. And so I
keep that with me at all times.
This one was given to me by my best friend,
Brittany Walloch, who I've known for over ten
years. She's been a dear friend, confidante, and
helped me get through a lot of hard times and been
there for me. I know, it's fucking cheesy, but you
asked, guys. Sorry. So this, to me, represents the
friends and the people that I have to support me
and help me through the hard times, and are
understanding when I get busy or get sad, and so
this one represents friendship to me.
This one here was a gift from a Critter, during
one of the Critmases. Little Tree of Life on
there, if you get a chance to see. This was
important to me because this represents you guys,
this represents the community. Represents everyone
who has come along with us on these adventures,
the Critical Role, and how you changed my life in
so many wonderful ways. So this, I wear this all
the time because it reminds me of you guys and
what we're doing in all this crazy silliness. So
now you have the story behind my wrist bands.
Probably the deepest explanation of them I've
given to date. I may have said too much about
myself, but whatever, that's what this afternoon's
about. There you go.
All right. The question, how did you and Marisha
meet? I'll try to make this a lot quicker than the
last story. Me and Marisha met through a mutual
friend, Becky Young, who was an actress friend of
mine. She played Samus in my web series I did back
in 2008-2009, called There Will Be Brawl. If you
haven't seen it, it's silly live-action film noir
crime drama of the Smash Bros universe. She was
doing improv and in one of her improv classes,
Marisha had just started doing improv. So they
became close friends and began doing scene work
and sketches together. Then Becky was going to
create a geeky sketch group for the internet. She
called in a bunch of her friends to be writers and
actors on it. She called me in, Matt Key, and a
few friends that she met through Brawl, then
brought Marisha over from her improv.
So we met at that first writing meeting and we
both immediately crushed on each other, but we
were both in other relationships and like, "Nice
to meet you!" That was, you know, we became loose
friends. Met at a couple social events over the
next year or so, but we, you know, we were this
distant, aw, if only, but alas. Then about a year
after that, we reconnected after not seeing each
other for a while. I'll get to the tattoo in a
minute. I had gone in for a mo-cap audition and
they wanted to know if I knew any females who had
dance experience, martial arts experience. I was
like, Marisha does! So I got her an audition there
and she called me to say thank you. Can I pay you
back with a drink some time? I'd love to! We never
actually had a chance to hang out one-on-one
before! So we went and got a drink and talked,
four and a half hours, and we clicked. It was an
electric dinner. Everything was perfect. I was
like, oh my god, this is amazing. I had been out
of my last relationship for about nine, ten months
at this time, and spent a period of time being
single. Tried the dating thing and it was weird,
didn't like it, and I was spending a lot of time
being solitary. She was on the outskirts of a
long-term relationship that had been dead in the
water for about six months, according to her. So
we went our own ways. About a week later she
called me and was like, hey, I just broke up with
my boyfriend. Do you want to get a drink? I need
to talk to somebody. I'm like, sure. So we went
out and got drinks again. From there, we began to
hang out more, and it eventually turned into a
romance and the rest is history. Now we're getting
married in October, which is crazy.
Anyway. Tattoo. So this is my first tattoo, right
there. This represents the art car of our Burning
Man camp, the Sensitron 5000. It's a triangular
metallic platform built on a truck bed that has a
large LED umbrella that comes off the top of it.
It's hard to describe. If you do a search for
"Sensitron 5000 Burning Man" you might see a
picture of it. There's these big colored silks
that hang off of it. But anyway, this tattoo is a
geometric drawing of the art car and it's a little
reminder of that little part of Burning Man home
and a place where me and Marisha have had many
great times together with a good camp family out
there. So that's what the tattoo means.
Now let's start getting onto the creature. Let's
do some fun stuff here. So for the creature, for
the encounter. Who has more shoes, me or Marisha?
Marisha. I own like two pairs of shoes. And
they're both busted. Actually one's a little
better, I replaced it not too long ago. But I'm
not a clothing shoe person. These are the fanciest
socks I own. Okay, so. For the monster encounter,
for the first bit here I want to ask: this
creature, what size do we want this creature to
be? I'll throw the ones out, you guys don't have
to put things in there because it's a limited
course here. I'll go with tiny, because what would
be greater than a really powerful, super tiny boss
fight? Medium, large, gargantuan, and small. So
tiny, small, medium, large, and gargantuan? I
think that's all. No, huge. I missed huge. So
we'll do tiny, medium, large, huge, and
gargantuan. I don't think we need to worry about
small because if we're going to go tiny, go tiny,
right? So those are the five. Tiny, medium, large,
huge, gargantuan. We'll throw that in the straw
poll and we'll see where that one ends up soon.
Now getting back to the questions here. Martyr85
asks, "When you get a rare chance to play, is
there a personality trait you have that you
purposely try to avoid while roleplaying?" I try
to avoid the Batman persona. Kind of like, "I'm
dark and broody, and I know everything and I'm
badass. And whenever anything story or emotional
happens, I don't care." I don't want to play
Drizzt Do'Urden, basically. I've played with so
many players over the years that all fall into
that archetype. Don't get me wrong, I love Drizzt
as a character, but that set up a precedent in the
late '90s and early 2000s that most guy gamers I
gamed with tended to lean in that Bruce Willis,
action-movie-star-type persona. That got a little
ridiculous for a while. So I try and make things a
little more kooky. I do try and make my characters
after the rest of the party has, so I can fill in
the gap. I'm a support player, I guess, in that
regard. So I'll wait for everyone else to choose
what they want and I'll see what's missing, and
then I'll go ahead and create something to fill
that space. That's generally how I do it. And I
recommend you do it too! It might force you into
some uncomfortable territory, you might end up
playing a class that you normally wouldn't have
chosen, but realize, that was actually pretty fun.
And a lot cooler than I thought it would be. You
can learn a lot that way, just saying.
Whatever happened to the aasimar kids? We'll find
out. Still in Whitestone, from what you guys know.
Which, by the way, there's a lot of NPCs. Lot of
NPCs in this world. I can't show them all, all the
time. When they become relevant they'll arrive, or
if the party searches for them, they'll be there,
maybe. But there's a lot of characters that I put
in this world as I realized over time and it's
getting a little nuts. So sorry if one of your
favorites hasn't showed up in a while. It's a big
world. Vox Machina can only cover so much ground
at any given point in time. Sorry.
Actually, do we have an answer on that one?
[offscreen] Tiny. Almost 99 percent.
Almost 99 percent tiny?! I love you guys so much.
I'm so excited for an extremely powerful, tiny
beast. I'm so excited for this. Oh my god. Oh, I
was hoping you were going to say that. Okay, so.
Tiny creature. Now, type. Creature type. I'm going
to have you guys throw some in the chat room.
These include undead, monstrous, beast,
aberration, construct, any of the classic Monster
Manual creature types. Start throwing them into
chat and I'll start pulling out the ones that seem
to get more votes as we go.
Yeah, fiends is one. Pixies, fey. We'll throw fey
on there, fey seems to have gotten a few votes.
Aberration's getting a bunch of votes as well.
Construct's getting a lot of votes. So we've got
fey, aberration, construct. Oh man, a lot of that.
Celestial, I'm seeing celestial a lot in there.
And we'll say... elemental. There we go. Those are
some five interesting choices. Those are the ones
I've seen the most, at least. So there we go. We
have fey, we have construct, we have elemental, we
have aberration, and-- what was the last one?
Celestial. There we go. So we'll get that straw
poll going and we'll figure out what that is here
in a moment. I'm going to go ahead and pour a
little port in here. Oh, look at that fine fire.
That totally real fire. It's real, don't judge me.
I have not had a drink on a Tuesday this early. At
least not a while, that wasn't a margarita. Okay.
So IAmVirus asks, "Skyrim or Witcher 3?" Witcher
3. I love me some Elder Scrolls, I've played them
all since Arena. But Witcher 3 all the way, I'm
sayin'. Deslog asks: "Question. Wine, whiskey, or
vodka?" I would have said vodka years ago, but
I've come to enjoy whiskey more in recent years.
That happens when your girlfriend's from Kentucky.
She brings bourbon into your life. But even then,
I'm not a heavy drinker so it'll be like one
drink, it'd probably be whiskey. Probably mixed
with something. I'm a girly drinker, I want sweet
shit. I can enjoy a nice straight, harsh liquor as
a sipping drink, but give me a mojito. Give me a
margarita. Give me something nice and fruity and
sweet. I'll deal with the headache, it'll be fine.
ZZZ195 asks, "How do you deal with rejection?" Oh
man. Not well at first. I remember when I was in
seventh grade--because I got rejected a lot--I had
a very interesting upbringing. Or at least a very
interesting childhood. I had a lot of asking girls
out whenever I got the courage, and them saying
"yes" on the spot and the next day going,
"Actually, no." And that sucked. I had a P.E.
teacher named Mr. Pickett who-- I just wouldn't
get up and run the mile in seventh grade after a
girl turned me down. A girl named-- I think it was
Jamie, in choir. Chorus. And he was like, "Is it a
girl?" I'm like, "Yeah." He goes, "It's okay, man.
Women are fickle." Which is a douchey thing to say
now in hindsight, but at the time it helped.
Pulled me out of my funk. And he gave me a
dude-to-dude girl talk and I was like, "Oh, I feel
better." Rejection sucks, no matter what happens.
But you have to remember, rejection is not because
you are a lesser person. Much like an audition,
you just weren't the right person. Don't take a
rejection, if it's from an individual you're
asking out, as an offense or that they don't want
to have anything to do with you. Sometimes it's
just, "You're not what I'm looking for. I don't
know you well enough." And some great friendships
I've seen come out of rejection from multiple
sides. But there is a habit I've seen, and a lot
of this "nice guy" syndrome happen online where
it's like, "I will be a friend to a girl and the
minute that I begin to ask her out and she says
'No,' then I'm like 'fuck her!'" and it's an
unhealthy behavior. Because you're missing
opportunities for great friendship, and two, she
just wasn't into that aspect, at least not now.
Give her time to get to know you better or let it
blossom into a friendship and focus on somebody
else who might be more your style. As far as
career rejection-- keep focused on the next
venture. The more you obsess and concentrate on
any sort of rejection or falling out of a
prospective path, it's hard, but if you focus on
the next endeavor and try and be like, "Okay, that
didn't work out. What can I focus on now?" That
not only takes your mind off of it, but it already
gets you in a better direction, focusing on what's
right and what could be the next venture.
Yeah. I had a lot of interesting experiences as a
kid. Actually I want to bring this up real fast,
because I feel like it's important. I want to
apologize legitimately to anybody who felt
uncomfortable in the story of the last Taryon
episode and the reveal there. And I apologize if
that hit too close to home, if that was not the
representation of your story that you wanted seen,
and I understand that it made a lot of people feel
uncomfortable and I'm sorry, I'm legitimately
sorry. I put a post about it on Twitter, but text
is easy to be misconstrued and you only have so
much brainspace to put out there. And I'm sure
I've been torn apart on the internet, that's fine.
I admit that. However, I do want to say that I
think it's an important story to tell from what we
understand of it. And when I say "what we
understand of it," y'know, we all come from
different backgrounds and-- this is going to be a
little real here for a second. We have our
experiences to pull from when it comes to story.
We as actors, we write and we only create from
experience. And Exandria is very much an open
environment for the most part. Sexuality is an
open thing in society. There are couples of all
walks of life: asexual, trans, nonbinary, gay, bi,
everything, and it's all open in the world. Is the
world free of ignorance? No. That's part of life,
and part of the story because people are flawed,
people are stupid. It's minimized in my world
because I like to imagine a world where it is
largely minimized, but it's not something that's
not going to exist. And what little bit of Tary's
story we've touched on, a lot of it improvised by
Sam on the spot, and a lot we've talked about
since then, and we developed a little bit
beforehand to an extent, I think is an important
story to tell. And parts of it resonate. I've had
people concerned that we were making fun of his
awakening, or his coming to terms with his venture
in the last episode, and I can honestly say that
if it came across that way, I'm sorry. That is not
the case. We are very, very sensitive to these
things and many of us have lived very close to, or
dealt with homophobia on our end as well. I grew
up a very androgynous, long-haired pretty boy who
was quiet. And god knows I spent a number of years
of my youth being called "faggot" and being pushed
around, and I have a lot of very, very important
people in my life who have dealt with far worse
and have undergone a lot of terrible
circumstances. And I feel for that a lot.
My Uncle Ted, for instance. One of the most
impactful people in my life, probably, at a young
age. He was my dad's brother. He introduced me to
musical theater, he introduced me to Andrew Lloyd
Webber's Phantom of the Opera. We used to play
piano and sing songs around the piano and stuff,
and he's such a wonderful person. And as a kid I
loved him, he was my favorite relative on that
side of the family. He also dealt with the
difficulty of being married and having a child
with his wife and then one day coming to terms
with the fact that he was gay. And it sundered a
lot of that part of the family at the time, and it
was very hard to be in parts of the family that
didn't understand that. And even as a kid I knew
what was wrong, and what felt wrong, and what was
being said. And you know, and then getting-- and
then I had to watch him waste away over the years
because he caught HIV and then AIDS at a time when
it was very prominent in the late '80s and early 90s.
And then, you know, through the '90s, in a lot of
ways was very hard for people of alternative
sexualities because we didn't have communities. We
didn't have the internet, we didn't have tumblr,
we didn't have Facebook. There weren't places you
could go to feel safe if your lifestyle was
expected to be not the norm or not accepted. So I
had a lot of friends and a lot of close people
that had to just suffer inside and had nowhere to
talk, and occasionally meet somebody or find
somebody who was comfortable enough to be out and
proud. And then permission was given, but even
that was met with a lot of difficulty. I'm glad we
live in a world now, by comparison, where things
are much more respected. And it's still a fight.
God, it's still a fight. There's still so much to
be done and it's still so much bullshit and so
much disrespect and lack of empathy for people who
just want to be happy. And that bothers me on a
deep level and feel it really hard.
But I know that parts of Tary's tale may not be
the representation that some people hoped for in
media. But I've tried my best to represent other,
happier lives and things where that was an open
and viable circumstance. Tary's is important for
people that grew up like maybe a lot of my friends
did, and didn't have that open, welcoming
scenario. And I can't believe I'm doing this on
the internet.
Anyway, I'm sorry. I'm doing the best I can. And
not all stories are going to be for everybody. I
can't please everybody with all the choices we
make. And I mess up and I fail and I stumble. And
even if a few people get offended, I can't help
but feel bad because I hate hurting people. But I
promise I'm doing my best. That's all. You know,
when I said Tary's experience, his scenario at the
end of the last episode with Trish, reminded me of
a lot of friends growing up, you know. Every
person has a point in life where they struggle
with their own identity, and I had that too. I
identify as heterosexual but I've had my years
of curiosity, I've had my years of trying to
figure out what it was, who I was. And yeah, I
myself am primarily attracted to women but there
are men that I've also found attractive in life,
mostly about the person, the individual. And
sometimes it takes an experience like what Tary
had to finally feel confident in that. And not in
a judgmental way. His was a little more comical
because it's Sam, and we want to play up the
discomfort of a sequence sometimes with humor to
offset it, but we try and treat it with respect
because a lot of it plays to elements of our own
lives or people that are close to us. And so
Tary's journey is in some ways still a personal
one for myself and other people in some ways. So
just, you know. We're trying.
Anyway. Wow, that happened. Let's go to the next
monster thing. (laughing) Jesus Christ. (sighs) So
tiny. What type of monster we doing, yo?
Celestial. Tiny celestial encounter. That's going
to be-- oh, I'm good, no pizza, thank you. I got
popcorn and port, yo. And a fireplace. What more
could you want?
Ability score focus. What is this tiny celestial
really good at? We're going to make this a six
choice. A six choice straw poll here. So we're
going to go ability scores, of course strength,
dexterity, constitution, intelligence, wisdom,
charisma. The classics. I want to know what this
tiny celestial is really damn good at. What is it
really good at? So we're going to put that in
there, have you guys vote and we'll see just how
nasty this thing can be. So pay attention to the
chat, we'll have that up there in a moment. We're
going to go ahead and do some more questions. And
I'll keep it together going forward. (laughs)
Talisar: question, "How excited are you for the
new Bill Nye show?" I actually watched a few
episodes of it. I'm conflicted. I love Bill Nye,
and I grew up loving Bill Nye and I'm a firm
believer in everything he has to say. I think in
some ways we're entering this weird era that is
undermining intellectualism and fact and it's
really frustrating. And I think he's been a great
beacon for that in public spheres.
The tone of his show is a little strange because I
feel like it's a little preaching to the choir so
far. I feel like it would be a better message to
try and have the show presented in a way that is
speaking to the other side and explaining why it's
important to listen to what the facts or what the
science is. The show so far, from what I've seen,
comes across a little preachy and a little
condescending to those who many not believe, and I
don't think that necessarily befits his argument
in the best way. It's still a great show, and I'm
liking it so far, but that would be my one
critique on it is that it comes across a little
self-righteous in a way that might turn off the
people who really should be listening to it and
learning from it. Otherwise it turns into an echo
chamber. But I'm excited to check out the rest of
it and hope that that picks up a little bit and I
love everything he's done in the past. I think
it's important that we have more figures like that
that are both public figures, like Neil deGrasse
Tyson and Bill Nye, that are champions of science,
champions of reason, champions of fact and I'm
excited to see more of that type of content. I'll
see more of it.
I will say the new Mystery Science Theater is
fucking awesome. As a person who grew up watching
the original Comedy Central run when I was a kid
when I first moved out to California. I'm a Joel
guy. I love Mike, but Joel is my guy all the way
and I've watched every episode. I was so scared
for the reboot. So scared because it could have
gone wrong in so many ways. I legitimately teared
up multiple times watching the first episode of
the new Netflix show because it felt like the old
show to me. I was so excited, even the final
credits sequence. They even have a new version of
the old, sad orchestral version of the MST3K theme
and I was just tears and smiling. I tend to cry a
lot. I'm a sensitive boy if you haven't figured
that out by now.
Ability score focus, do we have an answer on that
yet? What is it? Charisma. This'll be interesting,
okay. Let's do three focuses here, this will be
combat-focus for the creature. So it's a tiny
celestial charisma-based entity. Do we want it to
be melee-focused? Not mee-lee. I'm trying to be
better about that. I grew up saying mee-lee and
it's an old habit hard to break. I know it's
melee. I'm trying, guys, I know it bothers a lot
of you. Melee, ranged-focused, or spell-focused.
Or you know what, environment-focused. So it might
get in the fray with people, it might attack them
from a distance, it might do a spell caster type,
or focused on using the environment to its
advantage. We'll throw those choices up in the
poll and we'll see what that one comes out to in a
moment.
An hour and a half goes fast, guys! Thanks for
chilling as long as you have and watch me be
ridiculous on camera with you for a while.
ScrubsFan06 asks a question, "What's your favorite
band?" Oh, that's a tough one. My father was a
musician, I was raised on The Beatles, Moody
Blues, Steely Dan, Al Parsons Project, so I come
from that background. Then I was also introduced
more to modern bands. I say modern, I was a kid of
the 90s like Stone Temple Pilots, Type O
Negative-- love Type O Negative, great
pseudo-almost-not-serious goth rock. It's
beautiful. But I think the musician that's
affected me the most would be Mike Patton and his
work on Mr. Bungle. Many other musical projects
that are fantastic: Fantomas, Tomahawk, Lovage,
some of his solo stuff, but his work on Mr. Bungle
is so avant-garde and strange and changed my
perspective on music and vocals. Gogol Bordello is
a great choice, too, Gogol Bordello is fantastic.
Mike Patton's work has been heavily inspiring in
so many ways. He's probably the closest I have as
far as a vocal match when it comes to music. So if
there's anybody I can sing along with in the car,
Mr. Bungle, I'm right there. I have a secret dream
that ever I end up with too much time on my hands
that I'll do a Mr. Bungle tribute band and do a
show once in the Roxie just for my friends. I want
to do that one day. Will it ever happen? I don't
know. Mike Patton's my boy.
Straw poll's up, guys, you got to vote! LolKeegan
says, "Matt, kind of stagnant in life with no
direction. Do you have any friends, or were you
yourself like that? How did you find your
direction and motivation or whatever?" Yeah, a
number of times. That's not an uncommon
experience. If anything, take solace in the fact
that all of us eventually find ourself there at
some point or another. Before I went to Burning
Man, I was in that place. Out of school, I was in
that place. Right before I met Marisha, to a
certain extent, I was in that place, too. Change
of scenery helps more than anything. Being stuck,
stagnant, and being in a place of comfort that is
affiliated with that stagnation, in my opinion,
can be a very stifling atmosphere without
realizing it. I recommend taking a drive by
yourself. Just drive. If you're near a coast, up
the coast and find a bit of beach to sit and think
for a few hours on your own. Bring some snacks,
bring some wine. Or go into the desert, or go into
the woods and commune with your surroundings. Go
to a place that's outside of what's normal and
comfortable to you. Both to force yourself out of
your comfort zone, but to put you in a space where
you can start thinking outside of the way you
normally do. I can't say that's a guaranteed
answer, but that can begin to help with forcing
you to think outside of the normal, "Woe is me, I
can't do anything, I can't change anything."
You've already changed one thing; you've changed
your scenery. You've already discovered a new
place that you can go to for solace. A place you
can bring a friend once you have these moments to
think to yourself. Maybe try a hobby you've always
wanted to and never gave yourself the gumption to
do it. You were always like, "I've always wanted
to try sculpting." Do it! Buy some clay. Look on
YouTube. There's so many great tutorials for
anything you could ever want to do, ever, period,
on the internet now! Buy some clay and start
sculpting in your house. Or go to a class if
there's one nearby that you can afford. Do some
life drawing. Something artistic, something
creative, something that spurs the brain outside
of the numbers and the mathematics. That may be
enough of a change of your normal way of thinking
that it might inspire different directions to
look. It might lead your right on the path or put
you in that direction. There's no guarantee,
there's no right answer to this, but that's
something that's worked for me and it's worked for
some people i know. At least, it might be a start.
Wish I had better answers for you, but I hope that
helps.
What's the answer on the straw poll? Environment!
Not going to lie, I was hoping you were going to
say that. That's going to be a fun, fucked up
battle. Okay! And last but not least, let's get a
name. Whatever cool first names come out of the
chat I'll start pulling them and we'll put them in
with a straw poll based off that. Don't be
offended if I don't pick yours. I'm going to grab
ones that seem interesting and throw them up
there. Look here for a second. You guys throw the
chaos at me. Let's do K-A-E-O-R-A. Let's do
B-A-L-K-A-N-U-S. Y-O-R-T. E-X-E-L-O-N. Ooh! I like
that one! Symphior. Symphony, but S-Y-M-P-H-I-O-R.
Going celestial here, folks. L-E-T-H apostrophe
E-S-S. Symphior, I think it was? Symphony,
S-Y-M-P-H-I-O-R. And we'll put that in. I hope
that's right. If it's not, that's what it is now!
We'll get that started and we'll start pouring
through some answers on that. We'll see what names
comes to! Congratulations. Oh man. I've already
got some ideas on this one. These might not appear
very soon in the arc, but they're going to be
worked into the arc. It'll be a surprise to you
guys as it will be for the players when they come
and we'll work this out. Should be fun.
We got about 20 minutes here, I want to get some
more questions. "What instrument would you play?"
from KosaWanKenobi. Funny, my father, a musician,
played many instruments. I got a lot of
instruments for Christmas over the years, messed
them for a day, lost interest, and gave them to my
little brother who then became the musician. He
plays trumpet, trombone, guitar, drums, piano,
everything. I'm bookended by extremely talented
musicians and all I do is sing. I'm a little
sheepish about instruments. I'm a decent drummer
in Rock Band. I hover in that Hard to Expert
level, or at least I was in my heyday. I've gotten
a little rusty since then, I'm sure. But if I
could play, like really play, I'd probably go--
any instrument? Violin. I love the violin. It's
such a beautiful instrument, such a beautiful
sound that can evoke so many rich emotions. You
can tell a story through just a note. I've had my
heart tugged on and smashed and uplifted by just a
single solo violin piece. It's a beautiful
instrument and it takes a lot of practice. Anyone
out there who plays violin, all the power to you,
all the love. I don't have the time. Maybe one
day. Maybe in my retirement I'll learn to play the
violin. But that's definitely my favorite
instrument of all.
KungFuPanzer asks, "How is this date going? Are we
going to see each other again? Does Marisha mind?"
I think it's a great-- probably going great until
I emotionally spilled all over you. That's when
you retract and go, "Okay! This guy's a bit much,
he's got some baggage." We'll be good friends, and
we'll probably hang out and get drinks and I'll
introduce you to Marisha. We'll all go out and
wander the CIA Bar of North Hollywood probably and
drink over a dead clown under a glass. That's a
real phrase about a real thing, you should look it
up! It's terrifying.
ButtAssBooty said, "Did you ever mow your lawn?" I
did. I said that earlier, but I wanted to say your
name out loud. So there you go. Congratulations.
Question: Do I like camping? from Asimilie. I love
camping! I love it so much. I don't get to go
anywhere near as often as I'd like. I think we're
trying to plan a Vox Machina group camping trip as
soon as we all get time because we all have wanted
to do that for a long time. Trying to find a
weekend that'll work. I love camping. I went a lot
with my family. We'd go up to Mount Whitney
through all the mountain ranges up through Big
Sur. Yeah, camping was great. My mom was
hilarious. She loved to camp, but she also loved
some amenities. She was the only person I knew who
would get up in the morning and heat up her
curling iron in the campfire to do her hair. While
camping. My mom, I love her to death. That's a
memory I will always hold dear in my heart.
Crouched down, dirty, heating up her curling iron.
That's awesome.
Interesting other questions. "What music are you
listening to at the moment?" from PwnagePanda. A
lot of CHVRCHES, as you've probably seen from the
shirt. Every single tiny trickle of Lorde that
comes out I obsess over and latch onto right now.
Good EDM, I enjoy as a good general creative
space. I say good EDM because there's a lot of
shitty EDM. I briefly fell in love with the
Chainsmokers then quickly fell out of love with
them after seeing interviews with the douchebros
that are them. Good EDM I really enjoy. Classic
Radiohead never dies. Paranoid Android era was
fantastic. Spotify's allowed me go back and listen
to a lot of old songs from my teen years that I
hadn't had access to in awhile, so that's pretty
rad. We got really heavily into CHVRCHES right
around the time me and Marisha got engaged, so
CHVRCHES has been our happy theme for a while, the
most recent album. That's a recurring theme with
us recently.
"Favorite sweet alcoholic beverage?" from
Aquajolt. If we're going dancing, and I don't want
to spend a lot of time drinking or spend a lot of
money on multiple drinks, I'll get a Long Island
Iced Tea because you just need one and it gets the
job done and you're ready to go dancing. If it's
more of a casual conversation, if we're all at a
small dive bar talking for hours, I'll probably
get a Kentucky Mule; some bourbon, ginger beer,
little bit of lime and sip on that for a while.
Those are probably my two current favorites.
Utility purposes different, definitely.
Question: Worst video game I've ever played by
Timmy32. Oh man. There are some bad games. But
they're known to be bad. I worked on some bad
games! I worked on a whole bunch of Shrek titles.
My job, before becoming a voice actor, I worked in
QA in game development side then worked into
producing in game development. I worked at a
company TDK Media Active for a number of years and
made Shrek licensed products that were terrible:
Shrek Party, Mario Party ripoff, but it was
Shrek-related. That was really bad. Oh man, there
were some really bad games. Fallout: Brotherhood
of Steel, the turn-based RTS tried to make. As a
Fallout fan who loved Fallout one and two broke my
heart because it was not a good game. For me,
having a broken game is terrible, but having a
broken game with a great license is even more
painful. That really kills me.
HoundRider9000's question: "Ever consider short
hair?" Yes, I don't look good with it, I don't
think so, not for me. Long hair's been my thing
for most of my life, long-ish. I've gone through
stages. You've seen it shorter sometimes on the
show. Yeah, I cut it a little shorter and it
eventually grows out. I just don't look good with
short hair. I feel cold and naked and alone if
it's too short, I don't like it. So my hair will
probably be some degree of long-ish or at least
ragged, I guess.
Zenez8 says, "Favorite voice line and what one
bugs Marisha the most?" Favorite voice line? It is
a gift, it is an absolute blessing that I have
been given a catchphrase in McCree. I'm going to
have it with me the rest of my days. As much as
people might be like, "Oh my god, he's so annoyed
to have to say, 'It's high noon' all the time,"
it's like, no, that's fantastic. I'm always happy
to say it if someone's very respectful about it
and not be like, "Hey, Matt, what time is it?" I'd
be like: all right, dude, relax. That's wonderful,
that's a catchphrase. Very few people get that. So
I love it. I'm really excited that I have that.
That would probably be the most iconic quote that
I have, character line. Bothers Marisha the most?
Any of the MacCready post-romance wakeup lines
from Fallout 4. We'll wake up in the morning,
sun's coming through our blinds in the bedroom and
she's starting to wake up and I'll lean over and
be like (MacCready voice) So are you ready to face
the day? (normal voice) And she'll punch me.
Rightfully so. I'll give her shit about that every
now and then. (laughs)
Playgratchansee question is, "Any tips on how to
deal with players who fight over items and gold?"
Talk to them and say, "Guys, seriously, you need
to work this out. Otherwise, we're not going to
play. Be respectful and figure this out." If
there's still a problem, maybe have them encounter
some sort of extremely powerful archfey entity
that is true neutral and really feels everything
should be fair and has found interest in them and
follows them silently, invisibly. If at any point
they start fighting over loot, threatens them with
complete and utter destruction. So be fair and
place nice, otherwise the fey will destroy and
consume you. Find story reasons to fuck with them
and force them to play nice, too. (laughs) Cursed
items! Also a great deal! That really greedy guy
who keeps grabbing everything, throw him a couple
of cursed items and let him deal. "Oh, man, you
took that first, put it on! Oh no, you're
withering!" Good on you for that, chat, that's
another great suggestion. Communist fey. Yes,
exactly!
"Question: Star Wars or Star Trek and why?"
Interesting question. I grew up loving fantasy.
High fantasy's my jam. I should love Star Wars as
much as the next person. I enjoy Star Wars, and I
watch the trilogy a lot. But I wasn't into it as a
lot of kids I knew. I used to have all the toys,
the bedsheets, everything. But I was a Tolkien
kid. For me, it was either high fantasy or high
fantasy in space. To me, I leaned more high
fantasy. But I love the original trilogy and I
watched it a bunch as a kid, too. When I got into
Star Trek right around the Next Generation era
when that first came out, that was so radically
different than anything I had gotten into that I
immediately leaned towards that. So my very
"realistic" sci-fi Star Trek utopian society, the
future exploring the cosmos in a very colonizing
harmony-type way was so radically different than
any other sci-fi I had experienced outside of Asimov
and Arthur C. Clarke books I had grown up with
that I fell in love with that. I definitely
started more as a Star Trek person. I've come to
enjoy Star Wars more as the years go on, but I
think Star Trek had more of an impact on my youth.
I had Lord of the Rings as more of my fantasy and
Star Trek as more of my sci-fi. Star Wars is in
the middle, I adhered to the two extremes, if that
makes sense. Don't hate me on the internet! Too
late.
Phalanx66, "Question: new tattoo?" I do have some
new ideas. When the campaign guide is over and out
there, I'm going to talk with Marisha, I haven't
decided yet, but I'm thinking about getting the
outline of Tal'Dorei tattooed on my back. Just the
outline of the continent and with each campaign
guide, if they keep happening, I'll add more
continents until eventually I have all of Exandria
on my back as just outlines. It's an idea I've
had. An idea. Don't know if it's going to happen,
but you know, that was something that came up.
"Favorite action movie character?" Hudson Hawk. If
you don't know who that is, you should watch it.
It's ridiculous. (laughs) "Nerd!" I know, I know!
And I own it. I should. "Favorite doctor from
Doctor Who?" from FireKnight7. Oh, we've got ten
minutes left, thank you for the reminder. Favorite
doctor. I grew up on Baker, so he was my
introduction to the world. Doctor Who was
originally that weird British show that came on at
5:00am. When I'd couldn't sleep or woke up way too
early as a kid, I'd watch and be like, "I don't
know what's happening, but this is weird and
awesome." So that was my introduction to Doctor
Who was through Baker who was a great doctor. Love
his personality, his whimsy is great. It wasn't
until the reboot that it came back that I got back
into it and Tennant won me over then. It's a close
match between Baker and Tennant, but I think
Tennant just wins out because he ran the gamut,
especially towards the end of his run. The fury,
the warrior doctor elements coming through, his
sorrow, his loss. I can't watch his final walk to
the TARDIS after he takes irradiation right before
his regeneration without becoming a blubbering,
absence of non-sad emotion. I am an absolute mess.
Mark Humes, actually, from High Rollers, when I
was London years ago, I dragged him to the Doctor
Who museum because he hates Doctor Who. I was
like, "You're coming with you because you're my
host." He hated it the whole time. It was me and
him and a bunch of kids and it was amazing. They
had the actual TARDIS console of the Tennant-era
TARDIS and it was all busted up and I was like,
"Cool, this is the console!" And I hear this music
and I was like, "Where's the music coming from,
it's really sad? That's really familiar." I look
over and I'm like, "That's the song of the Ood!"
And they have a big screen that had Tennant
walking through the snow, slowly making his way to
the TARDIS and I start bawling. I watched the
whole sequence of them saying, "I don't want to
go!" Tears everywhere and I'm blubbering, heaving,
sobbing grown man in the middle of a Doctor Who
museum a bunch of kids who are confused and Mark
with his arms crossed going, "Fucking hell, mate."
It was amazing. I've dragged that guy through some
shit. (laughs)
I'm trying to get through some of these questions
because we have to close this up soon. "Favorite
non-RPG game?" by AcetaMichelle. That's hard.
Almost all the games I like are RPGs. Street
Fighter. Actually, not that hard at all. Street
Fighter. I grew up playing Street Fighter
hardcore. For a brief time, I did tournament
Street Fighter and I can still hold my own pretty
decently in Street Fighter. There was a time I was
super intense about it. I got really good, my
prime of my life was during the Alpha Three era.
Alpha Three is still, to this day, my game. I got
really, deeply into Street Fighter; not just the
competitive aspect, but the lore. There is Street
Fighter lore! It's confusing, contradicts itself a
lot, but I got really into it. I owned a lot of
Japanese-import art books about it that I could
only get in Little Tokyo or order online at the
time off Ebay. I did Kuma for Halloween one year,
I've done Dan Hibiki multiple times. I learned a
lot of the Japanese phrases. Most Japanese I
learned-- which is very little-- I learned from
fighting games, mostly Street Fighter. So if I
ever go to Japan, all I can really do is get into
fights. Not as useful, but that it is what it is.
Street Fighter guy all the way.
Let's get to some more of these questions at the
bottom. Oh man. GhostlyMuse, "Question for players
who want to have more variety, are there any
resources you'd recommend for learning accents?"
Yes! Watch the new episode of Signal Boost to have
Liam O'Brien boost exactly what I'm about to tell
you, but the IDEA: The International Dialects of
English Archive is a fantastic, free website that
has recordings of people from all over the world
in all different countries speaking in English,
reading a story that has all the phonetics and
vowels and all of the different ways you can say
and pronounce things as part of its construct, and
then they talk about themselves. But it's a great
resource for listening and learning dialects and
accents from all over the world, if you're good at
picking them up by ear. Otherwise, you might have
to study a little more and get involved in the
IPA, which is the International Phonetic Alphabet.
That's a little more of an investment and probably
more if you're going to go into acting. But the
IDEA is a great resource. Recommend it.
Zipknoll. Best dream you ever had. That I can say
on air? Best dream only because it was so vivid.
It wasn't a good dream. It was a nightmare. But it
was so vivid and it was so-- I wrote a short story
about it in high school and I don't know where it
went. But I had a dream that I was walking home
from school. This was in high school. And the
entire sky was a roiling gray, cloudy mass. It was
dark and ominous. It was shifting and moving.
Occasionally, you'd see a skull shape emerge out
of it or a giant, skeletal hand reach out of it
and then retract into the sky. And there was a
sense. Everyone understood that something very bad
was going to happen. So I went home with my
family, my mom, and I was like, "What's going on
outside?" And she goes, "Have you seen the news?"
And when you look at the news, and as I look over
the monitor, I see this big mountain that was
visible from our house, this giant, slowly
retracting funnel was making its way down, not in
a massive tornado way, but it was slowly
descending from the sky, like it had deliberate
intent to land.
When you looked at the news, over in Japan-- of
course Japan, because that's where all cataclysms
start, apparently, this giant obsidian orb, a mile
in diameter, apparated. It was smooth and they had
the whole, you know, a bunch of different military
forces were brought there to look at it. No one
knew what it did. Then, one day, a door beneath it
opened. It sat there for a week and everyone was
like, "What does this mean?" Clouds are there,
this is happening, but nothing's going on. And
then suddenly, we watch, as this door retracted
from beneath and opened and multitudes of these
demonic spirits begin to spill out. Thousands upon
thousands upon thousands of them. They all looked
like devilish entities, but they were spectral.
They couldn't be harmed. They passed through all
physical matter. They didn't attack anyone. But
what we began to discover was each one of these
spiritual entities had one corresponding person in
the world, that it knew where they were and was
going right for them. And whenever it found them,
it embraced the person and they died. So it was
this extermination of the human race. Each one of
these demonic spirits designed to find the one
person that they were designed for to eliminate
them. And it was this wave as it went across all
of Asia to Europe and then made their way into the
U.S. And the rest of the dream was us waiting for
this to happen. It was this very ominous
acceptance of the end and looking out and seeing
these waves of entities coming over the mountain
that I started the dream with, and then coming
through the valley, through the neighborhood, and
coming towards us. And that's the last point I
remember. Dark as fuck dream and I apologize for
that! But it was so vivid, the imagery to me, that
I filled my sketchbook and I began to write a
story about it. And the imagery inspired me in
certain ways, so that was probably one of my
favorite dreams, but not one of the best dreams,
but one of my favorites.
Okay, we're having to close this up here because
we're getting to the end of the six o'clock period
here. You guys are awesome. Thank you so much for
coming and hanging out today. We ran a gamut of
emotions thoughts and we created a couple of NPCs
and monsters. This was a promise from a charity
game a while back, so thank you for being patient
with that. We're getting things geared up again.
But we appreciate you guys so much. Thank you
listening, hanging with me, hanging with my
awesome fake fire. And I hope you have yourself a
wonderful day. I'll see you guys Thursday for the
continuation of Vox Machina's adventures and is it
Thursday yet? In the meantime, some of us will see
you at Talks Machina in about an hour or so. Take
care.