MATT: The small village of Bronbog has recently
come under a baneful curse. The young are born
deformed and demonic. The denizens are driven to
madness and suicide. Those that remain, stubborn
as they are, have fallen silent. The nature of
this curse has drawn the attention of one man.
VIN: I am Kaulder, the witch hunter. An 800 year
old immortal. (growls)
MATT: Now, Kaulder, you've seen such curses before
drive whole communities to ruin. But from what
your experience as a witch hunter has taught you
is that the usual purpose of such a curse is not
just to spread pain and suffering, but to prepare
the land with enough misery and darkness for some
ulterior motive. To transform the fane of the land
into a sight ripe for dark ritual. You, in seeking
the source of this curse, have gathered up a
handful of proven warriors in the land to
investigate what is actually going down in
Bronbog.
LAURA: I'm Vex'ahlia, the stealthy half-elven
ranger. Separated from my twin brother and on the
hunt.
TRAVIS: I'm Grog, a goliath barbarian with a love
for combat, women, and ale.
JESSICA: I am The Headmistress, a human monk whose
family was killed during a civil war and who's now
out seeking vengeance!
DAN: I'm Dupont Dupont, dwarven rogue and if
there's coin to be had, I'll be there!
MATT: As the five of you trudge up to the
outskirts of the Dreamseep Marshlands, the sun
slowly begins to set. The mildewed, awful set
water smell of the swamp begins to take over your
senses. As darkness slowly descends upon the
landscape, you can see a bit of light poking
through the trees. As you slowly become aware,
you've reached the outskirts of Bronbog proper.
You see tons of huts and small villages all
darkened, left desolate. You hear the cricketing
sound of various insects in the swamp begin to
swell. The frogs calling out into the darkness.
You approach the only true sign of life in your
vicinity, a small hovel, mildewed on the outside,
with a single window that is aglow against the
darkness.
LAURA: Can we peek in the window?
MATT: You go up to the side of the window and peek
in the corner. The interior is almost a hoarder's
home. There are a series of crates and barrels and
papers scattered about like this place has been
packaged and unpacked multiple times. Someone's
been trying to decide whether to leave or stay.
You see in the light a female form, humanoid,
sitting over a desk in the corner, currently
sobbing to herself silently.
LAURA: She seems distraught.
DAN: We should probably knock.
VIN: Hmm.
JESSICA: We're all going to get destroyed by this
girl.
DAN: She's a hoarder! Is she going to put us in a
box, label us?
JESSICA: Tons of d20 lying about.
TRAVIS: It smells really good around here.
JESSICA: Knock. Who's knocking?
LAURA: Leader.
VIN: Am I knocking? Is that what we're doing. Did
this turn into Kaulder the knocker?
MATT: Every journey begins with a single knock.
VIN: I can't be surprised, so I guess I'm--
JESSICA: Shouldn't we perception the house first?
VIN: Maybe.
JESSICA: I feel like we're walking into--
MATT: Roll a perception check.
VIN: I will. My perception bonus is plus six.
LAURA: I think that's a 14.
VIN: I like a 14. It's a little bit of a fail
roll.
MATT: As you approach the door, the door itself is
not as mildewed as the rest of the building. There
is a general appearance to this that the rest of
the house, while old and weathered, this door is
much fresher than you'd expect. That's the best
you can ascertain of that nature. It does catch
your eye.
DAN: Well, at least she cleaned the door!
TRAVIS: Is everybody all hesitant? I'll knock! Let
me show you how we do this. I go up and pound on
the door real hard.
MATT: (thudding) The sound echoes through the
interior. You hear a voice go (startled yell) on
the other side. A couple of footsteps pitter up to
the side. The door slowly opens with a creak. A
young woman in her early to mid 20s, her face
streaked with tears and dirt, very simple
clothing. She looks through, peering at the group.
"I'm sorry. Is there a problem? What's going on?"
TRAVIS: I don't do well with emotions. I'm really
the group knocker. Somebody else want to take it
from here?
LAURA: Are you upset, dear? What's been happening
here?
MATT: "It's best you not be here. Death awaits
those who come. What are you doing? Flee! This is
"my cause! I chose to live here. Let me take this
onus. You still have a chance to get away!"
VIN: Onus?
LAURA: We don't run.
DAN: Get away from what?
MATT: "Curse."
VIN: We pillage.
JESSICA: I'm with him. We pillage.
VIN: She's saying we should run away from the
curse.
MATT: She seems honestly distraught in hopes of
trying to instill you with this same fear.
LAURA: But maybe she knows more. Have you done
research? Why are you here when everybody else has
fled?
MATT: "Because my family's always been here. It's
not much, but it's still home. If we all leave,
"there's no chance anyone will come and save us.
This whole land will fall to ruin. At the very
"least, if I die here, maybe that'll be enough of a
reason for someone to come and alleviate this
"terrible night's bane."
VIN: Who's responsible for the curse?
MATT: "I don't know for sure. We hear voices in
the night in the far ends of this swamp. We hear
"laughing and terrible gurgling in the swamp.
Voices of languages we don't know. We've had a few
"folks go out to try and stop this and they never
came back. Recently, I've heard terrible, wistful
"howling of voices moaning in the morning mists."
VIN: Do we know which direction the swamps are
from this?
MATT: You're currently a good hour's worth of
travel into the swamp to meet this. You're in the
heart of it right now. It goes further out towards
the distant mountain range. You gather from what
you have traveled, it gets more desolate, more murky.
The water level seems to sink even further.
TRAVIS: There's laughing, gurgling, moaning. We
sure it's not a bar? Might be so bad.
JESSICA: What can we get out of this?
MATT: "I can collect some change from the few that
have stayed. I've only got a bit of gold to my
"name as well, but we'd be happy to put it up if
you'll be of help. Please, I ask."
DAN: A bit is much better than none.
TRAVIS: You're greedy.
MATT: "I'll speak to the denizens around. If you
come back, alive, that is, we'll have all of
"our money ready for you. Yes, please!"
JESSICA: I think we should get half up front.
DAN: You drive a hard bargain!
TRAVIS: What do you have on you?
MATT: Go ahead and roll a persuasion check.
JESSICA: 11 plus one. 12.
MATT: Okay. She goes, "I'll offer you what I
have." She stumbles off and start thumbing through
all these boxes, making this loud clattering
noise. Comes back about five minutes later. "Here.
"120 gold. It's all I've got to my name, but if
this means to you that we have your service to aid
"us, please. This bravery is a welcome change
around here. If you'd like, I can take you to
"these ruins outside the village."
JESSICA: I grab the gold purse and I say: Go ahead
and show us the way. As I put it in my backpack.
MATT: "All right! This way!" She walks out past
you, closing the door behind her and locking it
with a key. Turns around. "Follow me into the
marsh." She steps out into the night air, deeper
into the swamp.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we follow.
VIN: No mounts?
MATT: No mounts to get here. You figure the swamp
is hard to traverse with beasts of burden. As you
step into the swamp, about an hour's worth of
tense travel continues. You hear the occasional
call of an owl into the night air. The swamp
itself grows more and more sticky. You're finding
yourself with each sloshing step finding more tension
and drag against the back of your feet. A slow fog
begins to roll in as the night truly takes hold of
the Dreamseep Marshlands. I would like you all to
roll a perception check.
LAURA: Oh, Jesus, really?
JESSICA: Mine's so bad.
LAURA: I rolled a one!
VIN: 13 plus six.
MATT: 19.
TRAVIS: 20!
MATT: Okay! What'd you get? Perception.
JESSICA: Eight.
DAN: Three!
LAURA: Natural one!
TRAVIS: Great.
MATT: As the woman and part of your party begins
to travel forth, Grog and Kaulder.
DAN: Perception is plus zero for me.
VIN: It is?
DAN: I'm not a wise man.
JESSICA: Can't even see your hand in front
of your face.
VIN: Thank god I've got some wisdom here. After
800 years, he learned a thing or two.
MATT: Pressing forward, part of your party steps
forward. Grog and Kaulder, both of you guys stop
for a second, your senses kicking in. the fog
that's rolling, while swirling naturally, is
beginning to coalesce and gather into shapes. You
see slowly piercing beyond the veil of the mist.
You can see arms appear and then vanish.
Occasionally a face chuckles and disappears back
into the surrounding vapor. You notice, just
beyond Vex, it begins to coalesce behind her in the
form of a humanoid wraith-like entity that begins
to reach out for her.
LAURA: I'm trying to pull my foot out of this
muck. I can't even see what's going on right now.
VIN: How far am I?
MATT: She's probably 20 feet ahead of you.
VIN: I should attack.
MATT: All right! Seeing this.
VIN: Specter, wraith, something's got to die.
MATT: There you go! You, rushing forward seeing
this entity, you burst forward with speed,
sloshing through the mud. As it reaches out to
claw, you run forward arcing your sword down in a
large strike against the creature. Go ahead and
roll an attack.
VIN: 13.
MATT: 13 is what you needed to hit its armor
class. Go ahead and roll damage on that. Cool, so
that's a total of five damage.
LAURA: I spin around. What the what? What are you
attacking?!
VIN: I'm attacking the wraith that's behind you.
LAURA: Oh!
MATT: You see coming up between the two of you--
LAURA: It's a wraith!
MATT: Grog, you're prepared for this, you pull
your axe out in preparation. I want everyone to
roll initiative.
DAN: It must have been terrifying to see a witch
hunter sprint toward you with its sword.
MATT: Kaulder is up first and then coming up the
rear end, we have Dupont.
DAN: Someone has to do it, may as well be me.
MATT: As you see a second wraith beginning to form
behind you in the center of the group. You're up
first so, Kaulder, what do you want to do with
your next round of combat?
VIN: Let me light up the sword.
MATT: You use your quick action, you bring the
blade back. As you concentrate on it, closing your
eyes, drawing on the mystical power from your
training. Reddish-yellow flames begin to burst up
the outside of this metallic blade. It lights up
the exterior of the swamp. The wraith recoils in
fear. What else are you going to do now?
VIN: I'm going to attack!
MATT: You get two attacks with your sword. Go
ahead and roll twice.
VIN: Nice!
MATT: That'll hit. Go ahead and roll the first
attack damage with an extra d6 because of the
fire.
VIN: Baller.
MATT: Right? That comes to a total of four damage
plus the four from the sword, so that's eight
against the entity. As you streak down with your
first attack, the flames send the creature
separating for a moment, the vaporous mist
bisected in the middle of the air. It slowly
reforms. Using that action, recoil for a second
strike downard. Go ahead and roll your next
attack.
VIN: 17.
MATT: 17. Roll damage for the second strike.
LAURA: That's beautiful.
DAN: Just obliterated.
VIN: What is that, 20?
MATT: With the second attack, you swipe down. This
time the orangish-yellow flame burning a bright vibrant
white with the intent as your witch hunter
instinct brings the blade down. The wraith screams
out in pain as it dissipates into the swamp air,
completely destroyed with Vex standing there
looking dumbfounded by it.
LAURA: Gah! Kaulder! Thank you!
VIN: You're quite welcome, Vex!
MATT: However, at that same moment, you hear the
creeping sound of the second wraith that seemed to
draw up behind you. Next in combat, that would
be--
VIN: Where's our friend right now?
MATT: She's currently back with Grog at this
moment, hiding behind the large goliath barbarian.
So what do you want to do, Headmistress?
JESSICA: Extra attack, I guess.
MATT: You dart up, your monk fists up. You see the
focus of your ki energy causes the exterior of your
flesh to momentarily harden like iron.
JESSICA: Hell yeah.
MATT: You rush up with unnatural speed. The wraith
not even realizing your presence. Go ahead and
roll three attacks.
JESSICA: 11.
MATT: That hits. Roll two more times.
DAN: Punched a ghost!
JESSICA: Two.
MATT: That is going to miss, unfortunately. Third
attack?
JESSICA: 12.
MATT: That hits. Roll damage twice. It's a d6 plus
four each strike.
JESSICA: Two.
MATT: That's six. One more time.
JESSICA: Five.
MATT: Nice! Nine damage. As you rush up, you punch
the wraith from one side. You see its form shimmer
from the impact, you go for a secondary uppercut,
it seems to disperse around your fist, completely
missing in the air. You rear back for a kick, this
time it's unprepared for the secondary attack. You
smack it upside. For a moment, you feel that the
wraith has physical form around your fist and it
takes the impact, drifting back about five feet.
That concludes your turn. Vex, you're up.
LAURA: I think Grog was next, he had 17.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: I take the greataxe and I swing it and I
go for a frenzied strike so I get an additional
attack.
MATT: Leaving the woman behind you, fearing for
her life, you go into an angry rage, froth forming
at the corner of your mouth. You charge up against
the wraith, flanking it from the side with the
Headmistress.
TRAVIS: Say: Here, Moppet. (yells) That's really
good! That's a 24.
MATT: That'll hit! Next attack.
TRAVIS: That's a nine.
MATT: Whiff. Third attack now.
TRAVIS: That's 14!
MATT: 14 does hit. Go ahead and roll damage
twice.
TRAVIS: d12. That's nine. Dang. 12.
MATT: That's twice. You missed the one. As you
swing up, you swing the axe wide. It cleaves
through part of it. There's now a burst of blue
ectoplasmic energy dissipates from the immediate
blast of the attack. You swing back with a
backhand, it dodges out of the way. It's going for
your throat. As you do, you bring the axe,
backhanding it to the side. The wraith is pushed
off of its axis. It's angry and now intent on you.
It is now the wraith's turn.
LAURA: Why?!
DAN: Directed by M. Night Shyamalan!
MATT: It turns to you, reaches out, its face
contorting from these large, angry ghostly fangs.
That's a 21 to hit.
TRAVIS: That'll hit.
MATT: Second strike as well. That's a 14 to hit.
TRAVIS: Nope! You miss.
MATT: As the wraith reaches out, it claws the
front of your chest, but the claws seem to seep
into your chest cavity, the arm going up to the
wrist. You feel a cold grip on your heart like it
stopped beating for a moment. You take 21 points
of necrotic damage and your hit points are
permanently lowered by 21 points.
(yelling)
VIN: That's kind of harsh!
MATT: Wraiths are harsh, yo!
LAURA: That's major!
VIN: Harsh DM alert!
MATT: You don't stroll into my danger. You got to
want to live!
DAN: Total party kill incoming!
MATT: A third wraith begins to drift out of the
mist behind Grog. Now it's your turn.
LAURA: I see what it's doing and I Hunter's Mark
that wraith.
MATT: As you concentrate on it, your experience
hunting ghosts clarify its vision. Go ahead and
make your attacks.
LAURA: Oh no! I'm so excited. Oh jeez, that sucks.
12.
MATT: 12 just misses.
LAURA: I'm going to do it again. That's better,
that's 18. No, that's 20.
MATT: The second arrow finds purchase inside the
ghostial entity, keeping its form semi-coalesced
to attack Grog last round.
LAURA: Ten plus Hunter's Mark, what's that? Is
that a five? 15.
MATT: 15 points of damage. As it goes back to try
and reach into Grog a second time, your second
arrow finds it. You see the face burst around as
the arrow just barely misses the side of your
head, disappearing into the distant swamp. The
second wraith is destroyed.
LAURA: Yes!
MATT: The third wraith, however, is still coming
up from behind Grog.
TRAVIS: Why me?!
MATT: Because you're big and scary.
TRAVIS: Makes sense.
MATT: Go ahead.
DAN: I've seen some really impressive things so
far, so I'm going to try to not shortchange this.
I'm going to sprint with all of my might, try and
backflip over Grog and the wraith and try to stab
it in the back.
MATT: All right! The dwarven rogue lowers his
head, ninja runs across the surface of the
marshlands like his body has no weight
momentarily. Leap off of the air. Make an
acrobatics check.
DAN: 29.
MATT: 29! With a deft silent landing behind the
wraith, you pull your daggers and go in for the dual
attack.
LAURA: This is epic.
DAN: That is 18.
MATT: 18 hits, go ahead and roll the second
attack.
DAN: That is a 17.
MATT: Both hit, go ahead and roll damage and sneak
attack damage on the first attack.
DAN: Oh man, I need 4d6.
LAURA: Here's a d6. Here's a d6.
MATT: That's a d4. Oh that's for the daggers,
right. Gotcha. Nine damage on the daggers.
JESSICA: I know, it's so tiny!
DAN: Plus seven so 16 plus nine, 25 damage.
MATT: 25 damage, nice! As the newly formed wraith
sneaks up behind Grog, you flip over it unnoticed
in the shadow, you being your stealthy roguish
self. Slam them both into the center of this
mystical center of the wraith. You see a flash of
blue ghostly energy and it screams out from the
pain, disperses. Your daggers no longer have any
physical purchase in the creature. It reforms
around, turning and looking towards you.
DAN: Uh-oh! Surprise!
MATT: That's your turn. Coming to the top of the
round. Kaulder, you're up next.
VIN: How far am I from the dwarf?
MATT: I'd say you're probably 25 feet.
VIN: Would it be worth a Mystic Blast?
MATT: Certainly, if you want to! Go for it.
VIN: Critical!
TRAVIS: Yes!
VIN: Critical, guys! Critical! Doesn't matter what
decade you're in, guys. A critical is a critical
and it's a Mystic Blast.
MATT: Roll damage and multiply it by two.
VIN: Can I just enjoy this critical for a second?
MATT: Heck yeah, dude, take it in.
VIN: Critical's dice is-- Okay.
MATT: Roll it again because you get to roll it
twice. That's ten damage plus your bonus.
VIN: Plus three.
MATT: As the entity's reaching up, now facing
Dupont. You turn around for a second, glance, and
there's a burst of purplish energy from your eyes
as you pull on your mystic background. As you pull
your arm back, you can see a bit of arcane flame
gather in your palm and you release it outward. It
goes streaking through the night air, lighting up
the forest that's around, slamming into the
wraith. You hear it finally scream out into the
air as it is dispersed and destroyed from the
blast of mystic energy. You're sitting there. The
front of your face is a little singed from the
nearby impact from the arcane energy.
VIN: Apologies.
DAN: Now that was a close shave!
TRAVIS: I think it's actually an improvement.
DAN: Thank you.
TRAVIS: You're welcome.
DAN: There's a ghost behind you.
MATT: It calms down for a minute, the adrenaline
still pumping through your system. You take a few
breaths before your realize the mist is recoiling
and the swamp before you seems to be unveiled,
showing the rest of your path.
JESSICA: It was worth the 120 gold in my opinion!
TRAVIS: Glad we collected up front.
DAN: He only lost half his life force!
LAURA: Oh.
MATT: The woman walks up to you and says, "That
power you hold. That's strange and ancient. What
"are you?"
VIN: It's a good question. I'm a witch hunter.
(laughter)
DAN: We all gasp.
(gasping)
MATT: She steps back with awe. "Well then, I'm
going to stay with you for the remainder of this
"journey."
JESSICA: Oh crap, she's coming with us.
VIN: Oh, she's coming. Okay, cool.
LAURA: Right. We'll protect you.
VIN: I'll need more gold.
MATT: She walks alongside you. You step further
into the marsh. Now, the actual liquid of the
swamp is up to your knee and thigh. Each step is
arduous. Eventually, you see a form in front of
you. A large, stone archway of a ruined castle or
establishment that has long-toppled over and
fallen into the swamp. As you look forward, I want
you all to make a perception check.
VIN: 13 plus six. 19.
DAN: 16.
LAURA: Nine! I suck!
JESSICA: 16.
TRAVIS: 20.
MATT: Barbarian being so perceptive!
TRAVIS: That never happens.
LAURA: I keep looking at the purple coming from
your eyes and I get distracted.
MATT: Kaulder, Dupont, and Grog, as you guys
approach, you see in the center of this ruin
elevated beyond the rest of the swamp water.
There's a large stone platform, a table, much like
this, that has on top of it a series of small
trinkets and bone shards. It has some sacrificial
nature to it. It is relatively fresh blood,
meaning probably over the past two or three days.
Make an investigation check to truly ascertain the
nature of how long it's been there.
VIN: Plus four.
MATT: So what's the total on that?
VIN: 11.
MATT: It's hard to really get the nature of how
long it's been there. You gather it's probably
been a few days. You can't tell if it's human or
not. Regardless, as you approach the table, the
moonlight seems to slowly wither and the room goes
very dark around you to the point where it's pitch
dark.
TRAVIS: I don't like it. I go into a rage.
JESSICA: Already?
TRAVIS: Yeah. I don't like the dark.
DAN: Should I light a torch?
LAURA: Yeah.
MAT: As you're all here lost in darkness, Dupont,
you light the torch. It bursts, but it seems like
the darkness is constricting it. You're still
getting light, but it's very low.
DAN: That's not good.
MATT: The night air is trying to strangle it.
LAURA: Can we hear anything around us? Anybody's
voices?
MATT: As you take a moment to take this in, the
silence hits and you hear this whispering
beginning to surround you. Directionless, it has
no real source, but it is enough to grow louder
and louder to instill a lot of you with fear.
JESSICA: I grab our tagalong and yell at her:
Where have you taken us?!
MATT: As you look for her, you do not see
her. The darkness is too constricting at this
point. You hear a voice come out from the darkness
from the other side of the ritual table you're
standing at.
JESSICA: We're all going to die, guys!
MATT: "How eager they are to walk on. Unknowing
they come to the seat of their destiny." Another
voice comes from behind, it's the voice of the
young woman following you. "An offering of
"outsiders."
JESSICA: I knew it!
MATT: "It cleans the palate. It tastes to come."
"Shall we begin the next offering, dear sister?"
"Yes, yes we shall." The woman steps out of the
darkness, her head turned to the side. You see her
form shimmer. Behind it, you see her flesh extend
as her arms grow overly long, her form large and
hunched, this disgusting swamp hag vision. As she
looks forward and cackles, a second one of the
same type of physical presence steps in the
opposite side of the ritual table surrounding you.
"Witch hunter, it seems you've come to your final
bout." What do you want to do?
VIN: I like this! Attack!
MATT: As your sword, still peeling with flame
behind you, you rush towards the first hag before
you. Go ahead and make a round of attacks.
VIN: That's a 17.
MATT: 17 hits. Roll a second attack. Yeah, it
does.
VIN: Critical! Guys, I don't make this up. It's
all 20s.
MATT: Go ahead and roll damage for the first
attack.
VIN: Seven.
MATT: So 12 points of damage on the first strike.
Streaks across the front of the hag. She pulls
back, the flames erupting from the wound in her
chest. You can see black, brackish blood beginning to
flow from the wound. She looks at you. Her face,
her crooked nose and evil, deep, sunken yellow
eyes. "It'll take more than that, Kaulder!" Roll
damage for the second strike.
VIN: For the critical?
MATT: Yeah.
VIN: Ooh!
MATT: Double both dice.
VIN: Yeah. That would be 26 plus--
LAURA: Three.
MATT: So 29 point of damage. How do you want to do
this? This is your finishing blow on this one hag.
Describe how you want to do this death blow.
VIN: Oh my god. This death blow's just so
delicious. Can I throw a little spin in it?
MATT: That's what I'm saying. Go ahead and
describe how you want the death blow to be.
VIN: Guys, stand back! This is going to get
really-- I literally have to throw a spin on it
because that's what Kaulder would do. My first one
is a beautiful swipe and as I spin, I reposition
my sword and lunge deep into the heart.
MATT: Second strike cuts through the front of the
torso. You can see her ribcage exposed as her upper body's having
a hard time keeping its physical form. Strange
spirits begin to streak out of her chest screaming.
She reels back, "Kaulder!" reaching forward on the
blade as you've brought the hilt up. You can feel
that cold crimson spill over the front of your
hand.
VIN: Beautiful.
MATT: Her face is in yours. You can see the eyes
twitching as life beings to leave her form. "There
"are more. They will find you!"
VIN: Silence!
MATT: As you push in, her breath escapes the
throat, her eyes fall back and the body falls limp
against your grasp. You draw the blade out,
flicking blood off, some of it onto the
Headmistress and Grog. The other hag, who had just
revealed her image, goes, "Another time, then."
Backs out, seemingly very frightened by the fact
that you just instantaneously disabled her
sister.
LAURA: Yeah, run!
MATT: Disappears into the darkness. The moonlight
creeps in again as the shadow that seemed to
consume the vicinity seems to fade. You're now
left amongst these cold ruins. The tension and
curse seemingly now vanishing. The light and
liveliness of the local fauna and greenery slowly
returning around you.
VIN: We have done some good.
LAURA: And we got the money up front.
JESSICA: Always ask for it up front.
TRAVIS: I never liked the old woman, I'm just
saying.
MATT: As your merry band of mercenaries head back
towards the city of Brombog, you are greeted by
the remainder of the partially insane, but very
grateful survivors of this recent curse. They come
out to you. The rest of the money they collected
amounts to about 320 gold pieces as well as a
handful of currently unidentified magical
artifacts that you keep at your side for future
identification.
LAURA: Gimme.
MATT: That's for you guys to decide. As you step
out of the bog, with a sense of accomplishment, the
five of you look on to consider 1. Where your next
venture will be, and 2. Where this other hag may
be wandering off to possibly set another trap and
gain vengeance for the death of her sister. And
that, my friends, concludes our adventure for
today.
(cheering)
MATT: As Kaulder and his band of mercenaries left
the small, saved, cleansed village of Bronbog,
they went out into the night air. What adventures
did this world hold in store?
[heroic brass music]