BRAIN: Are we on the internet? Denise?
ASHLEY: Denise isn't here, babe, we're on
vacation.
BRAIN: Psh, we're not on the internet. We're on
vacation! Sorry guys, no official Talks Machina
tonight. Instead, you'll be joined by the cast of
Critical Role for a very special Critmas episode.
We'll be back next week, but until then, stay turnt
my friends.
[upbeat music]
LAURA: I don't know what to do.
MARISHA: We don't have a host.
TALIESIN: We've really never had to deal with this
before.
LAURA: No, this is new.
DENISE: Hello!
TALIESIN and MARISHA: Denise?
DENISE: Say hello to everybody first!
LAURA: Hi guys, welcome to Talk Machina!
MARISHA: We need an adult.
TALIESIN: We have no adults here.
LAURA: We're gonna have a Critmas.
TALIESIN: Welcome to Critmas in May. We decided
that we would make a mess of the studio instead of
Matt and Marisha's house for once.
MARISHA: There's still a pile of cardboard from
our past Critmas. Need to handle that. Had to
handle our yard first.
LAURA: How's that going?
MARISHA: We fill up the trash bin or the yard bin
once a week. We think it's gonna be about a
six-week endeavor to keep filling the trash bin
with yard clippings.
TALIESIN: Yay 100th episode! It'll be great!
MARISHA: My yard will still maybe look like we're
cooking meth.
LAURA: By then all the weeds will have grown
back!
TALIESIN: They're already trying to turn again
aren't they?
MARISHA: Well actually now it's kinda happened
because the piles of leaves, the grass underneath
is just dying. It's going the extreme opposite
now.
LAURA: Good times.
TALIESIN: So we've been sent a lot of stuff over
the last couple months and we're aware we don't
actually have time to open everything but we're
going to do our best to at least-- The crew has
been generous enough to figure out some
interesting stuff and put it all together in an
order of interest.
LAURA: Liam and Matt are on the way by the way!
It's not just gonna be us three alone.
TALIESIN: Travis and Sam are on their way but
they'll be here by Thursday.
LAURA: Hey! There's somebody!
TALIESIN: Speak of the devil!
MARISHA: You made it sooner than you thought! Why
are you holding a bunch of stuff?
MATT: These are Critmas gifts from Joe Manganiello
for you guys.
TALIESIN: No! We were just talking about that! Oh
my-- what!
MATT: This is new dice for you to burn through.
LAURA: Really? Did he give me that glittery gold
one I saw online, because I wanted it so bad!
MATT: These are for you, Liam, Travis, and Ashley
because you guys need to take notes so Marisha
isn't the only one.
TALIESIN: Yeah, that's fair.
MATT: And then you and Sam got afterthoughts.
TALIESIN: That's excellent, my favorite.
LAURA: Look at these beautiful!
MARISHA: Oh those are cool!
LAURA: Now they're Yin and Yang, it's like me and
Vax!
MARISHA: They are and they're kind of slightly
see-through. Thanks Joe! Starting Critmas right!
LAURA: They're warm. Where have they been?
MATT: My car.
TALIESIN: I'm really hoping that's a
euphemism. There we are.
LAURA: My car!
TALIESIN: Ampersand!
LAURA: By the way, I didn't realize when I made the white dragon
armor that me and Vax are now white and black,
which is so fucking cool!
MARISHA: You're like the Rihanna S&amp;M music video!
Or when her and Britney did it together, she was in
white and she was in black?
LAURA: I was thinking like Oreo cookies. Or Yin
and Yang.
MARISHA: Nope, I went straight to Rihanna and
Britney Spears. Okay, let's open things!
MATT: Hey everyone! I'm taking my shoes off
because I want to stink up the place.
LAURA: I don't have socks on, so I feel weird
about taking these off.
MATT: I was going to say it's weird that you don't have
socks on.
LAURA: I know! Maybe I should have worn socks or
my Birkenstocks would have been better.
MATT: You're fine!
LAURA: You have some coffee! For me?
MARISHA: It's for everybody.
LAURA: Yeah, either of those two mugs are yours.
MATT: Thank you!
MARISHA: Matt, this one's apparently for your eyes
only, and it's heavy.
MATT: My eyes only.
LAURA: Look at this cutie, can I open it? Or is
this for all of us to-- Should I just start going?
Number one, this envelope has the most adorable
stickers on it. Including a llama, like Henry,
that is a painting in me and Travis's house.
MARISHA: Henry, I love Henry.
LAURA: What? What are you laughing at?
MATT: Jamie Herald Savage sent some cool custom
elements that I can't show you guys in case they
show up in the campaign at some point down the road.
It has here stats for and some cool elements of
creatures. So thank you very much. This is going
to go into future use.
MARISHA: What happened?
MATT: What did you get, Taliesin?
TALIESIN: Terry Kobel, I hope I am pronouncing
that right, got me a beautiful copy of "English
"Pistols and Revolvers," leatherbound!
MATT: That is Taliesin porn. That is a direct
hit.
TALIESIN: I want to look at the foiled edges. I'm
so pleased.
MARISHA: Can I take this off?
TALIESIN: Yeah. This is beautiful.
LAURA: I know, right!
MATT: Show us some pages. Open it up, and show us
some pages on the inside.
TALIESIN: Yeah. It's just gorgeous.
MARISHA: Wait. Go back to the other page.
LAURA: There it is! How did you find that again
upside-down?
TALIESIN: I don't know how. It's just magic.
MARISHA: Is that a flintlock design?
TALIESIN: That is a four scythes detonating lock.
That is actually a beautiful piece of lock. I'm
going to be reading this. I am very excited.
LAURA: This is cool!
TALIESIN: This is beautiful.
MARISHA: They're all dice bags, you guys.
LAURA: But they look like dragon scale dice bags.
Says she made these right after Vax had died. This
is right before-- spoilers-- the resurrection of
Vax. She didn't know if he was going to be alive
when she made these. We're supposed to guess whose
is whose. I'm guessing that's yours since it's got
the-- and that one is mine.
TALIESIN: It's got the bird skull and evil.
LAURA: And this one is Scanlan's. It's Matt's. I
don't know. She double layered them. This is
Travis because it's got bones and it's Groggy.
MARISHA: This is Pike, I'm going to say. Yeah,
definitely for Pike.
LAURA: This is Scanlan. This has got to be Scanlan
with the--
MARISHA: Yes! And this is Vax.
LAURA: And this is Keyleth! Yay!
MARISHA: With the antlers!
LAURA: This is adorable. This is from Karen. Thank
you, Karen. And bidet!
MATT: Thank you for my fist warmer.
LAURA: There's something in here. (shouting) Oh my
God!
MATT: What did you get?
LAURA: She crocheted me little Trinket ears!
MATT: That's adorable. Oh my god.
LAURA: That's so freaking cute.
TALIESIN: That's Terry from Illinois.
LAURA: Where do I put this stuff? I've got so
much, I don't know what to do with it. That's
yours. That's Liam's.
MARISHA: This one I actually opened first. This
person whose name is Joshua Owen Lusack or
Valkyrian Fate. Josh sent me an awesome knife,
that it was the first thing I opened when we pre--
ALL: Hey!
LAURA: Directing mode Liam!
LIAM: I am a professional.
MARISHA: You look like a professor in a JRPG.
TALIESIN: You never look this nice when we're
working.
MATT: You are ultimate sempai, right now.
MARISHA: Here, do you want a crochet dice bag?
LAURA: Did you bring your own coffee?
LIAM: Coffee? Yes.
LAURA: I poured you some coffee, but that's okay.
Me and you can share the other cup of coffee.
MATT: All you need right now to is fill in your
glasses with some white color so we can't see your
pupils.
LAURA: Oh my God.
MARISHA: Joshua also sent me a bunch of Sixlets.
TALIESIN: Oh my god! Those are very exciting. I
have some plans for those.
LAURA: (gasps) These are Sixlets?
MATT: Whoa! They made pearlescent Sixlets?
MARISHA: And here's a bag that I'm going to open
right now.
LAURA: These look like BB pellets.
TALIESIN: Yeah, no, I feel like I want to be
witnessed. That's really exciting.
LIAM: Who sent these, who sent these?
MATT: Kieran. Kieran sent those.
LIAM: "For the stealthiest and gloomiest boy
ever." It's like they know me. Yeah.
LAURA: @kirkwallman on Twitter.
TALIESIN: I love my tag, too. I'm not even going
to read it. It's so much wonderful shade. That's
so much shade. I love it.
LAURA: What do we open next?
MARISHA: Um, any one. Pick one, Liam.
LIAM: How's everybody's day?
LAURA: Pretty good, pretty good.
MARISHA: Here's someone who sent us all a bunch of
sniper laser pointers that I dropped.
MATT: Oh, that's awesome! Thank you for that.
LAURA: This is for Percy.
LIAM: What are they?
MARISHA: This one's for the twins. They're laser
scopes.
LIAM: I'll open it.
MATT: You guys lose the ones I got you, it doesn't
matter, but if you lose the ones a Critter got
you... So hold on to that.
MARISHA: It's not our fault the Twitch stage is
insanity.
MATT: I know, this is true.
MARISHA: I don't know where things end up once
they land on that stage.
LAURA: We finally have a storage place to put our
stuff in between shows, guys.
MARISHA: That's what they look like.
TALIESIN: Oh my god, what? This is a little
intense. Oh! The batteries now make sense.
MARISHA: Oh, it's such a big box for batteries.
TALIESIN: There was a weird battery box that we
were shown, and they were like, "Do you know why
"you ordered batteries?"
LIAM: Can we blind each other with these?
TALIESIN: Yes. More importantly, we can blind Matt.
LIAM: Leon Kennedy.
TALIESIN: I want to know which direction-- I'm so
sorry that I'm about to do this. I don't know how
to help it.
MARISHA: Anyone want some Sixlets?
LAURA: I just want one.
MARISHA: It's like the Macy's Day Parade.
LAURA: This feels like it could be really bad,
just to throw Sixlets at the camera.
MARISHA: Oh, good catch, Courtney.
MATT: Anybody else want Sixlets off-camera? Got
it, nice! Anybody else over there? So close!
Sorry, we're having a Sixlets battle, apparently,
off to the side, there.
LAURA: This looks so real. It's so warm over here,
next to the fire.
TALIESIN: Oh wow. That's a lot of laser.
MATT: I would recommend you not ever shine those
in my eyes, please.
TALIESIN: They also come with a triggering
mechanism. This is really nice.
MARISHA: You've never had Sixlets?
MATT: They're amazing.
LIAM: Trigger to what?
TALIESIN: You'll love this, this is great. This is
nothing but a good idea. This'll go so well.
MATT: Marisha, you're opening right now?
MARISHA: Sure.
LAURA: Is this another box? Is this what you just
pulled out?
MARISHA: Yes. Yes, it is.
LAURA: How do I do it?
TALIESIN: See the end of that coil? That's a
squeezy trigger.
LAURA: What? Whoa!
MARISHA: This is from--
LAURA: I don't want to shine it towards you guys.
MARISHA: This is from TrappedFox, and it says,
"Dear Liam."
LIAM: Let's see. Open the box.
TALIESIN: I'm in no way going to abuse this. Not
going to abuse this at all.
LIAM: Oh my gosh, that's perfect. Well, I'm going
to read this. You know, I'm always gun-shy about
reading things right away, because then there's a
little hidden note that says, "By the way, PS,
"don't read this on the air." Oh man, I launched
out of work like a cannon and I still got here late.
TALIESIN: In the meantime, there wasn't a card
yet, but I think it came out of this box. Someone
sent me this steampunk tarot set, which I have
admired from afar for quite a while, but I'm going
to-- I'm very excited.
MARISHA: That's fucking awesome!
MATT: There is no color in nature that should be
this vibrant. Kind of hard to see on the fire, but
if I-- that is a little, that's a nuclear blue.
And now it is inside of me.
TALIESIN: Okay. That got weird.
MATT: So. (singing) There is a thing here. Whoa,
what is this? What the heck?
LAURA: These are from Diana, a.k.a. @DruidKeyleth
on Twitter. "Thank you so much for what you do in
"the game, and for your various voice acting gigs.
I appreciate all of it, and I really hope you
"enjoy." The fanmixes! She made us mixes!
MARISHA: They're mixtapes.
MATT: That is awesome! Yay, I got a mixtape!
MARISHA: This is for Ashley, this one's mine.
LAURA: There's a copy for-- Mary gets one for
Zahra, there'll be another batch for Kashaw. Oh
man, that's so cool.
TALIESIN: I think you have maybe a series of NPC
ones.
LIAM: This is going on my desk at home. This is a
giant d20 that Chad has named the Kraken, and it's
made from the wood of a pistachio tree.
(laughter)
MATT: That's amazing!
LIAM: This is going to sit on my desk. Thank you,
Chad. This is a very special gift. Thank you.
MATT: That's brilliant. That's actually genuinely
really brilliant.
LIAM: Thank you, I'm really touched. Thank you for
that. Wow. This is not a die, this is a murder
weapon.
MARISHA: Is it heavy?
LIAM: Yeah, here.
TALIESIN: Oh, wow.
LIAM: Anyone who rolls up in my office is gonna
get bludgeoning damage.
LAURA: Wow, it's so beautiful. Do you want to roll
it?
LIAM: On a soft service, carpet. But what if I get
a one? That would be bad. Well, I'll just lie.
Here, I'll hide it. Don't tell the truth. You've
got the word "lie" right in your name. It's a 20!
It was a three. It still means a lot to me, that's
going to go right on my office desk.
LAURA: This is so pretty, though. These fanmixes
are so awesome. Mine's called "Winddancer". That's
really pretty.
MARISHA: I have to open mine, hang on.
TALIESIN: You know, I don't even want to look.
LAURA: I'll listen to this on my drive over before
the game, so I can get in my Vex mood.
LIAM: It's just two hours of Gregorian chant.
TALIESIN: One bullet is all I need.
LAURA: We need a box to put this stuff in. I don't
know what to do with the trash.
MARISHA: Trash box? I tend to just throw it into
the ether.
LIAM: Did we get the name of the fan?
LAURA: My arm movement wasn't on screen of that,
like, pathetic.
LIAM: Sis! Who made these?
LAURA: These were from Diana, a.k.a.
@DruidKeyleth.
MARISHA: Mine's called "Cloudburst".
LAURA: She made a Briarwood mix. That's so
exciting.
MATT: (laughs)
LAURA: What is it? What did you get?
MATT: I'll show you as soon as I get it all out.
MARISHA: What do you have over there?
MATT: I'll show you once I get it all out, be
patient!
LAURA: Did anybody send me some candy or some
brownies or maybe a donut?
MARISHA: Wait, there was another candy box over
there, hang on.
OFF-SCREEN: Go for one of the Australian boxes.
MARISHA: One of the Australian boxes, hang on. See
what's going on in there, because that's got
Whoppers on top.
LAURA: Wow, somebody did send candy!
TALIESIN: Yeah, we got a peek at Whoppers. I was
gonna say, we don't know what goes any further
than that.
LAURA: There's Whoppers and Skittles.
MARISHA: Ooh, sweet and sour Skittles.
LAURA: Oh, these are all for you, Marisha. Oh my
gosh. Wait, wait. You read that, and I'll pull
this out, because I want to show it to you.
MARISHA: Okay, okay. Oh man. Okay. "Well-wishes
and congrats, Keyleth, for completing her
"Aramente, though now she gets to begin the stress
of becoming a leader of her tribe and working
"through Vax's death, but regardless, I wanted to
make something and settled on a shawl, because
"girl, how are you cold--" Oh my god! This is so
cool! This is rad. What does the back look like?
I'm going to use the vanity monitor to see. It's
beautiful!
TALIESIN: Looks like a microphone hookup.
MARISHA: It looks like a lav. "I wanted to make
something and settled on a shawl." Because I do
sometimes get cold.
TALIESIN: Are we opening the Whoppers?
LAURA: Well, we will, but we also have these.
MARISHA: She modeled it off of the intro video.
That's so rad.
LIAM: Miles of candy. Where did Taliesin go? There
he is.
MARISHA: Thank you, Maple Scribbles! This is
amazing.
LAURA: This is for Brian and Denise and the
wonderful people of Talks Machina. "Thank you for
"bringing such an informative, fun, creative show
each week. I hope that the TimTams lead to more
"amazing times. From Shantel. Thank you ever so
much Shantel. If Brian were here, I'm sure he
"would say thank you as well."
DENISE: Thank you!
LAURA: Black Forest TimTams, Caramel TimTams.
MATT: Guys, Emerita Colleen, elf. First off, great
letter. I'm going to go ahead and read this
offscreen, as per your request. However, she has made,
by hand, some miniatures. Tiny rat Grog.
LAURA: Wait, she made that?!
MATT: She made these with actual removable sword
of Craven Edge, which looks amazing. That's
actually really cool and really well made, with
his throwing hammer and chain of returning
attached, which is fantastic. There is a little
Pike that has her holy symbol and her mace, which
is adorable. Little armor on and everything. And
then for you, Laura Bailey, there is your Vex,
right? You have to actually string your bow, but
it's a bow with two arrows of dragon slaying
attached.
LAURA: What? This is crazy. Look at this
cuteness.
MATT: Isn't it adorable? So we will put these on
the Talks Machina set until the corresponding
individuals come to retrieve them.
LAURA: This is so cute. I feel like Vanna White.
MATT: Thank you so much, Emerita. These are really
amazing! I'm going to put them on set right now.
LAURA: I've got to string my bow, yo.
LIAM: What's up, Dani Carr?
MARISHA: You startled her with her name. It's
weird. Oh God. Someone is saying my name. Okay,
these are fun. This is from Brandy Ires aka
@elvyralani on Twitter. She says she has been
watching us since the beginning, that she plays a
druid because of me.
LIAM: Worst class.
MARISHA: Suck it, rogue.
LIAM: Love you.
MARISHA: Love you. "I've been wanting to make you
something for quite some time, months and months
"actually. While I have never been able to draw, I
am a crafter. You'll see that I made each of you a
"cross stitch featuring your characters."
LAURA: Is this what we saw on Twitter?
MARISHA: I think so. "You might see some fun color
play across a few of them." These are her own
patterns. "Matt, I am working on a special one for
you that will come at a later time."
LIAM: So special.
MATT: It's made of gravy. I don't know what that
means. It's been a long couple of weeks. I'm going
crazy.
MARISHA: Thank you so much, Brandy! Okay, ready?
Here's Scanlan Shorthalt.
MATT: Trinket on a bonsai.
LAURA: I unstrung it. Are you sure that's a
Trinket?
MATT: It says Trinket on bonsai. There's a bunch
of pictures here of the minis they've made.
LAURA: This is amazing. Thank you.
MARISHA: It's a bird, you know. That makes sense.
LIAM: Alt universe. I got it. Aw!
MARISHA: I know. Wait, let me hold them straight.
LIAM: I wish I could show these to my Grandma
O'Brien.
MARISHA: Here you go, Taliesin. What's it say?
TALIESIN: "I live as long as Whitestone lives."
Oh, I was preparing for, "Life needs things to--"
Oh, look at it with the little mask! Oh my god!
LIAM: (singing) Happiness is a cursed gun.
TALIESIN: It's a really nice-- Oh, you've got it.
LIAM: Yeah, man. Yeah I do. Since last week.
LAURA: Oh my gosh! "It's the only way to really
grow!"
MARISHA: "I would to rage!" for Grog, of course.
Pike is, "I am a monstah!" Oh my gosh!
LAURA: Is Travis watching? Baby, look!
LIAM: Oh, are we a football game?
LAURA: Maybe. He might have it on on his car ride.
Don't watch this while you're driving, Travis!
MARISHA: Thank you so much, Brandy! This is
amazing!
LIAM: Can I see other people's? Can I see your
stack?
MARISHA: Oh, "And I walk away."
LIAM: Yeah, man. Thanks for the pity chuckle!
Denise, also capable of rolling a 43 on stealth.
Every week.
LAURA: All right, bitches. Do you want to open the
coconut and lychee, the salted caramel and
vanilla-- that's my top choice-- or the Black
Forest?
TALIESIN: I think salted caramel.
LAURA: I think Black Forest sounds really fucking
good too. Dark chocolate and cherry, or salted
caramel?
MATT: Ooh, that's a rough choice. You pick. It's
your choice, Laura. You have to decide.
LAURA: Let's open both the Black Forest and the
salted caramel.
MATT: There we go.
LIAM: Is that your final answer?
LAURA: Here, you open this one.
MARISHA: Dani! Dani!
LIAM: This one looks exciting. I'm going to
search.
LAURA: I feel like, if Ashley was watching this on
her vacation, she'd want to come home from her
vacation just to eat this salted caramel.
MATT: Oh, it's nice and warm. Slippery.
LIAM: What's in here is cool, but I want to see if
there's a name anywhere. No?
MATT: I'm going to be an adult now and do a Tim
Tam Slam, out of red wine.
MARISHA: I did do a Tim Tam slam once, when I was
in Australia. It was a very good thing.
TALIESIN: Is that a thing there?
MARISHA: It's something I did.
LAURA: How is it?
MATT: Pretty good, actually.
LIAM: That is the only way to sneak
methamphetamines. So guys, we got some custom-made
Pop! toys, and there's notes inside, so I'm just
going to hand them out. You play Percy. You play
Kiki.
MATT: Okay, the Black Forest Tim Tam slam with red
wine, legitimately really good.
LIAM: Pass this on down to my boyfriend Shaun
Gilmore, and then we'll hold Grog and Scanlan and
Pike here. I'm taking the Vax out. Taking Vax out
is a euphemism.
TALIESIN: All right, this is happening.
LAURA: I'm going to read my letter before I open
the present.
MATT: I'm going to do the same.
LAURA: This is from Carly Scott!
LIAM: Who's it from?
TALIESIN and MARISHA: Carly Scott!
LIAM: Oh, @rudenesses is the Critter who gave me
the "Raishan Shot First" T-shirt that I wore
recently! So thank you again.
LAURA: By the way, she says that Vex is her
favorite. I just want to put that out there.
LIAM: Oh, she meant Vax.
TALIESIN: I've got to say, the amount of
unbelievable handwriting that comes my way because
of this is always spectacular.
LIAM: How many people are watching us reading?
MATT: By the way, congrats on DMing Pathfinder.
That's awesome, by the way.
MARISHA: I love it. "Yep, Florida. I know." That's
just a great one-liner in general.
LAURA: Oh, I can't wait to look! And with glitter
tape, too!
MARISHA: Aw, thank you so much, Carly!
LAURA: Oh! And she's winking! That's adorable!
MATT: Aw, look at little Gilmore! Oh my god! He's
amazing! Look at that man's majesty! I love his
little cuffs!
MARISHA: She's got coppery, shiny hair!
LAURA: Where will this show? I'm going to put this
right behind-- can you see her behind Liam?
LIAM: Oh!
LAURA: That is so cute! Look at the earring! Did I
get an earring too? Oh my god, we all have
earrings!
MATT: Oh my god, she looks awesome! You do, you
have little sparkle earrings! Oh my god, Percy,
yours looks so good!
LIAM: Carly, thank you so much.
MARISHA: I love our earrings.
TALIESIN: The hair is really killing me.
LIAM: Ugh, I love you, but ugh, you pissed me off,
but aw, I love you! Oh no, his ear didn't make it.
I need some Krazy Glue for his ear! We got it.
MARISHA: Okay, this is from Shantelle and she
crocheted a scarf. She said it reminded her of
Keyleth's spellcasting. Wow, that's awesome! Wow,
that's crazy! How are you guys so talented? How is
everyone so good? Oh, look how pretty. Hey buddy,
first Tim Tam?
LIAM: Ah, screw you. Oh, it's melting in my hand.
MATT: Yeah, they're a little warm.
LAURA: I feel like we need music or something.
DENISE: We have the fireplace.
LAURA: Oh, it is? Oh, so other people can hear
that?
MARISHA: Thank you, Shantelle!
LIAM: I haven't had a sugar snack in weeks.
MATT: All right, do we just pick one?
LAURA: I don't know, maybe? This looks like
something.
MATT: Sure, I'll take this one, whatever this one
is.
LAURA: Wait. I can't tell.
MATT: It's from Mark Ball.
LAURA: This is for Vax and Percy. This is for
Marisha.
MATT: "Hi Matt. Lately, I've been having
nightmares. In my dreams, you are playing the new
"Mansions of Madness expansion, but with unpainted
figures, or even worse, sometimes
"professionally painted miniatures. These minis
don't match up to the amateurish paint job that I
"did on the core set. I don't want to live in a
world where you have to play Mansion of Madness
"with mis--" Oh! You guys have the actual, the
original set with painted minis, which I still
use? Oh my god! And donated $50 to the Nature
Conservancy for Marisha Ray, which is fantastic,
from Mark Ball. That's incredible! Mark, it's
amazing! And the new Beyond the Threshold Mansions
of Madness expansion. Wow. Oh, the minis! Oh! I'm
so happy! Oh, wow! You make me a happy man, Mark!
MARISHA: That's awesome. I really want to play
now.
MATT: We haven't messed with the expansion. This
is new to the second edition.
MARISHA: Oh, the newest one? Ooh.
MATT: This is all stuff we haven't played yet.
MARISHA: This is from Lisa. She said one of her
customers brought in to sell on consignment, and
she said they're pretty much the coolest earth
elemental mini she thinks she's ever seen. And she
thought we could put them to good use. So let's
see here. What you got, Lisa? Oh, those are sick!
Look at that! There's one. You have the other
minis.
(yelling)
MATT: Yeah, that's now your mini. I love the green
gems together!
LAURA: I just took this from her hand. I'm sorry.
MARISHA: No, it's good. Here, I'm trying to see a
little bit of a backdrop now.
LAURA: It's really hard to do that. Brian does it
every week with the Wyrmwood and it's hard.
MATT: That's so cool!
LIAM: Lauren G. Meyers sent Taliesin and I skull
casts. Wow. Thank you so much.
MARISHA: Are you going to make a--?
TALIESIN: I don't know. I'm definitely going to do
something exciting with it. Something exciting's
going to happen with it.
LIAM: Yeah, I might be able to do something with
this soon.
TALIESIN: I tapped my microphone like a terrible
person. Thank you so much. This will be added into
something fun.
MARISHA: Man, I recognize these! It looks like
there's another red!
TALIESIN and LAURA: Oh my god!
LIAM: Screw those bastards!
MARISHA: Oh, what are these?
LAURA: Unicorns! Who are they for?
MARISHA: Let's see, because we already got the
first round.
LAURA: I took the white one last time.
MARISHA: She said sorry for her crappy writing,
that her two-year-old was demanding her attention
at the time of writing this. "Dearest Matthew
Mercer and Marisha Ray--"
LAURA: It's all for you.
MARISHA: "Having watched the Vox Machina
methodically--" Hang on, wait. Oh, "destroy the
"dragons, therefore--" Right, hang on. Aw, she
wanted us to have a complete set.
MATT: That's so sweet!
LAURA: It's so much work!
MARISHA: She knew I didn't want to give up Raishan
to Patrick, which I still haven't yet, so that we
could actually give the original to Patrick and I
could have the second Raishan. This is amazing. I
can't believe that you went through all of this
again.
LAURA: Does it say that we have to give the
pegasus to somebody specific, or does it say that,
if you're at the opening of the Critmas presents,
and you really like the pink pegasus, you can have it?
LIAM: Laura, take it. It's yours.
MARISHA: It was an alicorn to represent Gilmore.
MATT: Oh, for Shaun? That's amazing.
LAURA: How's that reading going for you?
MARISHA: And apparently, wait, gray elephant?
LAURA: Wait. There's a gray dragon. Oh no! We're
missing a gray elephant!
MARISHA: Right? "Also, the gray elephant is for
Taliesin." Right? That does say--?
TALIESIN: It does. I think it does.
MARISHA: "One blunderbuss away from becoming a
quarterman."
TALIESIN: That's pretty cute. Highly entertained.
MARISHA: Anyway, thank you so much, Stacy! These
are all Stacy and Glenn for round two.
ALL: Thank you!
MARISHA: We will read your letter in detail
later.
LIAM: This one doesn't say who it's from, unless
it's from the company Field Notes Brand, but it's
a bunch of little field notebooks, and I can only
believe that somebody wants the rest of us to take
the heat off Marisha and start taking notes.
LAURA: I take notes! Just not as good as Marisha
takes.
MARISHA: Well, we have pillars. You're good as the
treasury.
LAURA: I do take really detailed treasury notes.
MARISHA: Yeah, you do take detailed treasury
notes, and Travis takes detailed Bag of Holding
notes.
MATT: All right, we have a bunch of presents here
from what looks like @ACL_TeamKilla that sent a
bunch of bags of varying Skullsplitter Dice.
Different colors and types, so Laura, you can tear
through as many to your heart's content of various
dice sets.
LIAM: I want some! Laura doesn't get them all!
LAURA: All for me!
MATT: We have two large bags, so you guys have
plenty. We can go through and distribute. I'm
going to put them over here. And a letter that I'm
not going to say because he's nudging things that
you players need to remember anyway.
LAURA: Here's a wonderful present from Kristin and
Brad, and I'm going to read this letter because
it's short and it's perfect.
MATT: Who wants some Bilar? Sorry.
LAURA: Okay. I don't know what that is.
MATT: They're like gummies.
LAURA: I'll eat it. "We figured you guys were
getting tired of looking up potion types all the
"time, so we made these super awesome bottles for
you to use on your adventures. One set for each
"table. Each bottle contains the appropriate number
of d4s that you need for your roll, ranging from
"common to supreme. Good luck, and keep being
awesome. Kristin and Brad." Kristin and Brad are
super duper cool, and by the way, have we ever had
a supreme healing potion?
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: We have? With 20d4?
MATT: It's not 20d4.
LAURA: Yeah, superior, eight. Supreme, 20. We've
never had a supreme.
MATT: I'll double-check.
TALIESIN: I had been working on putting one of
these together, and now I don't have to, which is
very pleasing.
LAURA: That's so cool.
MARISHA: Oh, shit! I don't know who this came
from, but this is a journal, it's a leather
journal, and they've got "kaitiake" stamped in
it.
MATT: Oh my god, that's awesome.
LAURA: Is it spelled right? Is that how you spell
"kaitiake"?
MARISHA: That is the official Maori spelling of
it. I've changed it a little bit originally, but
that's the original spelling, so it's accurate.
That's amazing.
LAURA: The green ones don't taste as good as the
pink ones.
LIAM: I have a present for us here from Derek
Wilson, @cart_exists. He sent some customized
coasters, two for each of us. Some of the quotes
you might remember, they stand out, like Scanlan.
"You spice?" And Matthew's say "How do you
derr-de-derr-derr?" But some of them are
lesser-known. Grog's is "I have an intelligence of
six, I know what I'm doing." Keyleth's says "We're
"all cows, just embrace it." Percy's medium-iconic,
"I'm in the pyjamas with the butt-flap. The
"butt-flap is down." Pike, "This temple goes to a
six." Vex's say, "I'm going to attack it twice,
"because I'm original." And Vax's says, "She's
working for the Illuminati and we're basically the
"A-Team, so I think she might know a little
better." Thank you very much, Derek.
LAURA: These are for you.
TALIESIN: I've got a thought. I'll show one of
them, just so they get the notion of it.
MATT: I've found the right note, so @AC_teamkilla
is actually from Sweden, it says, "Greetings from
"Sweden." And this is a box of their love and glory
of Grog. So most of these gifts are for Grog, so
the two big bags of dice? They're for Grog. The
drinking horn in here? That's for Grog. So I'm
going to put those in here, and you can bring
those home to Travis, and he can enjoy and
distribute as he sees fit.
LIAM: No, no, Travis said that anything that he
got when he's not here goes to me, so I will take
those home.
MATT: Gave me metal dwarven dice as well. That's
fantastic. That is really, really cool.
LAURA: Oh my gosh, wait. This is from-- hold on,
I've got to see who it's from, because this is
really cool. This is from Jay Anthony Pierpoli and
the rest of the Critter community, who sent,
number one, a fanfiction that I will definitely
read that they say is phenomenal by Sarah Louise
Harper. And also, this is so cool, I wish Sam was
here. I'm opening his present for him, because I
like opening things.
MATT: What?!
LAURA: It's a wrap for his giant mug.
(exclamations)
MATT: That is incredible. Look at the leather-work
on that!
LAURA: I know, it's amazing! He said he made it
before he realized Scanlan was not here. How cool
is this?
MATT: That's badass. Little holders, too!
LAURA: Insane! Where's his little mug? Is it up
here?
MATT: Let me check. I'll go get it.
TALIESIN: I'm going to do this and hope to not
make a mess. Hah. Oh, wow, we've lost Matt. Oh
yeah, the mug's probably in the-- yeah.
MARISHA: Oh, that's awesome. John and Deb O'Brien
sent a copy of one of their favorite bands for us
to listen to. So thank you so much, John and Deb.
And then-- oh, I see what you're doing.
LAURA: We have to put it on so he'll have it in
the next show when he finally brings his mug out
again. Oh my god! It looks so cool.
MATT: We're not going to tell him about it. He'll
just find it with it on.
LAURA: Oh man. I don't have anything. I'll take
it.
MARISHA: Okay, Matt, this is from Beth Fleven.
LAURA: From Joseph, we need to remember it's from
Joseph.
MARISHA: She sent us something in a diapers box. I
don't know if that's--
TALIESIN: I think she's sick and tired of us
getting up in the middle of the game. Message
received. That will be the last time you saw any
of us get up in the middle of the game.
LIAM: Check this out. Check this out.
LAURA: So ridiculous.
(laughter)
LIAM: Best t-shirt I've ever been sent. Of all the
other t-shirts I've been sent, this is the best
one. Look at that!
MARISHA: That is a very fluorescent orange shirt.
LIAM: Yes, and I will don it proudly.
MARISHA: Go jogging in that shirt.
LIAM: Yeah, okay.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Oh my. This is from @irish_mike. "To
Taliesin: To conquer your fear, you must face it.
"Stay beautiful." And I got a bag of Swedish Fish.
I fear these, but not for the same reason. Thank
you. Thank you very much. Oh, I'm going to be in
trouble when I bring these home. Oh, this is so
exciting.
LIAM: This print-art shirt is from Jeff Kielessen,
who lives where many of my kin live.
MARISHA: Okay, so Beth wrote a letter to Matt and
I, but the gift is for Liam. Beth is thanking us
for the game, she says, "Enclosed in this box is a
handmade gift for Liam. I began making it just
"after he defeated Thordak. I thought it fitting
that the slayer of Thordak should have one of the
"eggs to keep as a trophy." There you go, bud.
LIAM: Can I see the letter? Hold on. Oh, man. Oh,
I got a letter, too. I'm going to read the letter
first. No, you all are waiting on me.
LAURA: No, too bad, I'm doing this one.
LIAM: Look at this amazing motherfucker right
here. Oh, yes! Yes. Ah, facehugger's in it!
MATT: I did it! It's on. That is ridiculous.
LAURA: How heavy is that?
MATT: What, the whole thing? It's got a nice heft
to it.
(laughter)
MATT: Now fill it with liquid.
LAURA: Oh my god. How does he pick this up? Does
he pick it up one-handed?
MATT: Gnome strength.
LAURA: What does he put on the bottom? Oh, it's
his little code.
TALIESIN: Where is this from? This is "To Matthew
Mercer." Where is this from?
MARISHA: From Elliott Cole from Australia.
MATT: What is in the thing? What are you finding
in the thing?
TALIESIN: All right, let's see what happened.
LAURA: Oh, wow!
MATT: What?
LAURA: I know! This is so cool! This is from
Jennifer Knight. She designed this and stitched it
herself, with a panel for each character, and
these panels are super duper detailed.
MATT: I love the frame on this.
LAURA: The frame is awesome! The freaking
stitching is awesome! With museum glass.
MATT: Where a bunch of nerdy-ass voice actors roll
dice and play Dungeons & Dragons. Aw!
LAURA: Look at these panels! This is so cool!
MARISHA: That's so great!
LAURA: We should hang this on set.
MATT: That's fantastic.
TALIESIN: I'm actually excited because we have
room for art suddenly because we just redecorated
a bit.
LAURA: Oh wow, it's really well done.
LIAM: Beth, thank you, and thank you.
MARISHA: Amazing! What's happening?
TALIESIN: I don't know what this is. But things
are happening.
MATT: Progress is occurring. (singing) Freedom!
Sweet freedom, freedom! You've got to give what
you take.
TALIESIN: They wrapped this very well.
MATT: Whatever it was is in seven pieces.
TALIESIN: Another door!
MATT: It's just a small door. It would make so
much sense.
MARISHA: Are you getting it out?
TALIESIN: Yeah, we're getting there.
MATT: I'm so curious now.
TALIESIN: It's just an infinite amount of
wrapping! All the way down.
MARISHA: Oh my God! You guys!
MATT: What? It's a guitar.
LAURA: It's pink.
LIAM: What! Whoa! Oh my God!
MATT: (yelling) What?!
LAURA: That is so cool!
LIAM: On the set!
MATT: (Gilmore voice) "That is glorious. What else
can you say but, that's glorious?"
LAURA: Do you want to hold this, Matthew?
MATT: "Now you know where to shop, am I
right?" That is incredible!
LAURA: I feel like we just won the lottery.
MATT: Look in the back, it has our symbol engraved!
Elliott Cole, incredible work, Elliott! That is
amazing! One day at home I'm like, "You know, just
make up some magic shop with some dude named
"Gilmore." Years later-- That's amazing.
LAURA: I wonder if it'll fit in one of those boxes
above Trinket's head.
MATT: It's a bit big for one of those.
LAURA: Oh, I mean the cross-stitching. Gilmore can
maybe go right there next to the other Gilmore!
Gilmore is world famous.
MATT: I just want this in front of our house now.
LAURA: I know, right! Can you just hang that in
your living room? I wouldn't blame you if you want
to take it.
MATT: It's incredible! Holy shit! Oh man, it
should live on set for a little while at least.
Then I'm going to take it home.
LAURA: Just above your bed?
TALIESIN: We need more hooks. We definitely need
more hooks.
LAURA: Yeah. Oh gosh, careful; those were hung
pretty precariously. But that's okay! No, it's
great. We'll rearrange our--
(yelling)
LAURA: That's really remarkable.
MATT: I can't function right now.
LAURA: It's done so well!
MATT: It's done really well. Have you seen it up
close?
TALIESIN: I have not seen it up close. Oh my God,
really? What lunacy. What lunacy is this?
LIAM: This is something for Sam. So many Critters
were involved in this. So many! This is a list of
the Critters involved in the making of this.
LAURA: Is that the same people who do the quotes?
It's a quilt?
LIAM: Yeah. This for Sam, we should show it on air,
right?
LAURA: Oh, I feel like Sam should be the one that
opens it up, though. It's his quilt?
LIAM: But like, don't we want to acknowledge the
work put into this?
LAURA: Maybe we can give it to him on Thursday.
Because I loved mine.
LIAM: Okay. God, I recognize so many names on this
list. Yeah, that's what we'll do. We'll bring it
on Thursday on the top of the show.
LAURA: What happened?
TALIESIN: The note went-- The tape's not sticking
anymore and it just gave me a mild heart attack.
That's all.
LIAM: For Sam for later.
MARISHA: Okay, I think these are fun. That one
goes to Liam. This one's Taliesin, Laura, and
Matt. We already pulled Ashley and Sam's and
Travis' and put them over there. Isn't it
adorable?
LAURA: Oh yeah, read the card!
MARISHA: Oh, they put 'Risha' on here. I haven't
been called Risha since high school.
MATT: "There once was a DM called Matt/He could
swap characters at the drop of a hat/His city he
"burned/But his trust was returned/And his story
never once fell flat."
ALL: Aww.
LAURA: "What can I say about lovely Laura/Her
friends and the fandom adore her/Her comebacks are
"quick/Her winks are slick/There's not a soul alive
that abhors her."
ALL: Aww.
LAURA: If you read that sarcastically...
(laughter)
MARISHA: "Marisha, a word to the wise/There are
those in the world who despise/Rise above the
"hate/Spread love to relate/Or just crush them with
your strong-as-heck thighs."
(laughter)
MATT: That's amazing!
LIAM: Is that a feat you took?
LAURA: Chun Li thighs?
TALIESIN: "It's hard to write rhymes about
Taliesin/Wild imagination he's boundless in/The
"true executive goth/With words he's no sloth/But
his deeds you can find no malice in."
MARISHA: Oh, I can think of a few.
TALIESIN: I can think of a few, too.
LIAM: "There once was a swell guy named Liam/Many
players just wanted to be him/He often played
"risky/But never played briskly/To his haters, come
on, it's a ga-em."
(laughter)
LIAM: No, seriously, it's life or death. There's
nothing to joke about. This is Dungeons and
Dragons.
MATT: Thank you so much, Vee, these are so cute!
LAURA: What did you do?
MATT: They're all shirts of my face. What? What?!
LAURA: They're team hoodies! They are team
hoodies!
MARISHA: Oh my god, mine says 'Keteor'!
LIAM: #FateTouched.
MARISHA: Hunter's Mark. What's yours?
MATT: That's incredible.
LAURA: Team hoodies! Just in case you guys didn't
know who I am.
MATT: Layering all the sweaters right now.
Multi-hood.
TALIESIN: We multi-hooding?
MATT: I'm multi-hooding.
LIAM: Oh my goodness gracious. Oh my goodness.
We've got to go bowling right after the show.
LAURA: (gasps) We have to go bowling in our
hoodies!
OFFSCREEN: Nerdiest biker gang.
MATT: Yeah, you're not wrong.
LAURA: Can we just all go somewhere in our hoodies?
MATT: This is ridiculous.
LAURA: That's awesome. Wait, who's that from?
That's from Vee. But I can't see the full name, it
just says Vee!
MATT: And we got chocolates from her, too.
LAURA: And she gave chocolates.
MATT: Thank you, Vee, you're amazing!
LAURA: Or he!
MARISHA: And chocolate.
MATT: It's Vee. You don't know what Vee is.
LAURA: You have so many more boxes.
MATT: I just like making Max do stuff, actually.
TALIESIN: I'm getting a little warm, actually. I
was okay, and then I realized, no, I'm cooking a
little bit.
MATT: From @lightningsource, the book of-- what?
What?! 5e game supplement, The Book of the
Tarrasque.
LAURA: What is-- oh no! That's the scary guy,
right?
MATT: No, no, he's fun, he's the teddy bear of
D&amp;D.
LAURA: Is that the big scary figure that I saw at
your house?
MATT: No.
MARISHA: He's lying, Laura, he's lying!
MATT: That one, you mean?
LAURA: (yells) Yeah, that one.
MATT: That's so cool! It's like a tarrasque
coloring book/adventure module-- oh my god, this
book is so cute! It's so awesome! With a foreword
by Ed Greenwood. Yeah, baby. Got some Forgotten
Realms blood in this.
MARISHA: Someone sent Chozo fine quality coffee.
LAURA: Maybe there's weed in there! That's how
people--
MARISHA: Send weed. Where does it open?
LAURA: You didn't hear that from us. I just had
heard that on the internet.
MATT: I'm genuinely excited because the base rules
for the tarrasque in 5e are all right, but there
are some cool elements of the tarrasque from
previous editions that didn't make it in. This has
a whole separate page for optional tarrasque
rules, which include things like its tiered
regeneration, which I kind of miss, and other cool
elements. The rush-- oh my god, trample--
(cackles) I'm so excited! This is so cool! I
didn't know this book existed! I'm so happy! Who
sent this? I don't know who sent this. This is
from @lightningsource. I guess?
TALIESIN: See if there's a slip of paper.
Sometimes there's a little slip of paper.
MATT: I'm looking! Whoever sent this, you're
amazing, thank you! I don't see. Tell me. Message
me or e-mail me. Thank you, that's so awesome.
(off-screen laughter)
MATT: Don't laugh at me. I'm forever 12, okay?
TALIESIN: (laughs)
MATT: Taliesin, you can laugh at me if you want.
TALIESIN: I was about to say, I feel like I've
earned that right. I've seen things. Terrible,
terrible things.
MATT: What? I got a-- "Guaranteed forever, Husky
utility knives". That's actually extremely handy.
LAURA: He's set. He's three daggers in. I've got a
tag on the inside of my sleeve. I've got to get it out.
MATT: Well, thank you, whoever sent utility
knives.
TALIESIN: Is there a note with--
MATT: Oh, there you go. Here we go. There it is.
"Hi Matt. After watching you post Christmas
"holiday on Periscope with Marisha and Taliesin and
Brian, I thought these might come in handy. Love
"the show and everything you do. Please avoid
needing stitches. Casey Wall." Yep, you knew
exactly what I was talking about. Those are
actually going to be really handy. That's so
awesome. Thank you so much.
MARISHA: They sent box-cutters?
MATT: Yeah. We kept losing ours, and we couldn't
find the one of the two we had, and then two
disappeared. Thank you very much.
LIAM: All right. Vicky Banks made us individual
goodie bags with different things in them. I'm
going to pass yours down. There's a letter with
each. I read the overall letter. Thank you,
Vicky.
MATT: Thank you, Vicky.
LIAM: The bags are individualized. I got a theatre
nerd bag.
LAURA: Of course.
TALIESIN: I have "Life needs things to live."
LAURA: Ooh, that's Marisha's.
MARISHA: "Call me 'child' one more time."
LAURA: With Hamilton on the bag! Did you guys get
Hamilton on the back of yours?
MATT: Mine has the Witcher symbol on it, I'm so
happy. It has the medallion.
MARISHA: Mine has little grasping vines.
TALIESIN: Ooh! Ooh, a Thor's hammer on a string,
excellent. I will wear that.
LAURA: Oh, cool.
MARISHA: I got a wine cork. They know. They know.
TALIESIN: Oh, blue glitter. No, that will go. I
know what that is.
MARISHA: Oh, this is adorable. It's because I am
the winespeaker. Eat, drink, and be married.
LAURA: Oh, that's wonderful.
LIAM: Oh, hi, you guys. Do you like my new hat?
MATT: That's fantastic.
LIAM: I don't know what you're laughing at. What's
this? I don't know what this is.
MARISHA: Okay, this is an amazing letter.
LIAM: (Gollum voice) What is it?
MARISHA: This is an amazing letter from Marsha
Hanif, or @1opinonated on Twitter, and she tells
this amazing story about her and--
MATT: Too many heads.
MARISHA: --about one of her characters getting
into a fight because she didn't want to get thrown
into a fight that they couldn't handle on their
mission, and it reminded her of Keyleth versus
Kima in the Underdark and how much their game has
become better by watching Critical Role. Thank you
so much for all the kind words, Marsha, this is
amazing. Truly amazing.
MATT: Got an awesome Matthew bottle opener. Sorry,
I'm still going through Vicky's present.
LAURA: Yeah, me too.
TALIESIN: I know, it's got layers.
MARISHA: Gloves and hat. Oh, this is so cute!
MATT: When the DM smiles, it's already too late.
That's awesome. Mercer '82.
LAURA: I got a DCA: Dice Collectors Anonymous
t-shirt.
MATT: It's about time you finally admitted you had
a problem, Laura.
ALL: Thank you, Vicky.
MATT: These are so cute! Oh my god. I love the
bag, too.
LAURA: That's adorable.
TALIESIN: Thank you so much.
MATT: These are from Dennis Archimbault Jr. I
should not read things from the side. Dennis
Archimbault Jr. sends a bag that is-- it's a pizza
box.
TALIESIN: Also, it's been over 30 minutes, so it's
free.
LIAM: It's kidneys. It could be a dead thing.
MATT: Oh, what?
LAURA: What is that?
MATT: Oh my god. This is a person's entire
Warhammer ogre army collection, handpainted by
them. All of their individual Warhammer ogre
minis. This is awesome. They said they haven't
touched them in about five years, so "in interest
of the minis finding a better life than spending
"eternity on a shelf, decided to bequeath them unto
you." I hit my microphone, sorry. These are
amazing. These handpainted ogres.
LAURA: I mean, they're really detailed. Look at
that guy!
MATT: Dennis, not only did you do an amazing job
on painting these, but I have all the ogres-- oh
yeah, I know that guy. That's incredible. The
ogres are some of the cooler models in the old
Warhammer fantasy stuff. That one, let's pull it
out, let's see what he's all about.
LAURA: He's got like a mask.
LIAM: Yeah, what is that?
LAURA: What's this thing? (gasps) It's a little
goblin in there! And he goes on his back. Goblin
down, goblin down!
MATT: There he goes. He's got like a standard with
a little goblin riding on his back. That's so
cool! Dennis, you're amazing! I will take good
care of this. Thank you so much.
LIAM: You're turning into one of those old ladies
from Labyrinth with the 500 things on her back.
MARISHA: Yeah, totally.
LAURA: A really eclectic grandma.
MARISHA: Hey, Matt. Are you okay with this being
your future?
MATT: Oh, I was just assuming we'd both be bag
people eventually. I make no illusions.
MARISHA: I've got to get over to the 99-cent store
before they close for the day.
MATT: We live in the Valley, we die in the Valley,
all right? Thank you so much, Dennis.
LIAM: "Do you have any purple soda left?"
MATT: Dennis, oh my god. Oh my god.
LAURA: Is that full? Oh my god. Did we open
everything?
MARISHA: Well, this is a really big one that--
guess who's in? You know what this is.
(gasping)
MATT: The Conclave is complete!
LAURA: Oh gosh, oh gosh, here's the letter.
MATT: Read the letter.
LAURA: Okay, okay, I'm reading it. This is to the
cast of Critical Role. Wow. "Congratulations. The
"adventure that spanned nearly a year, taking our
intrepid heroes across the planes of existence to
"the very threshold of death's door and back, has
finally come to an end. Enclosed is the mounted
"head of the final member of the Chroma Conclave to
fall to the valiant Vox Machina, Raishan, the
"Diseased Deceiver." This is so cool. "What an
adventure this has been. This little undertaking
"started just as a fun project to work on with my
sister, and thank you all for the wonderful work
"that you do to bring this amazing story to so
many, but it quickly turned into something much
"more important than that. It was the spark that
reignited my passion for my craft and rekindled my
"love for the wonderful shared storytelling
experience of Dungeons and Dragons, and for that,
"I can't thank you enough. With the death of the
final member of the Chroma Conclave--"
(exclaiming)
MARISHA: I love that they're to scale.
LAURA: You've just got to lance them, you know.
Sometimes you've got to go to the doctor, even, if
it's too big--
LIAM: Do it at home with a pencil.
LAURA: It's satisfying, I think.
LIAM: You gave me that mirror.
TALIESIN: Oh no.
LAURA: "With the death of the final--" That's just
scary. Don't do this. "With the death of the final
"member of the Chroma Conclave, it brings this
wonderful project and my own adventure to a close.
"It has a been a truly incredible experience to be
able to share my sister's and my talents with you
"all, and with the amazing Critters. We now embark
to find our next project and see where that will
"take us. If I could make one request: when you get
all of the mounts hung, could you get us a picture
"of the set, please? That would make me and my
sister two very happy Critters."
MATT: Oh, don't worry. I love in the back it's
written here "HDYWTDT, Kerrek, 1-27-2017". They
signed it. "They have weathered the Iron Storm,
starved the Hope Devourer, thawed the Frigid Doom,
"eradicated the Diseased Deceiver, and extinguished
the Cinder King. They are Vox Machina."
(cheering)
LAURA: Also says, "Liam, the offer still stands."
Do you know what this is? "If you or your kids
"would like a custom trophy mount to commemorate
their victory over a mighty foe", they'd be happy
to send one your way.
LIAM: Oh, wow. I'll take that.
MATT: You were my favorite villains.
TALIESIN: So far.
MATT: I was hoping you'd live until the next
campaign.
LAURA: Oh, too bad Vox Machina killed you.
MATT: Yeah. That's okay. It was a fitting end.
LIAM: We saved thousands.
MATT: You did in the long run. How cool is that?
Check it out.
LAURA: How heavy is it?
MATT: It's pretty light, actually. Thordak's the
big, heavy one, as it should be.
MARISHA: I love that they're all kind of to scale
based on--
LAURA: Wow, I can't wait to see all of them hung
up next to each other.
LIAM: Also, I can't wait, I hope to live to see
that after civilization falls and you guys trick
out your Mad Max car with five dragon heads on
it.
MATT: Don't you even worry.
LAURA: I feel like these are just too fragile to
be in a car fight.
LIAM: Well, if we all have shotguns, we'll keep
the attackers away.
MATT: We're not fighting with the dragon heads,
they're just intimidation tactics.
LAURA: No, but I'm saying if they're hanging on
the front of your Mad Max car, they're going to
get damaged!
MATT: Yeah. We'll figure it out.
LIAM: Yeah, but they'll be witnessed.
LAURA: They will be witnessed. Witness me!
MATT: Oh, is this something?
LAURA: Where should I put this so it doesn't get
damaged?
OFF-SCREEN: I think that should go on the set.
TALIESIN: Actually--
MATT: Well, no, I'm thinking, now that we have all
the heads and if we get the new set finished, we
might put them all up in the new set.
TALIESIN: We've got the wall as well.
MARISHA: We've got new flats coming.
LAURA: Oh my gosh, yeah.
TALIESIN: Yeah, there's a lot of new space for
art.
MATT: Marisha.
MARISHA: I think we've hinted at it. We just don't
know exactly when we're going to--
MATT: "Hey, Marisha and Matt, congrats on your
engagement. Couldn't be happier for the two of
"you. Here's a gift to commemorate the occasion.
Hope you enjoy it. All the best, your friendly
"neighborhood Bonertown."
ALL: Bonertown!
MARISHA: Where has he been? I'm sure he's still
been around, I just feel like I haven't heard of
Bonertown in a while.
MATT: Right there should be fine. Oh. What!
TALIESIN: This is going to be a two-person job,
isn't it?
MATT: Marisha. Marisha.
MARISHA: What?!
TALIESIN: Oh no. Oh no.
MATT: Turn that to the camera. That is
incredible.
MARISHA: I already know where that's going.
TALIESIN: The gold foil ink is nuts.
LAURA: This is super limited printing, by the way.
132/175.
MARISHA: Bonertown! Oh my god. You guys.
LAURA: You made sure the tape on that side didn't
touch the picture, right?
TALIESIN: No, I'm pretty sure.
LAURA: There's tape on that side of the paper.
Yeah, let's just keep that away from it.
MARISHA: Holy crap.
LAURA: We're good.
MARISHA: Is that everything?
LIAM: I've got a couple things over here.
TALIESIN: There's also this. I want to put this
somewhere super safe.
MATT: "To Critical Role, from Kyle Jackson."
(laughs) Yes!
LAURA: Stop hogging the joke!
MATT: We have an updated one. "Mercer &amp; Four Eyes
&amp; Antlers &amp; Taryon Darrington &amp; Doty &amp; Short Stuff
"&amp; Jumbo &amp; Little Elf Boy &amp; Little Elf Girl &amp;
Friendly Bear." That is brilliant. Well, I'm
wearing that on Thursday.
LAURA: That would be great, because you need to
get back at Sam for something.
MATT: You know what? When I find time, I'm going
to get him back so hard.
TALIESIN: Everyone, don't tweet at him. Don't
tweet at Sam, he doesn't have to know.
MATT: This is a precursor. This is an accidental
venture. I have things planned.
LIAM: I have a big page of limericks and some
gifts from Adam Schwartz, Tiamat_ZX, who I see
active on Twitter. He's sent us a big page of
limericks. I'm going to read two, because there's
a lot. Let's do both of Sam's. "Oh Scanlan he
could lie and deceive/But when alone his mother he
"would grieve/He never showed his true colors/To
himself nor the others/But by the time they knew,
"he'd made his leave." Too soon. "If you've heard
of Tary the daring/Then you know he is quite
"overbearing/He's naive and a fool/But he's skilled
with a tool/And his compassion is not a red
"herring."
ALL: Aww.
LIAM: And he sent along two Dungeons and Dragons
Kre-O sets that I am commandeering for Sam and my
children. Thank you, thank you!
MARISHA: Those are cool! I didn't know they made
Lego sets.
LIAM: Well, it's not Lego, it's Kre-O.
MARISHA: Those are pretty cool.
TALIESIN: It's Lego-adjacent. Oh, it has a little
catapult, look at that. And tiny fish, which I
don't understand but I'm excited for.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Comes with catapult, goblet, and tiny
fish.
MARISHA: Does it say 'tiny fish'?
TALIESIN: No, it's just there.
LIAM: You know, the Hobbit Lego, Gollum comes with
tiny fish.
TALIESIN: Does this one come with tiny fish?
LIAM: I don't know, but if it doesn't, I don't
want it.
MARISHA: Okay, well, Sam's kids can have that
one.
TALIESIN: This one comes with far more traditional
fare. No tiny fish.
(laughter)
MARISHA: I don't understand.
TALIESIN: It comes with a treasure chest with keys
and gold coins and another catapult and a spider,
but no tiny fish.
MARISHA: Okay, I think we have one more over
there.
LIAM: I've got another one over here.
TALIESIN: We're reaching the end, though.
MARISHA: That one, and then I think that one's the
last one.
MATT: This one here?
LIAM: This sounds like dice. It's dice!
LAURA: Give it all to me!
LIAM: No. "To Vex and Vax", "To the wonderful cast
of Critical Role." You read the one to the twins
and I'll read the one to the cast of Critical Role.
LAURA: Okie-dokie.
LIAM: Who's it from? Joshua Green. Does it say to
keep private? I don't know. Australia. Okay.
TALIESIN: Lot of Australia. What's going on down
there?
LAURA: Oh, this is literally-- this is to Vex and
Vax, from your aasimar childhood friend, Velandris
Dawncollar. I remember him. That's awesome! Oh no.
"By the way, I need your help, Vex and Vax, and the
"help of the rest of Vox Machina, and if you come
across any vampires, put a few down for me, and I
"hate those mockeries of living." You got it,
Velandris Dawncollar.
MATT: That's awesome.
LAURA: That's so cool.
LIAM: One of these-- there's four sets of dice in here.
I'm trying to figure out what's going on. Oh my
gosh. What the hell is going on? The green swirl
dice. Green swirl dice? Yeah, that says Kiki.
MARISHA: Oh yeah, these are cool.
LIAM: This also says Kiki, so that goes to Marisha
as well. Laura gets the pink one. Oh, I get none
of these. Pass this down to Laura and this to
Matt.
LAURA: Ooh, these are pretty. I don't have any
blue this color.
MARISHA and TALIESIN: Lord Fourth Wall.
LAURA: Okay, these are actually really pretty blue
dice. I've never seen any like that.
MATT: Mine's Creamsicle!
LIAM: Yeah, but what color is your die?
MARISHA: Mine's got a little brown in it.
LAURA: I have to roll. 18!
LIAM: Thank you, Joshua.
MATT: Thank you so much!
LAURA: I'm going to go put it with my dice.
MATT: This here is from Scott Ismael. All right.
MARISHA: Do you need assistance?
MATT: Maybe. It's big things.
MARISHA: Oh, jeez Louise, you guys.
MATT: Oh my god.
MARISHA: Get out of here, cardboard.
MATT: Go, box. Go.
MARISHA: No advertisement for Scotch! No! None for
you!
(laughter)
MATT: That's my girl. Not today, not tomorrow, not
ever!
LIAM: Oh no, Scotch Tape just unfollowed us.
MATT: Wow. Wow!
ALL: Whoa!
MATT: That's badass.
TALIESIN: We just need him to build a full wall of
art, now.
LAURA: We can make a gallery wall. I love gallery
walls.
TALIESIN: All those Batman posters in the
hallway.
MARISHA: Yeah! We have a bunch of movie posters in
the studio that we didn't make.
TALIESIN: They magically vanish over the next 72
hours. That could happen.
MARISHA: We should have a gallery wall. You're
really good at it! Just put Laura on it.
TALIESIN: All right, I'm down.
LIAM: Laura is the physical reincarnation of Pinterest.
MATT: Scott, this is amazing. And a perfect
example that there are many if not all crafts that
are artistic in their own way. This is a brilliant
piece of woodworking, and I am honored. That is
fantastic.
MARISHA: He made that?
MATT: He made that, yeah.
LAURA: Does it say what kind of woods it is?
MATT: I don't know. I will look back in the paper.
He does not say.
LAURA: It's beautiful.
MATT: Don't neglect the brain. Thank you so much.
That's amazing.
MARISHA: Well, that's Critmas in May, you guys.
LAURA: Thanks for joining us for another
exciting episode of Talks Machina.
(cheering)
MARISHA: Yay, we did it!
TALIESIN: And if you didn't see your package on
air, it's entirely possible that we did get it.
Packages are not necessarily opened in the order
that they are received, nor are they received in
the order that they were sent, nor were they
necessarily sent in a way that actually was
received by us. We have them. We've possibly
opened them. We're pretty sure we have them. We
don't open everything on air, so it's entirely
possible that we did get it, just because
sometimes we see a package and get curious. Like a
small woodland creature.
MATT: Or it says, "Open now or you will be cursed
for seven years."
LIAM: Or the PO box office says, "Get your ass
over here, god damn it."
TALIESIN: Yeah, they yell at us.
LIAM: "What's wrong with you people?"
MARISHA: And as always, we definitely implore you
guys to go check out the Critters' Guide to
Critmas, if you want to be involved. Check that
out first, because there's a lot of great
charities that we definitely love you guys to
check out and consider donating to, because giving
is fun and nice and makes you happy and feel
good.
LIAM: And please give to the Planetary Society
before our planet implodes.
TALIESIN: And 826LA, as always, and First Place
for Youth.
MATT: First Book, Nature Conservatory.
LAURA: My Friend's Place.
MARISHA: What was Sam's? Oh, Pablove. Yeah,
there's a lot of great charities that we love and
support. So yeah, don't feel like you have to buy
us stuff to still experience the joy of Critmas.
MATT: Nope. In fact, few things bring us more
pride than the fact that you guys are giving back
to the world and helping those who could use help
in many different facets in the name of nerdy
roleplaying games.
MARISHA: Yes, and we always read you guys' letters
where you talk about running games in schools and
libraries and stuff that you guys are doing. We
read it all, we have a big notebook that we keep in--
MATT: Multiple notebooks.
TALIESIN: It used to be a notebook. It's not a
notebook anymore.
MARISHA: We keep all of the fan letters, so know
that even if we don't say out loud, we keep and
read all of them.
TALIESIN: You all have excellent handwriting. It's
actually very impressive.
MATT: Yeah! It makes me very self-conscious about
my handwriting.
TALIESIN: Very self-conscious about my handwriting
thanks to the fandom here.
LIAM: You can keep sending pegasi to Laura Bailey,
though.
LAURA: I will gladly accept.
TALIESIN: Cue all the pegasi.
MARISHA: And amazing crocheted goods.
MATT: Thank you guys so much! You're amazing.
MARISHA: This is amazing. What does Brian always
say? Oh, and as always, it's almost Thursday.
MATT: Oh, I've got to prepare.
[upbeat music]