ALISON: All right, we are back! I'm Alison
Haislip. You are watching the live stream for Geek
&amp; Sundry and Smart Girls for MDA. With me are the
people who need no introduction, I think, to
anyone in chat, but I'm here with Critical Role.
(cheering)
ALISON: They are going to critically roll very
shortly, but first we have to take care of some
business. As you know, in our last segment, we hit
$30,000. $33,000! LootCrate matched the last
thousand, so that got us up to $34,000. I think we
are now over $35,000, so thank you, everyone at home.
TRAVIS: That's incredible.
ALISON: But the biggest surprise that I had to
tell everyone is that you guys throughout this
whole stream have been buying shirts, much like
this one, the Critical Role shirt with MDA on the
back of it. You guys have raised over $7,000 with
the shirts. We are adding that to the ticker right
now. And on top of that, Geek &amp; Sundry and Smart
Girls have decided to donate to get us up to $50,000.
(cheering)
ALISON: Critical Role, you are starting off the
counter at $50,000. We now want to get up to 60
grand before this thing ends. This stream is going
until about ten o'clock tonight. Yes, we know
that's over 24 hours. It's like a 27-hour
livestream. But check in the link. You can still
buy t-shirts like this. The link's in chat. You
can still buy shirts like this and many other
ones. You can find out how to donate there as
well. I'm going to stop talking because I know so
many people here have been waiting for you guys.
Thanks for sticking with me. I am signing off, and
I'm leaving you in the capable hands of Critical
Role. Donate, donate, donate!
MATT: You guys have been amazing. This is amazing.
We'll be playing this for the next three hours.
Come hang with us. Let me meet you over at my
table.
TRAVIS: He's got to run into the other studio.
He's got to take the elevator down to Studio-- oh, hey!
LIAM: How did you get there so fast?
MATT: Magic. Dungeon master magic. Although,
however, I'm not a dungeon master today. Today, I
am a marshal.
LAURA: (drawling) Well, all right.
MATT: Because we're playing Deadlands Reloaded.
For those of you who aren't familiar, Deadlands is
one of my favorite settings, called the Weird
West. And we're playing Deadlands Reloaded, which
brings it over into the Savage Worlds system,
which I've had to learn over the past few days. So
bear with us. It's going to be a rusty run for a
lot of us, learning and picking up things. We'll
probably going to get a shit-ton of things wrong,
and that's okay, because we're going to have fun
while doing it. Anyway. We're playing Deadlands.
And to give you guys the idea behind the world
that we're playing in, this takes place in the
19th century. Around 1864, an event called the
Reckoning transpired. What had happened is, as the
people of America began to push further west,
pushing a lot of the Native Americans out of their
land, and a bunch of terrible things happened to
their people and their tribes, a number of
disgruntled shamans and members of those tribes
came together and essentially did a giant shamanic
ritual to tear a hole between this world and this
extraplanar world of dark magic, introducing
entities called Reckoners that want to pass into
this world, and can they only do so by elevating
fear into this world. It also introduced magic. It
introduced a bunch of really weird, creepy things
into the old west, causing the Civil War to run
longer than it did in history, as well as a bunch
of other ridiculous circumstances. Nevertheless.
That is the setting that this game will take place
in. Before we get started, I want to go over a few
rules for you guys so you know what this charity
stream is all about. We have some cool things
called fate chips, which I'll get into here in a
minute. The fate chips, players and myself can use
to alter the circumstances in the game. A black
fate chip-- sorry for those of you who know the
rules, I didn't have any white chips, but they
work the same as white chips-- the black fate
chips can be spent by players to re-roll a single
trait or skill roll they're attempting to do. It's
a one-time reroll. The red chips can be used to
instead add a d6 to whatever trait or skill roll
they just made, but in using that red chip, I get
to pick one to add to my pool over here as the
marshal. A blue chip, which is probably the
strongest of them all, allows them to add that
same d6 to a trait or skill roll, but I don't get
to pick a chip out of there. That's pretty cool
for them. However, some of my more powerful
creatures or individuals in the game may have
their own set of fate chips. And if you donate,
looking at the list, you can go ahead and provide
additional fate chips to the players or me.
TRAVIS: Don't buy him shit.
(laughter)
LAURA: Or do. Donate. Buy him whatever you want.
MATT: Stack the deck however you feel it needs to
be stacked. Trust me on this one.
LIAM: Do we start out with one of each? Is that
correct?
MATT: You start with three of each. We're going to
get to that here in a moment.
LIAM: They're also delicious.
TRAVIS: Don't jump the... (dramatic pause) gun,
Liam.
(groans, laughs)
TRAVIS: Man. En fuego.
(donation music)
MATT: So. As it stands, if people want to donate
and affect the game, you can donate a hundred
bucks to give one of the players a black fate
chip. You can donate $150 to donate a red fate
chip to a player of your choice, $200 to give a
blue fate chip to the player of your choice, or
$200 to give me a fate chip of my choice, to use
against the players.
LAURA: Why do you get to--
MATT: Because I'm the marshal! I make the rules!
MARISHA: Is there ever going to be a situation
where you're like, "You know what, a black chip
will suffice. This'll be fine."
MATT: Possibly. Sometimes the rolls can be better
than additional ones. We'll see.
LIAM: Matt, I would like to point out that the
chat has typed the words "high noon" about 72,000
times in almost five minutes.
MATT: I can only assume so.
LAURA: If you donate $500, Matt will say "high
noon" whenever you want. (laughs) I'm sorry.
MATT: What have you done? What have you done,
Laura? In our final tier for this donating section
of this wonderful drive is if you donate $500 or
more, you get to add a single-sentence element to
the story currently. And the moment it comes into
play, it will be incorporated to and adjust the
current moment of the story's narrative, based on
your suggestion there. Try and be somewhat
respectful with that. We've had some crazy things
happen in the past that completely derailed the
game and that was fine for our Extra Life game,
which was crazy to begin with. This one-- if it's
a little crazy, I may tweak it a little bit to fit
into the narrative because I have to try and fit
it somehow, but I'm going to try to facilitate to
the best of my ability everything you guys suggest.
LIAM: Please don't break the universe.
MATT: Yeah. No Deck of Many Things in this,
please. That is the tier system we have in here
for this. To begin this circumstance--
LAURA: I'm so nervous!
MATT: Well, actually, before we do this, Laura?
Let's go ahead and introduce everybody's
characters, if you don't mind.
LIAM: They are so layered, and have so much
depth.
MARISHA: And we didn't all come up with them last
night.
MATT: Marisha, why don't you begin?
MARISHA: Okay. I tell them-- okay, yeah. We never
did this in Critical Role. I am Sudis. Sudis
Alifehr. I am a gypsy traveling vagabond who is
quite good at telling your fortune. Whatever the
cost, whatever the price, I can give you a little
bit of wisdom that might guide you on your way.
TRAVIS: Oh, snap. Okay. Wait, what was your name
again?
MARISHA: Sudis. Sudis Alifehr. I've got lots of
braids all through my hair, and probably like in
my mid-30s, and I also have a peg leg. Also, by
the way? Peg leg.
LIAM: Where do your ancestors hail from?
MARISHA: Romania. But it's also 1875, so who the
fuck knows what was going on then--
MATT: She's a mutt. She's an Eastern European
mutt. Grew up in the Bronx. It's awkward. Liam!
Who are you?
LIAM: Hi. My my name is Reverend Forrest Alton.
MARISHA: Hi, Reverend!
LIAM: I am from upstate New York, near the
Canadian border.
(laughter)
LIAM: I don't know what's funny about this. I am a
chaplain in the Union army. The troops usually
want me around near the medical tent, because I
think with my spiritual guidance they find peace
and quicker healing, and I've seen some terrible
things in the war, and really want the war to end.
I don't want mankind to give in to its greater
demons. But somehow I've ended up in the Dakotas, and
I can't wait to find out how.
MATT: All right. Laura. Who are you playing?
LAURA: Oh, hi there. My name's Juniper Langley,
but if you call me that I just might shoot you in
the mouth. Everyone knows me calls me Stinky
Jules. That on account of the fact that I don't
like to bathe. My mother was an escort, but I
always preferred shooting men to fucking them, so
I decided to pick up a gun and fight my way
through life.
LIAM: We're going to be the best of friends.
LAURA: You've got a pretty mouth, Rev.
LIAM: I don't know how to respond to that.
TRAVIS: Oh. I don't even want to go anymore.
(laughter)
MATT: Travis. Who are you playing?
TRAVIS: Yes, my name is Sydney Hopkins
Trivelpiece. I have come from afar to chronicle
the adventures of the Wild West while you seek
your fortune in your misdeeds. I am afraid I'm not
well-adapted to this climate, but I am quite
interested in your journeys for gold or glory.
Reverend, you look quite the outstanding
gentleman. I don't drink, but a good, clean glass
of water does sound lovely. You smell terrible,
and I'm not quite sure how I feel about you, but
if you know of anything going on that would make a
good story for me, that could really help my career.
LIAM: Question, because I have trouble scrubbing
Grog and you out of my mind, are you like a buck twenty?
TRAVIS: I'm very light. I don't eat very much. If
I'm in the sun too long, terrible things happen.
(laughter)
MATT: All righty. As a heads-up to all of you guys
watching, by the way, if your children are in the
room and you don't want them hearing a lot of
curse words, there's going to be a lot of swearing
during this game. Just a heads-up.
LAURA: Potentially. I could watch my mouth. Sorry
about that cussing earlier.
TRAVIS: Taint-sniffer.
MATT: All right, so. Let's go ahead and divvy up
some of these fate chips. I need each of you guys
to go ahead and pull three at random out of this.
TRAVIS: Just three.
LAURA: Oh wait, so we don't get to choose? All
right. I might get all blue.
MATT: Two reds and a black.
LAURA: Where's the bowl?!
MATT: Bowl's here.
LAURA: I don't care! Aw. Two blacks and a red.
LIAM: Guide my hand.
LAURA: Are there not as many blue ones as there
are--
MATT: Correct.
LAURA: Oh, well, that makes sense.
MARISHA: What just happened?
LIAM: Oh, one of each! Praise Jesus!
TRAVIS: Yeah, thank the Lord.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Man of God. You're like Russell Crowe in
Quick and the Dead, aren't you?
MARISHA: Two reds and one blue.
LIAM: I am the straight man, is what I am.
TRAVIS: You are!
MATT: Now, I'm going to go ahead and pull a few
here for myself.
LIAM: Three blues, one two three.
LAURA: Do we get to know what you got? Damn it!
TRAVIS: Really? Show us one.
MATT: Also, as a fun little quick here to start us
off, so Laura's character took one of the edges
called Veteran of the Weird West. Which gave her
some great opportunities, she's a more seasoned
character than the rest of them, she's seen more
about the world, but in doing so, some strange,
interesting circumstance in her background is
going to come into play, so I've shuffled these
cards, and I want you, Laura, to randomly select
one of them, if you don't mind. Take your pick.
LAURA: Where's that deck?!
TRAVIS: Where's that what?
LAURA: That deck. (laughs) Shut up.
TRAVIS: Said it twice, didn't get it.
MATT: Three of hearts, so looking at the table,
here.
LAURA: Oh no, what'd I get?
TRAVIS: Each card has a thing?
MARISHA: Do we get to know?
MATT: Sure, because why not? You chose the Hunted
card.
LAURA: Oh, shit.
MATT: Something or someone that you didn't finish
the job on is currently trying to find you. We'll
see how that works out in the long run.
LIAM: Wow.
MATT: (cackles)
MARISHA: I'm just saying that, you didn't need to,
I could've told you that. Just saying.
MATT: All right, so.
MARISHA: I know your gun looks cleaner than your
face.
LAURA: That's right. I like to take good care of
my weapons.
TRAVIS: You're very intimidating.
MATT: This conversation all takes place in a
carriage, as the four of you are currently riding
to your destination for your different purposes
and different reasons, which you may discuss at
your own leisure, or not, or make up at your own
leisure, or not. The four of you have been
traveling for days in this hot, humid, muggy
carriage, to your final destination of Deadwood,
South Dakota.
LIAM: (singing) Sweet little light of mine, I'm
going to let it shine.
MATT: Founded in the Deadwood Gulch at the
discovery of gold by an expedition by Custer in
1874, they had to abandon the government's
incursion to seize these gold veins when the
effects of the Reckoning, and the ensuing quakes,
began to swell in the western regions of the
United States. But word of the rich veins still
found their way to the public ears here and there,
and folks seeking quick money and an escape from
the mounting chaos of the still-dragging civil war
swarmed into the gulch to raise up this lawless
city of gold, sin, and vice. Managing to be far
enough away from politics, rumors still find their
way to this rugged town of strange goings-on in
the world, tales of slain Yankee and Southern
soldiers rising from the muck post-battle, of
shadows moving in the night to steal children. Of
mystics, calling spirits to do their bidding. Even
so, the people of Deadwood are toughened already
by harsh, untrusting reality, and such folk tales
have no place in a man's world. The sun has just
set as the denizens of Deadwood scatter to the
bars to get shitfaced.
(loud bang off-screen)
MATT: Everybody down! All right. That totally
distracted me. You all sit, after arriving,
exhausted and tired from your journey, within the
city of Deadwood, finding yourself at the
immediate display of the first place that comes to
your eyes, and seeking rest and an escape from the
worries of the world, you all step into and relax
in the Bella Union Saloon.
MARISHA: Ooh, the Bella Union!
MATT: Already got one?
OFF-SCREEN: Oh, several.
MATT: Oh no.
(laughter)
MATT: It's already started. How do I read the long
ones?
LAURA: Oh, jeez.
MATT: Pardon me a second. We've already got some
amazing donations, I have to read them all. There
we go. "All players start the scenario--" Uh-oh.
LIAM: Oh, we're making rules for us?
MATT: Apparently. You guys spend the evening
resting within the Bella Union. After drinks and
relaxation, the next morning's sun rises, and you
all realize you've all woken within the same bed
as the others. Not necessarily recalling what the
evening before entailed, but.
LAURA: That was fun.
MARISHA: Get off me.
LIAM: I don't even drink. How did that happen?
TRAVIS: Nothing, nothing.
LAURA: Sydney--
MATT: It's at this time you all realize you've
slept in rather late in the day, as it's now
apparently-- (McCree voice) It's high noon.
TRAVIS: Son of a bitch! How long would it take?
LIAM: Hey, Marshal? I don't know the rules really
at all in this game, but I think I read somewhere
that if I sin, I get negatives? So I don't know
that I've sinned, but I might have sinned. I don't know.
LAURA: I think you sinned.
MARISHA: Wait, can I do an onus check on him to
figure out what we did?
MATT: Hold on, I'm trying to keep up here, guys!
(laughter)
MATT: Mark down you each have a joker card now.
That can be used instead of a poker chip.
LAURA: What's a joker card?
LIAM: We've got to establish the rules before we
blow them up, folks.
MATT: I know, it's all good, it's all good.
TRAVIS: Somebody throw me a pen back there.
MATT: We'll begin the game here in a moment, once
I get through these. You guys-- oh, and I also
receive two random joker cards. So I have two
jokers. So. Those joker cards can be used in place
of a poker chip. We'll say the black on that one.
LAURA: A black poker chip?
MATT: All right, let me reset here and make sure I
get to the other ones.
(laughter)
MATT: Oh, and Travis, you go ahead and get a black
chip.
TRAVIS: Yes!
LAURA: Oh, damn it!
MATT: All awkwardly waking up at (McCree voice)
high noon (normal) you awkwardly gather your
things, finding yourself, the music in the
distance as the Bella Union is beginning to come
to life again. You can hear a piano playing and
some laughter, you hear some loud carousing on the
other side of your door to the inn, the second
floor of which you now currently are awakening.
TRAVIS: I do hate to trouble you. Does anyone see
the chamberpot in the room? I am afraid I have a
rather-- need.
LAURA: Lean your shit out the window.
TRAVIS: Out the window?
LAURA: Yeah, that's what they do here.
TRAVIS: Right. Okay.
LAURA: I'm going to go get some whisky.
MARISHA: This is a good place to actually make
good money off of fortune telling. I'm going to go
downstairs.
TRAVIS: Reverend?
LIAM: Yes?
TRAVIS: Do you remember what happened last night?
LIAM: I don't. I remember someone pouring
something into my glass, I assumed it was
lemonade. I need to take a walk and do a little
thinking. See you later?
MATT: As you guys step out at your own individual
pace, you pass by a gentleman who's on the
second-floor balcony staring down into the main
thoroughfare of the Bella Union--
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MATT: --a dark maroon coat and pants, short,
grey-ish hair, an intense dark mustache, and a
very, very angular face. He looks angrily down
amongst the people. And you can see at the tables,
the gambling tables are alight this early in the
day, and there appears to be a very intense game
of cards going on, and people are gathering
around, looking to see what the next stage is
going to be during this game. You guys go down to
find yourselves a drink?
LAURA: Shit, I want to watch the game.
MATT: Drinks first, or game first?
LAURA: Drink, and then watch the game, because I
really want to see the game. Fast, fast. Give me
some whiskey.
MATT: All right. You guys each throw a dollar
down. You go ahead and get yourself a very fine
pouring of some whisky.
TRAVIS: A sarsaparilla for me, if you don't mind.
MATT: The guy at the bar hands the drinks over and
goes, "Yeah, you would want a sarsaparilla,
"wouldn't you? Tell you what. It's on the house."
TRAVIS: That's very kind of you! There is chivalry
alive in the west!
LIAM: Could I have a black coffee, please?
MATT: "Black coffee? That can be provided."
MARISHA: Jules, did you spike our drinks last
night? Was that you?
LAURA: I don't know what you're talking about.
MARISHA: Never mind.
MATT: You drink your fine, fine alcohol, which
enables you to have a black chip.
LAURA: Oh, shit! I can't catch!
MATT: So. As you guys begin to gather around this
poker game, you look down and you can see folks
are tense and looking over. They're starting to
cheer. Some folks are making their own side bets
off the circumstance. The visible layer of tobacco
smoke is beginning to cloud the upper atmosphere
of the Bella Union. It's very palpable at this
point. Looking in, you can see four men at a table
that are all very intent, and one gentleman who's
very well dressed, similar in fashion to you. A
very nice light gray suit, a very well-trimmed
goatee, balding on top, with very short-cut hair
on the sides, and a little pair of spectacles at
the end of his nose. He's looking at his cards
with a big smile. Everyone starts putting the last
of their bets into the center.
LAURA: What's the other guy look like?
MATT: There are two other gentlemen you can see,
that both look greasy, like they haven't really
slept in a long while, covered in dirt and crud,
but they seem to have a large cache of chips at
their side. Probably some of the various claim
workers out here outside of the town. And you see
one of the gentlemen is wearing a top hat, similar
to the one that you're wearing, with a fine, long
mustache, handlebar out, a portly, older
gentleman, looking at his hand. "Oh, hell. I'm
"going in."
LAURA: He's bluffing. That one's bluffing.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MATT: One of them goes "all right!" and pushes
in.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Two of them are in? Two of the three?
MATT: The inspiration of seeing all this energy,
you being away, inspires you to go ahead. Have
yourself another black chip. You guys watch as
suddenly they all throw their cards down. Full house.
Pair of queens. Got a bunch of different cards,
and all of a sudden it comes to the well-dressed
character, who looks a little nervous now, and
goes, "Hmm. Straight flush." And everyone goes--
big upset. Loud uproar. You can see now as the guy
with the long mustache goes, "Oh, hell." Throws
his cards down and gets up from the table angrily
and turns around to walk away. The two other
gentlemen at the table glance out the side of
their eye as one of the guys you see at the edge
of this table game, an older, hunched-over
gentleman with glasses at the end of his nose and
a smearing of black powder across his face goes,
"I love poker! It's the most crazy game ever!"
(laughter)
MATT: "Do that?! It makes no sense!" At which
point, one of the guys at the table goes, "You're
"right, it doesn't make sense. This guy's a
cheater! We have a goddamn fucking cheater here!"
LAURA: That's right! He's a fucking cheater, I can
tell!
TRAVIS: I don't think so. I believe he had what
they call the nuts.
MATT: "Thank you very much. That man knows what
he's talking about. I'm not cheating! You've seen
"me play cards in front of you! This has been an
amazing game."
LAURA: Look up his sleeves! That one's cheating.
MATT: At which point you can see one of the guys
who lost in the game immediately goes for a
swinging punch towards the guy holding the-- who
won the actual last pot. And with that, whack!
Cracks it right across his face.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MATT: "All right!" he says as he punches him down.
Suddenly a giant brawl begins to emerge in the
center of this room. You can see people throwing
hooks left and right. The guy who currently won
the game is trying to grab the chips he has off to
the side as you can see the two guys at the front
of the guard of the Bella Union rushing in and
trying to hold folks down.
MARISHA: While the brawl breaks out, Sudis starts
trying to palm a few coins.
LAURA: I jump in the fight.
MARISHA: Oh, no! Oh, no, don't hurt me! Grabbing
all the coins I can. I'm innocent, oh!
LAURA: Yeah, I punched him.
MATT: Seeing this chaos...
LAURA: Oh, shit!
MATT: That was a good catch. Meant to be. All this
is breaking down. You can see punches going left
and right. People falling down. The guy who had
his chips in his arm gets socked again and lobs
them into the table. Folks start scrambling for
them.
MARISHA: Oh, no! Let me help you pick up your
chips!
MATT: Go ahead and make an agility trait check, if
you don't mind.
MARISHA: Okay, so I roll a d6. I roll 2d6, is that
what I do? And take the higher? I rolled five both times.
MATT: Five both times? All right. You manage to
pocket what would be about $200 worth of poker
chips from the ground. You start getting in the
fray there. All right, Stinky Jules. Who are you
going for? You can see a bunch of different
people.
LAURA: I'm going for the one that was cheating!
MATT: The one that was cheating? All right.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MATT: All right! (laughs) This black chip goes to
the new thief. That's the chip you find.
LAURA: Whoa, she got two of them?
MATT: That one is off the table. All right, so the
guy's: "Please, I'm just trying-- I won it fair
"and square!" Go ahead and make a fighting roll.
LAURA: Okay. What is that?
MATT: Whatever your fighting dice is, plus-- Your
fighting skill. Roll 2d6 and take the higher of
the two.
LAURA: Oh, shit. Two. Fuck.
MATT: Two? You swing towards him and he dodges out
of the way. "Oh, dear!" Grabs what he can of the
poker chips and darts out of the saloon.
MARISHA: Can I try and trip him?
MATT: Sure! As you're grabbing things?
MARISHA: I want to reach out and grab his leg, see
if I can trip him while I'm picking up--
MATT: Go ahead and make a strength check.
MARISHA: Four. Four again. I don't know! Doubles,
doubles.
MATT: A four? You reach out and you grab towards
his leg, and he trips over as you yank out the
ankle from underneath him. He goes spilling. All
the chips go scattering onto the front of the
Bella Union. And you can see, while the guards are
currently inside dealing with this fight that's
broken out, there's nobody outside to guard it. A
couple people on the street look over and, "Is he
"all right? Sir, are you all right?" They start
coming towards him to his aid. He turns around and
looks at you and goes, "Why would you do that?"
MARISHA: Well-- ow! You stepped on my finger! Ow!
TRAVIS: I would like to rush over to him and offer
him asylum in our room. Sir, you are impeccably
dressed. Please, follow me to my room upstairs.
Quickly!
MATT: "Thank you. Help me gather these things,
please, before they take my hard-earned winnings!"
You guys begin gathering up into the hats, getting
all the poker chips into the various hats. The
guys who were now brawling have been calmed down
at this point. You can see now the guards have
their pistols out. One of them fires twice into
the ceiling of the Bella Union, sending dust and
little bits of plaster debris to fall. All the
fight ends as one of the guys is now shouting,
"Everyone! Calm your shit. And you're all kicked
out for now while we assess what the hell just
"went down." You see the man who was looking over
the top of the balcony now has risen up over the
edge and goes, "Thank you, my good man. All of
you, understand we only want civilized folks here
"at the Bella Union. The man won fair and square.
Give him his earnings. And if I see any of you try
"and throw a punch in here again, you're banned from
gambling in my establishment."
MARISHA: What is 'civilized'?
TRAVIS: It means orderly. The opposite of chaos.
MATT: As you begin walking upstairs, both of you
carrying your hats and his nose in the air a bit,
walking with you, giving you a smile, and,
"Thanks, brother. I appreciate the assist."
TRAVIS: Not to worry.
MATT: As you pop upstairs, you, keeping watch,
feel a strange sensation touching your left
shoulder. You glance over and see a wild monkey. A
small monkey that curls up next to you.
(chittering)
MARISHA: Can I do a notice check to see if it's a
real monkey or where the fuck the monkey came from?
MATT: Go ahead and make a notice check, yes.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MARISHA: All right, I will!
LAURA: Whose shoulder is it on? Is it on his or on
hers?
MATT: It's her shoulder. All right. It is indeed a
real monkey. It is a straight-up real monkey.
MARISHA: Wait. If I roll a six, do I roll again?
On all checks?
MATT: On all checks. If you roll a maximum of the
die, you roll again and you add it to.
MARISHA: Nine.
MATT: There's your black chip, by the way. Oh,
man. You guys are going to be fine in combat when
we get to that. So. You at this point look over
and see the monkey. This is a live monkey, and as
you look in, it reaches in and grabs the edge of
your earlobe and whispers into your ear, "Do not
"worry. I've got your back."
MARISHA: (yelps)
(laughter)
MATT: You guys look over. There's no monkey.
MARISHA: I take him and I try and spike him on the
ground.
LAURA: Hey, Sue? What's your problem?
LIAM: You've had enough. Let's put this aside.
MARISHA: Is he still there?
MATT: As you throw the monkey to the ground, he
goes-- (angry noise) Climbs back up onto your
shoulder and says, "Why would you do that to me?
I'm here to guide you!"
LAURA: I think that shit I gave her last night is
fucking her up.
MARISHA: Monkey. You see?
LAURA: That's a shoulder, hon.
LIAM: You want to maybe get some fresh air?
MARISHA: I pet the monkey a bit.
TRAVIS: Oh dear. I'm afraid she's lost her beans.
MATT: As you're walking, you pass by the guy who
had the nice top hat and the mustache who's
sitting there, and he has an apron on and he looks
like, sleeves rolled up, a working fellow in the
camp in his later forties, and you hear him mutter
to himself, as I get a red chip, "That fella damn
"well cleared out the Gem last week and looks like
he's taking this place for all it's worth. Last
"time I go gambling in a while."
LAURA: So he was cheating. We weren't just saying
that so we could punch him?
MATT: "I'm only assuming he's cheating. He came
into this town no more than a couple weeks back,
"and damn well took all the Gem was worth before
coming here a week later."
LAURA: Was he wearing all them fancy clothes when
he got to town?
MATT: "He was."
TRAVIS: Sir, do you happen to know his name?
MATT: You're walking up the stairs away from this.
You're actually helping this gentleman up to put
stuff in the room. He goes, "I don't know his full
name, rightly so, but from what I've heard, he
refers to himself as Simon. Yeah."
LAURA: Sounds like a shit.
MATT: "Doesn't he? Sounds like a northern chap.
I've got to go, well, see what else I can sell to
"make up for this debt from today. Excuse me."
Turns around and says, "By the way, if any of you
"guys want to come by my place, we also have poker
there. Not quite as upper-class as this, but we
"have fine drinks, cheaper than you'd find at this
place."
LAURA: Where's your place?
MATT: "Oh, it's down past the main thoroughfare to
the left. It's by the alley side there." And he
adjusts his hat.
LAURA: You got a picture on the outside of that
place there? What's it look like?
MATT: "The Number Ten Saloon is what you're
looking for. Nice fine sign, yes. Recommend it.
"Any time." And he turns around and starts to
leave.
LIAM: You seem troubled. Are you carrying a heavy
load?
MARISHA: No, he's not very heavy at all, actually.
He's only like five pounds or so. (sighs)
LIAM: I've seen many soldiers shell-shocked in
war--
MARISHA: I wander off and I start speaking off in
my own language towards the sky.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MARISHA: All right.
(laughter)
LIAM: I give her her space. I'm a little nervous.
MARISHA: What do I call you?
MATT: "Call me Manatou."
MARISHA: Manatou. Okay. Okay, Manatou. All right.
MATT: Curls back up into your hair and seemingly
becomes weightless for a moment.
LIAM: Into her hair?
MATT: You don't sense him there. It's like he
vanished.
LIAM: He was behind your ear the whole time.
(laughter)
MATT: Stacking the deck over here for me, guys.
LAURA: Oh, shit, really?
LIAM: You fuckers.
LAURA: Why, why? Be nice to him so he'll help us.
MATT: You make your way up to the room and the
gentleman goes, "I greatly appreciate this. Thank
"you so much for your aid. If I could have my
chips, please."
TRAVIS: Oh, yes, of course. Hold out your hat and
I'll transfer them. That looks about it. There you go.
MATT: He's going to go ahead and look keenly into
your hat. I'm going to use a chip for that.
TRAVIS: Do I roll something?
MATT: Yeah, go ahead and roll-- do you have a
stealth skill? I think you roll a straight agility
check. Just go agility. See how quickly you can
maneuver this.
LIAM: He does have a copy of "You're Never Weird
On The Internet".
TRAVIS: That's a six, and a two, so eight.
MATT: Okay.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
LAURA: All right, he got all his--
MATT: "I greatly appreciate your help. Everything
appears to be good here. And what is your name?"
TRAVIS: Oh, I am Sydney Hopkins Trivelpiece, at
your service. Lovely meeting you.
MATT: Shakes your hand. It's a limp shake.
TRAVIS: You seem to be very good at this game.
MATT: "Well, I'm also new here. I can see by your
appearance that you also are new. Your clothes are
"far too clean to have been here."
TRAVIS: Yes, it's very difficult in this climate.
MATT: "Yes, it's dusty, even for winter out here.
Yes, well, Simon Tyrell."
TRAVIS: Simon. Absolute pleasure. Sir, how did you
get to be so good at that game? What is it you do here?
MATT: "Here, I'm finding my way. I'm a retired
business manager from Boston, but I came a long
"way at the behest of my cousin and I heard that
there was quite a booming gold trade in this city,
"so I came to, after building my luck up and
getting a small cache of money, realizing that I
"had a knack at this game called poker, and
apparently poker here can be very high-stakes,
"and, well, so far so good."
TRAVIS: Wonderful, you seem to be quite successful
at-- poker, you say? Goodness. If I may say, if
you find anyone having particular luck in that
gold boom, would you mind sending word my way? I
write to a very famous publication. I could put
you among the stars.
MATT: "Happily, happily. Good to hear from that.
We shall be in touch. Where are you-- are you
"staying here in this--"
TRAVIS: Yes, this room, with a few traveling
compatriots of mine. Watch out for some. Others
are smelly. Some are trustworthy and others are
quite strange.
MATT: "Right. Okay. I appreciate that. We'll be in
touch." And he goes to put his hat on. (chuckles)
"Close." Leaves the room, closes the door behind
him. You have got $60 worth of chips that you
managed to pull out of that, and a red chip to
Laura.
LAURA: Yes! (growls) Thanks, friends.
MATT: So. You guys regather yourselves. You've had
a bit of chaos in your--
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
LAURA: All right! This is a good day.
MARISHA: We're going to go places, Manatou, me and
you, bud. Me and you.
TRAVIS: I come down as well after he leaves.
LIAM: I've been making my way through the bar and
I'm sure there's some bloodied eyes and some teeth
knocked out, so I'll administer what limited first
aid I know.
MATT: Okay. Go ahead and make a medicine check.
Healing, this would be healing.
LIAM: Okay. Okay.
MATT: d8 and a d6, take the higher of the two.
LIAM: Okay, now. Two fives!
MATT: The first guy you walk up to is one of the
guys in the bar fight. You can see his eye's
fairly swollen, looks like he has a cut lip and
one of his arms is-- he's massaging a heavy,
swollen bruise on the side. As you approach him,
he's sitting at a table. What do you do?
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
LIAM: I say, all right. I have some bandages here.
No sudden movements, I just want to help you out.
Trouble leads to trouble, friend.
MATT: "Look, I don't mean any disrespect, here,
I'm just weird with medical stuff. I prefer to be
"holistic. Heal on my own."
LAURA: I'm with you, son.
MATT: "That's right."
LIAM: Well, it's funny. If you want to forego the
physical, I do have a little know-how with the
spiritual. Would you prefer we take it in that
direction?
MATT: "That's even stranger. I'm not going to
lie--" And he leans in to you and goes, "Sorry, I
"noticed you carousing with that there foreigner,
and I saw her speaking to the spirits and mumbling
"to herself, and--" You don't actually hear, you're just
out of earshot of this, unless you want to make a
notice check to overhear. Make a notice check,
actually.
MARISHA: Sure, yeah, notice check.
MATT: Black chip for Laura. They're loading you
up.
LAURA: Oh shit, I can't catch for shit.
MARISHA: Nine.
MATT: You overhear this even from a distance with
your keen ears. He says, "I have friends that come from
"eastern Europe, distant family member, we'll say.
There's something about her accent that's wrong."
MARISHA: That's probably true. That's accurate.
LIAM: I'm no man or woman's judge. I don't know
her. I'm happy to help you. You seem like you need
succor and aid, and I will give that to you. I
wouldn't be too quick to judge her.
MARISHA: Can I size him up from a distance? Get a
bead on him?
MATT: Make another notice check, and you, make a
persuasion check.
LIAM: That's-- the fuck is that?
MARISHA: Five.
LAURA: Hey, Rev! I could use some succor and aid.
LIAM: Six.
MATT: Okay, he goes, "All right. Go ahead and see
what you can tend to." As you start tending to
him, he starts whispering to you to the side. You
try and size him up. He looks like a brutish guy
who probably works in the mine quite a lot and has
made a lot of gold on the side that he probably
lost a bulk of in recent days. He's very
noticeably frustrated by the circumstance.
LIAM: Rub my hands together and lay them on the
arm and say, "Our Father, who art in heaven--"
MATT: "Oh, this religion shit."
LIAM: And however this game works, because I don't
know, I would like to heal him using--
MATT: Okay, make a faith check.
LIAM: Faith check, yeah.
MATT: You add a d12.
LIAM: Oh my god, I never use 12s when we play
D&amp;D.
I think it's not that one. It's this big
round one, yeah. I'd like to use a chip. This is a
trait check, right?
MATT: Yeah, if you'd like to use a black chip. Go
ahead, toss it to me. Thank you.
LIAM: What do I roll? Both again?
MATT: Just reroll the 12, yeah.
LIAM: Ten.
MATT: Okay. That's with a raise, too. As you touch
your hands, "I understand... What the
"fuck is going on?" You can see as this light
envelops him. People in the room glance over with
a strange look in their eyes.
LIAM: I know. I questioned it at first as well.
But the Lord provides.
MATT: You see tears well up in his face. He's
like, "I believe--"
LIAM: You can give in and no man will judge you.
MATT: "I'm sorry. It's just really scary these days.
There's a lot going on. I've got to get out of
"here. I don't want them to see me cry." And he
stands up and stomps out of the Bella Union.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
LIAM: Be with God, all right?
(laughter)
LIAM: Thus spaketh the Lord.
MARISHA: Can I sit down in the corner and pull out
my tarot cards? Kind of shuffle them.
MATT: Sure. You--
MARISHA: Fortunes! Come and get your fortunes
told.
MATT: Make a general persuasion check for the room
if you could. You find your way back down. The
gentleman you guys saw who went upstairs, at this
point, has now exited from the upstairs room, down
the stairs. He gives a smile to the room and then
leaves out the front of the Bella Union as well.
You follow suit, only but a few paces behind.
MARISHA: Four.
MATT: You see at the far end of the room, a--
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MATT: --rough-looking gentlemen that goes, "All
right! I got-- I'll go ahead and get myself a--"
(laughter)
LAURA: I just like the challenge of it.
MATT: Blue chip to everybody but me.
(cheering)
MARISHA: We love you, whoever you are. Oh jeez.
LAURA: Someday.
TRAVIS: You beautiful people.
MATT: The man walks over and says, "I don't really
believe in all this mumbo jumbo, but you look like
"a nice enough lady. Here." He passes you a dollar.
It's one little crinkled-up piece of paper.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MARISHA: All right. Can I do a notice check on
him? Can I get a profile on him?
MATT: Travis.
TRAVIS: Yes. (chip dropping on floor) Shit.
MATT: Blue. (laughter) It's going to be rerolls
forever.
MARISHA: Three. Not good at all.
MATT: You take your time putting the cards out in
front, and eventually you see his eyes start
wandering. He starts looking around. Loses
attention. He goes, "You know what? Keep the
"dollar. I learned my lesson." He stands up and
walks away.
LAURA: Wait, wait, wait!
MARISHA: It's fine. I made the dollar.
LAURA: You make money off of cards, and it's not
gambling?
MARISHA: How else am I supposed to make a living?
Yeah.
MATT: It's at this point, as you guys are talking
about this, a gentleman who's been standing in the
far back with a long-brimmed, dark hat, a very
well-kept mustache and goatee, a long, dark coat
that ends about waist-height, walks over. You hear
the jangling of his spurs as he approaches.
MARISHA: I mean, these cards. They're still gambling,
really. Cards are cards.
LAURA: Shh. It's a fancy guy.
MATT: "Good day, ma'am. I don't mean the bother you
much, but I couldn't help but notice you have a
"mind for the mystic."
MARISHA: Of course, I do. I can't help but notice
that you have a mind for darkness, it seems.
LAURA: If you want her to read your fortune, I can
do that too. I'm real good at it! I charge less
than she does, but I do it even better!
MARISHA: We're friends. We're not competing. Very
well. Please, sit down.
MATT: "Let me introduce myself."
LAURA: All right, sure.
MATT: "My name is Sheriff Bullock.
LAURA: Sheriff?
MARISHA: Ooh. I'm so excited.
MATT: "There's been some strange things going on
in the town here and not a lot of people are
"willing to offer help. The one priest we had that
was doing the best in this town has been ailing
"recently. I figure, maybe we can find folks with
other specializations."
TRAVIS: That's you.
LIAM: What is his name?
MATT: "What, the ailing fellow?"
LIAM: Yes.
MATT: "Well, you think you can be of aid to him?"
LIAM: I definitely think I could provide aid to
him.
MATT: "All right."
LIAM: Is he poorly?
MATT: "He's been poorly for some time. A madness
is taking to him. You know, his eyes are starting
"to wander--"
TRAVIS: Madness!
MARISHA: What kind of madness do you speak of?
MATT: "Dementia. But that's not why I came here,
though. But we'll talk. All right, let me say that
"there's been a series of mysterious deaths at the
time."
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MATT: "Excuse me, sir. We're talking."
(laughter)
MATT: Nearby table, guy who seems to have won kind of
shrinks down. "Sorry."
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MATT: "Thank you. I appreciate your
understanding."
LIAM: Not that sorry.
(laughter)
MATT: "But once every few weeks, we found bodies
turn up in the outskirts of town. Three folk,
"normal denizens here of Deadwood torn asunder,
ripped to shreds by some sort of creature. The
"docs had a few looks and sees no more than I do
about the logistics of it, but yeah, one of my--
"my wife who had just come to town with my son was
one of these victims."
LIAM: Are we talking about an animal here,
Sheriff?
MATT: "Well, you'd have to talk to doc to get the real
report, but I say it's an animal. Many folks here
"think it's some sort of a bear."
LAURA: So what you're need is some kind of, like,
guns or something for hire?
MATT: "Maybe."
LAURA: All right.
TRAVIS: Your wife or your son was a victim?
MATT: "My wife."
TRAVIS: I'm so sorry to hear that.
MATT: "I'm watching my son, still. It happens.
Terribly. But that's something I've got to deal
"with, not you. Anyway, (sighs) if you could be of
some help, maybe look around, see if your mystic
"knowledge could make out something we couldn't."
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MATT: "Sir, if you don't, I will take you down to
jail."
LIAM: It's really getting to be a little rude.
Really.
MARISHA: It's very loud in here. You are looking for
mystic properties. Are you looking for a peek into
your future, perhaps?
MATT: "No, I don't necessarily believe in that
stuff. It kind of worries me, honestly."
MARISHA: You don't have to believe. That's
what I always say.
MATT: There is a loud, calamitous crash sound as
the door that was partially closed at this point
smashes in front of you. Wood splinters go
streaming outward and you see what appears to be a
small fluff, a spherical bear form, roll in
and stop. Bright-eyed. A little bear cub.
"Hold it! Kill it!" You see the guards
start pulling their guns out and start aiming it
down at the bear cub.
MARISHA: No!
LIAM: Wait. It's a baby! Wait! We'll return it to
the wild.
MATT: The Sheriff who's had his hand on the side
of his holster goes, "This is a wild animal."
LAURA: Is this that damn creature that's been
tearing people up?
MARISHA: This is not the creature. It's too
small!
LIAM: It doesn't look like it can tear up a sack
of flour!
TRAVIS: It's a bit small...
LAURA: Maybe its mama is looking for him, tearing
people up to get to him. That's my--
LIAM: I'm going to crouch down and hold my hands
out.
LAURA: --investigational deduction.
MATT: You can go ahead and make a smarts check.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
(laughter)
LAURA: That's right.
LIAM: Is that for her?
MATT: For you.
LIAM: For me.
LAURA: I got a three there.
MATT: Do you want to reroll?
LAURA: Smarts. No.
(laughter)
MATT: This is a small bear. That's about as far as
you can get on that one.
LAURA: Hmm, it's a small bear.
MATT: You go ahead and reach down for the bear.
The bear comes forward and sniffs you.
LIAM: Come here, nugget.
MATT: A small voice at the side of your ear goes,
"Your destination is elsewhere, Reverend." You
turn around; there's nothing there.
TRAVIS: Second thoughts?
MATT: Kind of rub your ear.
MARISHA: What's wrong? This thing-- I don't know,
you frightened? Please.
MATT: The bear-- for you, Laura.
LAURA: (gasps) I caught it!
MATT: The bear sees you and goes, (bear cub
sounds) and passes around you and goes straight
over towards Stinky Jules and just starts rubbing
on your knee.
LAURA: Oh shit. What the fuck is this thing
doing?!
MARISHA: He likes you! Oh, you've made a friend!
LAURA: All right, all right.
MATT: It starts licking your hand, you're like
ugh. Bears.
LAURA: I guess I pet it. I mean, if it wants to be
with me, I ain't going to stop it, you know, but--
LIAM: But bears?
LAURA: I can't give you anything but
scraps, so you better get used to that.
TRAVIS: That's quite the responsibility, I hope
you know.
LAURA: You and me, kid.
MATT: A voice creeps in once again into your ear,
Reverend, but it's softer. It goes, "You're on the
"right path. Follow the leads. It will lead you to
your salvation."
LIAM: Follow the leads?
MATT: "Follow the leads." And you reach over
again. There's no source of the voice. You've been
a man of faith for a long time, but nothing's ever
spoken to you before.
MARISHA: Do I notice if this is similar to my
talking monkey?
MATT: No, he's just looks like he's trying to feel
his ear.
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: So.
LAURA: Do I get to keep the bear, though?
MATT: I don't know. How good are you with an
animal? The Sheriff goes, "I mean, respectfully,
"there's a lot of weird shit going down in this
town right now. And a lot of it has happened in
"the past five minutes since I walked in to talk to
you."
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MATT: "Sir! I warned you!" And the Sheriff goes
over and grabs the guy at the side table who's
been far too excited and screaming outward. He
says, "Sheriff, what are you doing?" He's like,
"I'm taking you down to go ahead and
clean up you-- I can smell the alcohol on your
"breath!" And he drags him out and you see as
Sheriff Bullock drags this poor card player out
into the street past you guys.
TRAVIS: Sheriff Bullock! Was there a particular
area that these attacks were taking place?
MATT: "Go talk to the doc! He's your best bet."
TRAVIS: The doc, yes.
MATT: He drags him out.
TRAVIS: Perhaps we should go find this doc?
MARISHA: All right.
LIAM: Sheriff, can you point me towards your
reverend, your ailing reverend? What's his name again?
MATT: Trying to look it up right now, actually. I
didn't have his name written down. We're going to
find it real fast here, thanks to IMDB.
LAURA: (gasps) Oh, he's a real guy!
MATT: "That'd be Reverend H. W. Smith. And the
doc's taking care of him right now, so that'd be
"your best bet."
LIAM: Oh, one-stop shopping, everybody.
MATT: "Indeed. I'm going to take this guy--" And
the guy's still fighting him on the ground, going,
"Sheriff, put me down! Put me down!" We hit 60k,
guys!
(cheering)
LAURA: Already? What the?
MARISHA and LAURA: All right!
MATT: Let me go ahead and say as part of that,
just to kind of pause here while you guys are
deciding your next path, we're going to go ahead
and put up-- we're going to have the community decide
on an NPC name that's going to find its way into a future
game of Critical Role.
TRAVIS: (gasps) Shut the fuck up. Are you
serious?
MATT: So we're going to go with that one. If we
manage to hit 65k before this game's done, we'll
also have a boss creature of some kind that I'll
design with you guys in the near future as well.
LIAM: Abjurist Pissbucket Shitwalla.
LAURA: (laughs)
MARISHA: Shitwalla?
TRAVIS: We're going to need help!
MATT: So let's get keep that in mind. All right,
so Bullock drags the guy off in the distance. You
all leave the Bella Union. Now it's mid-afternoon.
It's hot, even though it's winter time--
LAURA: It feels so good out here!
TRAVIS: Could we find our way quickly, please?
MATT: --you have carts going by, the ground is
muddy itself from a recent rainfall. What do you
guys want to do?
TRAVIS: Is there any horse shit on the ground?
MATT: There's plenty of horse shit.
TRAVIS: I really would care to stay out of it.
LAURA: But before I go, I want to get some whisky
in a to-go cup.
MATT: Fair enough. You go ahead and get yourself
some whisky and your canteen--
LAURA: That's my jug. That's right.
TRAVIS: A red Dixie cup.
LIAM: Is that a native word? Togo?
LAURA: That's right. And I go find the doc.
MATT: Okay. Do you want to make a street smarts
roll? Go for it.
LAURA: Oh shit.
LIAM: The Sheriff pointed us there, didn't he?
MARISHA: To the doc?
MATT: He said where the doc was and he was going
to point and he ended up--
TRAVIS: Is it street wise or smarts?
MATT: Street smarts. Sorry.
LAURA: What if we don't have that ability?
TRAVIS: I got it!
LAURA: You have street ones?
TRAVIS: I'm a journalist!
LAURA: Oh, that's true. Reroll that shit! We need
to find the doc!
TRAVIS: Okay, I'd like to reroll with a black.
MATT: Go for it.
TRAVIS: That's better. Four!
MATT: Four, okay! It takes you about an hour or so
asking around, but you do manage to lead the group
to the doc's place. As you come up to it, it's a
really, really simple-looking hovel that's jammed
against a stable, but everyone seems to point to
say where's the doc, and on the outside you do
see what appears to be a wooden carving of the
classic medical symbol over the doorway.
TRAVIS: Yeah, Sydney Hopkins Trivelpiece here. I
was just curious if the the doctor was within?
(nervous laugh)
MATT: You knock on the door?
TRAVIS: Yes.
MATT: A moment passes. All of a sudden, the door
opens and you see an eye peeking through a pair of
old, dirty glasses, big grey hair and a greyish
moustache goes, "Who the hell's coming to my door?"
TRAVIS: This one. She was quite rude.
LAURA: Hey there.
MATT: "I'm awfully busy, all right? We got
something I'm working on--"
LAURA: I know. People getting hit, getting
attacked right? Shit like that?
MATT: "Yeah, I can't take any more patients for
now. All I have is work!"
LAURA: We don't got no patients for you. Shit. Pay
attention!
MARISHA: We were sent here by the sheriff. He told
us to find you.
LIAM: You have a man of the cloth here as well and
I've come to help.
In ways that you are not accustomed to.
MATT: "Well, help is always welcome. Come on in,
come on in." He opens the door. You guys come
inside, and there is a terrible smell. A terrible
smell-- to you, Liam, right there.
LAURA: I don't smell anything.
MATT: Yeah, you're used to the scent. You come
inside and a smell of decay and death permeates
the entire place.
LIAM: That's worse than you.
MATT: You can see, across the way, there are two
tables with two current injured individuals, one
of which seems to be a man who is wrapped up and
missing an arm and has been wrapped up, and he's
just rolling around in a feverish state. You also
see a man dressed in long, black robes who is
humming to himself as he's writhing in place. One
arm is curled up across his torso. To the other
side of the room, as you violently vomit into your
hat, you see what appear to be a number of tables
that have piles of viscera.
LAURA: Piles of viscera.
MATT: Of what look to be once-human bodies that
are bloodied and flies are gathering.
LAURA: Gross. That's foul.
MATT: The doctor turns around, now. You can see
him, sweaty, his long, crimped grey hair there.
"All right. You said you're here to help."
LIAM: Who's who here, doc?
MATT: "This here's Gerald." He points to the guy
who's having a fever and says, "Had to amputate
"his arm, 'cause the damn fucking fool got it torn
off in an accident with some machinery."
LAURA: I go over and give him some whisky. The
feverish fella.
MATT: Okay. He's partially asleep, and as you pull
out the whisky, he goes, "What-- what--"
LAURA: Have some whisky. Make you feel better.
MATT: "Okay." Puts up his arm and grabs the
whisky. It spills out a little bit. He's like,
(gulping).
LAURA: All right, that's enough!
MATT: "Thank you."
LIAM: Doc, is this one worse off?
MATT: "He'll be fine, he's just making his way
through the fevers. I gave him some sedatives. He
"should be okay. More worried about the Reverend.
Reverend Smith over there appears to have some
"sort of a brain tumor pushing on him. There's not
much we can do about that right now, unfortunately."
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MATT: The guy who's now drunk goes, "All right!"
(laughter)
MATT: "That's some good whisky. Thank you." Passes
out at the table.
LIAM: Let me see him. At the very least, I can
offer him the word of the Lord.
MATT: You walk over to the Reverend. The
Reverend's sitting there, muttering to himself,
singing low under his breath. Chip of my choice.
TRAVIS: Oh, snap.
LIAM: Pick the shitty one. I place a hand on his
head with the thumb right here, right at the
temple. Reverend Smith.
MATT: "Yes, do you speak? The Lord, I can see the
light. The Lord has brought you to me. That's correct."
LIAM: It's not your time.
MATT: "When it's our time, it's time to go."
MARISHA: Yeah, I don't know. It might be his time.
Just saying.
LIAM: Give me a minute.
MATT: "I appreciate your solace. You're a kind
soul, I can see. Thank you." And you can see one
eye's wandering off to the side, and the other
eye's just staring out before him. He feels your
presence, but he's in a rough place.
LIAM: I pray to the Lord. I will heal this man.
Miracle.
MATT: You spend two more power points.
LIAM: Okay, how many do I have, total?
MATT: Total is ten.
LIAM: Ten. So I've used four. Oh, I've used four
already?
MATT: You gained one back. You have three uses.
LIAM: I still have to--
MARISHA: Yeah, you can't take it back now, you'd
be that dick.
LIAM: No, because my hindrance is heroic. So I
can't divvy out. Yeah, I've got to, right now.
MATT: You gain one back as an hour has passed. You
gain one back every hour.
LIAM: So I have seven total, and I'm going now.
MATT: Go ahead and roll your faith check.
LAURA: While he's doing that, can I poke around
them piles of bodies and see--
TRAVIS: Why would you do that?
LIAM: Ten.
MATT: Go ahead and make an investigation check. A
ten? Okay.
LAURA: Is that, like, notice?
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
LAURA: Does it take guts to look?
TRAVIS: You can do it, but you've got to roll a
minus two to it.
LAURA: Oh, what do I roll?
MATT: Roll a d4 minus two. And a d6.
LAURA: Like a d6. I get to roll again, 'cause it's
six?
MATT: Roll again.
LAURA: Oh, 11, there. While I'm poking through
them bodies.
MATT: 11 minus two, so it's a nine. All right, so
we'll get to you in just a moment. You feel-- this
man is seriously ailing, and for a miracle that
can heal wounds, this is going to take some
serious faith to try and push this through. Even
with what you have. You don't know if this is even
within your skill set.
LIAM: So Liam is asking-- am I throwing dice? Yes,
I'm going to pray harder.
MATT: Okay, what are you going to do? Use some of
these chips, you have a lot of them!
LIAM: Wait, so I could use a chip to go higher
than I already did?
MATT: You can use a red chip to add a d6.
LIAM: Oh, add a d6. Well, now I can see that I
don't understand the rules, can I use this now to
add a d6?
TRAVIS: I'm hurting. I'm hurting, y'all.
LIAM: One. Can I use another red chip?
MATT: No, you get the one.
LIAM: One. Just a one. So that gets it to 11.
MATT: 11?
LIAM: All right!
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
LIAM: See? Come on.
MATT: The guy who's in a feverish state is
half-asleep and just--
(laughter)
MATT: And fine laudanum that the doc gave him to
calm him down, so he's going to be yell-shouting
"All right!" for a while here. So. As you go ahead
and complete this miracle with the faith best you
can beyond that, I'll let you use another chip if
you want to add the number to it.
LIAM: I have to. Come back to me, Reverend, come
back to me.
MATT: Use another red chip to add another d6.
LIAM: All right! All right!
MATT: All right. So what's it now? 13? I'll let
you do this for the sake of this. So, as you push
through with the double-raise to your faith check
on this, you see as this bright, vibrant light
suddenly fills the room from one sunbeam
coming through the singular glass window striking
you in the shoulder and enveloping the entirety of
Reverend Smith. All of a sudden, you in the
distance, as you're inspecting the corpses, you
can't help but glance over your shoulder, and you
watch as this ray of light envelops his body. As
it does, he lifts gently off the table two, three
inches, and the doc goes, "What the fuck have you
brought into my place?" And he inspects, and as you
see the Reverend slowly turns over in place, his
eye corrects itself, a smile comes across him of
serene joy, and he's lowered down onto the table.
The light subsides, you take your hand away, and
he sits up in place, goes, "My lord. My mind-- my
thoughts are mine again."
LIAM: Welcome back, Reverend. The Lord will
abide.
MATT: "The Lord is stronger in you than anyone I've ever
met."
LIAM: Please, don't thank me.
MATT: He starts crying and gives you a big hug and
pulls you in. "There's no faith stronger than what
"you've brought this day."
LIAM: Take him by the hands. We all find ourselves
low and in place of trouble. It's always time to
come back to his faith.
MATT: You've lost interest in this whole
circumstance about the bodies, and this is for
you, Travis.
LAURA: What? Like a special note just for him?
MATT: I'm not the only one that suffers. So you
get into this, and keen as you are, you've done
some hunting in your time and you've seen some
wounds spent to various creatures that have been
mauled by individuals. You find specifically that,
one, it seems like a bear or at least something of
a bear's size would have to have done this, but it's
wintertime. Bears usually aren't wandering. And
the wounds here are thorough. Not killed something
and ate pieces of it. There is no indication that
there has been portions of these bodies eaten, in
fact. They have just been killed and torn apart.
LAURA: Just for no purpose.
MATT: The doc, at this point, stunned by the whole
miracle that just transpired before him, walks
over to you and goes, "Here's what gets me. Each
of these bodies were found on the outskirts of
"town. Not deep in the woods. Some of these folks
weren't seen leaving."
LAURA: Like somebody wanting us to find them.
MATT: "I think some of these bodies were placed
after being killed."
TRAVIS: How ghastly!
MATT: "I don't know if these people were outside
of the town when they were killed, even. So I'm
"confused, just as you are, about this."
LAURA: So you think that whatever did this could
actually be staying inside of this town?
MATT: "Or at least, whatever did this is working
with someone within the town."
MARISHA: Have you noticed any suspicious activity
in the town?
MATT: "Have you been to this town for long? It's
full of suspicious activity!"
MARISHA: We just arrived this morning. I don't
know.
MATT: "Fucking damn it. This whole town's full of
cocksuckers, and I don't know how to separate the
"good from the bad. I wouldn't even believe what
you're saying if this guy didn't come in here and
"fucking prove that God exists to me as an atheist.
I'm having a lot going in my head right now."
LIAM: Hallelujah.
MATT: "Halle-fucking-lujah. If you want to help,
find out what the shit did this! I need a drink."
And he goes over and grabs the bottle of laudanum
next to the guy.
TRAVIS: Oh, no, no!
MATT: Who he was helping. "Don't you 'no' or shush
me. I know what I need."
TRAVIS: Okay. Oh, good gracious.
LAURA: Don't be stingy.
MATT: "Fuckin'--" Make a persuasion check.
TRAVIS: Stinky Jules.
LAURA: Hold on, I'm about to drink.
MATT: Two red chips to the Reverend.
LIAM: Man down!
LAURA: Wait, zero, but I'm going to add a red
chip, so I can get some of that.
MATT: And a black chip to you, Sydney.
LAURA: So five. Yeah, but here's my chip that I
just used to get that.
MATT: He goes, "One sip. I ain't got a lot of
this."
LIAM: Wait, can I make a persuasion check on her?
MATT: You may.
LIAM: Yeah, I'd like to. Juniper.
LAURA: Don't you fucking call me Juniper! I don't
know you.
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
LIAM: Technically, you do know me. Biblically.
LAURA: Oh, that's true. Did you check your junk?
(laughter)
LIAM: You don't want to go down that hole.
LAURA: I think you already went down it, if you
get my meaning.
LIAM: I'm not good with comedy. This is very
awkward. I just don't want to see you going over
an edge you can't come back from. What do I roll
to stop Laura Bailey from having drugs?
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
LIAM: Yeah, okay. Okay, all right, it's not the
worst.
(laughter)
LIAM: Four, both four, and I will add five, so a
total of nine.
MATT: Total of nine? I want you to go ahead and--
I'd say for this, roll a spirit.
LAURA: Spirit? It's going to be hard for me to
beat, seeing as how I've only got a d6 here. Five.
MATT: Okay. You going to add anything to that?
LAURA: Yeah, all right, I'll add a black chip-- no,
no, no, I don't want to reroll it, I've got to add
to it, and I'm out of my colors here. All right,
I'll add a red. What's that? Nine?
LIAM: Yeah, so equal numbers.
MATT: Both of you guys roll a d6.
LIAM: Dance-off.
TRAVIS: Same time, do it same time.
LAURA and LIAM: One, two, three.
LIAM: Six!
LAURA: Damn it!
MATT: Normally, no one could keep you from a sip
of laudanum, but watching the miracles that
transpire around this bright and bushy-faced
gentleman, you think maybe you should drink this
when he's not around, and you gently give it back
to the doctor.
LAURA: Fine. I wasted a chip to talk him into
giving it to me in the first place.
LIAM: Listen, I'm going to give this to you. It's
a bar of soap, it's my last one. Use it.
MATT: "I appreciate you all having your
conversations, but if you could do it outside, I
"got business to tend to."
LAURA: Oh, that tastes like shit! What is this?
LIAM: It doesn't go in your mouth. You know what
soap is, right?
TRAVIS: Yeah, it's made of lye, it's for cleaning
yourself with.
MATT: As he starts pushing you guys outside of the
place, and you get outside, before he closes the
door, he goes, "Just a word, I don't know if this
will help much, but each of those that were killed
"inside here were plot owners in gold and silver
veins."
TRAVIS: You don't say.
MATT: "Except for the last two."
LAURA: What were they?
MATT: "Hugh and Kilmer. The ones you were looking
at. They were under the employ of Al Swearengen in
"the Gem Saloon. Now, get out!" And he slams the
door behind you.
LIAM: The video game developer?
(laughter)
LAURA: Shit. Sounds like it was rich folks getting
killed in this town.
TRAVIS: Quite glad to be out of there.
MARISHA: I can think of many reasons to kill rich
people. Many.
LAURA: Who should we talk to to find out what kind
of creatures have been living in this city?
MATT: You hear a voice creep in the back of your
ear, Liam, once again, that says, "The only path
"to goodness is to find who murdered these people.
Follow the trail. Be a hero."
LIAM: Can I pray for guidance to know if this is a
devil or an angel talking to me?
MATT: Roll a faith check.
LIAM: I have to. I'll be screwed later, but I have
to. Shit. Two and two, shit. Shit! Four.
MATT: It's hard to tell. You've had a lot of
miracle stuff happen recently, so you figure this
is probably an angel sent from God, but it's hard
to tell.
LIAM: Here are two that I've used.
TRAVIS: Salty Jules, I was wondering, would you
mind if in my notepad I did a small sketch of your
bear cub? I do fancy him so.
LAURA: Oh, is it still following us?
TRAVIS: Yes, yes. Would you mind if I looked after
him and maybe did some drawings?
LAURA: Feel free. No one's stopping you.
MARISHA: You want to keep the bear?
TRAVIS: Yes, I would love to look after him, if
that's all right. I just--
MARISHA: I foresee this bear possibly killing you
in your future, but you know what, go for it. You
have a good time with him. You have a good time.
LAURA: You've gotta be strong when you're raising
such a creature, now.
TRAVIS: All right.
LAURA: So make sure you discipline him, but also
give him lots of love and whisky, but no
chocolate, I hear that's bad for him.
TRAVIS: Whisky, love, whisky, and chocolate.
LAURA: No chocolate.
MATT: The bear, which is nuzzling under your hand,
Stinky Jules, and is like, just licking.
LAURA: What can I say? He just loves the way I
smell.
TRAVIS: I hope he'll be as affectionate with me.
May I?
LAURA: You can try.
TRAVIS: Oh, thank you. And I would like to grab
the bear and try to cuddle it.
MATT: It begins to growl as soon as you get
close.
TRAVIS: No, no! Did you give it a name?
LAURA: Trinket.
TRAVIS: Trinket. Oh yes. Like a little cork.
Hello, Trinket. It is your Uncle Sydney.
MATT: Bites at your hand. What is your parry?
TRAVIS: My parry is six.
MATT: Six. All right. So the bear bites out
towards your hand, doing seven points of damage.
What's your toughness?
TRAVIS: My toughness is five.
MARISHA: Hang on, wait! I'm going to use my snake
oil salesman to contest your roll. You can do
that, right? Your roll on the bear, the bear
attacking him?
MATT: It's not snake oil salesman you're referring
to.
MARISHA: Oh sorry, my knack of the seventh sun
ability.
MATT: I didn't use a fate chip. You can negate
me using one. You can't force me to reroll. When I
use a chip, you can be like, nope.
LAURA: Do you announce when you use a chip?
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: You don't know the rules you learned
yesterday?
MATT: So the bear bites down on your hand. You
pull back. You're considered shaken for the moment.
TRAVIS: I'm quite shaken!
MATT: But the bear's still so fucking cute!
TRAVIS: He's so lovely. Quite a voracious little
energetic one. I'm still-- my god. Can you see the flesh?
LAURA: I wonder if this little beast can lead us
to another beast?
MARISHA: Good, good.
LAURA: I mean, it is a baby, I don't know.
TRAVIS: Quite cute.
MATT: Just licks a little bit of blood off of its
teeth and grins at you.
MARISHA: We could probably use him as bait.
LAURA: That's true, we could. It is so hard to
fight the motherly instinct. I know I'm not, but
it's real hard to fight it!
MATT: What's the plan now?
TRAVIS: Well, perhaps we should go to this Mr.
Swearengen's place, see what the people in his
employ were actually up to.
LAURA: That's smart. You're smart!
TRAVIS: Thank you, yes, I do a lot of reading.
LAURA: Well, lead the way, Smarts.
TRAVIS: Yes, of course.
MATT: You actually saw the Gem Saloon. It's not
too far from the Bella Union.
TRAVIS: This way. Mind the horseshit.
LAURA: I step right through the horseshit.
MATT: She does. Right up to the ankle.
TRAVIS: To each their own.
MATT: You eventually make your way towards the Gem
Saloon. As you walk up, there is piano being
played, but unlike the Bella Union, it's not quite
as fanciful and the interior's a little more
dreary. As you step inside, you can see a few
patrons around, you can see a few of the female
workers of the establishment who are all leaning
in the back corner in various states of undress,
but all look hot and not really into it at the
moment.
TRAVIS: Reverend, avert your eyes. Hello!
MATT: As you walk in and say that, you see across
the way, a man with a big, black beard and long
hair, little bowler cap on with a rifle across his
shoulder and a white shirt with a single strap
over for his overalls, looks over and starts
walking towards you with his rifle in his hand.
Just goes, (Clarota voice) "What brings you here
to the Gem Saloon? Sorry, I got punched in the
"throat and it's healing."
TRAVIS: That sounds awful. We may have someone
that might be able to help you. My name is Sydney
Hopkins Trivelpiece.
MATT: "What you cocksuckers doing here in the Gem?
What you looking for?"
LAURA: Them bodies in the doc's place. They came
from you?
MATT: "They're a couple men we lost, yes, but
that's not our problem."
LAURA: I mean, but why? They been teared up by a
beast or something. Figure out what that is? You
seen any beasts around here, outside of this
little bear?
MATT: "I've seen no fucking beasts. If you're here
to drink, fucking get in here. Otherwise, I need
"you to step off."
LAURA: All right. I go up to the bar and get some
drinks going.
TRAVIS: If you don't mind, sir, what is your
name?
MATT: Looks at you for a second. Make a persuasion
check.
TRAVIS: Oh, shit.
LAURA: That's good!
TRAVIS: That's not bad. That's balls. I'm going to
spend a reroll.
LAURA: That's the eight you reroll.
TRAVIS: Oh, I do reroll the eight if I use a black
chip? Oh, thank god. Hey! Eight!
MATT: Roll again.
TRAVIS: 15!
MATT: Gives you a look-over and his demeanor
shifts, changes again, and he goes, "Sorry. Just
"doing my job. Name's Dan. Yeah, Doherty." Shakes
your hand for a second. "So right now you know
"who's boss."
TRAVIS: My writing hand. Dan Doherty.
MATT: "So if you want a drink, over to the bar.
Otherwise, sit down. Listen to some music. Buy
"yourself some pussy. Doesn't matter to me."
TRAVIS: Oh, pussy, yes.
LIAM: Dan, if you've got means here to boil some
water and some whisky that you've got, I could
probably help you out with your throat, if you
like. A little background in medicine. Your choice.
LAURA: I like the way you sound, Dan!
MATT: He gives you a look. "You ain't look like
you ever suffered more than suckling your mother's
"tit, and I don't trust anyone who don't drink, nor
anyone who don't have to shave."
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MATT: "That's what I said." He goes and high-fives
the guy at the table next to him, this older,
drunk fella who heard the whole conversation and
is laughing at your rather mousey--
LIAM: Dan, I've seen the brains pour out of a
man's head on the field of battle on the Eastern
coast. You can have my help if you want, or you
can suffer.
MATT: "I'll take suffer. I prefer to heal on my
own. The proper way. None of your fucking
"godmongering types here saying that the word can
help." And he spins around, keeps an eye over his
shoulder, mistrusting towards you, with the rifle
still at his side.
LIAM: God bless, Dan.
TRAVIS: I'm sorry, could I ask you all a question?
I've always been quite curious about the
employment of the American whore. I was wondering
if you wouldn't mind if I went and interviewed one
for my journal. Perhaps you could do me the
queries here, and I might leave you for a moment?
MARISHA: Are you asking permission to go speak to
whore?
TRAVIS: Yes.
MARISHA: If you want to go fuck whore, go fuck
whore. You don't have to ask permission.
LAURA: There's plenty around.
MARISHA: Don't try and say you're interviewing
whore when we know what you want.
MATT: The voice returns and goes, "Men and women
are born every day through a union of others.
"Go. Be merry. Touch. Feel."
TRAVIS: Just curious, Padre. I don't know quite
what your denomination is--
LIAM: Protestant.
TRAVIS: Oh, Protestant, lovely. So would you care
to perhaps get an adjoining room? Just because I'm
afraid I'll feel rather exposed upstairs.
LIAM: I'm not really sure what you're asking? Are
you asking me to babysit while you--
TRAVIS: No, just perhaps join me for a trip down
the old lane?
LAURA: Was that a blink?
(laughter)
LAURA: Did you just blink at him?
TRAVIS: It was a double-blink.
LAURA: So you want one of them whores?
TRAVIS: To speak to one, yes.
LAURA: I pull up the closest whore to me. Hey.
Which one of you are the least itchy? (clicks tongue)
MATT: They all look at each other. They're all
giving you a very, very curious look, and they all
put their hand out like, "Honey. We're all clean.
The doctor takes care of us. You going to pay or not?"
LAURA: They're all clean. I don't believe a word
she says, but they're all clean.
MARISHA: It's only matter of time.
TRAVIS: Yes, I would like to acquire one whore,
please.
MATT: "Ten dollars, take your choice."
TRAVIS: Ten dollars. Is that a going rate in the
States? Ten dollars it is, yes. Ten dollars.
MATT: She takes you by the hand and starts leading
you up the stairs.
TRAVIS: Quiet room. Hopefully secluded from the
others.
LAURA: He wants to interview you!
MATT: He gets closed behind the door. Three of you
guys, what are you doing?
LAURA: I go and ask one of them whores about the
guys that are dead. I want to find a whore and ask
her about-- (laughs) Ask her about them bodies I
found over at Doc's place.
MATT: You find a woman, a brunette, rosy make-up
cheeks who's sitting at a table, just fanning
herself off in this strangely muggy warm day in
the middle of the winter.
LAURA: Oh, yeah, it's hot, isn't it?
MATT: "You're telling me. This day's been all
sorts of muggy. How can I help you?"
LAURA: Hey, I saw them bodies over at Doc's place.
Tored up.
MATT: "I don't want to talk about that."
LAURA: Wait, wait, don't-- I just, did you know
those dudes? Those guys?
MATT: "Kilmer was one of the nicer fellas who
worked here at the Gem. He, well. Sad to hear that
"he met a weird fate."
LAURA: And he actually worked here?
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
LAURA: All right, that's good to know. What about
that other fella?
MATT: "Hugh worked here as well, but I'm honestly
kind of glad Hugh got what he had coming."
LAURA: Hugh. He's a fucker, wasn't he? All right,
when did they go missing?
MATT: "I don't rightfully know. You'd have to ask
Mr. Schwerenger about that."
LAURA: Where's Mr. Schwerenger?
MATT: She looks up, and you can see at the top of
the stairs, it curls around and there's an office
with a closed door on the second floor.
LAURA: We allowed to go up there? That looks like
lock-and-key sort of shit.
MATT: She points over to-- you see Dan at the
corner with his rifle, keeping a very close look
on you. "You got to talk to him."
LAURA: Talk to Dan? All right. Hey. Thanks for the
help, there.
MATT: Holds her hand out.
LAURA: Aw, shit. I hand her some money.
MATT: Okay. Takes it.
MARISHA: Sudis actually wanted to go talk to Dan.
MATT: Okay. So as you turn around, Sudis has
walked up to Dan. As you approach, he has the gun
at his side, and he begins to pull back the
trigger. "Can I help you?"
MARISHA: How do you say name again?
MATT: "Dan. Dan Doherty. That's far enough. You
come any closer, I'm going to go ahead and take
"your eye out."
LAURA: Oh, don't mind her. She's just a fortune
teller.
LIAM: (hiccups)
LAURA: You all right there, Rev?
MATT: He pulls a small black feather out of his
mouth after the hiccup and is confused by the whole thing.
LIAM: I suppose it is a little funny. (hiccups)
We're all tested. Each in our own way.
MARISHA: Looking at the aura, the energy
surrounding you, I don't think you'd pull that
trigger, would you, Dan?
LAURA: I think he'd pull it there, hon.
MATT: Make a notice check.
MARISHA: What do I do? Five.
MATT: Five? He would definitely pull that trigger.
You get the sense he's pulled a lot of triggers,
and he's aiming right at you. "One more step."
MARISHA: I'm sorry. I just thought you might like
a little bit of insight into your future. I can
see great potential in you, Dan.
MATT: "I don't want any of this. Too many fucking
weird things happen in this town. Don't want any
"of your god damn magical bullshit. Get the fuck
out of the Gem before I shoot your eye out--"
LAURA: Hey, hey! Sue, Sue.
MARISHA: All right. I was going to save your life,
but have it your way. Oh, and watch your back.
LAURA: She's scary as fuck.
MATT: "Don't trust them gypsy types at all."
LAURA: Hey, Dan.
MATT: "What you want? You might need someone. Go
on."
LAURA: Your employer up at the top of them stairs.
How do I get to talk to him?
MATT: "No one talks to Al unless they get
permission. What you want to talk to him about?"
LAURA: How do I get permission to talk--
MATT: "Tell me what you need for him, I'll talk to
him, and he'll tell you no."
LAURA: No, I want to help you kill the
motherfucker that killed your motherfuckers. Now
you seem capable.
MATT: "Is he all right?"
LAURA: He's done some crazy shit today.
MATT: "I can see. You're supposed to cook the bird
first, asshole!"
LIAM: What?
MATT: "It's the throat thing, I'm sorry."
LIAM: I know, I can-- never mind.
MATT: "Sit the fuck down. You get the fuck out of
the Gem, or I swear to fucking god, I'm going to shoot."
LIAM: I take a step in front of the gypsy. Dan.
MATT: "You got until three to calm your friends
the fuck down, or I'm going to go ahead and take
"'em both out."
MARISHA: I'm quite calm. Do I look aroused? I
don't--
LAURA: Calm down, you guys that are really revved
up right now.
LIAM: I'd like to reach my hand down to--
LAURA: Down to what?
LIAM: --Stinky Jules' revolver.
LAURA: Hey, get your fucking hand off my gun.
Don't fucking touch my gun.
MATT: Reach for her revolver?
LIAM: No, not to take it, to cast Smite on it.
TRAVIS: Sometimes reaching's all that needs to be
done.
LIAM: Give her the ol' reach-around.
LAURA: You're going to reach for my gun when a
motherfucker's pointing a gun at you?
MATT: So Travis, first off, while we're in this
moment, as time has passed, I would like for you
to go ahead and roll a spirit check.
TRAVIS: That's a four. Four.
LAURA: Add something to it!
MATT: You got chips, guys, use 'em.
LAURA: I know, we've got so many.
TRAVIS: Shit, still a four.
LAURA: No, you rerolled, yeah.
MATT: Red one would add to it. If you wanted to
use a red one to add to it, you can.
TRAVIS: Yeah, why not?
MATT: All right. So add a d6 to that one.
TRAVIS: Fucking dick-licking piece of-- five.
MATT: Five. Do you want to use another chip to add
more to it?
TRAVIS: Yeah, why not?
MATT: On the important rolls.
TRAVIS: What is the deal? There's no--
MATT: So, total of six?
TRAVIS: Yes! I have giblets. This is terrible!
MATT: A respectable five minutes pass before he
makes his way outside of the room, nice and sweaty.
TRAVIS: With my sleeves rolled up.
MATT: You come down immediately to see what
appears to be a stand-off, rifle drawn, right at
the Reverend, as you begin to reach towards her
gun on the side--
LIAM: Okay, I know I'm in front of her. Where's
Stinky?
MATT: He's up the stairway.
LIAM: He who? She?
MATT: She's maybe four or five feet from you.
LIAM: Do I need to touch the gun to-- oh, okay.
Then I can't do that at all. She's five feet
behind me.
LAURA: Also, I'd probably murder you for trying to
touch my weapon.
TRAVIS: She was very forthcoming. Gave me quite a
bit of difficulty at first, but-- oh, what happened here?
LIAM: I'm backing up, I'm backing up. Relax,
relax. Hand behind me.
LAURA: Put your hands down.
LIAM: I brush my fingers across her gun and cast
Smite.
MATT: Okay, against her gun? Spend two points.
LAURA: Would I have noticed that he brushed his
hand?
MATT: Make a notice check.
LIAM: It's called the dick graze.
LAURA: I don't got a dick.
LIAM: What do I roll for this? Spirit, right?
Faith.
MARISHA: Just the tip.
LIAM: God damn it.
LAURA: I got a four. Well, I've only got one blue
chip, and the other one's a reroll, so I can't get
any better.
LIAM: Total of nine.
MATT: All right. So that's with the raise, so you
go ahead, and there's a dull glow at the side of
her holster as you manage to enchant her weapon
with Smite.
LAURA: What's that mean?
MATT: You don't know. You do manage to glance to
the side and notice that he brushed his fingers
past, and there's a slight glow off of your
holster. "Two!"
MARISHA: Dan. Pull that trigger and it will be the
last trigger you pull. So says the dark entity
behind your shoulder.
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
TRAVIS: Which way is Dan facing in relation to
me?
MATT: You're looking down the stairs. You see
Dan's-- they're both at the side, looking at each
other from your perspective, down below.
MARISHA: I'm going to use a black chip just to see
if I can do better. Six again. Six.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MATT: All right! I'll pick it up later.
(clang)
MATT: Thank you. Oh, it sounds good when you do
that.
LIAM: You don't want to shoot an unarmed man, do
you, Dan?
MATT: So he's still-- glances over his shoulder.
Doesn't see anything. You do hear a door slam in
the distance, and a voice comes blaring out. "Who
the fuck is causing problems in my saloon?"
LAURA: Al?
MATT: "And who the fuck is calling my name?" At
this point, Dan puts his gun down. "Sir, I didn't
"mean nothing by it, had these folks come in--" He's
like, "I will gut you like a god damn fish, Dan."
MARISHA: Sudi starts crying. No-- no English.
MATT: "What do you want, or get the fuck out of my
place!"
LAURA: We're here to help. Me and these weirdos
that surround me are here to look for the people
that have been killing your men.
LIAM: You smell like cow plops.
TRAVIS: Mr. Schwerengen, Sydney Hopkins
Trivelpiece. We're on a mission to find--
MATT: "The more you talk, the less I want to talk
to any of you. You. Looking to see if you can help
"my men who got killed, right?"
LAURA: That's right.
MATT: "Get on up to my office." He turns around
and goes back inside. Storms back out again and
goes like, "And Dan? You tell me next time we have
guests looking for me. Do not point a gun at
"them." Glances over at you and goes, "I don't
trust her. Go ahead and go that way. The rest of
"them, let them up."
TRAVIS: Stinky Jules, be quick about it.
LAURA: Be quick about what?
TRAVIS: Your meeting.
LAURA: Why?
TRAVIS: No reason. The gentleman in the lobby
seems very aggressive.
LAURA: Sure.
LIAM: What just happened? Al invited the three of
us?
MATT: Three of you guys up, and was like, "You can
stay."
MARISHA: (groans) I go over and I start talking to
the whores, seeing if they want their fortunes told.
MATT: All right. The three of you guys make your
way up to the office.
LIAM: (Sudis voice) You're going to fuck a guy...
MARISHA: I see many STDs in your future.
MATT: Desk is up there, there's papers strewn
across, there's a balcony with a door half-open,
and you see a partially dressed woman currently
leaving out of the far bedroom, rushes past you
guys. You enter the room. "Would you mind closing
the door behind you?"
LAURA: Close the door, Rev.
LIAM: (creaking sound)
MATT: "All right. So. To who the fuck do I owe
this pleasure?"
LAURA: Well, I'm Stinky Jules. Nice to make your
acquaintance.
TRAVIS: I would ask if I may speak.
MATT: "Oh, be my guest."
TRAVIS: Oh. Lovely. Sydney Hopkins Trivelpiece, at
your service, from the great country of England,
here to chronicle the glory and power of the Wild
West. You, sir, your name has quite the renown--
MATT: "Whereabouts in England? I actually had some
time there myself."
TRAVIS: Yes, well, point of fact, I am from
Tawnyland, and by route of Shepardshire. But I
took a barge and landed in the beautiful state of
Mississippi.
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
LIAM: Is he faking it?
LAURA: Is he faking what?
LIAM: Do you think he's from New Jersey?
TRAVIS: Six. Ten.
MATT: "All right, calm down, calm down. Usually
folks aren't so eager around this place. Jittery.
"All right, so. You say you're here to help with my
men. All right." (sighs) And he walks out, looks
over the balcony for a second. "Fucking cocksucker cleaned
out the tables with a grin. You seen this asshole
"walking in town, taking all the money?"
LAURA: Oh. Yes, we did. Well, I tried to punch
him. I almost punched him. But we did in fact see
him cheating at poker earlier today.
MATT: "Next time he crosses your path, go ahead
and punch him for me, if you don't mind."
LAURA: I will certainly try to do that again,
sir.
TRAVIS: That's Simon he's speaking of.
LAURA: Simon.
MATT: "Is that his name? Simon. Good to know.
Certainly hope he took Cy for all he's worth, too.
"There goes a joyride for the trees alone. You see
him again, deck him. There's some cash in it for you."
TRAVIS: Understood.
LAURA: What's wrong with you?
TRAVIS: The hand is hurting quite a bit.
MATT: So. He says, "All right, so I've heard some
terrible fucking news. A new interest is coming to
"town soon. George Hurst. The same rich fucking
loadrunner's Hurst. Hurst, Hagen, Tevvyson,
"cocksucker's company. Last thing we need in this
place is another fucking company man without an
"appreciation for allies."
LAURA: Yeah. I don't have any idea what he just
said.
MATT: "I'll tell you what. You want work? Pay you
$400 to split, and a free run of the ladies for
"the night, if you bring me anything linking Hurst
to these rumors of silver going belly-up in this town."
LAURA: What the fuck does this have to do with
that damn creature killing people? I'm confused.
TRAVIS: Yes, I do believe it was two of your men
that were torn asunder by this horrible creature.
LAURA: Do you think it was Hurst that killed
them?
MATT: "Very possible. You find that out, you come
back with some information about that. Or, if it's
"this fucking bear they keep saying it is, bring
back the bear's hide. $200 to you to spread as you
"like for the hide of whatever fucking creature
killed my boys."
TRAVIS: So $400 for the silver and $200 for the
beast.
MATT: "It's hard to find dependable men these
days, and some heroics in town can only bring
"spirits up. Higher spirits make for higher-paying
customers."
TRAVIS: Yes, yes.
LAURA: Sure. Where would we start to look for any
of the shit you just talked about?
MATT: "If I knew, I'd go looking for it
my-fucking-self! What am I paying you for?"
TRAVIS: Mr. Schwerengen, I am quite familiar with
Cy's establishment.
MATT: "Shut the fuck up, please."
TRAVIS: I was just saying, I have information.
LAURA: He has information.
MATT: "Spill it."
TRAVIS: I was just saying, I could lead these
intrepid band of investigators over to Cy's place and--
LAURA: Cy? Simon?
TRAVIS: Yes, Cy. He runs the-- what is the name of
the saloon--
MATT: "The Bella Union."
TRAVIS: The Bella Union. Oh, wait, that's where we
had our...
MATT: "So. Want some cash? Find out who the fuck
killed my men. See if Hurst is behind any of this."
LAURA: All right. We will do that.
MATT: "Now, get out. Your choice: stairs or the
balcony."
TRAVIS: Stairs.
MATT: "Good. Wise choice." Slams the door behind
you guys.
LAURA: Kind of wanted to go out the balcony.
MATT: You, in the meantime, there is a woman who
has come up to you and said, "Actually, I've always
"wanted my fortune told, if you don't mind."
MARISHA: Absolutely, darling. What's your name?
MATT: "Lisa."
MARISHA: So what does Lisa look like? Can I do a
notice check on Lisa?
MATT: Yeah. The voice in your head, once again,
Liam, goes, "Come. Take one. Any of them. It'll
"right your connection with your lord."
MARISHA: Seven. Lisa, Lisa, come here, darling,
Lisa. Let me get a good look at you.
MATT: She's young, she hasn't been in this
business long. You can see a bit of fear and worry
in the back of her eyes.
MARISHA: Looks like someone hurt you in your past.
Da?
MATT: "Get hurt a lot in this line of work."
MARISHA: So are you running or are you chasing
pain, Lisa?
MATT: "What do you mean?"
MARISHA: Be careful.
MATT: "Careful of what?"
MARISHA: This work you do could very easily
consume you. But it hasn't yet.
MATT: As you can say that, you can see one of the
whores nearby trips and knocks her down onto the
table, knocking out her front teeth.
MARISHA: Wait, the woman I was just talking to?
MATT: Yeah. (muffled screams) And just begins running
off. The other women take her in and then start
picking up her teeth on the table.
TRAVIS: What did you do to her?
MATT: "You get out of this place, you fortune
teller. You get out of this place."
MARISHA: I did not see that coming.
MATT: You hear (gun cocks) and Dan has his rifle
up at the back and is like, "I told you to keep out."
LIAM: I swoop and I hook her on the arm and I just
guide her out the door.
MATT: All right.
MARISHA: Don't worry, we'll meet again, Dan. As
well as the demon on your shoulder. Bye, demon!
Bye-bye! (blows kisses)
MATT: He looks over his shoulder again, kind of
nervously.
LIAM: Strong stuff you serve. Strong stuff. Come
on, out the door you go.
MARISHA: I made like five gold doing that.
TRAVIS: I'll be with you shortly. Mr. Doherty? If
I may. The whore that I was able to interview
upstairs. What was her name?
MATT: "Which one was it?"
TRAVIS: The red-haired one. Lovely blue eyes.
MATT: "Virginia."
TRAVIS: Virginia, yes. Would you do me a favor and
follow up with her in a bit. I did do quite a
number on her. I just want to make sure that she's
all right.
MATT: "I'm sure she is."
TRAVIS: I was quite proud of myself. Anyway. Oh,
Stinky Jules! Unfortunately, Sue knocked all the
teeth out of the woman she was trying to tell the
fortune for. Dan, here, was about to put a hole in
her head again, so we're going to--
MARISHA: I did not touch that woman. I was simply
giving her fortune.
LAURA: How'd she lose her teeth, then?
MARISHA: She just tripped. One of the other women
pulled her down and she tripped and fell. It had
nothing to do with me.
LAURA: Can't blame her for that! I mean. Lots of
people are drinking in this bar. Accidents happen.
MARISHA: Not everything is necessarily a pull of
fate's strings, okay? It's sometimes shit just happens.
TRAVIS: Perhaps we should find our way to this
spot. Bartender, may I have some whisky? Could you
pour it on this hand? It's throbbing quite badly.
MATT: As you turn at this point, you see Dan still
has his gun up and says, "Go ahead and find whisky
"elsewhere. You four are fucking not welcome right
now until you come back with what Al was asking about."
LIAM: Understood, Dan. Thank you for your
patience.
TRAVIS: Mr. Schwerengen has said--
MATT: "Out."
LAURA: Get the fuck out! Let's go.
MATT: You guys find your way outside of the Gem
Saloon.
LAURA: Why are you petting air?
MARISHA: Just itch. Bit of itch.
LAURA: It's better if you're itching to actually
touch your body. I've found it has a better effect.
MATT: The monkey in your ear whispers out. "Follow
the trail of gold and silver. This is where you
"must go." And curls back up into your hair.
MARISHA: Ah, Manitou.
LIAM: Hockmanitou?
TRAVIS: It's her foreign tongue, I'm sure.
MARISHA: Just thinking out loud.
LIAM: I'm trying to figure it out. I heard you say
"Da." Are you Russian?
TRAVIS: Stinky Jules, could you pour some whisky
on my hand? I'm afraid it's infected. I'm feeling
a bit feverish. I feel-- oh, please, careful now.
LAURA: I poke at it.
TRAVIS: (yelps) Oh, it's quite pus-ridden. It
feels wonderful.
LAURA: I push it out. Okay. Yeah, that looks
pretty.
TRAVIS: Quite. Careful. Thank you.
LAURA: Sure, take some whisky there.
TRAVIS: Yes, if you don't mind.
MATT: Pour some whisky over the hand. You feel
inspired. Travis, you get a red chip.
LIAM: I'm going to take-- Come here, Mr. English,
or wherever you're from.
TRAVIS: Mr. Trivelpiece.
LIAM: Right. Let's take ten minutes to take care
of this.
TRAVIS: Oh, no, no, that's quite all right.
LIAM: You want the pus?
TRAVIS: I must learn to be as tough as the lands I
am interviewing.
MATT: Go ahead and make a guts check.
TRAVIS: I don't know where that is.
LIAM: Where'd it go? I don't think you have it.
TRAVIS: Minus two for me, if I don't have it?
LAURA: Just a four minus two.
TRAVIS: I'm going to add a blue chip, because that
sucked so much. So five.
MATT: Five, okay. You, after saying that, shake it
off and look down. You can deal with this.
TRAVIS: Yes, it's quite all right.
MATT: No longer shaken by it, you feel like this
wound will subside in time.
LIAM: I'm going to pull Stinky off into an alley
for a second. Stinky.
LAURA: You want some more of this action, Rev?
LIAM: You know, I'm not a Sunday school child. I'm
not a blushing flower. I understand how the world
works. I don't need the money. So you can have my
share. Helping this town is enough. But I do want
to understand-- I realize you have a higher
tolerance than I do. What happened last night?
LAURA: Oh, yeah, we had sex. Well, you had a lot
of sex with the Sue girl, a little bit of sex with
brains over there.
LIAM: Okay. That was very candid.
MATT: The voice in your ear creeps in and goes,
"It's all true."
LIAM: I know that's a fucking devil.
TRAVIS: He shakes his head no.
LAURA: Is that not all right with you, Rev?
LIAM: People find comfort where they can.
LAURA: You were real, real, real into it, I just
want to let you know. You were having a lot of
fun. I even, at one point, asked if you wanted to
stop, because it seemed a little bit obscene even
to me, but you kept on go--
LIAM: Do you have any whisky?
LAURA: I do. Here, have some.
LIAM: Can I have it?
MATT: At this point, the sun has begun to set, and
you hear in the distance what sounds like a gunshot.
LAURA: Did you really just drink my whisky?
LIAM: No.
LAURA: Yes, you did.
TRAVIS: A gunshot?
MATT: A gunshot in the distance. A second
gunshot.
LAURA: Shit! I take off running.
MARISHA: Let's follow.
MATT: Okay. You guys go charging off now, on the
sound of this distant gunshot.
MARISHA: I'm on my peg leg.
TRAVIS: Come on, Trinket.
LIAM: Ever consider marriage?
MATT: You make your way to the outskirts of the
town, where you see there's now people surrounding
what looks to be an individual who is torn open,
their stomach pulled out, but they're holding a
gun, and they're on the ground, passing out at
this point.
LAURA: Oh, shit! I pull out my gun and look around
for whatever it was that was just attacking him.
TRAVIS: I run down to the poor individual.
MATT: Notice check.
LAURA: Notice, notice. Damn it. I'm going to--
wait. Damn it! All right, I'm going to spend a blue.
LIAM: Hey, Marshal? You think I got two minutes
for the bathroom before the shit hits the fan, here?
MATT: Sure, go for it.
LAURA: It's because he just drank all that whisky.
Going straight through him.
LAURA: Can I-- I only got four.
MATT: You got a four? Looking around the darkness,
as the shadow's started to take the nearby forest,
you see nothing before you. But you do see some of
the other folks in town who are starting to bring
out what looks like torchlight and starting to
make a little posse to go out and seek. You see
the well-dressed gentleman who wandered up
earlier, Simon. "What's going on? This is-- what?"
MARISHA: Simon, was it?
MATT: "Yes. Hello again."
MARISHA: What brings you out here? You came quite
fast.
LAURA: Simon! I walk up and I punch him.
(laughter)
MATT: Go ahead and roll fighting.
MARISHA: Yes! Yes!
TRAVIS: And while they're with Simon, I would like
to be with the guy that's holding the gun and torn open.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: I got a five.
MATT: You got a five? Okay, go ahead and just roll
a d4. Or what's your strength?
LAURA: Strength is-- oh, it's just four.
MATT: Yeah, so roll a d4, add one to it.
LAURA: Two.
MATT: All right, so you-- is that your fighting
roll?
LAURA: Oh, I want to reroll.
MATT: Oh, go ahead and reroll. The fighting is a
d4?
LAURA: I fought him, I got--
MATT: No, you got the five, yes, so you're going
to reroll the--
LAURA: The attack. Four! And add one to it, so
five.
MARISHA: Right before her fist meets his face, I
go, pain incoming.
MATT: And he goes, "What?" (impact) Her fist comes
out of the side of your visual perspective. His
hat gets flung off to the side. He hits the
ground.
MARISHA: See? I can predict future!
MATT: He's now missing a tooth.
LAURA: I pick up the tooth, and I put it in my
pocket. And I tell everybody, everybody saw that!
If anybody asks, I did in fact punch that man.
MATT: A man rushes out and picks him up and goes,
"Are you okay?" And helps Simon up off the ground.
You see a man looking with a sad turtle-like
wrinkled face, a paisley-blue velvet outfit that's
worn, dirty, a hat much like yours, and he
stammers as he lifts him off the ground. "Why? Why
"have you taken this moment to feel it important to
impart onto my gentle cousin your fist?"
LAURA: Oh, because I was asked to by Mr.
Salinger.
MARISHA: Schwerenger.
LAURA: Schewerenger.
MARISHA: There we go.
MATT: "Al? Al told you to? Did you piss off Al?
That's dangerous."
MARISHA: What they call you, cousin? Or is your
name Cousin?
MATT: "He is my cousin. I'm E.B. Farnum, the mayor
of this fair town, and I am also the owner of the
"Grand Central Hotel, if you ever want to come stay
with us. You're more than welcome. Is she welcome?
"She just punched you." And Simon's still coming to
his senses and goes, "I-- Why?!"
LAURA: I just walk away from him and start asking
people if anybody saw who attacked that other feller.
MATT: Okay. Folks are confused at this point, and
they're pulling out their torches and their guns.
The guy on the ground, by the way, as you're
searching him, has--
TRAVIS: Is he alive?
MATT: He is expiring rapidly.
TRAVIS: Is he? I bend down and say--
LIAM: Who is he? What's going on?
MARISHA: We've got a guy in the street.
MATT: "It was teeth and fur." And he passes out.
LIAM: I'm walking out to him and laying on hands.
MATT: All right, go ahead and make a faith check.
Two more points.
LIAM: I know. Okay.
MARISHA: Did you recover any?
LIAM: I don't know.
MARISHA: He recovers every few hours, right?
MATT: One.
LIAM: Okay, I'm going to use-- the reroll is the
blue?
LAURA: No, the black is the reroll.
MATT: Other ones add d6s. Thank you.
LIAM: 12.
MARISHA: Ooh!
LIAM: Put those innards back in, son.
MATT: As you reach down, your hand touches him. In
the darkness of the newly formed dusk, you see
warmth begin to emerge from your medic's hands,
and all the intestines slowly pull back into the
body, the wound closing, leaving the shorn shirt
of the individual. He comes to consciousness with
a deep breath.
LAURA: That's just fucking crazy.
LIAM: You're okay.
MATT: You can see E.B. Farnum's like, "What is
going on? Everything's turned upside-down. I don't
"know what's happening."
TRAVIS: Reverend, perhaps you could speak some
calming words to Mr. Farnum.
MATT: Simon turns to him and they whisper to each
other.
MARISHA: I'm still standing next to Simon. Do I
hear what he says?
MATT: Make a notice check.
MARISHA: Ugh, I'm going to spend a reroll. Not
much better. Three!
MATT: Give this to Laura, please. Three? No, you
don't hear anything. You hear some whispering, and
you notice that Simon nods and looks about
shiftily and darts off into the town as E.B. takes his
place with a big smile.
MARISHA: Can I follow Simon? Stealthily, like
blend in with the crowd behind him?
MATT: Go ahead and make a stealth check.
MARISHA: I'm not trained in this. Ooh, I rolled a
three, though, which is pretty good. Minus two. So one.
MATT: As you turn around, E.B. goes, "Ma'am, I'm
sorry to bother you. A lot of things have been
"happening in this town as of late--"
MARISHA: Your palms are very sweaty. Don't touch
again.
MATT: "Sorry, it's a thing."
MARISHA: You seem nervous. Why nervous?
MATT: "I always seem nervous, but as the mayor of
this town, I feel--"
MARISHA: Mayor? Who made you mayor?
MATT: "I did. And Mr. Schwerengen. I don't have to
talk to you! Look, miss. There has been a terrible
"incursion of an evil sort, a blight on our fair
city, and I think it's important that we as a
"people figure out who is responsible."
LAURA: I agree with that statement.
MARISHA: I know, E.B., I know. And I reach out and
I touch his face.
MATT: Smacks it away. "Unhand me, gypsy foul
demon-woman!"
TRAVIS: You know, the Reverend is quite good at
calming the nerves. He has quite the touch.
MATT: At this point, the man who he's healed
stands up. Black chip for Laura. And goes, "I
"don't know what to say." You see now, he's an
older gentleman with a big, thick beard and a
bowler hat and he's shorter, stockier. "You saved
my life, and I appreciate that."
LIAM: All I ask is that you use your time more
kindly and more wisely.
LAURA: And tell us who it was that attacked you.
MATT: "Name's Charlie. Charlie Arthur. I was out
taking a walk in my thinking hour, when I noticed
"something moving on the outskirts of town. I went
to check it out, like one is wont to do in my
"place here in town. Something with a lot of fur
and teeth came at me from that way." And he points
out towards the north end of town that leads out
towards the various mining claims.
LIAM: How big a creature are we talking about,
Charlie?
MATT: "About the size of a bear, best I could
tell. But not bear-like. It was more savage, like
"a dog. But this dog was on its hind legs, it
looked like. Then it wasn't, then it ran like a
"bear. I don't know. I got two shots off, didn't
seem to stop it, then it tore out the side of my
"stomach and left me for dead."
LAURA: But you're not dead!
TRAVIS: Your wounds seem to have healed
miraculously.
MATT: "Excuse me while I go get a very firm
drink."
TRAVIS: Perhaps I can walk you there.
MATT: "You keep strange company, and while I
appreciate what you've done, that weird shit--
"I've had enough of it for the day."
LAURA: We should go check out that
bear-walking-dog-bear beastly sort of creature and
kill it.
MATT: You can see E.B. is still looking over your
shoulder as you're talking with him, and he's
pushed you away. "I'm sorry. I think it is time
that I returned about my business and left you,
"woman of the arcane dark arts, out of my sight.
Good day."
MARISHA: Oh, don't worry, E.B., I don't have to be
in your sights.
LAURA: Again, aim for the actual part that itches.
It helps, I swear.
LIAM: Charlie. It's a gift from above. Don't waste
it.
MATT: "Oh. Ugh." And he seems like he's super
confused and torn by the whole thing that's
happened. He just walks into town. Some of the
people are out now, forming parties who go out
into the middle of the forest.
TRAVIS: I'll be with you in one moment. I chase
after Charlie and I put my hand on his shoulder
and I say, dear sir, might I get a quote for my
book? Or rather, may I give you one?
MATT: "I'm sorry, I don't know what you're talking
about."
TRAVIS: (deep voice) "Well, some people don't get
to escape death." And I take my bowie knife out of
my sleeve and I stab him in the heart and turn the
wound so it opens.
MATT: Okay. Go ahead and make a fighting check.
LIAM: He's a faker, yeah. Big surprise.
TRAVIS: I'm going to reroll the strength check.
That's an eight. That's a six. That's a 14.
MATT: With two raises, or raising the attack. So
go ahead and roll damage, plus an additional d6.
TRAVIS: How do I roll damage?
MATT: It's under your bowie knife.
LIAM: Oh man, Jesus is displeased with you. I just
fucking healed that guy.
MARISHA: I told you, you are only prolonging the
inevitable. By 30 seconds, yeah. Sometimes people
are just meant to die.
LIAM: Hey, man, Liam's agnostic. I get you.
TRAVIS: Oh, sorry, this guy.
MATT: Yeah, so roll that twice.
TRAVIS: Five.
MATT: Plus two, so seven. Plus your d6.
TRAVIS: Ten.
LAURA: Seven plus four is 11.
TRAVIS: Oh, I'm sorry, 11.
MATT: Do you want to use a red chip to add another
d6 to that? Just 'cause why not? Add another d6.
TRAVIS: Three. 14.
LIAM: Does he explode into a mist of blood?
MATT: No. As you walk away, arm over him, do you
keep walking with him? He goes limp in your grasp.
TRAVIS: Oh, no, no, someone come quickly! It seems
his wounds have been extremely grievous! Oh,
please, somebody help Charlie!
MATT: You guys now see as Charlie has collapsed to
the ground, now, just a gout of blood out of his
chest where the previous scar wounding was.
TRAVIS: Oh, my dear, oh, I wasn't quite ready for
this.
MARISHA: Can I do an insight check on Sydney?
MATT: No insight.
TRAVIS: Please, I'm afraid his blood will get in
the bear wound.
LAURA: All right, let me check it out. Maybe we
should pour some more whisky on that. Just push on
the wound.
TRAVIS: Don't fucking touch-- yes, yes. The whisky
alone would be great.
MARISHA: Nine.
MATT: If I could have you go ahead and make a
persuasion check.
TRAVIS: Okay.
LIAM: While he's doing that, question: he dropped
his accent for a second 20 minutes ago. But I
don't catch that if the dice don't catch it,
right?
MATT: Correct.
TRAVIS: I'm going to reroll that. Yes! So that's a
seven.
MATT: Seven? You going to add anything else to
that, or no?
TRAVIS: I'm going to add a d6. That is nine. Oh
wait, no, seven plus three is ten.
MATT: Ten? He looks earnest. It looks like somehow
the wound has reopened and Syndey is genuinely
fearful of what has just happened.
TRAVIS: I'm really not quite prepared.
MARISHA: I told you he was meant to die.
LIAM: Can't trust the English, if we've learned
anything.
TRAVIS: I was only trying to escort him back. Oh,
well. I suppose--
LAURA: Well, shit. We should get that doc out here
and take care of them wounds again. In the
meantime, maybe we should all go find that bear.
MARISHA: We need to start at some of the mining
locations. Some of the gold and silver veins.
TRAVIS: The bear is just here.
LAURA: The bear ran out into the woods. It's right
that way.
MARISHA: I know, but I think we should follow it
towards one of the mining--
TRAVIS: Is anyone adept at tracking such an
animal?
LIAM: I pull out the sharpened crucifix I have.
It's that way, and I just walk off.
MATT: Towards the woods? You guys watch as your
reverend fellow walks off into the woods.
MARISHA: Well, it's a start.
LAURA: We start following him.
TRAVIS: Yes, of course!
LAURA: I push Sydney in front of me, and I say,
maybe you should follow behind the reverend there, Sydney.
TRAVIS: Well, of course, it'd be my pleasure! Shall
we?
MARISHA: I peg leg behind. (stomping)
MATT: You guys begin to make your way up into the
woods. At this point, I want to mention real fast
we just hit $65k.
(cheering)
MATT: Which is fantastic. That is amazing so we're
going to have a boss named, created with me and
the community at some point in the near future to
show up in Critical Role.
LAURA: Oh man!
MATT: If we hit $70k this special one-off, and
what it's about to unveil as it continues, will be
uploaded to geekandsundry.com by Friday. If we can
hit $75k, it'll be uploaded by Wednesday. Also,
we're going to be giving out a signed cast
poster of the purple, no longer available,
showdown poster.
TRAVIS: Those are like in the vault. They're very
rare.
MATT: So we're going to sign that poster and give
it away, since that is no longer available, if we
hit $75k. So anyway.
LIAM: Welcome Vox Monica, I am Skizzbucket
Tatertaint.
(laughter)
LAURA: Why do you keep calling them Vox Monica?
LIAM: Why not?
MATT: Don't give them any ideas.
LIAM: It's going to stick! It's the new hotness.
Come on!
MATT: So as you guys step into the dark forest,
the evening air has definitely consumed this area.
You can hear the crickets in the distance
chirping, and the occasional distant hooting of a
night owl (owl hooting).
MARISHA: What does the moon look like?
MATT: You look up and the moon is a bright vibrant
circular white. It looks to be--
MARISHA: So it's a full moon?
MATT: --close to full, or full. And that light is
aiding you to get through some part of the forest
as scattered as it is amongst the trees.
MARISHA: Would I have any occult knowledge
about--
MATT: Make an occult check, knowledge/occult.
MARISHA: --the moon, and maybe things come out at
the moon times?
LIAM: (accented) That is a moon.
MARISHA: (accented) That is a moon in the skies.
(dice hitting the floor)
MARISHA: Oh noes.
LIAM: Fail.
MARISHA: Oh it was a four, can I keep it? You're
not going to let me keep it.
MATT: On the table.
MARISHA: Three. I'm going to spend a blue to add a
d6, right?
MATT: Yep, thank you.
MARISHA: Ooh, and a four. So seven!
MATT: Yes, a full moon's particular furry beasts
with the nasty teeth, various forms of lycanthropy
are affected at this point in time. Based on the
information that these attacks happened every few
weeks, and the cycle of the lunar cycle, you
gather there's probably a very good chance that
this beast that's been seen multiple times is some
sort of a shapeshifter.
MARISHA: The full moon, it has mystical powers.
I'd watch out for any type of lycanthropy in the area.
LAURA: What the fuck is lycanthropy?
MARISHA: You goods? You've had those hiccups
for--
LIAM: (spits) Ugh.
LAURA: What did you eat, son?
LIAM: I don't know what happened last night.
MARISHA: You shouldn't eat from the traveling
street carts. Those are bad.
LIAM: I have a lot of praying to do.
TRAVIS: Would you pray for me as well? It burns
when I pee. I think it might have had something to
do with last night.
MARISHA: Did you also eat from the travelling
street cart?
TRAVIS: No.
MARISHA: Don't eat from food trucks!
TRAVIS: Oh, okay!
MATT: A couple of things. One, ladies, red chips.
LAURA: Yeah!
TRAVIS: Just the ladies?
LIAM: I sneaked it. It's mine!
MARISHA: You fucking--
MATT: The men get black chips.
TRAVIS: Oh good! At least I have one more now.
MARISHA: What? Well, that's fine.
TRAVIS: I have two chips. Two chips! Just saying!
MATT: Roll a smarts check if you could, Sudeis.
MARISHA: Just straight smarts?
MATT: Yes.
LIAM: (accented) Smart check.
MATT: Add to the d6 as well, Let's see what you
find.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
LAURA: All right!
MARISHA: I'm going to re-roll. Do I re-roll both,
or which one?
MATT: Just one, the big one.
MARISHA: The big one? That's not great. Ugh.
Five!
MATT: Five, you add anything to it?
MARISHA: Don't bait me, Matthew Mercer. I know
what you're doing.
MATT: You don't have to.
MARISHA: Trying to get me to use all my tokens.
MATT: You get more information if you--
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MARISHA: (growling) Yeah, the blue one.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: If you finish this game and you have chips
on your table---
MARISHA: No wait. I don't want blue. I want a
red.
LAURA: No! But no, with the red--
TRAVIS: It's already been done.
MARISHA: Oh, because he gets one, right?
LAURA: Do the blue, do the blue.
MARISHA: All right, I'll just use the blue. I
already threw it to you.
MATT: Add your d6.
MARISHA: I would like a d6.
MATT: Like a d6.
MARISHA: Ooh, that's good, ten!
MATT: Ten! You do also recall, as you're putting
these beats of information together: full moon,
lycanthropy, seemingly rumours spreading wide
you've heard of silver mines drying up or being
purchased up.
MARISHA: You know there are certain things that
really like silver when they're also lycanthropes.
LAURA: What the fuck is that word you're
saying?
TRAVIS: Like, or don't like?
MARISHA: Like.
LAURA: Like.
MARISHA: I don't know, do I know things that might
like silver?
MATT: People like silver.
MARISHA: I know certain things are afraid of
silver.
MATT: Werewolves--
MARISHA: They hate silver.
MATT: For werewolves, lycanthropes, it's the only
thing that can kill them.
TRAVIS: Thank you!
MARISHA: My immediate thought would be, if I was
werewolf--
LAURA: There's a, wait. What are we talking about
werewolves? I thought it was a bear?
MARISHA: That's what lycanthropes are,
werewolves.
LAURA: Oh! I understand.
LIAM: Is that a thing that we would all know
about in this--?
MATT: Folklore has heard stories and such, you've
never encountered one. It's occasionally maybe
heard of in fairy tales and such, times have been
weird as of late.
MARISHA: If I was werewolf and had vulnerability
to silver, I'd want to control all the silver. So...
LAURA: Oh.
MARISHA: That way no one can hurt me.
LAURA: So we got a big old wolf trying to
quarantine off--
MARISHA: Or a bear, or it could be other beasts.
TRAVIS: Wait, wait, wait, didn't Swearengen say
that Cy had bought all of the gold and silver
mines? You don't think that Cy could be...
MATT: He didn't say that Cy did. He said that
they'd been purchased up. Cy had lost a lot of
money. He's worried that Hurst might be buying
them up.
TRAVIS: Oh yes, George Hurst, actually.
MARISHA: I also saw Cy run very quickly right
before the moon came out.
TRAVIS: Troubling.
MARISHA: Just saying.
TRAVIS: Troubling. Troubling thoughts.
MARISHA: I think we should keep an eye on Simon.
LAURA: Should we keep looking for a wolf then, or
should we talk to these people in town that
you think might be a wolf?
TRAVIS: I think George Hurst's establishment would
be a good place to visit.
LIAM: Is our trail cold here?
MATT: You guys are deep in the forest. Where are
you going? Are you heading towards--
MARISHA: If it's full moon then he's out in beast
form. We have good chance of finding him in beast form.
MATT: Who wants to make a tracking check?
LAURA: I'll try.
TRAVIS: I would love to.
LAURA: But I don't got a thing.
TRAVIS: Is it tracking-- yeah, it's tracking.
LIAM: Can we all make a tracking check?
MATT: You can all make a tracking check, all
unskilled I'm pretty sure.
LIAM: And then do we roll-- if you've got no skill
in it, is it two d4s?
MATT: No, it's a d4 and a d6, and then minus two.
LAURA: Oh, I did it wrong.
MARISHA: So do you add the d4 and the d6
together?
MATT: No. You take the higher of the two.
LAURA: And if you get the top, you get to roll
again?
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: Two!
MARISHA: Three.
TRAVIS: Six, four.
LAURA: 16.
MATT: Minus two, 14.
LAURA: 14.
TRAVIS: That was a good stack.
LAURA: That was.
MATT: So as you all are lost entirely in the
middle of this forest, middle of the night, the
moonlight the only thing that's giving you any
sort of visual reference. All of a sudden, you
Stinky Ja-- Stinky Jules!
(laughter)
LAURA: I wondered what you were going to call me
there!
MATT: Stinky Jules, you look over and you see
particularly little spats of blood, and larger
beast tracks, recent ones that scale up this way.
You begin to follow, and you guys follow behind
Stinky Jules. You come over a ridge looking down
to where a lot of the plots, a lot of the set
claims are all set up the side and separated with
flags and various markers and such. You can see a
number of them have been closed and boarded up.
MARISHA: The mines?
TRAVIS: What do you see?
LAURA: Uh... a bunch of things have been boarded
up. Can we take them down and go in the place?
MATT: If you want to, there's a number of ones you
can go and check out.
TRAVIS: Not in the terribly condemned,
haunted-looking--
LAURA: Why don't you lead the way, there, Syd?
TRAVIS: (high-pitched) Me?
LAURA: Yeah, you look like you're capable.
TRAVIS: Look, I've already got quite a bit of blood
on my sleeve. I was not quite prepared for this.
Maybe I could draw the outside of this
establishment. I'll go, all right, fine.
LAURA: Yeah. All right.
TRAVIS: And I'll go up to the entrance of the
mine?
MATT: It's a campsite that is currently abandoned,
and it looks like it's been abandoned for a while.
There are a number of wooden boards that are
placed up against the entrance. You look around
and you can see a bunch of leftover discarded mining
materials and what looks like most of the remnants
or the scraps that are left behind in one of the
big mining carts that's currently outside-- make a
notice check. This'd be investigation, make an
investigation.
TRAVIS: Investigation, okay.
Ooh, four.
LAURA: Ooh.
TRAVIS: Ooh, five! I'll take the five.
MATT: You glance around and look inside this and
look around the exterior of it. The dust around
here is silver specifically in nature. This is a
silver mine.
TRAVIS: My fellows, this appears to be a silver
mine. Crazy.
MARISHA: Mm-hmm.
LAURA: Right. Should we look inside the mine?
LIAM: Yeah, whatever this thing is a scourge.
LAURA: Do we see tracks of a beast around?
MATT: The beast tracks faded once it got over the
ridge and went down to the claim area, so...
LAURA: What about this little bear cub that we got
with us. Does he smell anything around?
MATT: (laughs) I'll roll for the bear cub. Bear
cub kind of (sniffing), (cute growl) kind of
leans up against you.
LAURA: Tell you what, he's useless, but he sure is
damn cute.
TRAVIS: Yes, he is.
MARISHA: I still say we use him as bait.
LIAM: Also, I don't understand. Are we saying that
silver is a danger to these creatures? Is that
what you're implying? Why would he have run into
the middle of a silver mine?
MARISHA: Probably wouldn't have.
TRAVIS: Unless he was wounded by the gun that poor
late Charlie was holding.
LIAM: It doesn't make sense, if silver is a bane
to these creatures it wouldn't have run right into
the heart of it.
TRAVIS: It must be empty, then. Stinky Jane, um,
Jules. Why don't you take a look inside?
LAURA: All right. I go and look inside the mine.
MATT: Okay, so you pry open some of the board--
LAURA: Yeah, pull back some of that wood.
MATT: The air is dry and musty in there. You get a
few feet in and it's pitch black. There's no light.
LAURA: Do we got any sort of-- I've got some
matches.
TRAVIS: I do too!
MARISHA: I've got a lantern.
LAURA: Oh! Hey, who's got a lantern?
MARISHA: I come in with a lantern.
TRAVIS: Lead the way. I'm sure it's totally empty.
I'm right behind you.
LIAM: I'm going to walk behind.
MARISHA: Come on, Jules.
LAURA: All right.
MARISHA: The ladies are leading the way. What do we
see?
MATT: You guys glance inside. You walk about 20,
30 feet into the mine before it opens into two
different paths. But immediate at a glance, as--
LAURA: I'm holding my hand above my pistol.
MATT: Okay. You look down both sides of the split
Y formation deep into this mine, and you can see
areas that have been heavily mined. But the thing
that catches your attention is, for being boarded
up and abandoned, there's still a lot of apparent
silver veins in the walls that are in the middle
of being mined before they were left behind. You
see visible veins, even this quickly in.
LAURA: Looks like somebody's trying to--
LIAM: (hiccups and spits)
LAURA: Watch them feathers. Somebody's trying to
keep people from getting this silver.
LIAM: Chat loves a serial killer.
LAURA: What?
TRAVIS: I take offence to that, good sir.
MARISHA: So they bought the mine simply to--
LAURA and MARISHA: Shut it down.
MARISHA: Da.
LAURA: We should get some of that silver though.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MARISHA: All right.
TRAVIS: Should we explore, perhaps see if anything
was left behind?
LAURA: Well, I see some silver's left behind. And I
try to get some.
MARISHA: We should probably get silver-- yeah. Can
we get some silver pieces?
MATT: Yeah, and actually it takes you about half
an hour or so, but you manage to scrounge up some
decent chunks of silver. Probably about five
pounds' worth, which is quite a bit.
LAURA: I don't want to cart around that much. I'm
going to take about a pound of it. Stick it in my shirt.
MARISHA: I'll take the other four pounds.
LAURA: All right.
MATT: (laughs) All right.
LAURA: What's wrong with your damn wrist?
TRAVIS: It-- it does pulse quite a bit.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
LAURA: All right, give it to me. I'll take a look
at it again.
TRAVIS: I'm quite thirsty too. I have a bit of
cottonmouth going on.
LAURA: I'll just keep on pushing.
TRAVIS: (pained) Motherfuck-- I would appreciate
it if you didn't quite press on it quite that hard.
LAURA: Something's weird with this guy.
LIAM: Is there any hair coming out of that hand?
MATT: Nope, not that you can see. Make a notice
check.
LIAM: Okay. Uh, no idea what that is. What do I
roll?
MARISHA: 1d4.
LAURA: And then minus two.
MATT: You're not very good at noticing things.
You're a faithful man. You take faith--
LIAM: All right, three plus--
MATT: The d6 to see which is higher.
LAURA: Yeah, you also roll a d6.
LIAM: Thanks man. Five minus two is three. And I'm
going to waste a blue. So that's a three plus two
is five.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: I'll settle at five.
TRAVIS: Toss that blue. Send it flying.
MATT: Best you can tell, based on the wound, it's
a mild wound. It's a little swollen. It seems to
be fine, but no other visual effect than that.
TRAVIS: (pants) It's so hot in here, isn't it? I
do feel perhaps it's the lantern (pants) and I'll
actually take off the outer coat and really just
roll up the shirt.
MATT: Big pit stains.
LIAM: Are you sure you don't want a poultice on
that?
LAURA: Do you want to hold some of that silver?
LIAM: It's really a simple thing for me to do, to
wrap some mud and some water.
TRAVIS: I feel like I'm earning my marks. I'm
quite proud.
MATT: You hear from the far, far depths of the
mine--
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
MATT: A faint sound going, not "All right".
(laughter)
MATT: It goes, (creepy exhale).
LAURA: Oh shit.
MATT: A deep echoing exhale from deeper in the
mine.
TRAVIS: Oh no. Um. I don't suppose any of you had
gas, just then?
LAURA: Well, I did, but it's usually silent.
MATT: (creepy exhale) It's still a ways away, but
it's getting slowly louder.
LAURA: What the fuck is that?
TRAVIS: Uh, hello?
MARISHA: We should go deeper.
LAURA: I bet that thing's in here!
TRAVIS: What thing? No!
LIAM: Well, we have to make a choice. We either go
in now, stop it from escaping, if it's our killer.
Or go back for reinforcements.
LAURA: Let's go kill it!
TRAVIS: Yes, but could we take a moment to
consider that it was boarded up?
LAURA: I want to go kill it.
LIAM: I take out my crucifix and lead the way.
LAURA: Yeah! Let's go.
MARISHA: Before we walk off I go, Sydney, catch!
And I toss him a piece of silver.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: Oh! Thank you. What is this for?
MARISHA: Just...
TRAVIS: Last night? Yes, jolly good!
MARISHA: I thought it'd be good if we all had
some.
MATT: All right, you guys begin to curl around the
left side where the sound's coming from, and as
you come into a larger mining chamber--
LAURA: I'm holding up silver and I got my hand on
my pistol.
MATT: You see--
MARISHA: I've got the lantern.
MATT: --not a furry creature. As your lantern passes
by, all of a sudden it catches a darker shadowed
shape that looks like a human but with a larger
head than normal. Its body is black and bulbous
and it looks almost shiny like it's covered in
oil, but that's its natural form. It glances over
real fast and its eyes glow as it flashes in the
light and (hisses) it scatters out of the light--
LAURA: Ugh, I shoot it!
MATT: --into a far corner. You're going to shoot
it?
LAURA: Yeah!
MATT: All right, go ahead and make your shooting
skill check.
LIAM: Are her bullets still smited?
MATT: No, the smite only lasts for a few rounds.
LIAM: God damn it!
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: I mean, God bless it!
(laughter)
LAURA: What do I roll for this?
LIAM: You're asking me?
LAURA: What's R.O.F? Is that what I roll-- a six?
Do I roll a d6?
MATT: You do.
LAURA: Okay.
LIAM: 2d-- oh, that's the damage.
LAURA: I'm going to re-roll.
MATT: d6 on your shooting? Your shooting is a d10,
I think.
LAURA: Oh shit! Awesome.
MATT: Look where it is. I think it's pretty high.
TRAVIS: Yeah, it's a d10.
LAURA: Okay. All right.
MATT: And what was the d6?
LAURA: It was uh-- oh, a d6. I didn't--
MATT: Yeah, as well with that one.
LAURA: So that was a nine total.
MATT: What's the lower of the two?
LAURA: The lower of the two is a four. So it adds
to eight.
MATT: Right, as the bear-- is this you
re-rolling?
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Yeah, she wanted to re-roll the trait
die.
MATT: Okay, got you. And the six was a four?
LAURA: Yes.
MATT: Okay, so the bear, thinking that you're its
mother and sees suddenly the fear, runs to your
side and clings to you and in doing so disables
your shot, and you have to go with the lower
strike on that one.
LAURA: Damn it!
MATT: But you do get a black chip from that one.
LAURA: Well, that's good. Hand it over.
MATT: And the bear is heavily-- Blue chip to you
Liam.
LIAM: Oh my god, that was your boob.
MARISHA: I'm great, it was my knee. My knee
deflected.
MATT: The bear is shaking against you and making
it harder to shoot. The gun ricochets off the far
back wall, sparking across the stone.
LAURA: I'm pushing the bear off my leg.
MATT: And you hear once again (creepy breathing).
TRAVIS: I said that's supposed to be mine!
MATT: Heavy breathing. I'll have you guys go ahead
and each draw a card at random from your deck.
LAURA: Oh jeez. Okay.
LIAM: Shuffle one more time.
LAURA: You're going to shuffle it?
LIAM: Hey, question, way earlier in the game, as I
shuffle my cards, you said that I gained two
miracle points back. It's been a while. Do I, or
do I not?
MATT: You gain one more back, so you've gained
three total of what you've used.
LIAM: So, say that last bit again? Because I
thought I was down to one, so if you're giving me
one, now I have two?
TRAVIS: Ladies first. Pick a card.
MATT: You've cast three miracles, correct?
LIAM: Oh Jesus, I don't know. I was marking it
down and, before I asked you that question, I was
at one point.
MATT: How did you get one point? How much do your
miracles cost?
LIAM: I did a lot of shit, man! I thought it was
two a miracle.
MATT: It should say on them. Then yeah--
LIAM: I healed a couple of people. I smited her
bullets.
MATT: Right. So that would be--
LIAM: Three?
MATT: Three uses. Four uses, but you've regained
three. So you would have been at two, to five.
LIAM: So I'm at five now?
MATT: You're at five now.
LIAM: Okay.
LAURA: Wow. Did you pull a card?
LIAM: I did not. I'm going to pull this one.
LAURA: Oh Jesus, really?!
MARISHA: Son of a bitch!
LAURA: Do you see what just happened, with the
three of these?
MATT: Wow, that's great! Great! And what do you
have Laura? A jack. Okay. First things first. As
you were not quite fast enough--
MARISHA: Can we use fate chips to redraw cards?
MATT: Nope! (chuckles)
MARISHA: Fucking fuck!
MATT: This strange creature who's keeping in the
shadows just outside your lantern-light, you hear
the (rasping growl), and it lunges out at you, being
the closest to it. It swoops out towards you. You
can see it's bulbous, it's only about three feet
tall in its size, but its larger head is
awful-looking and it's just a terrible-looking
thing, large saucers for its face. It strikes out
towards you with two of its claws. I want you all
to go ahead and roll a guts roll, by the way.
LAURA: Guts roll. Oh, jeez.
MATT: Minus one.
LAURA: Man, come on. I'm rerolling, just in case.
Oh, sorry, I should warn you.
MATT: I'm going to reroll that.
MARISHA: No. I'm going to spend a fate chip to
counter your reroll.
MATT: Okay. I'll use another one to reroll.
TRAVIS: I'm going to add one to mine.
LIAM: I'm adding.
LAURA: All right, all right, I'm going to add one
too. I'm going to use my blue and add it.
MARISHA: Running out of fate chips.
MATT: All right, so what do you got?
MARISHA: Three on my guts.
LIAM: Nine.
TRAVIS: Five.
LAURA: Eight.
MATT: All right. You, everyone else has managed to
take this back. You are finding yourself shaken
from the perspective of this, and you're now
holding the lantern. There's not much else you can
do at this moment. When it comes to your turn,
you'll have to see if you can reveal that.
However, it does swipe out at you. That's going to
be-- so, what is your parry?
LAURA: Five.
MATT: It rolled a six. It hits you, it strikes
out. You go ahead and suffer, from that, that's
going to be-- I'm going to go ahead and add a d6
to that.
MARISHA: What did you use?
MATT: It was black. All right, that would be eight
points of damage. What's your toughness?
LAURA: Five.
MATT: Five. You are shaken right now as it strikes
out at you, and strikes its claw across your
front. You manage to pull it off, and it just
barely cuts the skin, but it's enough to freak you
out at the moment. That ends its turn. And then
you're up next, actually. At the top of your turn,
go ahead and make a spirit check to try and regain
your composure.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
LAURA: All right, I will! Ooh, yes. Nine.
MATT: Nine? All right. Black chip here. You shake
it off, you're no longer shaken, but that's all
you can really do this turn, as you go ahead and
try and steady yourself and start going for your
gun now to pull it out. I'll say you can pull your
gun out for this turn as well. All right. The rest
of you guys, now, you go ahead and see if you can
make a spirit check to not be shaken.
MARISHA: Just roll a d6? 2d6.
MATT: It would be 2d6 for anything you roll as a
trained check, so yeah.
MARISHA: Ooh, six. Seven, total.
MATT: So you're no longer shaken. That's the end
of your turn. You guys, what do you want to do?
TRAVIS: Go ahead, Father.
LIAM: I want to stab this thing with my crucifix.
MATT: Go for it. So go ahead and roll fighting.
LIAM: Okay, so-- oh, I do have skill in that. So
it's a d4 and a d6? Okay. Four and a four, and I'm
going to give you a red-- no, I'm going to use a
blue chip and add to that for eight.
MATT: Eight, okay. Versus its-- all right, so two
damage. It is now shaken.
LIAM: You are not welcome here!
MATT: As you slam it with the crucifix, (shrieks),
it shrieks back in this high-pitched wail and begins to
push back into the shadows away from you. But
not far enough away to go ahead and give you a
secondary melee attack against it, so it's right
in your face, out of the line of the lantern. All
right, that brings it to you, Travis.
TRAVIS: I kneel down and I say, oh! Look, a
weapon! And I pull out of my boot a bowie knife,
and I would like to rush the creature.
MATT: Go for it.
LIAM: I really admire you.
TRAVIS: Oh shit, what do I roll?
MATT: This would be fighting.
LIAM: (Sydney voice) There seems to be a railgun
over here.
TRAVIS: Nine.
MATT: A d8. Has to be max die.
TRAVIS: Oh, that's right, sorry. That was d6, for
a four. So let me add--
LAURA: That's a reroll.
TRAVIS: Oh, fuck, balls, ass. Okay, well, let's
try it. That was worse.
MATT: Which of the two?
TRAVIS: The six.
MATT: Six. Six does hit. Go ahead and roll your
damage. So 2d4 plus two.
TRAVIS: One. Three. Five. A total of five.
MATT: Toughness of six. You go ahead and strike
with the dagger, and as you hit its hide, it scrapes
in, but does not appear to leave a wound, its
somewhat crackled, black, shadowy form absorbing
most of the impact of the blow, and it turns and
hisses at you, its horrible, small, baby-like
mouth filled with layers of sharp teeth. All
right, your turn back, we're back at the top of
the round. It goes back. It's now going to lash
out at you, Sydney. It's going to go ahead and
make its strike at you. I'm going to go ahead and
add six to that. That is-- that's going to be a
ten. What's your parry?
TRAVIS: Six.
MATT: Six, okay. So it does hit you. It is not a
raise, so it doesn't get the additional d6 damage.
I will spend another blue chip to go ahead and add
a d6 to the damage it's already doing.
MARISHA: Blue chips, I don't have any blue chips
to counter.
MATT: All right, that's going to be 11. What's
your toughness?
TRAVIS: Five.
MATT: Five, that is six points of damage to you,
so that is considered a raise, so you actually are
shaken and you take a wound. You are actually
wounded. The creature leaps out and jams its claws
into your side and bites into your throat. You
freak out and push it back. It doesn't manage to
pull anything free, but it does leave these giant
bite marks on the side.
TRAVIS: I'm leaking. (yelps) Please! Help me!
MATT: All right, you're up, Stinky Jules.
LAURA: All right. I want to shoot it a whole bunch
of times. I'm going to fan my hammer.
MATT: Okay. All right. So your gun's already out.
You're going to go ahead and take all six rounds
on it, at minus two.
LAURA: Yeah, let's do it. I have no idea how
that--
MATT: Make your shooting roll six times, minus two
for each roll.
LAURA: Okay, so that's just a six?
MATT: Whatever your shooting is. Shooting is a
d10. You're really good at shooting.
MARISHA: Hey, that's good! Same thing, yeah, do
it. Nice!
LAURA: Or wait, I'm going to reroll the third one.
So I got eight on the first two, so that's six for
the first two, and then I'm going to reroll the
third.
MATT: They both hit, all right.
LAURA: That's five on the third hit.
MATT: Okay, roll the next three.
LAURA: I'm rerolling this one. Four on the fourth.
Six on the fifth. Rerolling on the sixth one.
Sorry. Oh shit, off the table. And six on the last
one.
MATT: You guys watch as there's a series of
flashes in the center of this room as Stinky Jules
unloads an entire fully loaded gun into this
creature. Go ahead and roll damage for each of them.
LAURA: Oh my gosh. So did I hit every single
time?
MATT: Every single one hit. So roll 2d6 for the
first shot.
LIAM: Jeepers.
LAURA: Six plus one is seven for the first.
MATT: All right, so it is-- all right, next one.
LAURA: Seven for the second.
MATT: All right, next one.
LAURA: Ooh! (gasps) 19. Oh my gosh. 24 on the
next.
MATT: So before you get to the rest of the shots,
you, just screaming, echoing, you unload as this
creature turns around and its face gets shredded
by a hail of bullets from your gun. As it slumps
to the ground and turns to ash and shadow before
dissipating with a (sizzling) sound, you're still--
LIAM: Ease down. Ease down. It's dead.
LAURA: What the fuck was that thing? What's up,
Lucas?
MATT: We have ten minutes left on this game to go
ahead and get to $70,000, guys.
LAURA: How close are we?
MATT: How close are we?
OFF-SCREEN: We're at about $68,000.
TRAVIS: $68,000, just $2,000 away!
MATT: All right, so.
LAURA: I used so many of my chips on that one!
OFF-SCREEN: We're only at $67,000.
LAURA: Oh, $67,000.
MATT: So, after the creature's down, you spend a
while searching the mine. Nothing else of this
type seems to be down here. As you make your way
outside of the mine, you glance and see what looks
to be in the distance about four individuals
running away who seem to have been tracking you.
You see them run towards a distant place, into the
shadows--
MARISHA: How far away are they?
MATT: About, at this point? 200 feet or so.
MARISHA: Still far enough away to where I can
shout at them?
MATT: It's up to you.
MARISHA: Sudis will shout, if you run, only death
will come and find you, and I'm going to attempt
to try and shaken them.
MATT: Okay, go ahead and make a persuasion roll.
LAURA: I'm going to reload my gun while we're
leaving the place.
LIAM: I'm going to bless her bullets.
MARISHA: Ooh, I rolled an eight with a five, so
that's 13 plus two. 15.
MATT: All righty. You watch as most of them run
away and one gentleman stops and turns around.
"Death? I don't want death to follow me!" At which
point, suddenly, you watch as a large cougar leaps
out and just tears his throat out and starts
chewing into his corpse.
LIAM: How did you do that?
MARISHA: I told you. I told you.
LAURA: A large cougar?
TRAVIS: That's a big fucking cat.
LAURA: Should we shoot it?
MATT: It's large for a cougar, but it's not quite
what you were looking for.
LAURA: Okay, all right.
TRAVIS: I mean, there are three of them left,
right?
MATT: But they've all run into the forest. You
guys have options now. You have some silver at
your disposal. You have-- hmm, okay. You have
silver at your disposal, you know some entity's
out there right now. What are you going to do?
LAURA: Find the fucking entity. We should kill it.
We should kill it while we're on the hunt, I mean,
we're ahead of it.
LIAM: Right, but that thing you just killed,
that's not what we were following. We need to
press on.
LAURA: Right, but we can find-- what?
MARISHA: Should we chase after people who were
following us? Or should we maybe check other
silver mines?
TRAVIS: (low voice) I think-- (normal voice) I
think we kill the motherfuckers. We chase them down.
MARISHA: The accent's already rubbing off on you.
TRAVIS: I'm sorry. I'm losing quite a bit of
blood. Reverend, if you would be so kind.
LIAM: It's going to take me a couple of minutes.
LAURA: Can I walk up to him and just punch him in
the gut?
MATT: Sure.
TRAVIS: (grunts) (low voice) You fucking bitch!
And I hit her back.
MATT: Smack across the face. You feel the pain and
sting on the side of your cheek.
LAURA: What the fuck are you?
TRAVIS: I'm terribly sorry, I have quite the
temper.
LAURA: What's going on with you?
TRAVIS: I'm bleeding from the throat.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Please--
LAURA: Are you the monster we're looking for? I
take out the silver and I push it on this face.
MATT: It does nothing.
LAURA: I take it and I push it on his hand.
TRAVIS: Besides the pressure, it's doing nothing,
my dear.
MATT: You watch, at this point, as stepping out of
the sunlight you see E.B. Farnum walking out with
his hat. He goes, "They're right there." And he
turns away to the side, and you see stepping out
as well the gentleman Simon you met earlier and a
few other individuals. You see, holding a couple
of guns trained on you, standing in the center, Cy
Tolliver. You see him step out. His outfit is
shredded. He's like, "If you guys had all just
decided to not go poking where it didn't belong--"
LIAM: We can handle this peacefully! Stinky, put
your gun down. And I bless her bullets.
MATT: All right. Go ahead and make a faith check.
We just hit $70,000, guys.
(cheering)
LAURA: Good job, guys!
LIAM: I'm going to add to that with a red, so it's
six plus two is eight.
MATT: Eight. That is a single raise, so you do
plus four damage for the next three rounds.
LAURA: Awesome!
MATT: All right. We shall see now at this point.
So, at this point, I want you guys all to pick a
card, see where you're at.
TRAVIS: Don't even need to shuffle it.
LAURA: I'm going to choose the one second to the
left. Oh, he's shuffling, I saw the king.
LIAM: This one's the good one on top. Five of
clubs.
LAURA: Did we get a straight? What'd you get?
TRAVIS: Nine.
MARISHA: Four.
LAURA: Aw, so close.
LIAM: Mediocre as hell.
MATT: Immediately, at the top of this round, you
have the nine. You watch as, as you're preparing
yourself for this moment, Cy hits the ground on
all fours, shirt begins to tear, his fur bursts
out of his back, and all of a sudden his mouth
extends, teeth and it seems like an endless supply
of saliva dripping onto the ground. (roars) You're
up first.
TRAVIS: Well, once more into the (deep voice)
fucking breach. I throw both bowie knives that I
have in my sleeves, and I tear after him, just run
at him, both knives out.
MATT: You get right into his area. Go ahead and
roll. Are you going to attack with both of them?
So two attacks at minus two each.
LIAM: You're still skinny as fuck, though, right?
(high-pitched battle cry)
TRAVIS: Matt, I'm going to reroll this one. I'll
leave that there. Okay, so that's six. And I would
like to add a blue chip.
MATT: Okay, here, have one back. Everybody gets a
blue chip.
(cheering)
MARISHA: Yeah, to whoever did that.
LAURA: Thanks, guys!
TRAVIS: Can I add more than one chip to a roll?
MATT: For right now? Sure.
TRAVIS: I can send it back.
MATT: Blue chip to Marisha and a red chip to
Travis.
TRAVIS: So that's 16 total.
MATT: One of each to Marisha.
LIAM: Opa, opa, opa.
MATT: Travis, what are you doing? 16 total for the
first hit? Okay.
TRAVIS: Well, actually, I thought I was just doing
one, so. Hey, I guess I did all that on the first hit.
MATT: So that definitely hits. Go ahead and roll
damage with an additional d6.
TRAVIS: Okay, an additional d6. Six. Ten.
MATT: Ten. All righty. You go ahead and strike
down with the blade, jamming it across the front
of the werewolf's form. It roars, you can see the
exposed wound in itself. It seems to be taken
aback and shaken, but nothing directly beyond
that.
TRAVIS: My second bowie knife.
MATT: Go for it. The small bear named Trinket, by
the way, just begins to slowly hump your leg,
distracting you momentarily.
LAURA: What? Why the fuck?
TRAVIS: That was a five. That's nine.
MATT: Nine. Black chip to Laura. Inspired,
apparently, by the small bear coming to
adolescence. That hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: I'm going to reroll that. That was short.
I can't believe I shorted it. That was even worse.
That was a one.
MATT: Total one. With the plus two?
TRAVIS: Oh, with the plus two is three.
MATT: Three. This one strikes through. Does
nothing. You can see it hits the flesh and tears
across, not able to pierce the outside of this
hardened werewolf exterior. All right, ending your
turn, anyone have five or lower?
LIAM: I had a five.
MATT: All right, you and the wolf go at the same
time.
LAURA: Did Trinket humping me make me not get to
go?
MATT: Oh, you had an eight. Okay, sorry, so you're
going next.
LAURA: Hah! I want to shoot it. I'm going to shoot
the werewolf bear creature. All right.
LIAM: You fucking smell like balls.
LAURA: I do. I'm going to fan my hammer again,
man. I'm going to reroll the first one.
LIAM: They're blessed, they're blessed! Plus four
to--
LAURA: That's seven. Oh, so three on the first
hit, which probably doesn't hit.
MATT: Three misses.
LAURA: Ooh, that's good.
MARISHA: Big money, no whammies, yeah! Go, Laura,
go!
LAURA: So eight, eight, nine on the next ones.
Nine on the one after that, so I've got one more.
Nine-- no, that's a six, damn it.
MATT: Five hit.
LAURA: Okay. All right.
LIAM: Plus four on the damage.
DONATION PROMPT: All right!
LIAM: That's what I said.
LAURA: 12 plus five is 17, plus five, actually. 17
plus five is 22 on the first one. 11 on the second
one. 11 on the third. 18 on the next one. Oh my
god. 15, no, 17 on the next one. Do I get one more
hit? Eight on the last one.
MATT: All right. You unload, bullets blasting into
the werewolf's body. You see it seems like almost
none of the wounds have slowed it down.
LAURA: Oh my god. I'm going to reload.
MATT: You reload your weapon with your quick
reload. All right, ending your turn, now it's your go.
LAURA: I'm going to back away from it, too.
LIAM: I want to bless the crucifix that I'm
holding and attack, which I can do, right? Does
that work?
MATT: Yeah. It'll be minus two to your attacks.
That's to Marisha, actually.
LAURA: Damn, Marisha.
MARISHA: Are we trying to end the game at one
minute?
LIAM: So five is what I roll for
that--
LAURA: Wait, we don't get to finish the game?
MATT: We'll finish it, don't worry.
LIAM: All right, eight on the faith. And then the
attack is what gets gunked, right? Four minus two,
plus four, so six for the stab to the eye.
MATT: You swing, and it actually grabs your hand,
catches it in the air, pulls you right in towards
its jaws. What are you doing?
MARISHA: I'm going to start walking up to it, and
I'm going to say, tonight is the night that you
die, and I'm going to attempt to shaken it with my
persuasion thing.
LIAM: (hiccups)
MARISHA: Because I have it, this I get to just add
a d6 to the roll, right? Fucking fuck. Ooh, 11
plus another five, so that's 16.
MATT: 16, okay. As you say this to the wolf, who's
holding the preacher in his face, it appears to be
still in the same shaken state that it was
previously, its eyes darting around.
MARISHA: How far away am I from it?
MATT: You're about 30 feet.
MARISHA: Can I walk up to it and make it?
MATT: What's your speed?
MARISHA: 20 paces.
MATT: Nope. Peg leg. You're getting closer, but not close
enough.
MARISHA: You're going to die.
MATT: As you finish that, E.B. Farnum pulls out his
gun, with the other two guys who have their
pistols ready, and they unload upon you guys.
LAURA: Oh shit. Is there anything to duck behind?
Probably should've done that.
MATT: Okay. That's a hit to you from E.B., who
says, "I like my hat better!" That's going to be
an eight. Nine. What's your toughness?
TRAVIS: Five.
MATT: Yeah, so that's going to be four over.
That's a raise. You take a wound, which you
haven't been healed since the last one, have you?
So you're now at two wounds. Oh wait, that was a
raise, 'cause you were already shaken, so that's
three wounds. You go right down. You just get shot
in the chest and fall to the ground, and you're
bleeding out now.
TRAVIS: (deep voice) Well, ain't that some fucking
shit.
MATT: The two other gunmen go ahead and start
firing at you and you, being the scariest ones at
that. That's going to be, yeah, with the range
here. You get hit, and you, I'm going to go ahead
and add six to that.
MARISHA: No, you're not!
LIAM: Uncanny Dodge.
MARISHA: No.
MATT: Okay. Add another six to that.
MARISHA: That a red? Is not in the cards for you,
my friend.
TRAVIS: Or we could get a good ending.
MATT: So the other shot towards you does not hit
you. You, however, do suffer-- that's going to be
14 points of damage. What's your toughness?
MARISHA: Four.
MATT: Yeah, so you're shaken and you take a wound.
You now see Simon from earlier pulls out a deck of
cards before him, and you see this sparkle of
bluish energy across his fingers as he goes ahead
and attempts to release a torrent of beams.
LAURA: I think you suffer two wounds.
MARISHA: Two wounds or just one wound?
TRAVIS: Two wounds, because you went ten over.
LAURA: Yeah, she went ten over.
MATT: Oh yeah. You were already shaken before,
weren't you?
MARISHA: No. I shook it off.
MATT: Shaken and then a wound. You're fine.
However, each of you guys. Hits, hits, you're
already on the ground. Each of you guys-- what are
your toughnesses?
LAURA: Five.
MARISHA: This is Simon doing this? Is he shaken,
though?
MATT: Simon wasn't shaken. The werewolf is.
LIAM: Bring us home, Marshal, bring us home.
MATT: So that's going to be a second wound for
you. That's going to be six. What's your
toughness? Five. So you are shaken, now. Against
you, that's going to be six. What's your toughness?
LAURA: Five.
MATT: You're already shaken? You are shaken now.
So, given the circumstances, as they are, you have
no silver weapons and no silver bullets. The fight
presses on for a few more minutes as you all do
the best you can to combat this overwhelming
source, but the perpetual spray of bullets in your
direction eventually puts most of you onto the
ground. And as the wolf tears into your face,
Stinky Jules, you scream out as the jaws of Cy
Tolliver, now extended into white and bloodied
fangs, rips the face from your body, taking out
your jugular. You freak out, E.B. Farnum manages
to get a crack shot that takes off the top half of
your head. You--
LIAM: Thank you, Lord, for letting me sleep with
two women and a man.
(laughter)
MATT: You hear a familiar voice in the back of
your head go, "Yes. You followed the right path."
And you feel this crackling of flames over your
shoulders before-- as now you realize that this
voice indeed was not leading you down the right
way.
LIAM: No shit.
LAURA: What about Trinket? Is he alive?
MATT: Trinket's over your body now as the werewolf
has let it alone.
LAURA: Humping?
MATT: And is just humping your knee as you bleed
out. It's horrible. Time limits.
LIAM: Wait, flames on my back? What?
MATT: You feel flames on your back, knowing that
this entity that's been whispering into your
head is not from your deity. However, the werewolf
walks over, grabs you by the arm, and lifts you
back onto your feet. Turns back toward you, the
preacher, and goes, "Do what you're meant to do.
"Cy commands it." You watch as the visage of the
fantastic Sydney dissipates, and in his place, now
standing before you instead, is a humanoid
cat-like tiger creature with two backwards hands.
(laughter)
LIAM: Thanks, chat!
MARISHA: Thanks, chat. Thank you for that.
TRAVIS: Oh, I hated that fucking accent anyway. I
want to see what you look like on the inside. And
I shove a blade right under his belly button and
open him up from bottom to top.
MATT: You pray as hard as you can to your deity,
but the pain is too hard, but you can't help but
scream out in horrible agony as you are gutted
like a fish--
LIAM: We call him Jesus, but.
(laughter)
MATT: Yeah, there are multiple deities in this
world.
LIAM: Hey, there's one god, clearly one god,
clearly.
MATT: And he's helped you a lot tonight. As you
are gutted in the full moonlight, you hear the
chuckle of Cy Tolliver with his somewhat nervous
allies, evening falling darker still on the future
of Deadwood here, amongst the reckoning. You guys
got wrecked.
TRAVIS: Yeah, Deadlands!
(cheering)
TRAVIS: I'm alive! Murdering another day.
LIAM: R-E-K-T, rekt.
MATT: That was rough. Yeah, going after it without
the silver bullets or using the silver to armor
up, there was no way.
LAURA: We didn't have time for it.
LIAM: Where's the silver bullets? We don't got a
smelting machine.
MATT: Somebody to smelt it.
MARISHA: Well, we only had five minutes left in
the stream.
TRAVIS: Oh, excuses, excuses, dead people.
LAURA: Man. That was a fun game. What did we get
to?
OFF-SCREEN: Over $71,000.
(cheering)
OFF-SCREEN: We still have a little bit more stream
going, just to end it off, so looking like if we
get to $75,000, should we still give them the
75,000 goals that we had, including the--
TRAVIS: Absolutely. Yeah, 100%.
OFF-SCREEN: And they can commemorate this chat,
because these are still available.
MATT: You guys did an amazing job. Thank you so
much for tuning into this absolute chaos and adding to it.
MARISHA: And 100% of the proceeds from those
shirts are going to the MDA.
LIAM: Thank you for donating. Thank you.
LAURA: You guys are amazing. Thanks for all the
chips.
MARISHA: I wish I had a few more minutes to wreak
havoc.
LAURA: I know, right?
MARISHA: Just a few more is all I needed.
MATT: You know what, you saved a few people in
town. They'll probably inevitably be destroyed by
the incursion of Cy Tolliver--
LAURA: Eventually, yeah.
MARISHA: That was fun.
MATT: This is a lot of spoilers for the Deadwood
movie coming up, by the way. They have to compete
with Supernatural and Walking Dead, so they're
just throwing werewolves in.
LAURA: My throat hurts from talking like Stinky
Jules the whole time. All right!
TRAVIS: Caught what she caught, huh?
MARISHA: What's happening now?
MATT: Nice, that's fantastic. You guys have raised
such an incredible amount of money. Thank you so
much for tuning in and being so generous and
helping this amazing cause. We're going to go
ahead and prep you guys for the next bit of
entertainment closing up the rest of this charity
stream. See if we can hit that 75k goal. That
would be incredible. Thank you for making my first
foray into the chaos of Savage Worlds what it was,
though I'm pretty sure it usually doesn't involve
so many fate chips and a lot of-- there was a lot
of intrigue we didn't hear that just got thrown
out the window as soon as shit started happening.
That's okay. That's the nature of these wonderful
games. Guys, thank you so much. We're going to go
ahead and clean up here and prepare for your next
performance, and yeah. We'll see you guys-- you'll
see these guys this coming Thursday, and me and
Marisha will see you the following Thursday for
the next episode of Critical Role. Lots of love, guys.
TRAVIS: Thank you!