(cheering, applause)
MATT: This is a lot of people. Before we begin,
just want to let you guys know a large part of
this panel is a Q&amp;A. We do have a microphone right
up here in front, so if you have a question you
want to ask, line up now so we can get that chaos
started before the panel. So ♫ make your ♫
♫ way to the mic right there. Contra your way to the
mic right there. ♫ Don't actually do
that. That's a very bad idea. All right, cool. Now
that we've got that flow going, I would like to
welcome all of you guys to this afternoon's
Critical Role panel here at
Wizard World, Portland.
(cheering, applause)
MATT: My name is Matthew Mercer. I am the Dungeon
Master for Critical Role and I personally want to
thank you all for coming. This is more than I
expected and I'm--
(cheering, applause)
--really excited about that. I'm a voice actor. We
started playing this crazy game and a Dungeon
Master wouldn't be much without his players so let
me go head and start bringing the rest of our crew
here today onstage, beginning with the incredibly
talented, hilarious Scanlan Shorthalt, played by
Sam Riegel.
(cheering, applause)
SAM: Hi, guys. Good to see you.
MATT: Followed up by the wondrously tinker-worthy
human gunslinger Percival von you know the name,
played by Taliesin Jaffe.
(cheering, applause)
MATT: Say hi, Taliesin.
TALIESIN: Hello. Hi, Taliesin. Oh, good, the
microphone works. Hi! Oh, wow. My god, that's a
lot of you.
MATT: Next up, we have the masterful,
professional, mentally possibly challenged
barbarian of strength and might, Grog
Strongjaw, played by Travis Willingham.
(cheering, applause)
TRAVIS: Thank you, Kimmy. (clears throat) Also
ale.
MATT: Let's bring in our lovely ladies of the
group as well, following up with the wondrous
Vex'ahlia, one half of the half-elf twins, the
ranger gathering Trinket the bear through the
wild, we have Laura Bailey.
(cheering, applause)
TRAVIS: Wow!
LAURA: What's up?
TRAVIS: That was a good twirl.
LAURA: How are you guys doing?
MATT: Bringing up the rest of our intrepid band of
adventurers, we have the Air Ashari half-elven
druid Keyleth, played by Marisha Ray.
(cheering, applause)
TRAVIS: What a peaceful bow.
MARISHA: The water bottle bow.
MATT: And our mystical empty chair will also join
us on the edge of the panel.
SAM: It's Gilmore.
MATT: This chair represents our two party members
who could not be here, unfortunately, but sending a
little bit of love from here to Ashley, who
plays Pike, which we have a wonderful
cosplayer in the audience.
TRAVIS: That's a great looking Pike.
(cheering, applause)
TRAVIS: This is a bunch of people, man!
MATT: Yes! And Liam O'Brien, who plays the other
half of the twins, Vax'ildan. Much love to you, Liam.
TRAVIS: Much love, Liam!
(cheering, applause)
LAURA: And Trinket. You forgot to introduce
Trinket.
MATT: I mentioned Trinket, but everyone was
screaming over me. But yeah, Trinket of course.
Your favorite.
SAM: I love Trinket.
(laughter)
SAM: I would love him sizzled over a nice grill
with some salt.
MATT: I should've sat you next to her. That
would've been fun.
TALIESIN: That would've been fun.
MATT: So, yeah, guys, we're excited that you came!
Who here doesn't know what the hell's going on
right now?
TRAVIS: Yes! Welcome!
LAURA: Join us!
(speaker feedback)
MATT: So we are ... apparently about to explode.
We're a bunch of professional voice actors working
in video games and animation who also happen to be
huge nerds who play Dungeons and Dragons. We began
streaming our campaign about two years in, almost
a year ago, actually. We're coming up on our
anniversary soon. We stream on Twitch for Geek and
Sundry every Thursday at 7 PM Pacific Time. We
weren't sure if this was going to go anywhere and
anybody would like to watch it, and well, I think
we were very wrong.
TALIESIN: Apparently. It's pretty amazing.
MATT: Which is great. We're happy to be here and
why not kick this off with some of you guys' fan
questions and see the stories roll out from there?
So don't be afraid to jump in if you have any
random thoughts or ideas. You, sir, the front.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Yes, sir.
LAURA: Warn us if you're not up to date.
TRAVIS: You should say if you're current or not.
MATT: We're trying to keep spoilers out of this
discussion if possible.
LAURA: Which is going to be hard.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: I'm one episode back. I didn't
get a chance to see Thursday but I'm expecting to
watch it on Monday.
TRAVIS: Everybody from here over is dead.
(laughter)
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Don't worry.
MATT: Which is really weird for me. You kill the
DM, your game gets a little strange.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: So that actually kind of brings
up my question. About two or three episodes ago,
Liam said, "Oh, well I guess next week we're
playing Shadowrun." Are we one TPK away from a
different game? Or are we rolling up new
characters and going up next week?
LAURA: That's a good question!
(laughter)
MATT: You know, this world of Exandria that I've
kind of created and they've kind of helped build
that with their character moments and backstories
and such. If any characters were to die, they
would roll up a new character and we'd incorporate
them into the story to then join Vox Machina going
forward. If it was a TPK, if I survive the
internet's backlash, we would pick up where the
story left off probably with another band of
adventurers to continue the plot from a different
angle in some way.
SAM: What if everyone dies except Scanlan?
Could I have my own show that's just me
and you and a triceratops?
(laughter, cheering)
SAM: Like a buddy comedy.
MATT: I think you have your answer. Sorry, guys.
Sorry.
LAURA: It's all right. I understand.
MATT: Great question.
MARISHA: Lean all the way up to the mic.
MATT: The mic is your friend.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Oh, yes, indeed. What were you
guys' inspirations for the characters? I can tell
a little bit with Grog it's kind of a Conan the
Barbarian kind of deal? What were your inspirations?
TRAVIS: I'm an idiot, so Grog's an idiot.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: The first game that we had was at Liam
O'Brien's birthday party and Matt had given us
classes, races, all that stuff, and I was like,
uh, I don't want to be an orc. I'll be a goliath!
Goliaths are big. I'm big, that'll be fun and I'll
be a barbarian because I suck at math and spells
seem complicated and whatever. I didn't even come
up with a name and he sat down and he goes,
"What's your character's name?" and I was like...
Grog? There was a lot of thought that went into
some of these characters.
TALIESIN: You were very excited about your boots.
I do remember that. The boots were very intense.
He made boots.
TRAVIS: I made fine leather boots.
LAURA: He was so proud of that fact. And it has
not come into play at all.
MARISHA: It has not come into play since he
established that.
TRAVIS: Nope. He makes shitty leather boots.
That's probably the better way to say that.
LAURA: But he thinks they're fine.
MARISHA: I imagine Grog has an Etsy store in his
spare time, making boots.
TRAVIS: Bootmaiden. That's my Etsy name.
LAURA: I like it.
TRAVIS: Inspiration for your characters? Other
inspirations.
TALIESIN: Mine was based off of a short story that
I had written and never done anything with. Percy
takes a lot of cues from the movie Plunkett and
MacLeane. That movie is ridiculous and I'm so
proud that it exists. That and a short story about
what the poor jerk who invented the first gun
would've been like and what awful circumstances
would've led to that. It's changed quite a bit
from there but that's kind of where I came from.
LAURA: That's where it started?
TALIESIN: It was exciting. It was a class I'd
never played before. It was Pathfinder.
I was curious.
LAURA: That very first game, though, you were
something else.
TALIESIN: I was a dragonborn paladin.
LAURA: Our very first game that we played, nobody
really knew how to play except for Matt and
Taliesin and Liam had played some.
TALIESIN: In high school.
LAURA: But we all were floundering. We had no
idea. So they brought Taliesin as the ringer so if
we got into trouble he could be like, "I got you
covered."
TALIESIN: There were several times things just got
worse and worse and worse and I was finally like,
okay, coming in, fixing it. All right, let's move
on.
TRAVIS: He literally came in like Doogie Howser
and just brilliantly solved a puzzle that we were
all nearly about to die from.
LAURA: We're going to die!
TRAVIS: The look on Matt's face was like this is
first grade and you're all dead already.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: I'm so glad I don't have to do that
dragonborn accent anymore. That was so awful.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Do it!
TALIESIN: He was just sort of heavy and dry and
everything, he was, ugh, god awful.
TRAVIS: Woohoo!
TALIESIN: Why?
TRAVIS: It's kind of sexy.
(laughter)
SAM: My character came about because I didn't know
anything about Dungeons &amp; Dragons and I asked Liam
what's the dumbest character and he said,
"Probably a bard." I was like, "What's the weakest
character?" He said, "I don't know, like, a
gnome." I went to Dungeons &amp; Dragons name
generator and that's how I found the name.
LAURA: No way!
MARISHA: I didn't know that.
SAM: I totally half-assed it.
(laughter, applause)
SAM: Yeah. Totally just like "Yeah, sure,
whatever." We were going to do it one time! It
wasn't important!
TRAVIS: Were you hoping to die in one session so
you could come back as something--
SAM: Well, we were all going to just play once for
his birthday and that was it. So I was like, eh,
I'll just be a dumb character. And then it turns
out I'm the best one!
(cheering, laughter)
SAM: I'm super powerful and awesome! I can do
anything! It's amazing! Who knew? And I I get to
sing. I love it. What'd you say?
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Including crapping on a bed.
SAM: That's right. I can crap on beds. That's an
extra class feature.
MARISHA: I had tried the druid in 4th edition and
I hated it and I thought druids were useless. And
then we did this game and I was like all right,
yeah, I guess I'll give druids a shot one more
time. This was Pathfinder and you could pick a
domain kind of like clerics could, and I couldn't
decide between any of the elements, so I was like,
well, I'll just start with air and I'll just make
it my thing to go get all of them. And that's how
she was born, not really out of character
development, mainly out of selfish min/maxer
shit.
(laughter)
MARISHA: I'm a huge Avatar: The Last Airbender
fan.
(cheering)
MARISHA: I didn't mean to make her based off of
The Last Airbender. It subconsciously seeped in
and happened that way.
LAURA: Nice.
MARISHA: Yeah. That's it, really.
LAURA: I wanted to be a rogue, but Liam had
already taken rogue. And I wanted to be a
half-elf, but Liam had already taken half-elf.
Then I realized that Liam and I actually in real
life share a birthday and so I'm like, "What if we
were actually twins in the game?" He loved it and
we went with it. I was debating between a ranger
and a druid. Actually, I didn't even know for sure
which one I wanted. I just emailed Matt and I was
like, I want a pet. What class can I have a pet
with? And he said either a druid or a ranger, so I
went with ranger so I could have Trinket.
(cheering)
LAURA: Who's wonderful.
MARISHA: Yes.
SAM: He's the best.
LAURA: I just started multiclassing into rogue,
though, because I figure it's been long enough, I
can start learning the stealthy moves from my
brother.
TRAVIS: That was a great question. Who wears a
2XL? Here, have a jetpack fighter shirt. I'm
giving out stuff when awesome questions are
asked.
MARISHA: I don't even know where you pulled that
from.
TALIESIN: You don't want to know. We're throwing
stuff at everyone.
TRAVIS: Goliath's got huge cavities.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: They said one question. Matt,
what comes first? The voice or the NPC?
MATT: For me, it's the NPC. For me, the character
inspiration for the NPC comes from where they fit
in the story, where they fit in the civilization,
what their drives are. Then I start thinking about
their history. Then I decide, depending on from
that point, what their racial traits and lifestyle
would lend them to have a specific type of
cadence, texture, vocal pitch. The voice is the
last thing that actually goes to it. But I make
sure to note next to every NPC what the voice type
and dialect is because inevitably they're going to
be pulled out of nowhere. It's fine if it's a home
game and a character's voice changes from session
to session, but when you have CritRoleStats
scanning every episode--
TRAVIS: He's got his notepad right now!
SAM: He's taking notes.
MATT: "How many character NPC inconsistencies has
Mercer done since episode one? Let's look at the
time code."
TRAVIS: He's our court stenographer.
MATT: Right, I know. That's also forced me to kind
of step up my game a little bit, too. You guys
have helped me with that. So I go character first,
voice second, and then make notes to remind myself
where that lies.
SAM: Then do you choose how many fingers they
have?
(laughter)
MATT: That's only come up recently. That's called
character progression.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Oh, that's so good.
SAM: Soon it will be less than three.
MATT: Well played.
TALIESIN: That character came out of nowhere, too.
Like that was, apparently, I just found out that--
MATT: Yeah, Victor wasn't planned. Victor was an
NPC that was pulled out of the ether when we were
in Vasselheim the first time, and Percy's like,
"I'm going to go buy some black powder. Where can
I find that?" And I'm like--
SAM: Better think quick!
MATT: Well, let's find out. (nervous strangled
sound) Like, even when he asked, "What's your
name?" and I just went "Victor!" He was like,
"What was that?" and I went, in my head, "I don't
know. What did I just say?"
(laughter)
MATT: "It sounded kind of like Victor. Victor it
is!" It came out of nowhere, so sometimes NPCs get
created simultaneously.
LAURA: Had you created Gilmore before we ran into
Gilmore?
MATT: Yes, I had designed Gilmore's Glorious Goods
as part of the Abdar's Promenade in Emon
intentionally, as one of the characters you might
encounter as you went through the city, so I was
very glad that he got to have his moment to shine,
and continue to shine. I wasn't expecting him to
become so central to parts of the story.
SAM: Shines so brightly.
LAURA: We just love him so much.
TRAVIS: There is no life without Gilmore.
MATT: "He's a majestic one." I only recently
realized, looking back at the episodes, that his
hand is like this. He just has a hand, at all
times, he's presentary, and then when he's,
"Mm-hmm, of course." It's almost like he's holding
a fan but there's not one there? I don't know.
It's weird. Good question!
AUDIENCE MEMBER: This is for you for later.
MATT: Oh! All right!
SAM: Okay, that was a good question. Someone's
getting a t-shirt.
TRAVIS: Just throw it a hard as you-- First row.
MATT: You're just hitting that front row, man.
TRAVIS: You made it to the first row.
SAM: My arm is spaghetti. I'm a young boy.
LAURA: You have little boy arms!
TRAVIS: I'm a little boy. Don't hit me!
MATT: Yes!
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Here's a question I'm sure the
people at CritRoleStats would like to know about.
It's directed at Taliesin. As far as the feat you
chose for Percival, we've seen two of the three
choices that you've made for him. Will we be
seeing the third choice?
TALIESIN: No, you've seen all three!
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Oh, really?
SAM: What are they?
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Hex?
TALIESIN: Hex, Minor Illusion, and Friends.
LAURA: Oh, that's right!
TALIESIN: Friends is the third one, which I have
now used a couple times.
SAM: (hums Friends theme)
TALIESIN: I was about to use it on you if things
started getting way too bad in the shop.
TRAVIS: Ah, shit.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: I was going to very gently suggest that
you just hand everything over to Vex, and enchant
you to do so. I was prepared to--
TRAVIS: I didn't know you could do magic!
TALIESIN: That's my money!
MARISHA: Instead, you pulled the amazing Minor
Illusion move.
TALIESIN: Minor Illusion worked out great.
TRAVIS: Missed that too!
LAURA: I have to say, this is the best thing,
because Travis legitimately did not know that
that's what he did.
TALIESIN: Oh yeah.
LAURA: It wasn't a character choice. He just
didn't know.
TRAVIS: People were like, oh, Travis with the
amazing RP, playing a character. I didn't fucking
notice, you guys.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: After the game, he's like, "So what
would have happened if I'd put my hand in the
shadow?" I'm like, "Well, you would have grabbed
the skull then, wouldn't you?" And he's like,
"No!" You were so angry.
TRAVIS: Matt was gonna give it to me, too!
And I’m like, I don't reach in there! You with
your stupid shop water!
TALIESIN: I was trying to give you the eye when
that was happening, like don't do it! Don't do it!
AUDIENCE MEMBER: He's super dumb.
TRAVIS: You're all a bunch of dicks.
MATT: Good on you.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: This is as both you as people,
and as characters. It's hard because Liam's not
here, but do you guys think that Vaxleth is a
healthy relationship?
(laughter)
SAM: Is a healthy relationship?
LAURA: No! Not at all!
TALIESIN: No.
SAM: No, not at all.
TALIESIN: They're like the two friends in high
school who are dating, and like, this is gonna be
such an explosion.
(laughter)
LAURA: It's gonna be so bad.
MARISHA: This is the first time I'm hearing any of
this, by the way!
(laughter)
MARISHA: So no, tell me! How bad is it, guys? Tell
me. Let's get it all out right now.
TALIESIN: It's amazing.
LAURA: I just love-- no, wait, not everybody's
caught up.
TALIESIN: Do it.
MARISHA: Spoiler alert! If you're not caught up,
go la la la la la.
LAURA: Kashaw showing up in the last episode made
me so happy as a person.
TRAVIS: So happy.
LAURA: So good! And so angry, as Vex. It was
wonderful.
TRAVIS: It's pretty great.
MARISHA: Yeah, no, I'm starting to get used to
it.
MATT: Aww!
LAURA: I'm kind of going for it now, as Vex,
though.
MARISHA: Yeah.
LAURA: I'm kind of going for it.
MARISHA: I mean, we could talk about you and
Jarett.
(oohing)
SAM: He's so hot.
MARISHA: I actually did not expect that type of
reaction.
TRAVIS: It's the crossbow.
LAURA: He's pretty wonderful. He's pretty
wonderful.
MARISHA: It's a good question, dude.
TALIESIN: All right, good. Okay, XL, big XL. I'm
going over here.
MARISHA: I love our system. You have a good
question. Let's give attention to someone else. Is
that my-- too much?
SAM: It's just pointing over there. Let's move it
up.
MATT: Technology.
LAURA: Oh, right because it's all over to the
side. It's sliding.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: So, I've been a DM for a little
bit, and I--
SAM: Quick, DM off!
(laughter)
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Mainly a question for Matt, but
everyone else can help answer it.
TRAVIS: Okay, we'll help you.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Well, thank you. I've been having
troubles with my players actually trying to
roleplay in the games, I mean. I try setting up
the scenarios so it's easy for them to do it, but
one of them, his most creative side is to kill a
monster by poking it in the butt.
LAURA: (laughing) That's amazing!
MARISHA: That's a method, yeah!
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Yes, but every time it's not! But
I--
MATT: And then what happens if he comes back into
town and someone's like: "Oh, look, it's Gerald,
the Butt Poker!"
(laughter)
MATT: "All hail the Butt Poker!" And he becomes
known as the Butt Poker everywhere. Then you can
work it in.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: There's another one that, instead
of trying to escape a dangerous encounter that I
put him in, instead started to roll for a new
character while we were playing the game.
(laughter)
AUDIENCE MEMBER: So, how do I make them--
MARISHA: It sounds like your players have more
issues of optimism.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: -- get them more open to the
game?
MATT: For them to already be rolling a new
character during the encounter means maybe then
want to try a different class, which is fine if
they want to do that. As far as engaging people,
to use an old adage, you can lead a horse to
water. A person has to feel comfortable enough to
step out of their comfort zone to try it, so you
can't force it on them. You can try and coax them
into it over time. I also find it helps if you
engage them as the NPC directly. If you tell them,
"You walk into a tavern, the barkeeper
tells you, Ah, you should buy a room! It's
different than going, "He turns to you, squeaks
the inside of his jar and goes, Aye, miss,
"what can I do for you?" You know? And just that
eye contact? It becomes a conversation as opposed
to keeping them in their imagination, controlled
facet that feels more comfortable. It might take
a while. You can talk to your players and be like,
"Hey guys, it'd be cool if we could try and push a
little more into character RP and discussions, and
don't put any pressure on them for it but help
coax them out by addressing them directly and
taking into account that what they say is what
their character says. Something like, "Oh, I'm not
going to talk to this guy." Be like, "I'm sorry,
you're not going to talk to who?!" "Oh, I
mean-- I didn't-- That was him!" So you can
can play in elements of that and get them
comfortable with the idea of speaking as
their character. Not everyone will be, and
you can't force it.
LAURA: I'm seeing behind the screen right now and
it's kind of weird. To know that that's what
you're doing to us.
(laughter)
SAM: Puppet master.
TALIESIN: Things just work out better when we
actually RP.
MATT: Well that's the thing. RP circumstances can
also have their own rewards, too. If someone talks
their way out of a good situation, they'll get a
more profitable circumstance based on the quest or
mission they're on. They might uncover information
that is vital to their current plan and
disposition. They may end up unlocking an ally
that they didn't have previously. These are all
different ways you can reward good RP, as well as
just a nice little experience bump. I keep track
of good character moments, and I give little bonus
experience points.
TRAVIS: You do not!
(laughter)
TALIESIN: He does! Do you not read the emails you
get, like, every like-- oh, yeah.
TRAVIS: There's a bunch of numbers in them!
(laughter)
MARISHA: You realize we get different numbers,
right?
LAURA: We do? Wait! So those are-- Wait, wait!
MARISHA: We don't get the same.
LAURA: Do I get extra experience when I
haggle?
TRAVIS: No, nobody cares about that.
(laughter)
LAURA: Because you never write that in the email
that I get extra experience for that!
MATT: That was a great question. Thank you so
much!
(laughter)
TRAVIS: No, damn it! Oh, the door is
closed! He doesn't tell us crap!
LAURA: Nothing!
TRAVIS: And we try all the time.
MATT: It's fun.
LAURA: Travis texts him all the time.
TRAVIS: I text him when it's late, maybe he's had
a drink, maybe he's tired. "If I had actually
crushed his skull, what would have happened?" And
he's like, "You don't know." Son of a bitch.
(laughter)
MARISHA: I'm actually really excited because we
have planned, as soon as we all eventually die or
if this campaign comes to an end, we're going to
have a party that's us at god's gate. And it's
just going to be us asking Matt, "Okay, that one
time that we did this--" And it's just going
to be us asking Matt all the questions that
we've ever wanted to ask.
TRAVIS: Maybe we should just all die now.
LAURA: TPK.
TRAVIS: Suicide pact!
SAM: You sir, what's your question?
AUDIENCE MEMBER: First, if anyone hasn't seen
Thursday's episode, you have to watch it. It's the
best in a long time.
(cheering)
AUDIENCE MEMBER: My question is for Matt. I've
been DMing my own campaign for close to a year
now, and my question is about roleplaying,
specifically roleplaying women. Going into it, I'm
aware of all these tropes and pitfalls that I can
fall into for roleplaying women. How do you
approach designing and RPing a woman?
SAM: All women talk like this. (valley girl
accent) Hi. Oh my god.
TALIESIN: You are a master class, I swear. I feel
like a better actor just sitting next to you.
MATT: I actually felt the heat from Laura's stare
on that one.
TRAVIS: You don't want those dragon eyes.
MATT: It's interesting, because it is a comfort
hurdle for a lot of players and Dungeon Masters
alike to step into the opposite sex. You know, we
have a lot of cultural weirdness in places about
that whole thing, and you have to kind of look
past that initially. I was a theater kid, so I
didn't have any shame.
(cheering)
MATT: Woo! But also, it's just like any other
person. They're just a person. You think of their
wants, their needs, their fears, their drives,
their goals. As a female, you consider their place
in the world. Is it like our society was fifty
years ago where women were almost a second-class
citizen, and are they fighting to make themselves,
fighting back against the patriarchy? Are they
heralded as a matriarch? Is it like Lolth spider
queen style, where the men are just used for
fodder and mating, and are slaughtered? Figure out
their power dynamic in society, and be comfortable
that it's a strong character, not necessarily that
it's a woman. That becomes a secondary and
unnecessary facet to it, in my opinion.
MARISHA: And that's true for storytelling in
general.
LAURA: Yeah.
(clapping)
MATT: As far as just distinguishing-- I had this
question earlier, how do you change your voice to
be female? I don't change my voice that much,
really. There's a difference between chest voice
and head voice. You know, thinking of the
definition, it goes up more into your upper palate
and your sinuses, and for a man it just takes some
of the resonation out of it to where a character
that talks normally in this way can sound a little
softer, a little more--
TRAVIS: Light.
MATT: Gently domineering, which I really enjoy as
a strong female NPC. Allura skirts that line quite
a bit, and I like that a lot. More than anything,
it shouldn't be part of a focus. You always get
that dumb player who gets asked by the barmaiden,
"Can I get you guys a drink?", and he's like, "Oh,
she's a woman? Well I'm going to go ahead and slap
her on the butt." He's about to get pummeled by
the guards in the tavern. Remember, even in these
societies, sexism probably is not cool, and
whoever works at that bar has a lot of friends she
works with that are watching her back. Just saying.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: All right, thank you.
MATT: No worries. Good question.
TRAVIS: Great question!
(clapping)
LAURA: We have no more t-shirts.
MATT: Hello!
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Theater for life, first off.
MATT: Yes.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: I apologize if I ramble, because
I do that. Thanks to Critical Role and things like
Wil Wheaton's TableTop, watching people play
tabletop games has become very popular. More
popular than it has been previously, with tons of
Twitch shows like Critical Role, actual plays,
which are podcasts of people playing D&amp;D and
things--
MATT: Yeah.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: With all of that, are there any
secondary versions of Critical Role, actual plays,
things like that, that you guys enjoy? If so,
what? If not, would you?
SAM: To watch on our own, you mean?
AUDIENCE MEMBER: To watch, or listen to, or
anything like that. You can put it on your phone
as a podcast.
SAM: Well for myself, I can barely even make the
game that we play.
(laughter)
SAM: So I don't have a lot of time to veg out and
watch other people play and roll dice, although I
heard Laura was in, you both were in Titansgrave?
LAURA: Titansgrave, yeah.
SAM: I mean, that was cool.
LAURA: Thanks.
(laughter)
TRAVIS and MARISHA: (laughing) That was cool.
LAURA: Yeah, Titansgrave was really fun. Kurtis
Wiebe, the writer and co-creator of Rat Queens--
(cheering)
LAURA: They do D20 Babes, and we did a Star Wars
RPG with Kurtis. And it was really really fun and
they're great people.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I played a wookie. That was great.
(wookie noise)
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Couldn't talk. I loved it.
MARISHA: And there's always "Acquisitions Inc."
Acquisitions Inc has been around forever. They're great.
MATT: Yeah, that's really great. Also, there's-- I've enjoyed
it for a long time-- Real Role Play with itmeJP.
Those guys have done phenomenal games for a very long
time. There's also-- what was that?
LAURA: (muffled)
MATT: Oh, I confused myself. Also, recently the
Yogscast guys have done High Rollers which is DMed
by a good friend of mine, Mark Holmes out in the
UK. And they're kicking ass as well, so those are
a number of the ones that I watch and keep track
of, both for inspiration and to meet other people
in the community, so it's cool.
SAM: Good question.
MATT: Well done.
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: Your quest is fantastic.
MARISHA: Next question.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Hello.
MARISHA: Hello.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: I have a question that's a little more
specific than these other ones. It has to do with
the very first Critmas special, where toward the
end Marisha got an in-character letter from Pike
which included a psalm that was in Celestial, and I
was wondering if you ever got it translated?
MARISHA: To decipher the letter that I got from
Pike that was written in Celestial?
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Yeah.
MARISHA: You know, it's still on my to-do list.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: I have a translation for you.
MARISHA: I'm sure it's a wonderful, lovely
message.
TALIESIN: She owes me breakfast, so this doesn't
surprise me.
MARISHA: True.
LAURA: Did you write it?
MARISHA: Was that you?
AUDIENCE MEMBER: I brought the translation with
me, so you don't have to do the work.
(applause)
MATT: That's awesome! I was surprised, too, because
she took Celestial for three years in college.
(laughter)
MATT: She should have it.
TRAVIS: Eat more chicken.
SAM: That's a lot of cursing.
TALIESIN: Don't call it a comeback. I've been here
for years.
MARISHA: I'm going to cry if I read it.
TRAVIS: Don't read it.
MARISHA: Okay, keep going.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: So I'm the dungeon master for
our current group, and I've noticed on Critical
Role that, whenever you guys roll a one, it's
just an auto-miss, and you guys don't have a
fumble chart or anything for the ones. I was
wondering if that was something specifically for
the show, or if you as a dungeon master don't like
using them, or what was up with that, or if there
is just enough pain in the game as it is.
MATT: Right.
SAM: What is he saying, what? Translate. I don't
play Dungeons and Dragons. I don't know what he's
talking about.
(laughter)
MATT: In older editions, in some variations, if you
were to roll a natural one, it wasn't just an auto
miss, it was--
TRAVIS: You died.
MATT: You had to roll on a chart to see what
horrible thing happened to you for rolling so poorly.
SAM: Oh, okay.
MATT: Which is really fun. For my games, I
consider the natural one more of a narrative
failure. I like to explain the visual aspect of
why you failed so much, and in some cases it's
more of a shame than an actual-- more of
a mechanical horrible blunder.
MARISHA: It's always a shame, always shame.
MATT: And partially because I've played games
where people use those charts, and they're like,
"All right, you go to attack the orc. Critical
fail. You accidentally cut off your
"own head." And I'm like, "Really? How is that?
No."
SAM: How would you ever do that?
MARISHA: Yeah, what was the con we were at this
past weekend, and the guy was telling a story
about that, and he rolled to just gently kick his
friend awake, just kind of nudging his friend
awake, and so the DM made him roll for it, and he
rolled a nat one.
MATT: Natural 20.
MARISHA: Oh, it was a natural 20.
MATT: He was like, "Roll a strength check," and
I'm like, "To kick your friend awake?"
LAURA: He kicked his head off?
MARISHA: He kicked his head off!
(laughter)
MARISHA: You're 100% right. He kicked his head off
and I was like, "That's harsh. That's, like, way harsh."
LAURA: That's bullshit.
MARISHA: You just got punished for a nat 20.
LAURA: That's not okay.
TRAVIS: That's great.
(laughter)
MATT: So yeah, I think it's a cool system if you
want to incorporate it. I tried it for years for
certain things and it has its merits, definitely.
I felt for our game I like to make the fumbles
more of a narrative failure than an actual
mechanical failure. Because then it can get a
little too weird and really, really bite you back.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: I gave them the choice and they
chose the sheet
MATT: Well, fair enough, and that is entirely their
call.
TALIESIN: Heads will roll.
MATT: Let them burn.
SAM: Yes, sir.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Hello. This question is not so
much about D&amp;D as it much as it is about your
careers in general, and kind of just a fun
question entirely, but if you could steal one role
from one of your colleagues, like for example if
Travis wanted to steal the role of Krom from Matt,
or if Marisha wanted to steal the role of Maka
from Laura, would you do it and who would you take?
LAURA: Stealing a role from somebody else?
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Yeah, if you wanted to voice
somebody that one of these people--
SAM: A voice role.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Would you do it? Like who would
it be?
LAURA: Oh man.
MARISHA: I don't know if I've thought about it.
LAURA: I mean, Ellie-- she's not here, but Ellie
from the Last of Us
TALIESIN: I'd steal Ellie.
LAURA: That's an amazing character, but the thing
is, I can say Ellie-- Hey.
(applause)
MARISHA: Best con ever.
LAURA: I can say Ellie from the Last of Us, but she
wouldn't be that character. She wouldn't be that
amazing if Ashley hadn't played her.
MARISHA: Yeah, I kind of agree with Laura. It's
almost hard to say because the actors bring so
much of the characters themselves that it just
wouldn't be the same.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I agree.
MARISHA: But I guess if I had to pick one. Thor. I
want Thor!
TRAVIS: You can have him.
MARISHA: Tell that to Marvel.
TALIESIN: I'll take Black Widow, if you take
Thor.
LAURA: Hey, I like that.
MARISHA: All right, yeah.
SAM: I mean, I have a terrible nasal voice. I
would love to have some of Travis' sack.
TRAVIS: I'll trade you my sack for your beer.
SAM: You've got beer.
TRAVIS: That's not enough.
(laughter)
SAM: You, ma'am.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Hi, first of all, I am dressed as
Vex'ahlia today.
(applause)
SAM: Oh wow.
MARISHA: Oh shit, I just realized! It took me half
a second. Dope!
AUDIENCE MEMBER: First of all, Matt, thank you so
much, because I have wanted to Dungeon Master for
years and years and I'm finally doing it.
(applause)
AUDIENCE MEMBER: I'm starting a Pathfinder game
next week and I'm just so thankful for all the tips
and tricks and stuff you put online. I am so
thankful.
MATT: Thank you. I hope they help and there's a
lot of great communities online too, far before I
put anything up there, that expand upon these
tips as well, so don't be afraid to reach out to
the Reddit D&amp;D page and the RPG. Check out
all those guys.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: That being said, last year I
touched Wil Wheaton and my rolls have been really shitty.
MATT: Oh no, I'm so sorry.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: So do you have any things that I
can do to cleanse the Wil Wheaton?
MATT: We can try but, understand, it's a very
strong curse.
TALIESIN: The sage helped. The sage helped a lot.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: I'll just get a selfie with
Taliesin and it'll be fine, I'm sure.
TALIESIN: I specifically had sage powdered in
dragon's blood. It was really intense.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Okay, I'll try that too.
TALIESIN: Not kidding.
MATT: Step forward, step forward.
SAM: (singing)
TALIESIN: (singing)
TRAVIS: Wow, wow.
LAURA: You're officially the Little Mermaid.
Congratulations.
MATT: She's going get real angry when it doesn't
work.
MARISHA: She's even got the Vex swagger going.
SAM: You, sir, man with the beer.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Laura, you're getting a beer,
right?
SAM: The beer's really good.
TRAVIS: It's really hoppy and delicious.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: My question's for you, Matt: how
the heck do you come up with all the names for the
places around the world? That's the problem I'm
having because I'm trying to create a game. Just
naming places is my problem.
MATT: Naming convention is interesting. I've
always liked making up weird names anyway and a
lot of times I'll just start thinking of-- it
starts with letters that haven't been used very
often in other areas, so I'll be like, all right, I
made a Stillben, so that's an S name so I don't
want to make another S named town nearby, so I'll
go W. Westruun kinda came from just trying to
think of, it's to the west of where the main city
will be. Expansion sent it west. And then from
that point, I started taking inspiration from
different languages that would affiliate that area.
A lot of Norse language works near Vasselheim.
Looking into root words and certain spelling
techniques in other languages and jamming things
together that sound interesting and roll off the
tongue well.
SAM: What you do is you pick your middle name and
the street you grew up on and your pet name
and that's the name.
MATT: And there's also really good name generators
online for fantasy locations that you can go ahead.
SAM: (smug clicking)
MATT: Worked out well for some folks. But yeah,
just pull inspiration from books that you like,
campaigns that already exist, source books if you
have them, and take pieces from certain words that
you like and jam them together and see if it
sounds nice when you say it. That's all you really need.
TRAVIS: Name all your characters Percy.
MATT: All of them.
SAM: Percival de Rolo de Momo.
MARISHA: Frederick von--
TALIESIN: (singing) It's delightful, it's
delectable, it's de-lovely.
SAM: Next question, please.
TRAVIS: Wait, Vex wants to try.
LAURA: No, I've had some ale.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: I heard that. Hi! I have some
bracelets for you guys. I don't really have a
question. I'm going to give these to you guys. I'm
representing Extra Life. We raise money for
Doernbecher's and we raise money for children who
are sick, terminally, and I just want to give you
some bracelets.
MATT: That is awesome.
TRAVIS: Applaud this woman!
(applause)
MATT: Thank you so much.
TRAVIS: That's great.
TALIESIN: Yes, thank you.
TRAVIS: Thank you.
LAURA: Thank you so much.
MATT: I want to take a minute while we're talking
about this, actually. One of the really amazing
things to come out of this community, aside from
the perpetual beer.
TRAVIS: Seriously, best panel ever.
SAM: Yeah, this is the best panel ever.
TRAVIS: A bit of advice, write ale into your
backstory, bitches, because hey!
SAM: Hey, also don't write poop into your
backstory, because people send me poop all the time.
MARISHA: I love that if we wait for like ten
minutes one will just appear. They're spawning!
MATT: That's real magic. To take a minute off that
topic, one of the-- so many amazing things have
sprung out of this community, more than we ever
could have expected or hoped. But one of the things
that perpetually humbles and blows me away is the
generosity of all of you guys supporting all these
wonderful charities, all these wonderful causes.
You guys communally have raised so much money and
so much awareness to so many amazing, largely
overlooked in a lot of cases, charitable intents
and it's incredible. So give yourselves a huge
round of applause.
TRAVIS: Yeah, seriously, you guys are amazing.
(applause)
MARISHA: We are literally changing the world with
D&amp;D.
LAURA: It's crazy. It's so amazing that you guys
have done so much. And that Critmas is
the most amazing thing and the gifts that you guys
send are so wonderful, but the fact that you guys
are donating to other people and doing good in the
name of this community is so freaking amazing.
MARISHA: Ultimately, the whole reason we even did
this show was to share it out with other people
and to share the joy that is D&amp;D and gaming. It's
just even more of a compliment and an honor to
hear you guys paying it forward and to continue to
spread the gospel that is the Player's Handbook.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: The gospel.
MATT: You, sir.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: My question is for Matt. How do
keep your homebrew classes, blood hunter, witch
hunter kind of stuff, how do you work to keep those
balanced without making them totally crap or way overpowered?
MATT: Homebrew classes and races is a new thing to
me as well, like I never really created-- The
first real homebrew thing was just the transition
of your gunslinger over from Pathfinder and even
that took a while just testing and figuring it
out. Learning to balance something homebrew on
that degree, especially a new class or a new
archetype? It's something that comes with
experience and with community feedback. While I'm
happy that I'm somewhat decent at D&amp;D, there's so
many great communities out there that are far more
knowledgeable of how the game's original design
construct was based on, what is considered good
versus bad balance. When I threw my stuff out
there--it was to the wolves in a way-- because
everyone was like, "This is broken, this messed up,"
and I'm like, cool, thank you for telling me that,
now I can go back and fix it. How about now? "This
"is-- oh, this is better now!" Internet may be angry
and forceful sometimes with its feedback, but as
long as it's still constructive and it's awesome,
which most of the community is, that's a
tremendous source for you to use. There's the
Unearthed Arcana Reddit is a whole area that's all
about homebrew D&amp;D content and they're all very
knowledgeable and very willing to help you with
feedback on your own homebrew ideas.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Awesome, thank you.
MATT: Thank you.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Howdy, folks. My question is
actually for Portland, like a survey. So I'm going
to need some help here.
MARISHA: For Portland?
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Yeah.
MARISHA: All right, all the way into the mic.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: So I'll need a some help here, like
the survey, but I'm thinking we have Scanlan Shorthalt
right here, can we please tell him that Trinket
should always go with the party?
LAURA: Yes!
(cheering)
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Yes, Trinket!
LAURA: Don't you shake your head. You mother-- I
saw some of you shaking your damn head.
TRAVIS: I heard a boo.
LAURA: I heard a boo.
MARISHA: I know.
LAURA: How dare you?
SAM: If Portland thinks so, who am I to argue with
that? Trinket is just an unstoppable force of
power, grace--
LAURA: He has saved-- he has done some serious--
SAM: When he--
TALIESIN: I had to put my coat somewhere last
episode. That was very important.
SAM: When he saves me, I will respect him.
LAURA: He did save you! Didn't he?
SAM: No.
MARISHA: I think so. I think he did, like, once.
MATT: When CritRoleStats shakes his head no.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: The human encyclopedia says, "No."
LAURA: Wait, okay, but you know, how many times
has Trinket killed anybody?
AUDIENCE MEMBER: He bit a vampire's head off.
SAM: One?
LAURA: He bit a vampire's freaking head off!
SAM: Three.
LAURA: Three killings?
TRAVIS: Yeah, nine times.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: (inaudible)
MARISHA: Hey, hey, he's gotten two how do you want
to do this.
SAM: And I've killed at least that many. Listen,
Trinket is great.
TALIESIN: You're almost as useful as a bear.
(laughter and cheering)
TRAVIS: I think it just needs to be solved PVP.
Scanlan versus Trinket.
SAM: Yeah, I would do that.
LAURA: No, that would be so sad.
TALIESIN: We could make a lot of money bear
wrestling.
LAURA: Trinket only has 60 hit points, you guys.
TRAVIS: Yeah, but what if he gets lucky?
TALIESIN: Gnome versus bear?
LAURA: So that's why I don't send him in. He's
only got 60 hit points so if he dies then he dies
and I don't know what I would do.
TRAVIS: Y'all, this is truth. The one time before
the stream when I smacked the bear on the ass and
sent it through this minefield, I almost got
divorced. Like, legitimately.
LAURA: I don't know. What I love is when we were
fighting the dragon at our keep and he got frozen.
This was out of character, I'm looking at Travis
going, "You'd better fucking save--"
TRAVIS: I've got to save that fucking bear.
Because if he dies, there's no joy in the world.
(laughter)
LAURA: I feel like that was the one time Grog
really acted out of character, when he saved Trinket.
TRAVIS: She would walk home and all the flowers in
the front yard would die. Save that bear, man.
Rule number one.
SAM: I'm just saying that a ferret, or even a
goldfish...
TRAVIS: What is this, Hogwarts? Or an owl, or a
cat--
LAURA: If I could take the spell Polymorph, if I
could have that fucking spell, I would be so
happy. I hate that anytime I want to bring Trinket
and we're stealthing or something like that and
I'm like, "Marisha--"
MARISHA: Hopefully I've got it!
LAURA: "--can you use one of your spells that you
have a limited amount of to Polymorph my bear?"
TALIESIN: That red panda was pretty awesome.
MARISHA: I can turn him into a red panda, that's
generally all I care about.
SAM: I can always do that. And I never will.
(laughter)
MARISHA: It's true! It's true, he always has it.
MATT: Don't be sad gnome, be happy gnome.
LAURA: You motherfucker! You could do it?
TRAVIS: Okay, okay, okay. Rosie.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: First of all, thank you, Laura,
for rolling a nat one on my die earlier. While I was
in Beauty and the Beast, on the opening night,
Gaston's wig fell off, and I was wondering if you
guys ever had any embarrassing moments on stage.
MARISHA: Yeah, every episode? Let's cut to the
eight times between Laura and I that we've been
like, we just (sobbing) oh God, oh God, this is
crying. I mean, that counts.
MATT: Do you mean during the show, or do you mean
legitimately on a theatrical stage?
AUDIENCE MEMBER: On a theatrical stage.
MATT: Okay, so an actual stage show.
MARISHA: Oh!
TALIESIN: Oh, yeah.
LAURA: Yes.
SAM: I was in Les Miserables as a child. I played
Gavroche.
MATT: And where did you play it?
SAM: You know, in Broadway.
(laughter)
SAM: I did a national tour and I was performing in
Miami-- it was a long time ago, like '89 or
something -- anyway, I fell onstage and I injured
my knee and I was taken to the hospital. Long
story, but I was wearing rags and dirt and stuff,
and I was brought to the hospital and it just so
happened that in Miami that night there were
riots. Martin Luther King Day riots or something?
So they brought me in, this little boy, this
little white boy, and they were like, "Why are you
"here?" and I was like, "I fell off the
barricade."
(laughter)
SAM: And they were like, "There's a barricade?
Were you protesting?" And I was like, "I mean, I guess."
TRAVIS: Viva la revolución!
SAM: So they thought I was the youngest civil
rights protester ever.
TRAVIS: Little French boy.
MATT: That's amazing.
MARISHA: I'd never heard that!
MATT: I don't think any of us can top that.
TRAVIS: Please tell me there's a Getty Images of
that somewhere.
SAM: I wish.
MATT: Good question. When I knocked over an
inkwell during a production of The Crucible, as
Reverend Hale. I slammed the table during the
trial for the latter half of the play. And whoever
was being the clerk of the court had filled the
inkwell with ink, which he wasn't supposed to do,
but he wanted to write legitimately. I slammed the
table, and it (blurp) and spills out all
over my hand. I look down out of the corner of my
eye, and it's just like, blue ink across my hand,
and I'm trying to hide it. So someone else starts
talking, and Danforth, who's the guy running the
whole trial, starts getting really angry, and I
raise my finger to point. Ink all up his white
shirt, across his face. He feels it, and he
doesn't know what it is, he just knows he's got
something on his face. So he goes and tries to rub
off the "spittle," and there's this giant ink
smear across his face. None of us could tell him,
so he did most of the second half of the play just
with giant ink smears on his face. Yeah.
SAM: That's pretty good.
MATT: Theater.
LAURA: Oh, man. In high school I was doing this
play, and this guy that I had the biggest crush on
ever was sitting in the front row. I had one of
those hoop skirts on, and I sat down on the couch,
and I wasn't used to them. The hoop went up over
my head, and it was like a dress rehearsal, so I
didn't have the full costume on. So it was just,
like, underwear. So it was just like, hoop, and
panties. And I was mortified.
TRAVIS: Yes!
LAURA: (to inaudible audience member) No! He was
never my boyfriend!
TRAVIS: Are you sure?
LAURA: I am sure!
MARISHA: It's like a skin you can download in
Portal. It's great.
LAURA: I also did a production of Joseph and the
Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat, and I was playing
the narrator, and I was running out on stage.
TRAVIS: And you ate shit.
LAURA: I did. I ate shit. As I was running out,
leading the entire chorus out to do this big dance
number for "Go, Go, Go, Joseph," and my foot
caught in my skirt. I just planted it on the stage
and slid, and then had to get up and finish the
dance out.
TALIESIN: I got beat up by a goat on camera once.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: It was some show called Hell Town. It
only went, like, 12 episodes, and I was some
autistic kid who befriends a goat. That goat was
not friendly. That goat just jumped me and nailed
me in the face. I was cut. It was just bad. It was
a little goat, but I was a little kid, and it was
like, "Finally, a human I can beat the fuck out
of!"
TRAVIS: Why have we not killed a goat in the game as
vengeance for your real-life--?
TALIESIN: I've already taken care of that.
MARISHA: I guess the best one that I have-- it's
hard to top Gavroche. I was in a production of The
Nutcracker, and I was a soldier. We had to come
through the flat on the stage, and we had these
hats that came down, and we were soldiers, and I
missed the entrance and slammed into the flat.
Anyone who does theater, you know these flats are
made out of cardboard, so the whole thing went--
(shaking noise) and almost fell over.
LAURA: Oh, but it didn't.
MARISHA: It didn't fall over, but--
LAURA: Could have been worse.
MARISHA: It was very obvious that I smacked into a
flat. The entire section.
TRAVIS: I burned down a theater and killed
everybody inside.
SAM: Oh, wow.
TRAVIS: But nobody knows about that, so--
MATT: We should go. Now. You should-- okay, next
question.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: I'm Commander Shepard, and this
is my favorite show on the Citadel.
LAURA: Nice.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: No, serious DM question here. As
a DM who has a party of some odd races-- a mouse,
a fire genasi, and soon to be a tiefling-- your
game has a goliath. Travis, you can help me with
this one as well. Your game has a goliath
who seems to have a history as a marauder,
to put it nicely.
TRAVIS: A what?
SAM: A marauder.
TRAVIS: A marauder. That's a big word.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: So did that ever have any role
play issues early on? You have this big goliath
walking around town that used to be wandering
around in the fields robbing people, beating
people up, stuff like that.
MATT: It was interesting, because his father had
actually left his tribe, his band. They're
basically just like wild-living savage bandits
that destroyed and pillaged whatever came in their
territory. His father had separated from them
after his early trials, and made a name of himself
in the city of Westruun as a respectable
individual. That's how when he went and met Pike,
there wasn't-- People were not comfortable with
him in the city, and stayed away from him, but
there was no all of a sudden, immediate force of
the local guard going like, "I don't trust you.
"We're going to lock you up and cut your face." So
that wasn't a huge issue. But the band is still
out there.
TALIESIN: We ran into--
MATT: You did run into them once. It was a
large-scale battle with all these goliaths jumping
out. And the party was like, "We are so ruined."
The fight was about to go, and I think it was the
first time that I've ever had Grog stop fighting
and socially talk the party out of battle. Grog!
TALIESIN: It was amazing.
TRAVIS: It turned out to be one of my cousins,
which goes into a backstory thing that will
probably come up at some point, but I didn't want
to fight my family. Because we would have probably
all died. It was like seven goliaths.
LAURA: We probably-- yeah.
TRAVIS: It would have been bad.
TALIESIN: It was a while ago.
TRAVIS: But he gets one pass. And then he's dead.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: As it should be.
SAM: You, sir.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: First things first. Scanlan, as a
bard, you are a huge hero and inspiration to myself.
(cheering)
SAM: I know.
TRAVIS: Don't tell him that. Can we get a Bigby's
Hand?
SAM: (sings) Bigby's Hand!
(applause)
SAM: It's not even a bard spell!
MATT: I know!
AUDIENCE MEMBER: As characters, Vox Machina, do
you consider yourselves to be heroes? Do you
actively try to be heroes?
MARISHA: You're asking us as Vox Machina?
SAM: I mean--
AUDIENCE MEMBER: You've done some pretty horrible
things.
LAURA: We have done some pretty terrible things.
SAM: Collectively, we are heroic.
TALIESIN: Yes, collectively.
SAM: Individually. I don't think-- Scanlan thinks of
himself as a god that doesn't really need to prove
anything. He's just in it for the lols, for the
most part. But I think collectively we've done
some good things. We've saved civilization.
LAURA: We've done some terrible things, too.
SAM: We've rescued people, and we've killed old
people, which is always a good thing for society.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Percy's kind of starting to figure out
that he's not that great a person, but--
TRAVIS: (laughs)
TALIESIN: I knew, but Percy didn't know. But at
the same time, it's mostly because he's
acknowledging that we're all kind of awful people,
but together-- except for Pike. Pike's great.
Pike's fine. But together we're actually a
powerful force for good. Individually, not so much.
TRAVIS: Grog lives moment to moment. I have no
idea what they're talking about.
LAURA: I feel like Vax is a really good person.
Vax is probably, outside of Pike--
MARISHA: Vax is probably the best person. Vax is
probably most selfless.
LAURA: Yeah, because he really is in it to--
TALIESIN: Percy would have words about that.
LAURA: Oh, really?
TALIESIN: Oh, yeah.
LAURA: Has he done some shit?
I feel like I'm speaking for Liam now.
TRAVIS: Yeah, you can't RP for Vax.
LAURA: I can't speak for Liam, but based on
conversations that we've had.
TRAVIS: Why don't you speak for yourself?
MARISHA: Yeah, we don't really have these
conversations. We try and keep it for the game.
TRAVIS: Is this meta right now?
TALIESIN: This is meta.
MATT: Roll initiative.
(laughter)
MARISHA: Are we going to get shat on for
metagaming?
LAURA: Ah!
MATT: I don't know.
TRAVIS: We're all going to die! You killed us!
LAURA: We're all going to die!
TALIESIN: Way to go.
SAM: I will tell you this, though. Scanlan is a
bit of an existentialist, and, for a specific
reason, thinks or has thought up to now that life is
sort of pointless.
LAURA: Aww!
TALIESIN: I see that.
LAURA: Look at this guy!
MARISHA: It's interesting, actually, all the
different ideals our characters have evolved.
TRAVIS: Yeah, ideals.
(laughter)
LAURA: I get, sometimes, people online saying I've done
something that's really terrible.
TRAVIS: They're right.
LAURA: But for Vex, the motivation makes sense. It
makes sense, the reason she would do certain things.
TRAVIS: Oh, sure.
LAURA: And it's not bad in her eyes. It's not.
MARISHA: Everyone loves to comment on if Keyleth
did something right or wrong. Everyone seems to
have an opinion. And once again, people need to
understand where Keyleth is coming from.
LAURA: Keyleth is the worst of all of us.
TALIESIN: Oh, yeah. By far. She killed a kid.
MARISHA: I'm the evil bastard.
LAURA: Heart of ice.
MARISHA: Honestly, like legitimately, Keyleth has
probably done some of the worst stuff that's also
trying the hardest, so it just really messes with
her psyche.
TRAVIS: It's my favorite part.
MARISHA: It's true. I'm the worst! I try so hard.
TALIESIN: It's not that we're not heroes, it's
that we're flawed. We're flawed people.
MARISHA: We're extremely flawed. Everyone's
broken.
TRAVIS: We're a bunch of idiots, come on.
MARISHA: We have no fucking clue what we're doing.
Ever.
MATT: We've got about five minutes left.
SAM: Two more questions, maybe?
MATT: If there are two or three we can get through
quickly.
TRAVIS: Bless you! Can we name an NPC after him or
something?
TALIESIN: He's just going to get killed in five
minutes.
TRAVIS: Just make him the beer delivery guy!
SAM: Dean is your next NPC.
TRAVIS: We've got to build him a room!
(cheering)
TRAVIS: (excitedly) Beer wench!
LAURA: You guys, we're seriously going to be so
not functional.
TALIESIN: This is going to slow down the autograph
lines so much. There's going to be so many
misspellings and typos.
TRAVIS: We're going to sign one letter at a time.
LAURA: If we spell your name wrong later--
TRAVIS: Yes. Go for it! We've got five minutes.
MARISHA: Do you want my leftover one?
MATT: She gives me the half-drunk one.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: First, I want to thank y'all.
Y'all are the reason my wife and I play D&amp;D
together now, so thank you for that. Secondly, as
a DM of seven players-- so I feel that pain a
little bit-- as players, is there anything y'all
have ever wanted to do in game, but have thought,
"No, that would eat up too much time. There's
eight of us. We need to get the story moving
"along." Or do y'all just, "Nope, everyone can
wait, and I'm going to have my two-hour moment."
TALIESIN: I try and have my attack plan ready for
when it's my turn to fight.
MARISHA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: I don't start looking at the board when
it's like, "All right, you're up." No. Okay, I'm good.
TRAVIS: I feel like Matt does a pretty good job,
too, of being clairvoyant and sensing that if we
start to do something that's going to go way off
on a tangent and take up too much time, he'll cut
it off the second we start it, and he'll bring
something up that puts us back on
a more cohesive track.
SAM: But he also allows us to go on our little
individual journeys when we need to.
MATT: It's a fun little exploration element.
TRAVIS: That's where the black powder guy
came from, is some random tangent. Most
amazing NPC ever.
TALIESIN: He put the fear into me because he
said I was going to run out of bullets and powder
soon. I was like, "Oh god, you're right!" And I
didn't know what to do about that.
TRAVIS: And then you cast Friends on me, you
dick.
LAURA: I always feel slightly guilty any time we
have a shopping excursion--
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Because that can eat up time with
even four players, let alone seven or eight.
LAURA: Exactly. And not only because it's probably
boring for the other players, but I feel like it's
really boring for you guys to watch us go buy
potions.
TRAVIS: Shopping's awesome. I love going shopping
with other people.
(laughter)
MATT: It can be fun. It's about knowing as a GM
when to edit a scene. You can let things happen,
let it be fun, let interactions occur, and then
once you feel like the goal of that scene has been
completed or is close to resolution, you can nudge
the party and be like, "All right, so from this
"point, where do you want to go from here?" Or "As
time passes, you continue the transaction." You
can find a point where the fun has been had, the
major arc of that moment has hit, and you can help
hurry and bookend and then continue the next
moment.
SAM: That's the hardest thing to do in improv is
to both be in the scene and know when the scene is
over. That's super hard.
MARISHA: And we're also a bunch of A
personalities, so sometimes you have to fight if
you want to have a moment. If you want to have
something, you have to not be afraid to jump in.
And you've probably seen a hundred times where
some of us have started to do something, and then
it might have gotten cut off, and then you have to
let it go. You move on. Just like in life,
sometimes it is not the right time or the right
place.
SAM: What we're saying is you should sit down
now.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: That's more deep than what I
wanted.
MATT: We've got time for probably one or two more
fast questions. If we don't get to your questions
here, you're welcome to come and ask us at our
signing later.
LAURA: And we also have a panel tomorrow.
MATT: We also have a panel tomorrow at noon.
LAURA: Not here. In room C-123.
TRAVIS: C-123 tomorrow. And we're at our
tables. When we're not here, we're at our tables
the whole time.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: How hard was it to transition the
gunslinger from Pathfinder over to what you guys
do? Because for one of the games I'm a part of, my
girlfriend wants to be a dracomancer, and I didn't
realize that was in 4E, so I'm having trouble
helping her get it up to this one.
MATT: That's a tough one. For me, the archetypes,
especially for fighter and combat-based
archetypes, it's much more cut and dry as far as
the transition for natural physics. A gunslinger,
we know how ballistics work and some of the
possible tropes for gunslingers in modern media,
so that was an easy inspiration to transition and
change some of the things and still make it
interesting. When you get into stuff like that,
where you're dealing with more obtuse magics and
other creatures that are mythological, if you're
having a hard time, reach out to a community of
homebrewers like the Unearthed Arcana guys, and
ask for suggestions there. There may be things
that are already existing that are a good root or
basis that you can then tweak more into what you
want your final homebrew to be. And now there's
the DMs' Guild, which allows everyone to put up
their own homebrew stuff online, and there's a lot
of great content there that you can find people
with, and if you like it, you can toss them a
couple of bucks and show them how much you
appreciate it. I think it's really cool that
they've opened up the community to create their
own homebrew content and provide it like that.
TALIESIN: For safety, how many revisions have you
given me?
MATT: The gunslinger? Probably close to eight, at
this point.
TALIESIN: About eight?
TRAVIS: One more question.
MATT: Thank you very much.
MARISHA: I hope it's a good one.
MATT: Come by later on and we'll get to your guys'
questions later on.
TRAVIS: Because everybody from here over has to
pee so bad.
MARISHA: So bad! We've drank three beers in an
hour.
TRAVIS: We had a whole cask of ale from here
over.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: My question is a personal
question for Matt, so I'm sorry it's not a whole
group question. I'm just so curious. You've
inspired me to start writing again and to start
playing D&amp;D-- I'm really nervous-- and to remember
to myself to be who I want to be and to start
writing again, I bought my wristband because I
watch you. I see you; you wear yours constantly.
Mine, I got nautical-themed since my husband's in
the navy. It's got a ship wheel and a kraken. I
wondered, do yours have any significance? You wear
them constantly. Do they mean anything?
MATT: That's a very interesting question. They do,
actually. Each wristband I keep on me, not just
from a visual standpoint, but each has a very
specific meaning. This first wristband here was
actually gifted to me by somebody in the middle of
the desert at my first Burning Man, and it's a
representation of personal responsibility and
understanding where I came from and where I want
to go and make sure that I don't stray from that
path and be true to myself. It's a long story
where it got that meaning, but that's essentially
what it means.
This one here was actually granted to me by my
best friend Brittany Wallach for my birthday many
years ago. That's her right there.
(cheering)
MATT: This represents friendship and the people
that have held me in my dark times and got me to
where I am today, because honestly, no individual
gets there. It's a bunch of people that bring you
to your final fated future. Thank you, Brittany.
And this band here-- if you get a chance to look,
it has a bunch of numbers printed into it-- this
was made by Marisha for our anniversary a few
years ago. She dyed the leather, she printed in
the numbers, and these numbers represent the
actual coordinates of the beach where we had our
first kiss.
AUDIENCE: Aww!
SAM: Gross.
MATT: I know, right? So yeah, each of these have a
very special significance to me and are constant
reminders of good moments and people in my life.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: Thank you so much.
MATT: Thank you! It was a good question.
TRAVIS: Great question.
SAM: This was a fun panel, Matt. You did great
moderating.
LAURA: You've been awesome.
SAM: I'm drunk.
MATT: Good!
(cheering)
MATT: And you guys did a great job making that
happen.
(cheering)
TRAVIS: We love that you guys are here! So we will
be at the group signing table at 4:00. From 4:00
to 5:00 we'll be there; it's a short run, so if we
don't get to everybody, that's okay. We'll be over
at our tables until the close of the day, and then
we'll be back here when the hall opens tomorrow,
as well. We have another panel and a group signing
tomorrow, as well. Thank you so much for coming out!
MATT: Thank you so much!
MARISHA: Thank you, guys! We have to pee because
you've given us so many beers.
MATT: So 4:00 group signing, we'll be at our tables
after that, and then we'll be there tomorrow.
Thank you all so much. Is it Thursday yet?
TALIESIN: Oh my god. Oh.