>> HELLO AND WELCOME TO
TONIGHT’S EPISODE OF "CRITICAL
ROLE" WHERE A BUNCH OF US NOISY
ASS PEOPLE SIT AROUND AND PLAY
DUNGEONS AND DRAGONS.
>> YEAH, YOU GOTTA BAN DONE ODD
THAT ONE.
>> IT WAS MARISSA’S CALLOUT.
>> ONE, TWO, THREE.
>> WELCOME.
>> BEFORE WE GET IN TO TONIGHT’S
GAME, WE HAVE A FEW
ANNOUNCEMENTS, TWO STOP SOARS
UPON, FIRST IS OR RETURNING
FRIENDS AT D & D BEYOND.
>> D & D BEYOND, GUYS, SOME
AMAZING CRITTERS, SUPPORT US AND
SUPPORT RED NOSE DAY AND SUPPORT
D & D BEYOND BY SUBSCRIBING NOT
JUST CRITTERS HERE IN AMERICA,
BUT ALL OVER THE WORLD,
ESPECIALLY I WANT TO GIVE A
SHOUT OUT TOP TO OUR FRIENDS AND
CRITTERS IN AUSTRALIA.
AND BECAUSE WE ARE SUCH FINE
VOICE ACTORS, WITH TALENTED
ACCENT SKILLS, I AM GOING TO SAY
GIVE A SHOUT OUT TO THE
AUSTRALIAN CRITTERS IN THEIR
NATIVE TONGUE.
CRIKEY.
>> OKAY.
>> NO.
NO.
>> Sam: GOOD DAY, DOWN UNDER,
ALL YOU BRUISES AND SHEILAS IN
THE OUT BACK SHOULD KNOW ABOUT D
& D BEYOND.
IT DOES ALL THE REGARD YAKKER OF
GAMING FOR YOU.
SO YOU CAN RELAX AND STUB YOUR
BEER.
A TINNY OF CAB SAFE OR EVEN A
SLAB OF FROTHY FOR YOUR MATES.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> THAT WAS ROUGH.
>> Sam: BLOODY OAF.
THE D & D BEYOND APP IS SO EASY
EVERYBODY A DRAG OWE BRIDGER
COULD USE IT.
IN FACT, IF YOU --
>> Marisha: ARE YOU TOUCHING
YOUR EAR?
BR*.
>> Sam: IF YOU DON’T USE D & D I
DON’T UNDERSTAND, YOU’VE GOT A
FEW KANGAROOS LOOSE IN YOUR TOP
PADDOCK.
BILLABONG.
SO PUT ON YOUR SUNNIES, YOUR
THONGS, YOUR PLANES, YOUR
KNICKERS, YOUR TREKY DECKS,
LIGHT UP A SIGI, FIRE UP THAT
LAPPIE.
AND HEAD ON OVER TO D & DI DON’T
WANT.COM TO PICK UP THE NEWEST D
& D ADVENTURE.
THE NEWEST D & D ADVENTURE
GHOSTS --
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Sam: GHOSTS --
>> Sam: ADVENTURE.
GHOSTS OF SOUL MATCH.
GHOSTS OF SALT MATCH WHICH IS
CRIKEY AVAILABLE TODAY.
THE SWASHBUCKLING SPANKY
ADVENTURE IS HERE.
BEASTS OF PISS, WHICH I AM TOLD
IS A GOOD PHRASE.
WELL, I RECKON THAT NEWS IS
SWEETER THAN TIM TAMS COFFERED
IN VEGEMITE.
RIPPER.
SUS IT OUT AT D & D.COM.
AND YOU’LL BE APPLES, BEAUTY.
BACK TO YOU, MATT.
>> Liam: DID YOU ALSO DO THE
V.O. FOR THE OUT BACK STEAK
HOUSE.
>> HOW BIG IS THEIR STANDING
ARMY.
>> WE HAVE A NATURAL AUSTRALIAN
IN THE BUILDING, THAT’S ALL IT
TAKES.
>> Sam: OH, NO, HE’S WATCHING
THIS RIGHT NOW I AM GOING TO GET
SHOVED OR WHATEVER YOU CALL IT
IN AUSTRALIA.
I AM GOING TO GET BILLABONGED.
>> Marisha: WE ARE DONE, THANK
YOU, SAM.
>> Matt: I WAS FINE, NOW I AM
NERVOUS ABOUT THE GAME.
I DON’T KNOW ABOUT YOU GUYS, ALL
I CAN HEAR IS WHITE NOISE RIGHT
NOW.
THANK YOU, SAM, AND THANK YOU D
& D BEYOND FOR YOUR ENDLESS
PATIENCE?
SAM.
SECONDARY SPONSOR TONIGHT OUR
FRIENDS AT ROOK AND THE RAVEN.
RETURNING ONCE AGAIN, WE TALKED
ABOUT THEM BEFORE.
HAPPY TO BRING THEM FORTH AGAIN
TO DISCUSS THEIR FANTASTIC LINE
OF CAMPAIGN BOOKS THEY DO THESE
AMAZING HAND CRAFTED BOOKS.
YOU CAN KEEP TRACK OF ALL OF
YOUR INFORMATION.
MARISHA YOU HAVE ONE THAT YOU
HAVE BEEN USING.
>> Marisha: I KEEP ADDING PAPER
TO IT AND IT KEEPS GETTING
BIGGER AND BIGGER.
>> Matt: IT’S PRETTY BIG.
>> Marisha: IT’S GOOD.
IT’S WORKING.
>> Matt: YOU CAN EASILY ADD ROOF
PHAGES GREAT FOR TABLE TOP GAMES
OR YOUR CAMPAIGNS AND THEY HAVE
SPECIAL HE DIPPINGS FOR EACH.
YOU CAN CHECK OUT ALL OF THEIR
AMAZING STUFF AT THE ROOK AND
THE CRAVEN.COM/CRITICALROLE.
AND FOR A LIMITED TIME YOU CAN
USE THE CODE CRIT ROLL TO GET
$10 OFF YOUR ORDER.
GO CHECK IT OUT.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
>> YOU JUST HIT ME.
I JUST BLED A LITTLE BIT.
>> Matt: ALL RIGHT, A COUPLE OF
OTHER QUICK ANNOUNCEMENTS, TOO,
IF YOU HAVEN’T SEEN IT
YESTERDAY, WE SHOWED IT BEFORE
THE STREAM TONIGHT.
BUT IT’S ON YOUTUBE AS WELL.
WE RAN A VERY SPECIAL ONE SHOT
OF ME RUNNING A ONE-OFF HAD ONE
GAME WITH STEPHEN COLBERT AS
PART OF RED NOSE DAY.
IT WAS INSANE.
>> THAT WAS A REAL SEN STEPS, IT
WAS A REAL THING.
>> Matt: IT DIDN’T HIT ME UNTIL
YESTERDAY.
>> HELLO BEES.
THANKS FOR YOUR FANTASTIC
SUPPORT.
PEOPLE AT RED NOSE DOING
INCREDIBLE WORK TO END CHILD
POVERTY.
YOU HAVE RAISED AN EXTREMELY
GENEROUS AMOUNT FOR THIS.
YOU ARE AVAILABLE -- YOU ARE
STILL ABLE TO MAKE DONATIONS
RIGHT NOW.
STILL AVAILABLE AT
CRITROLL.COM/REDNOSEDAY.
IF YOU HAVEN’T SEEN THE VIDEO
IT’S ON OUR YOUTUBE CHAMPION.
>> IT WAS SO GOOD.
>> Matt: I THOUGHT I WAS IN LOVE
WITH STEVEN COLBERT BEFORE.
I THINK WE ARE STEADY NOW.
I WAS PRETTY HAPPY ABOUT THAT.
>> I THOUGHT HE WAS IN LOVE WITH
MATT MERCER BEFORE.
>> Matt: I DON’T KNOW ABOUT
THAT.
SO THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR SUPPORT
THAT GO, GUYS.
NEXT FRIDAY, MAY 31st,
7:00 P.M. PACIFIC WE’LL BE
AIRING A VERY SPECIAL MY LITTLE
PONY ONE SHOT.
LED BY OUR BUDDY MARK HUMES,
MARK, DOCUMENT TO SAY HI REAL
FAST.
WHAT’S UP, BUD.
>> HEY.
>> Matt: HE’S BEEN STORMING OUR
STUDIO THIS WEEK ABOUT BEEN
HANGING OUT.
JUST CHILLING OUTDOING STUFF.
>> GO LOW, GO LOWER.
THERE WE GO.
NICE.
>> LOWER, MARK, LOWER.
>> HEY, EVERYBODY.
YEAH, SO WE DID A MY LITTLE PONY
ONE SHOT WHICH I THINK THERE IS
A PROMO FOR IN THE BREAK, I
THINK WE FILMED YOU’LL GET TO
SEE THE CAST, THE COOL ARTWORK,
IT WAS A LOT OF FUN, LIAM AND
ASHLEY DEFINITELY KEPT ME ON MY
TOES ALONG WITH SOME OF THE
OTHER PLAYERS THAT YOU’LL SEE
AND IT WAS REALLY FUN.
>> Matt: HECK, YEAH THERE.
LOOK FOR THAT FRIDAY.
IN PLACE OF -- NOT IN PLACE OF
ANYTHING, IT’S FRIDAY.
THANK YOU, MARK.
>> FRIDAY, MAN.
>> BYE, MARK.
>> Matt: HE PLAYED IN THIS
CAMPAIGN BEFORE SO YOU SHOULD BE
FAMILIAR AND HE HAS AN AMAZING
SHOW CALLED HIGH ROLLERS, CHECK
THEM OUT AS WELL.
BUT, YEAH, SO AS PART THAT HAVE
WE HAVE OUR ASHLEY JOHNSON,
BRIAN AS WELL ASMAR KIA
McCARTHY WHO IS AMAZING,
JULIA NATHAN ITSON WHO IS AMAZIN
YOU SAW HER ON THE NIGHT BEFORE
CHRISTMAS ONE SHOT AND ROGER
CRAIG SMITH, THE VOICE OF MANY
THINGS INCLUDING SONIC THE HEDGE
HEDGEHOG, NOT THE MOVIE.
THAT’S ANOTHER FRIENDS OF THE
SHOW.
BEN SCHWARTZ.
IT WILL BE AVAILABLE ON YOUR
YOUTUBE CHAMPION THAT SUNDAY.
IF YOU MISS IT FRIDAY, YOU CAN
SEE IT THAT SUNDAY.
CHECK IT OUT.
AND I GUESS LAURA, YOU HAVE A
MERCH THING.
>> Liam: LA FUNNY YOU SHOULD
SAY, WHY, YES.
SHUT UP LIKE YOU DON’T KNOW,
LIAM.
>> WHOA.
>> NEW SHIRT ALERT LA YES, THIS
IS BY OUR AWESOME CRITTER.
IT’S REALLY COOL YOU SHOULD SEE
IT UP CLOSE, IT HAS ALL THE
STUFF.
>> WHAT IS THAT?
>> DETAIL.
>> Laura: IT’S OUR PATTERN.
>> A MAN DALTON A.
>> Laura: A PATTERN THAT
REPRESENTS THE MIGHTY NINE, ALL
THESE FUN DETAILS IN THERE.
>> THE CLOSER YOU LOOK.
THE MORE YOU SEE.
>> Laura: CHECK IT OUT ON THE
OUR SHOP.
SHOP. -- WHAT IS IT?
>> SAW IT IN AUSTRALIAN.
>> Laura: CRITROLL.COM/SHOP.
>> THAT’S A THING NOW.
>> Laura: ANYWAY, IT’S SUPER
COOL.
YOU SHOULD CHECK IT OUT.
THERE IS OTHER STUFF IN OUR
STORE AS WELL.
>> Matt: THANK YOU, LAURA.
>> YOU ARE FUNNY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Matt: END WITH THAT.
>> Laura: SORRY, I GOT REALLY
EXCITED TALKING.
COOL GUYS I’M EXCITED ABOUT.
>> Matt: SHOW THEM OFF.
>> Ashley: THESE WERE GIVEN TO
ME A LONG TIME AGO I JUST JUST
BRINGING THEM TO THE GAME.
THEY ARE IN THE SHAPE OF YOUR
DIFFERENT KIND OF CHARACTERS SO
LIKE DEFEND ON THE GROUND WHAT
YOUR DAMAGE IS, IT’S LIKE, OH,
THIS IS A SWORD AND IT ROLLS A
D6.
THIS IS AN AIRS IT’S AN EIGHT.
A POSITION POSITION.
THESE WOULD BE GOOD FOR YOU
MARISHA.
IT’S COOL.
AND I AM EXCITED TO USE THEM
TONIGHT.
YOU GO LIKE THAT.
AND THEN IT’S A 4 THAT I LANDED
ON.
>> YOU MUCH MORE SUCCESSFULLY
PLUGGED YOUR DICE THAN OUR
SHIRT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> CHECK OUT THIS AWESOME SHIRT.
>> THAT’S GENUINE LOVE.
>> Laura: I HAVE BEEN EXCITED
ABOUT THE SHIRT FOR A LONG TIME.
THIS ISN’T THE FIRST TIME I AM
SEEING IT, BUT IT’S THE FIRST
TIME YOU ARE SEEING IT.
>> Matt: THANK YOU, LAWYER A I
APPRECIATE THAT.
>> THANKS, LAURA.
>> OKAY.
>> QUICK SIDE-BAR.
>> Matt: YES, SIDE-BAR.
>> LAURA AND.
>> Taliesin: ARE TALIESIN ARE
DRESSED LIKE BEES.
>> IN HONOR OF ERIC.
>> Matt: ERIC THE BEE.
>> HAPPY HEAD RED NOSE DAY.
>> DAMN RIGHT.
REPRESENT.
>> REPRESENT.
>> Matt: ANYWAY, ENOUGH OF THIS
DILLY DALLYING.
OR SHILLY SHALL INNING.
DROP DOWN IN TO THE MOMENT THAT
WE LEFT OFF AND LAST TIME LET’S
DO IT.
JUST GO AHEAD AND JUMP IN TO
TONIGHT’S EPISODE OF CRITICAL
ROLL.
♪ MUSIC PLAYING ♪
♪ THE ADVENTURE BEGINS ♪
♪ THEY WERE ALWAYS BESIDE YOU ♪
♪ YOUR NERD EBERT FRIENDS ♪
♪ AND THE DM TO GUIDE YOU ♪
♪ AND THEY RISE FROM THE FLAMES
FOR THE BATTLES AHEAD AHEAD ♪
♪ VILLAINS BEWARE BECAUSE YOU
ARE ABOUT TO BE DEAD ♪
♪ THEY GOT MAGIC AND FLARE ♪
♪ THEY GOT CUNNING ♪
♪ THEY DON’T SEE OVER THERE ♪
♪ THERE IS A MONSTER COMING ♪
♪ INSPIRATION IS WAITING RISE UP
DON’T THINK TWICE ♪
♪ PUT YOUR FATE IN YOUR HANDS
TAKE A CHANCE ROLL THE DICE ♪
♪ ROLL ♪
♪ CAN YOU ANSWER THE CALL ♪
♪ DIGGING DEEP IN YOUR SOUL ♪
♪ IS THE LEGEND UNFOLD NEAT NOW
IT’S YOUR TURN ♪
♪ YOUR TURN ♪
♪ TO ROLL ♪
♪
HERRERIN AND WELCOME BACK.
>> GETTING IN ON IT.
>> YEAH.
>> NICE TRY.
>> Matt: SO, LAST WE LEFT OFF,
THE MIGHTY NINE WHO HAVE BEEN
RESIDING FOR A LITTLE BIT OF
TIME IN THE REGION, THE EASTERN
AREA ON WILD NAN IT.
YOU HAVE MADE ALLIANCES.
IN SHEET WITH THE BRIGHT QUEEN.
YOU RETURNED A BEACON, YOU HAVE
DONE A FEW DEEDS AND GAVE ON THE
BRIGHT QUEEN INFORMATION ABOUT
MOVEMENT THE EMPIRE WAS TAKING
IN THIS WAR WITH THE DYNASTY,
YOU ARE REWARDED AS SUCH AND
BEGIN TO PURSUE A THREAD OF
INFORMATION THAT YOU MIGHT WORRY
HAVE SOMETHING TO DO WITH THIS
WAR, WHATEVER IT MAY BE.
YOU HAVE SPIED UPON AN
INDIVIDUAL AND LEARNED OF A
DROPPING POINT OR SOME SORT OF A
MEETING THAT WAS TO HAPPEN IN
THE CITY.
UPON THE DATE OF THIS FAITHFUL
MEETING.
YOU FOUND A PLACE TO WATCH AND
LIE IN WAIT.
YOU WATCHED A NUMBER OF
INDIVIDUALS ENTER THE OVER CROW
APOTHECARY AND NOT BEEN ON A
STEALTH MISSION, MANAGED TO
AVOID DETECTION, A NUMBER OF
TIMES, SESSION FOR THE LAST ONE.
UPON DOING SO A BRIEF CONFLICT
TOOK PLACE WITHIN THE
APOTHECARY, IN WHICH THE FIGURE
THAT WAS MEETING WITH THIS
DRAGON-BORN CHARACTER ON
HORSEBACK, MANAGED TO FLEE THE
BODYGUARD LEFT BEHIND TO FIGHT
TO THE DEATH.
AND THE COURIER, IT SEEMS, THIS
DRAGON-BORN KILLED IN THE STREET
ALONG WITH HIS HORSE, HE MANAGED
TO DIFFUSE THE IMMEDIATE TENSION
OF THE NEARBY GUARD AND POPULOUS
BEING INTERESTED IN THIS SUDDEN
DISPLAY OF BLOODSHED AND
CONFLICT.
YOU MANAGED TO TEMPORARILY HOLD
OFF AND KEEP KIND OF NOT
PRISONER, BUT CERTAINLY UNDER
YOUR WATCH, THE OWNER OF THE
OVER CROW, THE GOBLIN, AS WELL
AS HER BUG BEAR BODYGUARD.
YOU HAVE DRAGGED THE CORPSE OF
BOTH THE DRAGON-BORN AND THE
HORSE TO THE BACK OF THE
BUILDING.
AND YOU HAVE GAINED JUST ENOUGH
KNOWLEDGE THROUGH YOUR SPELL USE
THAT THE FIGURE THAT ESCAPED,
THIS FIGURE HAS BEEN ON THE MOVE
NORTHWARD AND BEYOND THE REACH
OF THE SPELLS THAT YOU HAD
ALREADY CAST.
SO WE COME BACK TO YOU ALL
GATHERING AT THE OVER CROW.
AND FIGURING OUT WHAT TO DO
NEXT.
SO MIGHTY NINE, WHAT WOULD YOU
LIKE TO DO?
>> PULL THOSE BODIES THROUGH THE
WINDOW.
>> THE BODY OF A HORSE?
>> AND THE BODY OF THE DRAGON
BORN.
>> I THINK THE COURSE CAN STAY.
>> WE CAN PUT IT IN STORAGE.
>> WE’LL COVER IT WITH A BLANK
HE HAD OR SOMETHING.
>> PUT IT IN THE BACKROOM.
>> TURN IT TO COMPOST.
>> EVENTUALLY.
>> I START DRAGGING THE BRAG
UNBORN THROUGH THE WINDOW IN TO
THE BACK STORAGE ROOM.
>> IT LEAVES A LITTLE TRAIL.
>> I WOULD TRY PULL THE HORSE
THROUGH.
>> I THINK I MIGHT HAVE MESSED
UP, GUYS, I DON’T THINK THE
DRAGON BORN WAS AS IMPORTANT AS
I HAD INITIALLY THOUGHT.
>> YEAH, PRETTY SURE WE JUST
SHOT THE MESSENGER.
>> I AM SORRY ABOUT THAT.
>> IS THAT WHY THAT’S A SAYING?
>> YEAH.
>> WE JUST INVENTED THAT PHRASE.
>> LOOK, I AM PRETTY WITTY
PERSON.
>> BEAUREGARD JUST INVENTED THE
PHRASE DON’T SHOOT THE
MESSENGER.
CANNON.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> WHERE IS MARROW?
>> Matt: CURRENTLY IN THE SHOP
BEHIND THE COUNTER JUST KIND OF
SITTING THERE WATCHING YOU ALL
CAREFULLY.
>> MARROW.
>> YES.
DO YOU HAVE ANYMORE APPOINTMENTS
ON THE BOOKS FOR TODAY.
>> NOT PARTICULARLY.
THIS WAS IT?
THIS WAS THE ONLY MEETING THAT
YOU WERE BOOKED FOR.
>> THEY DON’T BOOK THEM IN
ADVANCE THEY JUST COME IN AND
PAY ME AND USE THE SPACE NOT
LIKE I HAVE AN EXTENSIVE LEDGER
WHERE THEY CONTACT ME WEEKS IN
ADVANCE AND PILL OUT A CALENDAR
AND MAKE SURE I CAN FILL IT IN.
>> INSIDE CHECK, DOES SHE HAVE A
LEDGER?
>> PLEASE.
WAY TOO SPECIFIC.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> Matt: THAT’S PRETTY GOOD.
THAT’S A 22.
>> YEAH.
>> I MEAN, I COULDN’T TELL BY
THE ACTION ACCENT, YOU CAN PICK
NEWEST D & D ADVENTURE ON D & D
BEYOND IT’S A SPOOKY ADVENTURE,
AND YOU CAN GET IT ONLY AT ONE
PLACE.
>> WELL, I THINK YOU GIVE IT
MORE THAN ONE PLACE, BUT YOU CAN
DEFINITELY GET IT AT D & D
BEYOND.
>> OFF PUTTING NOW.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> DID THEY TELL YOU HOW LONG
THEY WERE STAYING UPSTAIRS?
OR -- NO, THEY HAD NO PARTICULAR
INFORMATION ABOUT IT.
THEY JUST PAID FOR THE ENTRY FEE
AND TOOK THE TIME AND IF IT
OVERLAPSED I TOLD HEM TO COME
BACK LATER.
>> HOW MUCH IS THE ENTRY FEE?
>> CURIOUS, YEAH.
>> PER PERSON IT’S 25 GOLD.
>> DAMN, MORROW.
THAT’S A GOOD HUSTLE.
YEAH.
>> THANK YOU, I APPRECIATE THAT.
>> DON’T FEEL BAD FOR MYSELF.
MURDER IN HERE.
>> HOW OFTEN DOES PEOPLE GET
MURDER ED IN HERE,.
>> NOT VERY OFTEN I USUALLY DO A
MUCH BETTER JOB OF KEEPING IT
LOW KEY.
>> DID WE SEARCH THE DRAGON-BORN
BODY BEFORE WE PULLED IN THE
WINDOW.
>> BUT WE DID NOT SEARCH
UPSTAIRS, WE SHOULD GO UPSTAIRS
AND CHECK ON AROUND.
>> ANYTHING WE SHOULD KNOW ABOUT
BEFORE WE START LOOKING AROUND?
>> TRAPS, THINGS --
>> NO TRAPS, BUT THERE IS LIKE A
LITTLE SWITCH UNDER THE TABLE.
OPENS A CHUTE.
>> WHAT WHERE DOES THE CHUTE GO?
>> SHE POINTS TO THE STORAGE
ROOM.
>> MOTHER FUCK THAT’S HOW SHE
GOT OUT.
>> LET’S LOOK.
JOSH AND I WILL GO UP AND START
LOOKING.
>> OKAY.
I’LL HEAD UP -- I MAY HEAD UP AS
WELL.
>> IT’S A VERY PLAIN ROOM,,
INNING PENSION TENSION WILL HE
SO, NO DECOR JUST WOOD WALLS,
WOOD FLOORS, THERE IS THE ONE
WINDOW THAT’S SHUTTERED CLOSED
IN THE FRONT.
THERE ARE FOUR CHAIRS AND THERE
IS A TABLE.
THE TABLE IS BOLTED TO THE
FLOOR.
YOU KIND OF TAKE A MOMENT TO
LOOK UNDERNEATH AND YOU CAN SEE
UNDERNEATH THE TABLE PART OF THE
TABLE LEG THERE IS AN ADDITIONAL
IRON ROD THAT’S IN UP AGAINST
IT.
>> AN ADDITIONAL IRON ROD.
>> Matt: ON THE BACK OF -- ON
THE INSIDE OF ONE OF THE TABLE
LEGS.
>> YEAH.
>> IS THAT THE -- THAT’S THE
TRAP DOOR.
>> Matt: MIGHT BE, YEAH.
>> IT’S COOL.
>> ANYTHING ELSE?
>> SHOULD WE LOOK AROUND?
>> YEAH, LET’S LOOK AROUND.
>> OKAY.
TAKE THE DESK.
>> DO YOU WANT TO TAKE THE REST
OF THE ROOM.
>> BOTH OF YOU GUYS MAKE
INVESTIGATION CHECKS.
>> Laura: CAN I ASK A QUESTION?
>> Matt: YES, YOU CAN.
>> Laura: DID I ALREADY TELL HIM
WHAT I HEARD FROM THE MESSENGER?
HAVE WE TALKED ABOUT THAT AT
ALL?
OR DID WE BRUSH OVER THAT OR DID
IT --
>> Marisha: I CAN’T RECALL.
BUT YOU CAN DEFINITELY REKINDLE
THAT CONVERSATION IF YOU WOULD
LIKE TO CLARIFY.
>> Laura: I WASN’T SURE.
>> 16 AT THE DESK.
>> 8 FOR THE REST OF THE ROOM.
>> Matt: AT THE TABLE, THE DESK,
IT’S COLLEGE, IT’S A SIMPLE
TABLE.
THIS ROOM, ASIDE FROM THAT
SWITCH.
IS INTENTIONALLY LEFT BLANK,
BARON, NEUTRAL.
WHAT’S IN THE BEST INTEREST OF
THOSE THAT WOULD COME TO THE
PLACE OUT OF THE VIDIC SPECTRUM
OF THE REST OF THE CITY TO FIND
THE SPACE OF COMPLETE SAFE
NEUTRALITY.
>> AS WE ARE SEARCHING AROUND I
AM JUST GOING TO -- OH, IT’S A
SQUARE ROOM.
>> I AM SO SORRY THAT I SHOT YOU
THREE TIMES.
I DIDN’T MEAN TOO SHOOT YOU AT
ALL ANY TIMES, BUT THREE IS
EVERYBODY WORSE THAN ONE.
>> YEAH, IT’S OKAY, I CAN TAKE
IT, OBVIOUSLY.
BUT JUST I KNEW WE WERE UNDER
SOMETHING.
BUT JUST TRY NOT TO DO THAT
AGAIN IF YOU CAN.
>> I AM SORRY, I AM SORRY.
I AM SORRY, I ALSO DID ALL OF
THIS AND IS EVERYONE DOWNSTAIRS
MAD AT ME?
>> I DON’T EVEN THINK THAT THEY
ARE EVERYBODY THINKING ABOUT IT.
I THINK THERE IS A LOT OF OTHER
THINGS THAT IS ON EVERYBODY
ELSE’S MINDS.
YOU ARE OKAY.
>> OKAY.
>> YOU WARNED US, WE CAME IN
AND --
>> ARE YOU MAD AT YOURSELF I
SUPPOSE?
>> I JUST GOT VERY NERVOUS,
THAT’S ALL.
>> WHY DID YOU GET NERVOUS?
>> BECAUSE I HAVEN’T BEEN
DRINKING.
>> YOU HAVEN’T?
>> Sam: NO, BUT I THINK I SHOULD
START AGAIN.
I THINK I FUNCTION MUCH BETTER
WITH A LITTLE --
>> Ashley: WITH A LITTLE BIT OF
LIQUID COURAGE?
>> Sam: YES.
>> Ashley: I WOULDN’T TELL YOU
NOT TO DO THAT.
>> Sam: THAT’S THE KIND OF
ADVICE THAT I CAME HERE FOR.
THE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> WHILE SHE’S SWIGGING I SEND
HIM TO PITTER PAT UP THE PEEK OF
THE HOUSE AND GO BLIND AND DEAF
AND WANT TO SEE THE STREETS TO
SEE WHAT THE CITIZENS OF THE
TOWN ARE DOING.
>> OKAY.
>> OR IF THERE IS ANY GODS LIKE
RUSHING TO OR ANYTHING THAT IS A
PROBLEM.
>> PERCENT CHECK.
>> FOR TRUMP KIN.
>> YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
WHERE THE HELL DID THEY GO?
>> THEY ARE GONG.
>> I A ROLLED A 16.
>> Matt: FRUMPKIN TAKES A LOOK
AROUND, OCCASIONALLY YOU SEE
FIGURES WALKING AND WHISPERING
TO EACH OTHER.
YOU KNOW, THEY ARE LIKE ANY
FOLKS WHO LIVE KIND OF IN THE
OUTER BONNEYS OF THE CITY, WORD
GETS AROUND AND THERE IS A LOT
OF LOCALS WHO ARE PASSING BY AND
JUST INFORMING EACH OTHER OF
SOME SORT OF SCUFFLE IN THE
STREET YOU MAY THINK.
YOU DON’T SEE ANY GUARD GETTING
INVOLVED AT THE MOMENT.
BUT IT SEEMS THAT IT’S BEING
DISCUSSED.
>> SOY I AM GOING STAY IN THIS
STATE AND SAY THAT PEOPLE WHO
LIVE HERE ARE TALKING ABOUT
THIS, THAT IS ALL.
AND I SAY IN IT.
AND WATCH.
>> Matt: OKAY.
>> WE PROBABLY SHOULDN’T STAY
HERE ALONE THEN S.
>> Sam: BUT WAIT -- I AM NOT
THERE.
>> I DON’T KNOW IF BLONDIES WHAT
DID WE NAME HIM?
>> GREG.
>> IF GREG IS GOING TO SHOW UP
OR NOT.
I DON’T.
>> THE PEOPLE WHO WERE HERE HIS
BEE LEIGH A SONS OR WAS THAT
SOMETHING TOTALLY UP RELATED?
>> SEEMS LIKE A TRANSACTION WAS
HAPPENING AND HAPPENED.
>> MAYBE HE WAS SAYING THAT YOU
KNOW, HE WAS SENDING SOMEBODY,
MAYBE HE NEVER SAID THAT HE WAS
GOING TO BE HERE HIMSELF.
>> MORROW.
THE THAN, WAS HE HOLDING
ANYTHING WHAT HE PULLED?
, CARRYING ANYTHING?
>> Sam: HE HAD LIKE A POUCH AND
TRAVEL GEAR, BUT THAT’S ABOUT
IT.
>> HOW BIG WAS THE POUCH?
>> POUCH SIZE.
I WASN’T PAYING ATTENTION!
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> AND YOU ARE SURE YOU DON’T
KEEP ANY SIGN-IN SHEET, RECORD.
>> THAT’S WHAT I WANT TO DO IS
HAVE A LONG SHEET THAT HAS EVERY
ILLEGAL ACTIVITY THAT HAPPENS IN
MY SHOP.
>> GIVES YOU AN ALIBI.
>> YOU WOULD THINK THAT.
>> ALL RIGHT.
MR. KALEB.
>> TOTALLY DEAF.
>> HE’S BUSY.
HIS MIND IS IN ANOTHER PERSON
THING RIGHT NOW.
DO YOU NEED US TO TELL HIM
SOMETHING?
>> I AM GOING TO COME DOWN.
>> I AM GOING TO GO UPSTAIRS.
>> OH, --
>> OKAY, THIS IS JUST -- I’LL GO
LEFT.
>> I’LL GO RIGHT.
>> OKAY.
>> ALL RIGHT, YOU HEAD UPSTAIRS.
>> I HEAD UPSTAIRS.
>> YOU GO UPSTAIRS.
>> I WAS THINKING IF THERE IS A
WAY THAT WE CAN MAYBE MAGICALLY
KEEP TABS ON THE ROOM.
I DON’T KNOW IF THERE IS A
THREAD THING OR A THING THAT YOU
CAN DO TO LIKE ALERT US TO
DIFFERENT PEOPLE.
>> IF WE LEAVE SOMETHING BEHIND
THEN WE CAN DESCRIBE THROUGH IT.
NOT A BAD IDEA.
>> JESTER!
>> HOLD ON, I AM IN THE MIDDLE
OF SOMETHING.
I AM IN THE MIDDLE OF TALKING TO
YOU ACTUALLY.
>> OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, SUGGESTION.
>> DID YOU KNOW THAT GUY THAT
YOU WERE FIGHT SOMETHING.
>> I HAVE NEVER SEEN IT EITHER
OF THEM BEFORE IN MY LIFE.
BECAUSE I THINK HE KNOWS YOU.
I WAS SENDING HIM A MESSAGE
TRYING TO FAKE HIM OUT THAT HE
SHOULD COME BACK HERE, HE DIDN’T
FALL FOR IT.
HE WAS LIKE FOLLOW ME NORTH.
BRING HER.
>> BRING HERMENE SOMETHING.
>> I THINK HE MEANS YASSA.
>> YOU DO?
>> THAT’S WHAT I THOUGHT.
NO, HE DIDN’T, AND HERE IS THE
CRAZY PART, BECAUSE I HAVE USED
THIS SPELL A LOT, OKAY?
>> OKAY.
>> AND OKAY, SO HE SO I NEVER
SUE THAT GUY EVER.
AND SOMEHOW WHEN I SENT HIM THE
MESSAGE, HE KNEW IT WAS ME.
>> HE KNEW WHO YOU WERE?
>> YEAH, HE WAS LIKE I KNOW YOU.
>> THAT’S NOT WHAT USUALLY
HAPPENS HE USUALLY SENDS US AND
YOU HAVE TO SAY WHO YOU ARE.
>> QUELL, YEAH, UNLESS THEY KNOW
ME, THEY DON’T KNOW IT’S ME.
>> LIKE HE’S BEEN SPYING ON US?
>> I MEAN, WHAT IF HE’S GROWING
OUT THE WAY THAT THAT I HAVE
BEEN SPYING ON OTHER PEOPLE.
>> TO SKRY.
YOU NEED TO KNOW SOMETHING IN A
TRAVELING PARTY.
>> OR KNOW OF THEM.
HE COULD KNOW ABOUT YOU OR
SOMETHING AND HAVE BEEN -- I
DON’T KNOW.
>> I DON’T THINK I HAVE EVER
SEEN HIM BEFORE.
>> STYLES WHEN I CAN’T THINK OF
SOMEONE, I THINK OF THE FIRST
LETTER OF THEIR NAME, DOES IT
START WITH "A", "B" GO THROUGH
THE ALPHABET THAT WAY.
>> THE NAME.
--
\h--
>> SOUNDING OUT.
IS THERE ANYTHING THINKING OF
HIM, HE MIGHT HAVE BEEN
DISGUISING HIMSELF OR SOMETHING,
I WOULD HAVE DISGUISED MYSELF
COMING IN HERE.
I DID DISGUISE MYSELF AS A MOTH.
IT DIDN’T WORK VERY WELL.
>> YOU GOT THE TASTE OF --
>> THEY WERE SO GOOD.
>> YEAH, --
>> ACTUALLY, WHILE WE ARE
DISCUSSING THIS, I WALK OVER TO
THE CURTAINS AND GIVE THEM A
LITTLE MUNCH AS MYSELF AS WELL.
>> OKAY.
SOMEHOW LEFT TASTY IN YOUR
CURRENT FORM.
>> NO.
>> SO YOU DON’T REMEMBER THIS
PERSON AT ALL?
>> WELL, IF I THINK REALLY HARD
ON IT, THEN DOES HE SEEM
FAMILIAR TO ME AT ALL?
>> NOT PARTICULARLY.
YOU HAVE NOT -- YOU HAVE NOT
ENCOUNTERED MANY OR INTERACTED
WITH MANY IN THE TIME THAT YOU
GREW UP.
IN THE MORELANDS FOR THE MOST
PART THE TRIBES KEEP WAY AND
DON’T GET INVOLVED IN THE CREAN.
SO YOU HAVE NO RECOLLECTION OF
MEET THIS IS INDIVIDUAL BEFORE.
>> HE SAID COME NORTH.
>> DOWNSTAIRS DIDN’T THE HOBBY
GOBY ALSO CALL YOU SOMETHING?
>> YES.
HE CALLED ME BY THE NAME THAT
WAS GIVEN TO ME BY MY TRIBE.
>> WHICH WAS OR FIN MAKER.
>> YES.
>> THAT IS A COOL ASS NAME BY
THE WAY.
WELL, THANK YOU, BUT IT’S A
LITTLE WEIRD THAT SOMEONE KNOWS
MY NAME AND I DON’T KNOW WHO
THEY ARE.
>> SO THE ORPHAN MAKE SENIOR A
NAME THAT YOU LIKED?
>> WELL, NOT PARTICULARLY, MY
NAME IS CRASH A, BUT, YOU KNOW,
>> OH!
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> REFERENCE.
>> JUST CHECKING SOMETHING OUT
HERE.
>> DID YOU MAKE AN ORPHAN BY
KILLING SOMEONE’S PARENTS?
>> NO, I THINK WHEN WHEN YOU ARE
TAKING IN TO THE TRIBE YOU -- I
FEEL LIKE MAYBE I HAVE TOLD YOU
GUYS THIS BEFORE.
>> YEAH, I THINK YOU TOTALLY
HAVE.
>> Ashley: YOU TAKE A BLOOD OATH
THAT THEY CALL THE MARKING AND
WHEN YOU TAKE IT, THEY GIVE YOU
A NAME IN THE TRIB TRIBE AND SO
THE NAME THAT WAS GIVEN TO ME IS
ORPHAN MAKER.
>> BUT WHY THAT IN.
>> BECAUSE SHE’S TOUGH.
>> Ashley: WE ALL HAVE NAMES
LIKE THAT.
>> Laura: WHY AM I THE LITTLE
SAPPHIRE, I NEVER KNEW, I
COULDN’T FIGURE IT OUT.
>> YOU ARE SHINY AND BLUE AND
BEAUTIFUL.
>> YEAH.
>> Laura: OH, THAT MAKES PERFECT
SENSE ACTUALLY.
>> Ashley: YOU ARE A LITTLE
SAPPHIRE.
>> WHICH LEADS ME TO BELIEVE
THAT YASHA HAS KILLED SOMEONE’S
PARENTS.
>> NO, I DON’T THINK IT’S LIKE
THAT.
I THINK YOU ARE GIVEN A NAME IN
YOUR TRIBE THAT MAYBE CALLS OUT
WHATEVER YOUR DESTINY WILL BE.
>> OH, ROUGH.
>> Ashley: IT’S ALL -- WE WERE
ALL GIVEN NAMES THAT ARE.
[SPEAKING AT THE SAME TIME]
>> Laura: WHAT ARE SOME OF
ANOTHER SCARY NAMES THAT PEOPLE
GOT?
>> WERE THEY ALL SORT OF DARK
AND --
>> Ashley: THEY ARE ALL DARK AND
SCARY.
>> TURTLE DOVE.
>> Ashley: YES.
>> CHERRY BLOSSOM.
>> Ashley: THEY ARE ALL BIG AND
SCARY NAMES.
>> ARTERIAL SPRAY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Ashley: THEY ARE ALL LIKE
THAT.
THEY ARE SUPPOSED TO WHEN YOU
NEED ANOTHER -- MEET OTHER
PEOPLE OR OTHER TRIBES THEY ARE
SUPPOSED TO INSIGHT FEAR AND I
DON’T THINK -- I NEVER TOOK THAT
NAME TO HEART.
I MEAN, MY NAME IS YASHA.
BUT IT’S WEIRD THAT THEY KNOW
THAT BECAUSE THAT WAS ONLY KNOWN
IN MY TRIBE.
>> Laura: DO YOU WANT TO FOLLOW
HIM NORTH?  I MEAN, --
>> Ashley: I WANT TO KNOW WHY
THEY KNOW WHO I AM.
>> Laura: BECAUSE WE COULD DO
IT.
WE COULD GO AFTER HIM.
>> Ashley: MAYBE.
WE’LL SEE.
WE’LL TALK WITH EVERYONE AND SEE
WHAT EVERYONE WANTS TO DO.
>> A, NOT.
YOU PULL THAT DAMN SWITCH YET?
>> WE ARE STARING AT THE STUPID
SHOOT AND SEE WHAT HAPPENED.
>> YOU BREAK IT OR NOT WHAT?
>> I WILL FLIP THE SWITCH.
>> FLIP THE SWITCH IN THE BACK
CORNER OF THE ROOM, KIND OF JUST
COMES LOOSE, THERE IS A LITTLE
LATCH THAT IS LET LOOSE AND IT
IS ASS IT FLIES OPEN YOU WATCH
PART OF THE CEILING AND THE
STORAGE CHAMBER, THAT’S OFF TO
THE SIDE OF THE APOTHECARY.
HANG OPEN AT AN ANGLE AND THERE
IS ROOM FOR SOMEBODY TO SLIDE
DOWN.
>> Ashley: I GO SLIDE DOWN IT.
>> OKAY.
>> SON OF A BITCH, IT’S LIKE AN
ACTION FIGURE PLAY SET.
>> I AM TELLING FRUMPKIN TO KEEP
LOOK OUT AND TELL ME IF ANYTHING
COMES CLOSE OR IF THERE IS ANY
STIR BEYOND WHAT I HAVE ALREADY
SEEN DROP DOWN.
WHAT ARE WE DOING?
>> I THINK WE ARE GOING TO CHECK
OUT.
--
\h--
>> LAND ON KALEB COMING UP.
>> HEADS UP JESTER COMING.
>> DID YOU CHECK OUT THE PLAN IN
THE BACK --
>> A PLANE?
>> A PLAN.
THAT WAS THE BODYGUARD, THANK
YOU, THANK YOU, BRAIN.
>> IT’S ALL GOOD.
>> CATCHING UP.
>> IS THAT THE MESSAGE TO THE
GUY, HE SAID, FOLLOW ME NORTH IF
YOU REALLY WANT TO TALK TO ME OR
SOMETHING AND HE SAID BRING HER
AND I THINK HE MOONS YASHA AND
WE ARE PROBABLY GOING TO GO,
RIGHT?
>> WHAT’S UP, ORPHAN MAKER.
>> LOOK, WE ARE COUNTING ON
THIS, RIGHT, WE IS WE WERE GOING
TO DELIVER, IF WE COME BACK
EMPTY HASN’TED WE ARE NOT GOING
IT LOOK TOO CORRECT.
WHAT ABOUT THESE TWO?
>> THEY DON’T CARE.
>> ARE YOU SURE SOME.
>> NO, I WOULD THINK KALEB IS
RIGHT.
>> ALL RIGHT, MORROW, YOU HAVE
TO DIE.
>> ANY LAST WORDS?
>> NO, NO, I HAVE BEEN CORDIAL
AND GOOD ABOUT ALL OF THIS.
>> I AM OF THE OPINION THAT
THERE MIGHT BE AN OPTION HERE.
>> I AM LISTENING.
>> I THINK THAT WE CAN COME TO A
FINANCIAL ARRANGEMENT.
>> GO ON.
>> I THINK THAT MAYBE WE CAN
LEAVE A LITTLE GOLD IN RETURN
NOTHING IS SPOKEN OF, AND MAYBE
IF ANYBODY -- ANY OF THIS PARTY,
ESPECIALLY IF WE LEAVE A SMALL
SKETCH OF WHO WE ARE LOOKING FOR
ARRIVES WE ARE SIMPLY GENTLY
ALERT AND THE IN RETURN
EVERYTHING IS JUST LEFT AS IT
IS.
I MEAN, TO BE FAIR, EVEN IF THEY
ARE -- WE LEAVE RIGHT NOW JUST
WITH A GIANT PILE OF BODIES IN
HERE IS A BIG PROBLEM FOR THESE
TWO ANYWAY.
>> THAT IS TRUE.
>> WHERE IS JESTER AT?
>> Laura: I AM ON TOP OF KALEB.
>> HEY, JESSE, YOU STILL GOT
THAT SPELL THAT LETS YOU TRACK
PEOPLE WHENEVER THEY GO AND SO
THEY ARE INCENTIVIZED TO PLAY
ALONG.
>> Laura: OBVIOUSLY.
WHY DO YOU WANT DO THAT OVER
HERE?
>> Laura: YOU GOT IT.
>> MAKE A DECEPTION CHECK.
>> 20.
>> I TOLD UP MY TRAVELER SYMBOL.
A SAY BLANKY BLANKY TO YOU,
SHALA GAME.
THATSHALO.
I USED TO TO PLAY MY EYES AND
BLOW HIS HAIR BACK, HER HAIR
BACK.
YEAH.
YOU HAVE BEEN MARKED.
>> THAT’S THAT DOES IT, DON’T
YOU FUCK US OVER BECAUSE IT
COULD GO BACK FOR YOU.
>> IT’S OKAY.
>> REALLY STRONG ONE WHERE WE
SHUT DIE INSTANTLY IF THEY BREAK
THEIR.
>> I THINK THERE IS A
POSSIBILITY AFTER THIS HAS BLOWN
OVER MAYBE THIS CAN TURN IN TO A
BEAUTIFUL RELATIONSHIP FOR
EVERYBODY INVOLVED.
>> I AM ALL ABOUT FRUITFUL
RELATIONSHIPS.
>> AND YOU CERTAINLY DON’T WANT
TO PISS OFF THE EMPRESS ELF.
>> NO, VERY CONFUSED IN GENERAL.
>> THAT’S GOOD, YOU DON’T WANT
TO KNOW ALL THE DETAILS.
>> WE JUST WANT TO KNOW --
>> NOT AT ALL.
>> WHAT WE TELL YOU.
>> WE ARE WELL KNOWN FOR OUR
MIXED MESSAGES.
>> WHO WAS IN YOUR SHOP TODAY?
>> I DON’T KNOW.
>> UH-HUH.
>> HOW DID ALL OF THOSE BODIES
GET IN HERE?
>> IT’S A THE CRAZIEST THING, I
WOKE UP AND THEY WERE THERE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> WE’LL DO WELL.
YEAH.
>> ACTUALLY, I MIGHT SUGGEST
THAT WE TAKE A COUPLE OF THESE
BODIES WITH US.
>> PLEASE.
>> DO YOU TALK TO THEM?
>> THEY ARE VERY HEAVY.
>> WE CAN TAKE THEM UNDERNEATH.
>> GIVEN THE CIRCUMSTANCES -- WE
CAN ON TALK TO THE DRAGON BORN
ABOUT WHAT THAT HE BROUGHT.
>> WHERE DOES IT TUNNEL GO,
COULD BUT PUT THEM IN THERE.
>> IT GOES FROM THE FIRST FLOOR
TO THE SECOND FLOOR.
>> BOTH OF THEM INCLUDING THE
HORSE.
>> NO, THERE ARE TWO BODIES.
THE HOBB GOBLIN AND THE DRAGON
BORN.
>> LET’S TALK TO THEM.
I AM NOT 100 PERCENT CONVINCED
THESE WERE THE PEOPLE THAT WE
WERE LOOKING FOR.
>> YOU TALK TO THEM, I’LL TALK
TO THE HORSE.
>> OKAY.
>> DO YOU KNOW HOW TO SPEAK
HORSE?
>> I KNOW THOUSAND TALK TO DEAD
HORSES.
>> IS THAT TRUE?
>> YEAH.
>> WOW.
THAT’S COOL.
>> I ACTUALLY CAN’T TALK TO THEM
UNTIL TOMORROW.
>> I JUST UP VENTED THAT PHRASE.
>> NOT UNTIL TOMORROW.
>> CAN IT.
>> JUST TO CLARIFY, WE WERE
SUPPOSE TODAY INTERCEPT GREG,
BLONDE GREG WHO YOU DEFINITELY
HEARD SAY THAT HE WAS COMING
HERE IN PERSON.
>> NO.
>> DO I REMEMBER IF I DEFINITELY
HEARD THAT HE WAS COMING OR I
JUST HEARD THE DATE AND THE
ARRIVAL?
>> LET ME LOOK UP THE SPECIFIC
WORDS TO INSURE THAT I AM NOT
GETTING THIS WRONG FOR YOU
EITHER.
>> OKAY.
>> JUST A SECOND AS I GO TO MY
DROP BOX.
>> YOUR NOTES ARE DOPE HOW DO
YOU FIND ANYTHING.
>> THAT’S WHY I DON’T MAKE NOTES
SHE KNOWS IT.
>> WHAT FROM WHAT I WROTE DOWN
HAS THE EMBLEM AT THE OVERCROW,
YOU WANT TO MEET UP IN THE NEXT
WEEK, NO, THEY WERE LIKE SIX
DAYS, NO, THAT’S TOO SOON, 13
DAYS.
AND THEN THEY MENTIONED A FEMALE
IN HER PARANOIA.
THAT’S WHAT I DO GOT.
>> SOUNDS RIGHT.
WE’LL GO WITH THAT.
>> FEMALE PAIR PARANOIA.
>> GREG DIDN’T SAY I WILL BE
THERE PERSONALLY IN 13 DAYS.
>> NO, THAT THING WILL HAPPEN AT
THE OVER CROW.
>> THIS IS WHAT HAPPENED.
AND WE GOT THE MONEY AND NOW HE
HAS THE EM OR WHATEVER IT IS.
>> LET’S PLOT FOR THE NEXT --
THE WEEK AFTER.
THE OVERCROW.
>> HE, I HAVE THE EMBLEM, WILL
HE BE TRADING --
>> SO GREG SENT THE EMBLEM AND
SOLD IT FOR 50 PLATINUM, EIGHT?
>> WE DON’T KNOW.
>> THERE WAS 50 PLATINUM
INVOLVED.
>> WE DON’T KNOW IF SHE SAID --
HOW MANY MEETINGS DO YOU USUALLY
HAVE IN A DAY, MORROW?
>> LIKE ONE A WEEK.
IT’S NOT THAT OFTEN.
>> ONE A WEEK.
>> IS THIS THE ONLY ONE -- THIS
WAS THE ONLY ONE TODAY?
>> THE ONLY ONE TODAY, YEAH.
>> SHE KNOWS --
>> THIS MAY BE STUPID IF THEM
THE EMBLEM AND IT’S SIMILAR TO
OURS ARE THEY TRYING TO CREATE A
DISTRACTION ON THE WAR FRONT SO
THEY CAN DO A SINGULAR A TRACK
AND HIT SOMEBODY WITH IMPORTANCE
WITH THAT EMBLEM LIKE WITH A
FUCKING HE DEF CON ONE BADGE.
>> THAT’S A LOT.
>> THAT’S WRONG.
>> I DON’T KNOW.
>> OKAY.
SHOULD WE GO NORTH?
>> LET’S GO.
>> I THINK IT’S THE ONLY OPTION.
WE ARE LEFT HERE HOLDING THE
BAG.
>> LET’S FOLLOW HIM.
>> CRASH, A DO YOU RECOGNIZE
ANYTHING THAT SOUNDS FAMILIAR.
>> UPSTAIRS, YASHA SAID
SOMETHING REALLY INTERESTING.
RIGHT AFTER THE STREAM ENDED
LAST WEEK ABOUT THE WORD --
>> WE CAN’T HEAR.
TELL US WHAT YOU OVERHEARD.
TELL US EVERYTHING.
>> OH, YES, I HEARD THE ONLY
WORD THAT I CLEARLY HEARD WAS
BACK SEWS GENERAL.
>> I THINK THAT’S A PLACE, IT
SOUNDS SO FAMILIAR TO ME.
I DON’T KNOW IF I HAVE BEEN
THERE I THINK I HAVE SEEN IT ON
THE MAP.
>> YASHA, I THINK YOU ARE RIGHT.
>> I THINK YOU ARE RIGHT.
>> IT’S RIGHT ABOVE THIS BLOOD
SPRAY.
>> IT’S NORTH.
THAT’S WHERE HE SAID TO FOLLOW.
>> IT IS 100 PERCENT.
>> GREAT THINKING YASHA.
>> Y ASHI.
>> SO, HOW MANY DAYS’ RIDE DO
YOU THINK THAT IS?
>> WHERE ARE WE AT RIGHT NOW?
>> IF YOU WANT TO, BOTH FA YARD
AND BEAUREGARD MAKE AN
INTELLIGENCE CHECK, PLEASE.
>> ON THIS?
>> ON THE MAP?
>> JUST A CHECK.
>> 15.
>> OH, NO, THAT’S GOOD.
>> 19.
>> 19, YEAH, BOTH LOOKING AT IT,
YOU GET THE SENSE THAT THERE ARE
TWO PATHS THERE, YOU CAN GO
AROUND HE CAN GO ALONG THE
OUTSIDE PATH AND TAKE THAT AND
THAT TAKES YOU ABOUT FIVE DAZE’
TRAVEL, OR YOU CAN GO STRAIGHT
TO THE BARBED FIELDS AND THAT
TAKES YOU THREE DAYS TRAVEL.
>> I AM ASSUMING THE BARBED
FIELDS IS LESS DEADLY AND
TRAVELED.
>> NO, BARBS.
>> IT WAS THE GROUND ZERO FOR
THE FINAL BATTLES OF THE
CALAMITY.
>> OH, HELL YEAH.
>> WE ARE GOING THROUGH THERE.
>> TAKE KNEE THAT TMZ TOUR.
>> ROAD TRIP, YEAH.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> YOU HAVE OPTIONS.
>> NO.
THERE IS NO OPTION THERE.
>> IS THAT LIKE EVERYTHING IN TO
THE LEVEL 20 ZONE, THOUGH?
>> I DON’T CARE.
WE ARE HERE.
>> MORROW.
THE BARB ZONE, BARB ZONE, IS
THAT WHAT IT IS?
>> BARBED FIELD.
>> THE BONE ZONE.
THE BONE ZONE.
>> WAIT, I AM NOT FOLLOWING THIS
AT ALL.
>> DO YOU WATCH "STRANGER
THINGS."
>> I HAVE ONLY SEEN HALF OF THE
FIRST SEASON.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> HAVE YOU EVER BEEN THROUGH
THE BARBED FIELDS?
>> WHAT?
>> NO.
WHY WOULD YOU GO THERE.
THAT PLACE IS --
>> SCARY?
>> YOU ARE NOT FROM AROUND HERE
ARE YOU?
>> WHAT GAVE US AWAY.
>> WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT
THE BARBED FIELDS?
>> I HAVEN’T BEEN THERE I JUST
HEAR ALL THESE TERRIBLE STORIES
AND JUST REALLY TEAR ABLE TO GET
AROUND AND IT’S HOT DURING THE
DAY AND THERE IS ALSO THE
TERRIBLE CREATURES AND WEIRD
MAGIC THAT JUST KIND OF LINGERS
FROM BACK WHEN ALL OF THE CRAZY
ASS GODS WERE FIGHTING AND SHIT.
AND I DON’T KNOW, I JUST THAT’S
ALL I KNOW.
>> ANY GROUPS IN TOWN THAT
REGULARLY MAKE THEIR WAY OUT
THERE TO SAVAGE FOR RELICS?
>> NONE THAT I CARE TO REALLY
KNOW AND FEW THAT COME BACK, I
AM SURE.
>> YEAH, ALL RIGHT.
>> WHAT KIND OF CREATURES?
>> I DON’T KNOW, I HAVEN’T BEEN
THERE!
>> OH, GOD.
>> MAYBE WE TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
FRIEND, WHAT’S THEIR NAME?
>> DOCTOR FRIEND?
>> PROFESSOR --
>> I HAVEN’T ACTUALLY -- I
HAVEN’T ACTUALLY MET THEM TO BE
FAIR.
>> WACKO.
>> YEAH.
>> MAYBE TH*EBGD SHED SOME
LIGHT.
>> I DON’T FEEL LIKE TALKING TO
ANYONE I FEEL LIKE GETTING OUT
OF TOWN.
>> THAT ONE, LET’S DO IT.
>> I DON’T WANT ANYTHING GETTING
BACK TO --
>> THE QUEEN AND SEE.
>> DO THIS AWESOME, AWESOME
THING.
>> WE TOTALLY BIFFED IT.
>> OH, WHAT THE FUCK ARE THESE
LITTLE DO DADS ON THE MAP THERE?
>> THAT’S LANGUAGE YOU MAY NOT
UNDERSTAND WHAT LANGUAGE IT IS,
DO YOU KNOW?
>> DEFINITELY NOT DO DAD.
>> DO YOU KNOW UNDERCOMMON.
>> WHY DIDN’T I TAKE THAT.
>> ANYBODY THAT UNDERCOMMON.
>> NO, BUT I CAN READ ANYTHING
IF YOU GIVE ME SOME TIME WITH
IT.
>> THE INTO OUT AND I AM
STARTING THE RITUAL CAST.
>> YOU GOT IT.
>> HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE?
>> 10 MINUTES.
>> NONE OF US SPEAK UNDERCOMMON.
>> I DON’T THINK ANY OF US WOULD
SPEAK IT.
>> THAT’S A FIRST LEVEL SPELL.
>> I DON’T HAVE A CHOICE.
>> RITUAL.
>> PIKE SPOKE IT.
THAT DOESN’T HELP.
>> CAN SHE KIND OF, YOU KNOW,
HOLOGRAM IN.
>> HEY, GUYS.
>> LEVEL ONE.
>> ONE ACTION, 10 MINUTES.
11 MINUTES.
>> YOU GOT IT.
SO YOU EVENTUALLY CAN LOOK AT IT
AND IT SAYS THE DEEP RIFF MINE.
>> I WILL EVERYTHING THAT IS IN
A DIFFERENT LANGUAGE.
THERE IS A LITTLE BIT UP HERE AS
WELL.
>> THAT REFERS TO THE.
>> PUT DID DOWN SO HE WE CAN SEE
>> THAT IS THE ASH GUARD
GARRISON.
>> AND HERE?
>> THAT IS THE -- LET PIE GET MY
MAP HERE THAT WE ARE DOING THIS.
NOW THAT WE ARE DOING THIS.
>> HOLD ON UNTIL I PULL OUT MY
MAP.
>> ARE YOU WRITING ON THIS SHIT?
ARE YOU CRAZY?
>> YEAH.
WE WANT TO REMEMBER.
>> DALTON DANGLE.
>> OKAY, THERE WE GO.
THAT’S CALLED THE BLOOD WALK.
>> WHERE?
>> THAT LEADS ON THE ASH GUARD
GARRISON SO.
>> , THE BLOOD WALK.
>> WE HAVE A LITTLE MORE HERE.
>> THAT RIGHT THERE -- IT READS
AS THE EYES OF THE LAKE.
>> GOOD.
>> COOL.
>> ARE YOU WRITING THIS DOWN
SOME.
>> NOBODY IS.
>> YOU GOT IT.
>> TO WHAT END?
>> WE SHOULD JUST WRITE IT ON
THE MAP.
>> POST ITS.
>> IS THAT JUST PLAYER?
>> SOMETHING MINE, THE BONE
SHATTER MINE.
>> THAT’S WHERE YOU HAVE ALREADY
BEEN THAT’S WHERE YOU HAD TO
FREE THE GIANTS FROM.
>> LYING THE IDEA OF POST-ITS.
>> YOU CAN DO WHAT YOU WANT WITH
IT.
>> EYES OF THE BLAKE, BLOOD
PATH.
BLOOD.
>> BLOOD WALK.
>> UNIVERSITY CITY BLACK WALK.
>> AND THERE IS -- IS THAT ONE
RIGHT HERE TOO?
>> THAT IS.
THAT READS CHARIS.
>> I FEEL LIKE THAT HAS
SIGNIFICANT MEANING.
>> IT’S A HISTORY CHECK.
>> 26.
>> WHOA.
>> WE HAVE TO GO DO IT.
>> THAT’S THE BONES RIGHT NOW.
>> THAT’S THE BONE ZONE.
>> COMPLETE THE OTHER MISSION.
>> WHY CAN’T I IT,.
>> YOU HAVE VERY LITTLE
INFORMATION ABOUT THE LOTUS
GREENWOOD.
IT’S CONSIDERED A VERY, VERY
DANGEROUS FOREST.
THAT’S ALL YOU RECALL ABOUT THE
VICINITY.
SOMETHING ABOUT KIND OF
UNBRIDLED MAGIC AND IT’S JUST
THIS VERY DANGEROUS FOREST AND
YOU HAVE NO IDEA WHAT CHAR US
IS.
>> I AM SO AMPED RIGHT NOW.
CAN WE PLEASE GO TO GROUND ZERO.
>> I THINK WE ARE GOING ON
GROUND ZERO BY GOING TO BARBED
FIELD.
>> DO WEAPON TO GO FAST OR
PREPARE A BIT.
>> NO, WE JUST HAVE TO GO.
>> YOU HAVE TO GO FAST.
SORRY.
>> I AM SO SORRY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> YOU ARE FORGIVEN.
>> WE GET OUR BOUNDERS AND TRY
TO MAKE UP LOST GROUND ON THIS
FUCKER.
>> DO YOU WANT TO TALK TO THESE
THINGS?
>> RIGHT.
>> OR DO WE LEAVE?
>> WE CAN TAKE THEIR HEADS.
>> I AM SO SORRY,.
>> THAT’S DARK.
>> WHAT?
>> THAT’S A GOOD IDEA.
I AM IN TO IT.
>> WHOA.
>> I HOPE YASHA BEHEAD THE
OTHER.
>> OH, BOY.
>> WHOA.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> TIME IS OF THE FUCKING
ESSENCE.
>> I DON’T KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
>> Reporter: THAT’S GOING TAKE
WEEKS TO SCRAPE OUT OF THE RUG.
>> LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING, IF
YOU TALK, THAT WOULD BE YOU,
UNDERSTOOD?
>> I UNDERSTAND COMPLETELY.
>> SEE, NOW THAT’S DASHES.
>> WE DON’T WANT TO, THOUGH, I
DON’T WANT TO DO THAT HERE.
>> I AM GETTING A LOT OF WEIRD
MIXED MESSAGES FROM YOU GUYS.
>> JUST PLAY BY THE RULES AND
YOU DON’T GET TURNED INSIDE OUT
AND YOUR HEAD CUT OFF.
>> YOU GET IT.
NO WORRIES.
>> I TAKE OUT 15 PLATINUM FROM
THE PLATINUM THAT WE SCRAPED
OFF.
>> NO, WHAT ARE YOU --
>> WE ALREADY DROPPED OFF GOLD,
CONDITIONS WE?
>> DID WE GIVE HIM GOLD YET?
>> DIDN’T YOU IN YOUR PLAN?
>> I MENTIONED IT.
I DIDN’T ACTUALLY GET AROUND TO
IT.
>> DO IT.
IT’S ONLY MONEY.
>> ONE GOLD IS -- ONE PLATINUM
IS 10 GOLD.
THAT’S 150 GOLD.
>> IT’S WORTH IT.
>> DO YOUR THING.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> LONG CON ACHIEVED.
>> WHAT ABOUT NOW?
>> WE DON’T KNOW WHEN WE ARE
GOING TO RETURN.
JUST TAKE THE 150 GOLD, TAKE
THIS 15 PLATINUM.
AND LET’S CONSIDER US -- THIS A
DOWN PAYMENT ON OUR MEMBERSHIP
FOR WHATEVER WE WANT TO USE YOUR
FACILITIES.
HOW DOES THAT SOUND.
>> ALSO HAVE A REALLY GOOD DAY,
OKAY.
>> THANKS.
>> I READ YOU LOUD AND CLEAR.
GOOD DAY.
>> WHAT WAS YOUR BUG BEAR’S
NAME?
I DON’T THINK WE --
>> OH, --
>> DID WE GET HIS NAME?
>> IT WAS FRENCH OFF SOMETHING.
VERY BASIC.
>> KEN.
SOMETHING VERY SIMPLE.
>> MY OTHER NOTEBOOK --
>> I -- THAT’S FINE.
I KNOW.
>> I SPLIT UP THE REST OF THE
PLATINUM AND I GAVE EVERYBODY
FIVE PLATINUM.
>> I MEAN, THANK YOU.
>> WOW.
>> THAT’S A LOT OF PLATINUM.
>> ALL RIGHT, SO WE MOVE WITH
EXPEDIENCE BACK TOWARDS THE
MOORE BOUNDERS .
>> SO YOU HEAD BACK TO THE JORE
HOUSEHOLDING THE SEVERED HEADS
OF --
>> THE BACK -- OF WHICH ONES THE
DRAGON BORN.
>> THE DRAGON BORN.
>> AND THE HOBB GOBLIN.
>> NO, HE’S HOBB GOBLIN, YOU ARE
TOTALLY RIGHT.
>> AND THE OFFICERS.
>> NO.
>> OKAY.
>> WE HAVE THE HOBB GOBLINS
SWORD, TOO?
>> UH-HUH.
>> WE HAVEN’T IDENTIFIED IT OR
ANYTHING, RIGHT?
>> HUH-UH.
NO.
>> WE ARE BACK AT OUR HOUSE, AT
THE JORE HOUSE.
>> THE MORE BOUNDERS ARE THERE.
>> THE HOBB GOBLIN SWORD.
>> YEAH.
>> DID YOU IDENTIFY IT?
YOU DIDN’T YET.
>> DID YOU GIVE ME A SWORD?
>> IT WAS GIVEN TO ME TO
IDENTIFY.
>> IT LOOKS LIKE WE HAVE IT.
WE’LL TAKE IT BACK.
>> OKAY.
>> I FORGOT ABOUT THAT.
>> THAT’S ALL GOOD.
>> YOU HEAD BACK TO THE HOUSE,
YOU HAVE THE HEADS.
YOU -- YOU KNOW, IT SEEMS IN THE
TIME THAT YOU HAVE BEEN THERE,
YOU HAVE MANAGED TO AT LEAST THE
TIME BEING DISSIPATE MOST OF THE
DANGEROUS INTEREST OF THE EVENTS
THAT TRANSPIRED THERE.
YOU HAVE MADE AN ARRANGEMENT
WITH THE GOBLIN OWNER OF THE
OVERCROW.
HOPEFULLY THINGS ARE OKAY FOR
THE TIME BEING.
YOUR MOORE BOUNDERS ARE KIND OF
PACING BECAUSE YOU DIDN’T FEED
THEM.
>> WE SHOULD HAVE BROUGHT THE
HORSE.
>> THEY CAN EAT THE HEADS.
>> OH, WOW.
>> THAT’S TRUE.
>> THERE IS A LOT OF MEAT ON THE
HEADS.
YEAH.
>> OKAY.
LET’S GO.
>> LET’S TALK TO THESE HEADS IN
THE HAPPY ROOM OR THE WAR ROOM.
>> YOU CAN’T DO IT UNTIL
TOMORROW.
>> YOU HAVE TO TRAVEL.
>> LET’S TAKE THE HEADS.
>> THAT’S WHY I EVEN RECOMMENDED
IT BECAUSE THIS IS DEFINITELY --
>> SADDLE UP, PARTNERS.
>> ALL RIGHT.
SO YOU GUYS GRAB YOUR EQUIPMENT,
THE THINGS THAT YOU NEED, --
>> DO WE HAVE FOOD FOR THE MORE
BOUNDERS HERE AT THE HOUSE?
>> HAVE YOU PURCHASED FOOD FOR
THEM?
>> NO, WE SHOULD SWING PAST
MORROWS ON THE WAY OUT OF THE
TOWN AND TAKE IT WITH US.
>> OKAY.
>> YES, OKAY.
>> YEAH.
>> SURE.
>> OKAY.
SO YOU MOUNT YOU HAVE YOUR MOORE
BOUNDERS, GATHER WHAT THINGS YOU
NEED AND START HEADING, TEARING
THROUGH THE NORTH ENDS OF THE
CITY.
BACK THROUGH THE VARIOUS
DISTRICTS, OUT SIDE IN TO THE
CORONAS HEADING OVER TOWARDS THE
OVERCROW APOTHECARY ONCE MORE.
RUNNING UP ON YOUR MORE BOUNDERS
YOU OPEN UP AND THE BUG BEAR IS
IN THE PROCESS OF TRYING TO PULL
THE HORSE’S CORPSE IN TO THE
DITCH AND SCRAPING THE FLOOR.
>> YOU ARE BACK.
>> ABOUT THAT WE THOUGHT WE
WOULD MAYBE TAKE THIS WITH US.
>> PLEASE, BY ALL MEANS.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE HOBB GOBLIN
BODY, TOO, THEY CAN EAT THAT
TOO.
>> FEAST YOU UP.
>> ANYBODY GOT ANY EXPERIENCE
BUTCHERING BODIES.
AS YOU ARE SAYING THIS, THE MORE
BOUNDERS ARE INNINGED THE SIDE
AND THE DOOR FRAME KIND OF
CRACKS AS IT PUSHES THROUGH.
MORROW WAS LIKE.
>> NOT THAT GUY, ONLY THIS
STUFF.
>> HAZE BEHIND THE DESK.
YOU HERE IT UP AGAINST THE WOOD
AS THE BUG BEAR IS NOW IN UP IN
TO THE CORNER.
AND YOUR MORE BOUNDER STARTS
TEARING IN TO THE CORPORATION OF
THE HOBB GOBLIN.
>> SAVE SOME FOR YOUR BROTHER
AND SISTER.
>> IT’S SPRAYING ACROSS THE
ROOM.
>> I AM GOING TAKE GIANNIS TO
THE BACK AND START TRYING TO
HOIST -- WOULD YOU HELP ME
PLEASE STRONG WOMAN.
>> AND START HOISTING THE HORSE
ON TO THE BACK OF YANIK AND TRY
HIM ON.
>> IT TAKES TIME, THERE IS TWO
OF YOU.
I SAY WITH A THIRD PERSON TALKED
IT.
>> I WILL HELPFUL BETWEEN THE
THREE OF YOU YOU ARE ABLE TO GET
THE HORSE UP ON TO THE BACK AND
TIE IT ONTO.
>> NEVER MIND, HE STILL HAS HIS
HEAD, NEVER MIND, KEEP GOING.
>> THERE IS A CURIOUS JUGGLE OF
LIMBS AND BODY PARTS YOU GUYS
HAVE GOING IN THIS RECENT
SESSION.
>> I AM JUST KEEPING JANIK CALM
AND KEEPING HIM FROM TRYING TO
EAT THE DRIVENNER CREATURE NOW.
>> LOOK AT ANIMAL HANDLING.
>> YEAH.
MY STREAK GOING.
NO.
11.
>> 11.
LOOKS BACK AT THE HORSE AND
SPINS AROUND AND JUST STARTS
DIGGING IN TO THE BODY OF THE
HORSE.
>> JUST A LITTLE BIT RIGHT NOW.
>> BIG TOOTHY TUSKS.
>> I CAN’T SAY MAD AT YOU.
>> LICKS ASIDE YOU OF YOU SMEARS
HORSE GUTS ACROSS YOUR FACE.
>> I SHOULDN’T LOVE IT, BUT I
DO.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> MORE BOUNDERS ARE BIG.
THEY ARE FAST AND THEY ARE
USEFUL.
THEY ARE ALSO NOT INEXPENSIVE TO
KEEP FED.
SO JUST THINGS TO KEEP IN MIND.
>> OKAY.
>> DO THEY HAVE TO EAT EVERY
DAY?
>> YEAH.
>> JUST LIKE US.
>> WELL, SOME ANIMALS CAN GO A
DAY OR TWO, NO?
>> THEY GET REAL HUNGRY IF THEY
DON’T, THOUGH.
>> OKAY.
>> ALL RIGHT.
SO LEAVING THE MOORE BOUNDERS TO
FINISH THEIR FEAST.
>> DOCUMENTDO YOU WANT TO TAKE -
HAVE BEEN HUNGRY SINCE YOU HAVE
BEEN OFF DOING BUSINESS THERE IS
NOT MUCH LEFT OF EITHER OF THE
CORPSES.
>> THE GREAT.
>> GOOD.
>> SO WE JUST LET THEM GO TO
TOWN IN THE BACK.
>> WHILE WE ARE DOING THAT MAYBE
YOU CAN IDENTIFY THAT SWORD.
>> SURE, GIVE IT TO ME PLEASE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> SPELL BOOK OUT.
>> I’LL GIVE IT TO YOU AT THE
BREAK BECAUSE I DON’T HAVE IT ON
ME.
IT’S IN THE BACK.
>> I’LL GET IT LATER ON.
>> OKAY.
>> YOU CAN ONLY HOPE IT’S AS
COOL AS THE HYPE SWORD.
>> THE SWORD OF AMBIVALENCE.
>> INDEED.
ALL RIGHT.
PICKING UP BACK ON THE ROAD YOU
MAKE YOUR WAY TO THE EXIT WALL.
EXIT PAST THE GUARDS THAT WAVE
YOU THROUGH WITH YOUR BADGES OF
THE QUEEN.
MAKING YOUR WAY IN TO THE GHOST
LANDS.
NOW, AT THIS POINT, IT’S EARLY
AFTERNOON.
SINCE YOU GUYS BEGAN THIS FRAY.
LIKE LATE MORNING.
TRAVELED BACK AND FORTH AND
GETTING EVERYTHING READY.
TAKING ABOUT THREE CLOCK IN THE
AFTERNOON.
>> Ashley: AS YOU EXIT IN TO THE
GHOST LANDS PUSHING FORWARD,
PASSING BY THE RUINS THE LOW FOG
THAT HANGS THROUGHOUT THESE
DESOLATE PLAINS THAT SURROUND
THE CITY.
UNTIL EVENTUALLY, IT GOES FROM
PITCH BLACK NIGHT AS IT’S BEEN
TO MIDDAY BRIGHTNESS.
HOT SUN ON YOU.
YOU ESCAPE FROM THE RADIUS OF
THE ENCHANTMENT THAT HOLDS
ETERNAL LIGHT OVER THE CAPITAL
OF THE DYNASTY IN TO A CLOUDED
SKY THAT HAS BROKE THEN SPOTS
AND YOU CAN SEE THERE ARE BEAMS
OF LIGHT THAT COME DOWN, THESE
KIND OF GOLD-SPECKLED SUN RAYS
THAT PEEK THROUGH WHICH IS BOTH
BEAUTIFUL AND STRANGELY OMINOUS
AS YOU LOOK I DON’T UNDERSTAND
THE GHOST LANDS TOWARDS THE GRAY
AND RED TINT OF THE BARBED
FIELDS.
AND THE REST OF THE DAY’S TRAVEL
BEFORE THEY -- THE PROPER SUNSET
COMES AROUND.
AND IT IS NICE TO SEE A SUNSET
AS IT’S BEEN SINCE YOUR JOURNEY
OUT TO THE MINE SINCE YOU HAVE
SEEN ONE, YOU MAKE IT BEYOND THE
COUNT ARE BOUNDARIES OF THE
GHOST LAP ASKS JUST ON THE CUSP
OF OVER THE WHERE THE BARB GO
AHEAD FIELDS BEGIN.
YOU ARE AT THE POINT WHERE THE
HOLLOWED PATH MAKES ITS WAY
AROUND BOTH SIDE OF THE VALLEY
AND THEN LOOKING FORWARD, YOU
CAN SEE BARON TREES THEIR
BRANCHES GNARLED AND TWISTED,
LEAFLESS.
YOU CAN SEE WHAT LOOKS TO BE
LARGE PORTIONS OF THE GROUND
THAT HAVE BEEN IN UP IN TO
JAGGED STONE WORK FROM HEAVY
IMPACTS FROM LONG AGO.
YOU CAN SEE HEAVY DARK PUDDLES
WHERE RAIN WATER HAS SEEPED IN
OVERTIME TO CREATE THESE KIND OF
ALL OF OIL-SLICK PUDDLES THAT
OCCASIONALLY KIND OF BUBBLE.
AND MOST OF THE GROUND HERE FROM
THE RECENT REYNA PEERS CRACKED.
LIKE AS IF IT WAS A DUSTY DESERT
FLOOR THAT SUDDENLY BEGAN TO
BREAK IN ONE INCH INCREMENTS IN
A LONG SHEET.
IT’S JUST THIS TEXTURED BROKEN
SURFACE.
OF VARYING BROWN, RED, RUDDY
COLOR.
>> WHILE WE ARE TRAVELING CAN A
TAKE A SHORT REST ON THE BACK OF
THE MOORE BOUNDERS?
>> I WOULD SAY TO TAKE A REAL
REST, LIKE YOU ARE EITHER RIDING
THE MOORE BOUNDER FORWARD AT THE
SPEED DO YOU WANT GET THERE AS
FAST AS POSSIBLE.
WHICH IS BOTH ACTIVE FOR YOU AND
THE MOORE BOUNDER OR STOPPING
AND TAKING A SHORT REST IS LIKE
SITTING ON, DRINK YOUR WATER, OR
YOU CAN TAKE THE MOORE BOUNDER
AT A SLOWER PACE FOR AN HOUR
WHICH WILL TAKE SOMETIME.
>> I WILL BE FINE.
>> WE’LL HAVE TO SLEEP
EVENTUALLY.
>> I WILL BE FINE.
>> I HAVE A QUESTION AS WELL.
>> YES.
>> DURING THIS DAY OF TRAVEL OR
IN THE LAST 30, ACCORDING TO MY
KEEN MIND, HAVE I SEEN ANY KINDS
OF BIRDS IN THIS LAND?
>> Matt: YEAH, YOU HAVE SEEN A
FEW BIRDS.
MOSTLY ONES ONES -- ONCE YOU HAV
LEFT THE CITY.
THERE ARE SOME THAT STAY IN
THERE BUT THEY ARE DARKER BIRDS.
>> WHAT ABOUT OUT HERE, OUTSIDE
THE CITY?
>> Matt: OUTSIDE OF THE CITY AND
THE GHOST LANDS NOT MANY.
IN THE -- YOU SAW MANY BIRDS AND
THERE WAS A VIBRANT KIND OF
ECOLOGICAL SYSTEM THAT LIVE IN
THAT FOREST.
>> ARE ARE THERE CROWS?
>> Matt: CROWS, RAVENS, ALL
SORTS OF SPARROWS AND OTHER
BIRDS THAT JUST CALL THE LAND
HOME.
AT THIS EDGE FROM THE GHOST
LANDS TO THE BARBED FIELDS.
VERY FEW IF ANY.
AND THE ONES THAT YOU HAVE SEEN
TENDS TOUR LARGER, BIRDS OF
PREY, OR SCAVENGERS.
>> OKAY.
>> Matt: MEANING THEY ARE PRETTY
SPARS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> IS THERE ANY OTHER WILDLIFE
OR CREATURES ROAM THAT GO WE
SEE?
ANY OTHER THREATS?
>> PERCEPTION CHECK.
>> THAT’S NOT GREAT.
10.
>> 10.
>> Matt: I MEAN, LOOKING AROUND
YOU SEASON SECONDS THAT CRAWL
AMONGST THE MUCK AND THE
CURRENTLY DRIED AND CRACKED
SURFACE OF THE EDGE OF THE
FIELDS.
OCCASIONALLY YOU SEE WHAT LOOKS
LIKE AN ARMADILLO BUT THE PACK
OF APPROXIMATE.
>> Taliesin: IS FOLDED ALMOST
LIKE PLATED HIDE THAT HAS SPINES
THAT STICK OUT THE SIDE AND
CRAWLS ITS WAY ACROSS BEFORE
CURLING UNDER A ROCK TO GET OUT
OF ONE OF THE HOT POINTS OF SUN
BEAMS PUSHING THROUGH THE REGION
AND SLOWLY BAKING THAT AREA OF
THE FIELD EDGE AS IT CRUISES
ACROSS.
>> TOTALLY CHER CHERNOBYL.
>> YEAH.
IS THERE ANYTHING THAT I WOULD
KNOW OR ANY STORIES THAT I HAVE
LETTER ABOUT THE BARBED FIELDS?
>> Marisha: TAKE A HISTORY
CHECK.
>> COME ON,.
>> 16.
>> OKAY.
>> Matt: WHAT YOU KNOW IS IT’S
CONSIDERED BY SOME PEOPLE ON THE
NORTHERN SIDE AS SACRED
TERRITORY.
SACRED IN THE SENSE THAT IT HAS
A LOT OF MEANING.
IT WAS A PLACE WHERE THE FINAL
BATTLES OF THE CALAMITY
HAPPENED.
AND THOSE WHO WASH   -- WHO ARE
EITHER OSTRACIZED OR GIVEN
SEVERE JUDGMENT BY THEIR CLAN OR
BY SOME OF THE CITIES BEFORE THE
DYNASTY GOT INVOLVE IN THEIR
DAY-TO-DAY LIFE WOULD BE SENT TO
THE FIELDS TO SURVIVE AS A MEANS
OF PROVING THEMSELVES AND
POSSIBLY WORKING THROUGH THE
INFRACTIONS THAT WERE PERCEIVED.
NOT MANY CAME BACK.
THOSE DID USUALLY SPOKE OF IT
BEING A HELL ESCAPE OF SURVIVE S
THE.
WHERE -- SURVIVAL.
WHERE NIGHTMARES WALK THE EARTH
AT NIGHT.
LAMB ROVING BEASTS -- LARGE
ROVING BEASTS GO OUT TO HUNT AND
SAVAGE AS WELL AS OTHER THINGS T
THOSE DAYS.
ENTITIES FROM PLAINS PARALLEL TO
THIS POP THROUGH OR REMAIN
HUNTING FOR WHATEVER SENSE OF
LIFE THEY CAN COME ACROSS, BUT
PEOPLE ALSO TRY TO CUT CORNERS
ESPECIALLY MESSENGERS, OR FOLKS
THAT ARE LOOKING TO STAY OUT OF
THE EYE LINE OF THE DYNASTY.
OUTSIDE OF ITS LAWS AS WELL.
NOMADS, PEOPLE THAT WISH TO ROB
FOLKS THAT USE THE EX-TEAR YOUR
HIGHWAY, WILL USUALLY STAY
AMONGST THE PERIMETER OR ON THE
OUTSKIRTS OF THE FIELDS WHERE
FEW DARE TO FOLLOW THEM TO
ARREST THEM.
OR HUNT THEM DOWN, ONE OF THE
TOUGHEST BOUNTY HUNTERS WANT TO
GO DEEP ENOUGH IN TO THE BARBED
FIELDS.
>> WOW.
>> LET ME RELAY SOME OF THIS
INFORMATION TO YOU GUYS WHEN I
WRITE.
>> I FEEL GOOD ABOUT OUR
CHOICES.
>> DO YOU THINK WE’LL BE OKAY IN
HERE?
>> YEAH.
>> WE DON’T DO ANYTHING TO
ATTRACT ATTENTION, WE KEEP A LOW
PROFILE.
WE’LL BE FINE.
>> HAVE YOU SEEN OUR POSSE?
LOOK AT US.
>> PRACTICALLY THE OPPOSITE.
>> THERE IS NOTHING AROUND HERE,
THOUGH.
>> EXACTLY.
>> MAKES US STICK OUT.
>> YEAH, BUT NOTHING IS HERE TO
SEE US.
>> WELL, --
>> CURRENTLY.
>> YEAH.
>> WE DON’T NEED TO WORRY ABOUT
DIPLOMACY.
>> HOUR WERE YOU DRY?
>> A FEW DAYS.
>> THAT’S GOOD FOR YOU.
>> Sam: FEW WEEKS, I CAN’T
REMEMBER.
>> I THINK IT’S JUST A FEW DAYS.
IS.
>> IS AT THAT SOMETHING THAT YOU
WERE TRYING DO OR TRYING NOT TO
DRINK?
>> Sam: JUST SEEMS NOT -- NO.
I DON’T KNOW.
I GUESS SO.
YEAH.
>> I AM SORRY.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK NOW,
BETTER, WORSE?
>> Sam: BETTER.
>> NOT AS SCARED?
>> Sam: LET’S GO.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> Matt: OKAY.
SO AS THE SUN IS SETTING.
YOU GUYS ARE HEADING IN TO THE
BARBED FIELDS FOR A BIT.
>> HELL, YEAH.
>> RIGHT AS THE SUN IS SETTING.
YES, THAT’S FINE.
>> OKAY.
>> AS YOU BEGIN LEAPING YOUR WAY
TOWARDS THE CENTER OF THE
FIELDS.
>> HOLD ON A MINUTE, DO YOU WANT
TO TELL THE OTHERS YOU WANT TO
STOP?
>> I AM FINE.
AS I KIND OF LIKE CLUTCH A
BROKEN RIB.
>> YOU KNOW, I AM NOT FEELING SO
WELL.
>> OH, NO.
>> I THINK I MIGHT NEED TO REST
HERE.
>> OKAY, LET’S ALL STOP.
>> I FELL.
>> YOU DID?
>> WAS IT WHEN I FELL ON NEW.
>> YES, BUT IT’S NOT YOUR FAULT.
I AM VERY --
>> I DIDN’T KNOW YOU WERE SEE
WEAK.
>> OF COURSE YOU DID.
>> I KNOW I, I AM SORRY I JUMPED
ON YOU.
MY APOLOGIES WORKS IT BE OKAY IF
WE STOPPED HERE.
>> I THINK THAT’S PROBABLY EYE
GOOD IDEA.
>> OF COURSE, KALEB, IF THAT’S
WHAT YOU NEED.
WE WILL REST AS SHORT A TIME AS
POSSIBLE AND HEAD OUT AS EARLY
AS POSSIBLE.
AND MAYBE NOT GO THROUGH THERE
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE -- WHAT
TIME IS IT NOW?
>> Matt: AT THIS POINT IT’S --
YOU ARE ABOUT 7:30, 8:00.
>> AT NIGHT.
MAYBE WE DON’T WANT TO GO
THROUGH THERE FOR THE FIRST TIME
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT.
I AM SORRY.
>> WE CAN LOCK IT DOWN HERE AND
LEAVE AT FIRST LIGHT.
>> SURE.
>> CAN YOU BUILD YOUR DOME
UNTIL.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> AS WE ARE -- THEY START THE
DOME AND I GET OFF THE BACK OF
JANIK, AND SAY, MAN, MAKE IT A
VULNERABILITY LOOKS SO EASY.
>> IT IS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> IS THERE ANY WAY TO TIME OF
OUR MOORE BOUNDERS ARE ARE THERE
TREES?
>> Matt: YEAH, THERE ARE LIKE A
LITTLE WAYS IN TO THE FIELD,
LIKE, YOU KNOW, A QUARTER MILE
OR SO YOU CAN SEE SOME TREES.
>> SOMETHING WITH A LITTLE
COVER.
>> OR WE CAN JUST LET THEM ROAM
AND HUNT AND MAYBE COME BACK.
>> MAYBE COME BACK.
>> THEY’LL COME BACK.
>> DO YOU THINK WE’LL COME FLAG.
>> COME BACK, SHANE.
>> THEY USUALLY COME BACK.
>> UNLESS THEY ARE GET EATEN.
>> OH, YOU ARE WORRIED ABOUT
THEM THE?
>> OH, BOY.
>> UNLESS WE ARE THERE TO KEEP
THEM SAFE.
>> YEAH, I’M GOING TO BURN A
LITTLE BIT ON GENT OF REPOSE TO
KEEP THE HEADS FROM GETTING
WEIRD.
>> FAIR ENOUGH.
>> OKAY.
>> WHAT DOES THAT DO?
>> TO KEEP THE HEADS FROM
GETTING WEIRD.
2019.
>> LIKE MELT EOYORE --
>> Y OR --
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> DOYLE, THE WIRE, AND FRUMPKIN
ON THE WIRE AND SUSIN SENSE TO
RESUMMON FRUMPKIN, AS WOULD YOU
ALLOW ME A VULTURE?
OR IS THAT TOO MUCH?
>> WHAT IS THIS?
>> OH, MAN, IF NOT I WILL GO
CROW.
>> I DON’T THINK IT WOULD BE AN
ISSUE YOU FEEL LET ME DOUBLE
CHECK.
>> IT COULD BE A SMALL VULTURE.
>> CHALLENGE ZERO.
>> YEAH, THAT WILL BE FINE, DO
YOU THINK THAT.
>> ONE DIRTY VULTURE SIT ON THIS
DOME.
>> SO AS YOU GUYS PREP AND BED
DOWN FOR THE NIGHT.
ARE YOU FEELING COMFY YOU WERE
THE DOME AND EVERYONE IS TAKE A
LONG REST TOGETHER.
>> A WIRE.
>> IN A DOME.
>> FRUMPKIN WILL MAKE WAKE ME UP
IF ANYTHING BAD HAPPENS.
>> FRUMPKIN IS JUST UP ON TOP
GETTING USED TO THE NEW FORM.
ALL RIGHT, YOU GUYS GO TO SLEEP
YOU COMPLETE YOUR LONG REST.
WITHOUT MUCH ISSUE.
YOU WAKE UP WITH THE MORNING
LIGHT ANOTHER WELCOMED SIGHT AS
IT’S BEEN A WHILE SINCE YOU HAVE
SEEN A DAWN.
STRANGELY MUGGY, WARM MORNING.
THE CLOUDS OF THE RECENT STORM
HAVE BROKE ABLE BIT AND YOU ARE
SEEING A BIT OF THE ACTUAL KIND
OF BLUE SKY PEEKING THROUGH.
AND IT’S A LITTLE UNCOMFORTABLE
FROM THE MORNING FROM THE
MORNING HEAT AS IT COMES DOWN
UNFILTERED ONTO THE BAKED FLOOR
OF THE FIELDS.
BUT YOU ALSO GET A GOOD VIEW AS
THE SUN GOES ACROSS AND YOU CAN
SEE IN THE DISTANCE THESE LARGE
KIND OF POINTED SPIRES THAT
LITTER THE DISTANCE ACROSS.
AND YOU GET A SENSE THIS MIGHT
BE WHERE SOME OF THE NAME COMES
FROM.
THERE ARE LARGE KIND OF ROCKY
ALMOST HOOKED IN SOME PLACES,
POINTED AND LIKE STRAIGHT IN
OTHERS SHAPED ON THE HORIZON OF
THE FIELD.
TOO FAR TO MAKE OUT MUCH DETAIL
BUT YOU CAN JUST BARELY SEE THEM
ACROSS THE HORIZON.
>> AWESOME.
>> HOW IS EVERYBODY FEELING?
>> GREAT.
>> I DON’T KNOW.
>> DO YOU NEED TO -- I MEAN, ARE
WE JUST GOING TO GO STRAIGHT TO
THAT TOWN?
YOU DON’T HAVE TO MESSAGE HIM
AGAIN OR ANYTHING?
>> UNLESS YOU WANTED TO THROW
HIM OFF THE SCENT.
TELL HIM DON’T COME BACK, YOU
HERE.
>> GEE WHIZ THAT WOULD HAVE NICE
TO BE FOR YOU GUYS TO DO IT LAST
NIGHT SO WE ARE NOT VENTURING IN
TO THIS DAY --
>> OR WE COULD MESSAGE MARROW
AND ASK IF ANYONE ELSE SHOWED UP
YESTERDAY.
>> YEAH, I WILL BE SURE TO DO
THAT AT THE END.
DAY TODAY IF I DON’T USE UP ALL
MY STEALTH.
GEE QUIZ ARE WHIZ, YOU GUYS WHAT
IF WE NEED ME TO GO FOR
SOMETHING.
>> GOSH.
>> USE THE SPELLS TELEPHONED THE
DAY.
>> OKAY, FINE END.
>> ARE WE TALKING TO THE HEADS
THIS MORNING?
>> AT THE END OF THE DAY.
>> AT THE END.
DAY.
>> AT THE ETCHED DAY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> SEEMS BREW AT THE PRESENT
TIME DO IT TELEPHONED DAY.
>> WHAT IF YOU USE YOUR SPELL
AND YOU CAN’T DO IT AT THE END
DATE.
>> IF EYE USE MY SPELL I AM GLAD
I DIDN’T TALK TO THEM TELLS DAY
TO GET TO THE POINT TO TALK TO
THEM AT THE END OF DAY.
>> I’LL FOLLOW CRASHER.
>> WHAT IF THEY HAVE IMPORTANT
INFORMATION.
>> JUST KEEP TALKING AND WE’LL
SEE YOU ACROSS THE WAY.
>> ARE YOU GET ON THIS MOORE
BOUNDERS.
>> NO, WE ARE JUST WALKING.
>> MAYBE WE SHOULD.
LET’S GET ACTION ON HERE.
>> I AM STILL PICKING MY SPELLS
FOR THE DAY.
>> I DO SOME PUSH UPS TO MAKE
MYSELF FEEL USEFUL.
WHILE SPELL CASTERS PICK SPELLS.
>> Marisha: THERE ARE A HANDFUL
OF EMPTY SHELLED PLATED BACKS
FROM THE SIMILAR LIKE ARMADILLO
LIKE CREATURES THAT YOU SAW
BEFORE.
BUT THEY HAVE BEEN FRESHLY
CLEARED OUT BY YOUR MOORE
BOUNDERS, THEY ARE JUST KIND OF
STREWN ABOUT ABOUT EIGHT OF THEM
IN THE VICINITY.
YOU CAN SEE A LITTLE BIT OF LIKE
SMEAR ON THE FRONT OF THEIR FACE
THEY HAVE BEEN HUNTING AND
EATING WHILE YOU WERE SLEEPING
AND AS YOU KIND OF CONSCIOUSNESS
THEY ARE RESTED ON THE OUTSIDE
OF THE DOME CURLED UP AND WAKING
UP SOUPS YOU GUYS START MAKING
NOISE AND MOVING AROUND.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ]
DOESN’T APPEAR TO BE, NO.
A FAIRLY SAFE NIGHT.
>> ALL RIGHT.
ANYTHING YOU WANT TO DO BEFORE
YOU START CONTINUING YOUR PATH.
>> I HAVE PICKED MY SPELLS SO I
AM TAKING JANIK FOR A RUN AROUND
AND PRIME FOR THE DAY.
ABOUT A QUARTER MILE OUT FROM
THE DOME.
NO, THE DOME IS GONE.
>> Marisha: IT’S GONE NOW.
>> Matt: YOU ARE TAKING HIM FOR
A RUN.
>> I WILL MAKE FOOT FOR
EVERYBODY.
>> AND I’LL KEEP WATCH WHILE
THIS IS HAPPENING SINCE WE ARE
DOMELESS.
>> LAST KNAT 20.
>> Matt: OH, NICE.
>> 22.
>> Matt: OKAY.
LOOKING A OFF TO THE PATH AHEAD
OF YOU, YOU BEGIN TO SEE THERE
ARE POCKETS THAT ARE SAFER THAT
OTHERS, AREAS WHERE THAT KIND OF
WHERE THAT THICK TAR SLUDGE
SEEMS TO POOL AND SPREAD ACROSS
AREAS AND YOU BEGIN TO MENTALLY
TAKE NOTE OF WHAT SEEMS TO BE
THE MOST VIABLE PATHS THROUGH
THAT PATCH.
YOU CAN ALSO SEE WHAT HASES LIKE
LARGE CRATERS AREAS OF LAND
WHERE IT SEEMS TO DROP OFF IN TO
THESE HEAVY PITS.
YOU DO NOTICE A FEWELL.
S ON THE PATHED OF YOU TO MAKE
IT A SAFER JOURNEY.
>> THE THAT RAIN AHEAD IS GOING
TO BE GONE SO, MIGHT HAVE TO
MOVE AT A THREE QUARTER PACE
INSTEAD A DEAD SPRINT.
>> DO YOU THINK THAT BLACK
SLUDGY SHIT WILL HURT NEW.
>> I MEAN, IT’S A FAIR BET.
I DON’T KNOW WHAT IT IS.
THERE ARE WHOLE POCKETS OF EARTH
AND AREA THAT ARE JUST GONE.
>> BOTTOMLESS PITS.
>> YOUR GUESS IS AS GOOD AS
MINE.
>> THIS IS WHERE THE WARS
HAPPENED LONG AGO?
>> I UNDERSTAND IT, YEAH.
>> SHE SAID THE FINAL BATTLE.
>> DANG.
>> YEAH.
LEFT SOME POCKMARKS.
>> WELL, --
>> WE ARE ALL GOOD.
WE GOT FOOD.
>> ENOUGH FOR THE MORE BOUNDERS
AS WELL.
>> THEY ARE NOT GOING LIKE IT.
BUT IT’S -- YEAH.
SUSTAIN UP TO 15 HUMAN OIDS AND
FIVE STREETS FOR 24 HOURS, PLUS
WATER.
>> JESUS, THAT’S AWESOME.
>> THIS IS YOUR TOFU JELLY.
BONE A BALLS.
>> 15 HUMAN OIDS OR FIVE CITIES.
OR FIVE CITIES.
>> 15 HUMANOIDS YOU CAN FEED --
>> MOUNT MEANTIME I HAVE THIS
JAR OF BEADS THAT WOULD FEED US.
>> ONE ANIMAL.
>> YOU CAN ALMOST FEED ALL THE
MOORE BOUNDERS YOU CAN FEED YOU
GUYS AND 1 1/2 MOORE BOUNDERS,.
>> THEY SEEM TO BE EATING WELL.
ALL THE FOOD IS FINE.
>> LET’S GO, THIS FUCK FACE IS
GETTING AWAY FROM US.
>> YEAH, YEAH.
>> YEAH.
>> DON’T YOU YEAH MY --
>> CAN ANYONE SEARCH FOR TRACKS
AS WE GO?
ANYONE WHO YASHA KNOWS THE AREA
OR --
>> I AM KEEPING AN EYE OUT FOR
THINGS.
>> Matt: WHO WANTS TO LOOK FOR
TRACKS.
>> I WILL LOOK.
THEY MOVED THROUGH HERE MAYBE IF
THEY TOOK THIS ROUTE.
>> THEY PROBABLY TOOK THE SAFE
ROUTE.
>> I WILL LOOK.
>> Matt: KALEB AND WHO ELSE?
>> I WILL LOOK, SURE.
>> Matt: YOU MAKE SURVIVE THE
CHECKS PLEASE.
>> 18.
>> Matt: 18, OKAY.
YOU HAVE -- THIS TERRAIN IS VERY
ALIEN TO YOU AND YOU HAVE NO
IDEA HOW TO LOOK AT PATTERN AS
CROSS IT, AT ALL.
YOU ARE FLUSTERED BY IT.
JESTER LOOKING’D, LOOKING AROUND
TRACKS.
SOMETHING OF THEM LOOK LIKE
SMALL CREATURES, SOME OF THEM
LOOK LIKE LARGE CREATURES.
SOME OF THEM LOOK HUMANOID AND
OLDER, BUT NOTHING -- YOU HAVE
NO DISCERNING WAY OF KNOWING
WHAT TRACKS MAYBE THE INDIVIDUAL
YOU HAVE BEEN SEEKING OR NOT.
THEY ARE ALL SORTS OF MATTER OF
TRACKED AROUND.
>> YOU LOTS OF FOOT PRINTS AND
STUFF.
>> OKAY.
>> Matt: KEEPING’ EYE OUT FOR
ANYTHING UNUSUAL.
>> WE ARE NOT ON A TRAIL PER SE
IT’S OPEN.
>> Matt: IT’S OPEN TO THIS
POINT, NO SET TRAILS HERE.
>> 26.
>> Matt: 26, GOOD TO KNOW.
OKAY.
SO PROGRESSING FORWARD.
, ONE HOUR, TWO HOURS, THE SHEET
BEGINS TO COOL A BIT.
THE THE CLOUDS BEGIN TO CLOSE
BACK IN.
THE BRIGHT SUN LINE THAT WAS
PEERING THROUGH BEGINS TO VANISH
UNDER THE FAMILIAR GRAY SKIES.
FOLLOWING FJORD’S LEAD YOU
MANAGE TO MOVE AROUND SOME TAR
POCKETS AND AS YOU GO BY, THEY
ARE A DARK, DEEP, BROWN-GREEN
COLOR AND AS YOU APPROACH, THERE
IS STILL NOTHING SEEMS TO --
THERE IS NO WIND WHERE YOU ARE
CURRENTLY, AND IT’S JUST KIND OF
A SLICK, ALMOST REFLECTIVE
SURFACE.
JUST KIND OF MANEUVER THROUGH
THE PATCHES OF IT.
YOU GO PAST ONE OF THESE LARGER
PITS AND YOU CAN SEE WHAT LOOK
TO BE LIKE A GRAY ISH MOUND IN
THE CENTER OF IT.
ABOUT FIVE FEET ACROSS, YOU
MANEUVER AROUND PAST THAT.
>> IS IT A BEING THAT GOT STUCK?
>> Matt: PERCEPTION.
>> IS IT MOVING AT ALL?
>> 7.
>> Matt: HARD TO TELL.
BUILDING YOU -- I WILL SAY WITH
YOUR PERCEPTION CHECK YOU HAD
EARLIER, A GENERAL LOOK, IT
LOOKS LIKE BONE.
AND THAT MAYBE A CREATURE THAT
GOT CAUGHT AND DID NOT ESCAPE.
THE ELEMENTS THAT REMIND YOU OF
TAR.
EXCEPT FOR THE COLORATION.
>> RIGHT.
YOU NEED SAMPLE OF THIS FOR ANY
REASON.
>> Matt: GROUND-GREEN KIND OF AT
CERTAIN ANGLES AND BITS OF LIGHT
IT SHIFTS FROM ONE TO THE OTHER.
>> OKAY.
>> Matt: OKAY.
CONTINUE ON.
A FEW MORE HOURS.
YOU BEGIN TO NOW APPROACH THE
LARGE SPIRES THAT YOU HAD SEEN
ON THE HORIZON BEFORE.
SOME OF THESE ARE BITS OF DARK
ROCK.
THAT DON’T MATCH THE BROWN AND
RED FLOOR OF THIS WIDE
BATTLINGS.
IT’S LIKE A DEEP, DARK GRAY,
THEY ARE RANGING ANYWHERE
BETWEEN 15 TO 40 FEET TALL.
AND THEY ARE THIN AND THEY ARE
JUST JUT OUT OF THE GROUND LIKE
THEY WERE PLACED THERE.
ON ARE PUSHED OUT FROM
UNDERNEATH.
YOU DID BRIEF ENCOUNTER THE
RANGE WHEN YOU WERE GOING
TOWARDS THE STONE GIANT’S FORD
AND THE COLORATION AND TEXTURE
OF THIS ROCK SEEMS SIMILAR.
SO THIS ROCK SEEMS TO BE OF THE
SAME ROCK THAT MOUNTAIN RANGE IS
MAILED OF.
BUT THEY DO NOT -- THEY SEEM
LIBERALLY PLACE AND THE THEY ARE
MASSIVE SIZE AND SOME OF THEM
BEING MOVED TO A POINT.
IT’S JUST CURIOUS AND UNNATURAL
FEEL FOR TO THEIR PLACEMENT.
>> SEEMINGLY RANDOM PLACEMENT?
>> Matt: YEP.
>> YEAH.
>> Matt: YOU COME ACROSS TWO AND
KEEP A WIDE BERTH.
THE FIRST TIME YOU CAME UP
NEARBY IS 20 FEET TALL JUST
STRAIGHT STICKING OUT OF THE
GROUND.
>> IS THERE ANY RESEMBLANCE TO
BONES THEMSELVES?
LARGE BONES?
>> Matt: DO YOU WANT TO TAKE A
LOOK?
>> I WILL SEND FRUMPKIN TO LAND
ON TOP OF ONE.
>> Matt: OKAY.
>> AND TAKE A LOOK.
SO YOU ARE LOOKING IN FRUMPKIN’S
EYES.
ROLL A MEDICINE CHECK.
>> MEDICINE CHECK.
OOH.
22.
>> Matt: 22.
BEST YOU CAN TELL, THESE DON’T
APPEAR TO BE BONE.
YOU ARE JUST NOT -- THESE ARE
NOT -- YOU KNOW, NATURAL FROM A
CREATURE’S BODY.
THEY ARE LARGE STRUCTURES MADE
OF STONE.
YOU JUST HAVE NO IDEA OF WHOM OR
WHERE OR HOW OLD THESE MAY BE.
>> AND THEY ARE POINTED AND
JAGGED?
>> Matt: RANDOM DIRECTIONS .
>> THERE ARE NO ETCHES OR GIVES
ON THEM?
>> Matt: NO.
>> YOU GO AHEAD.
>> 15 TO 40 FEET TALL?
>> Matt: YES.
>> LIKE TONS OF THEM LIKE
FORTRESS OF SOLITUDE?
>> Matt: NO, YOU COME ACROSS ONE
EVERY MILE OR SO.
>> OH, OKAY.
THAT’S COOLER.
>> Matt: SOME POINT YOU COME
ACROSS TWO OR THREE WITHIN A
MILE.
SOMETIMES YOU GO A CHECK OF FIVE
THEY ARE RANDOMLY DISTRIBUTED
AND DIFFERENT SIZES AND ANGLES
THEY ARE PLACED ACROSS FIELDS.
>> I WONDER IF YOU FLY UP REALLY
HIGH IF YOU WOULD SEE A PAT
THEN.
>> MAYBE.
>> THAT’S A GOOD IDEA.
>> Liam: I WAS GOING TO ASK DID
THEY WILL BE LIKE THEY WERE
ERUPTED UP OR JUST BEEN HERE TOO
THONG TELL?
>> Matt: MAKE AN INTELLIGENCE
CHECK.
>> 21.
>> Matt: 21.
THESE HAVE BEEN HERE LONG ENOUGH
WHERE THERE IS NO WAY OF
KNOWING.
>> WOW.
>> Matt: THE EARTH THAT’S BEEN
AROUND THEM HAS -- IT’S A
COMBINATION OF JUST GATHER
THROUGH WIND AND DUST THAT HAS
CAUSED A SLIGHT, YOU KNOW,
GATHERING AROUND THE EXTERIOR OF
THE BASE, BUT NO SIGN OF ROCK
ERUPTED AROUND IT FROM A RECENT
IMPACT OR COMPARATIVELY IN
TRACKS THAT SHOW, THEY HAVE BEEN
THERE LONG ENOUGH WHERE THEY ARE
MERGED WITH THE SCENERY.
YOU ARE NOT ABLE TO ASCERTAIN
THE DIRECTION IN WHICH THEY
ARRIVED.
>> MUST BE AT A HALT SINCE WE
ARE THE ONLY ONE WHO CAN RIDE
THESE THINGS AND TRAINING THEM
SO SHE CALLED THAT OUT SO I WILL
SENT FRUMPKIN SPIRAL UP QUITE
HIGH TO LOOK DOWN.
THIS WILL PROBABLY TAKE A FEW
MINUTES.
>> Matt: OKAY.
>> Liam: LIKE A MILE IN TO THE
AREA.
>> Matt: OKAY.
FROM TIME TO TIME KIN GOES A
MILE IN TO THE AIR AND LOOKS
DOWN AND SEES FROM HIS POSITION
OF SEVEN OR SO, WITHIN SIGHT.
>> Liam: THEY DON’T CREATE A BIG
SMILEY FACE FROM UP ABOVE?
>> Matt: NOT FROM HIS
PERSPECTIVE, NO.
>> A BIG DICK.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Liam: NO PATENT,.
>> IS IT A BARB FIELDS.
>> THESE ARE THE BARBS.
>> Matt: I WILL ALSO SAY THAT IF
THEY WERE TO DROP FROM THE SKY
OR SPRUNG FROM THE EARTH WHAT,
DO THEY SPRING FROM?
MIGHT BE SOMETHING UNDERNEATH
THEM BUT THAT WOULD P --
>> TERRIBLE AND HORRIBLE.
>> Matt: A LOT TO TAKE CARE OF.
>> IT’S SO OLD IT’S PROBABLY
DEAD BY NOW ANYWAY.
>> Matt: MAKE A HISTORY CHECK.
>> OH, NO.
>> ARE YOU GOING ROLL LUCK?
>> IT’S A SPELL.
12.
SO YOU HAVE TO HAVE IT PRECAST.
>> Matt: 15.
NOTHING IS RINGING A BELL FOR
EITHER OF YOU GUYS
UNFORTUNATELY.
>> BUMMER.
>> Matt: THAT’S ALREADY.
>> ROLLED A TWO IN, WHAT ARE YOU
GOING?
>> Matt: WHAT YOU ARE YOU GOING
TO DO.
YOU CONTINUE TO PRESS ON DEEPER
IN TO THE BARBED FIELDS YOUR
FIRST FULL DAY OF TRAVEL.
NORTHWARD, HOURS GO BY, THE SUN
BEHIND THE CLOUDS, YOU CAN FEEL
THE TEMPERATURE GETTING COOLER
AND COOL ARE HE CAN EVENTUALLY
THE LIGHT BEGINS TO GROW DARKER
AND DARKER AS IT GETS CLOSER TO
DUSK.
PASSING BY -- WHAT ARE YOU
LAUGHING ABOUT?
>> NOTHING I AM GOOD.
>> A DOODLE.
IT’S PROBABLY LEWD.
>> PROBLEMATIC.
>> Matt: PUSH AGOPUSHING ONWARD,
BEGIN TO -- I TOTALLY LOST MY
TRAIN OF THOUGHT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Matt: IT’S BEEN A WEEK.
>> IT’S BEEN A WEEK.
>> Matt: ANYWAY.
>> I AM THROWING UP MAJOR ARMER
AND GIVING THE GIFT OF ALACRITY
TO BOW RAH GUARD.
>> IS THAT THAT THING?
>> Matt: SO AFTER KALEB CASTS
MAJOR ARMOR ON HIMSELF AND
REACHES OVER AND TOUCHES YOUR
SHOULDER THERE IS THIS SLIGHT
GATHERING OF DARK ENERGY THAT
SWIRLS AROUND HIS HAND AND THESE
TYPY LITTLE SPECS OF LIGHT THAT
BLINK THROUGH IT AS IT REACHES
OVER AND GRABS YOUR SHOULDER YOU
FEEL THIS BRIEF SURGE THROUGH
YOUR BODY AND FOR A SECOND
EVERYTHING GOES IN TO SLOW
MOTION AND REVERTS TO NORMAL.
>> THAT SHIT IS ALMOST
UNSETTLING IF IT WASN’T SO DOPE.
>> Liam: PAR FOR THE COURSE I
JUST INVENTED GOLF CANNON.
[ LAUGHTER ]
I HATE YOU ALL.
>> THE MASTERS COURSE OUT HERE
ON THE BARBED FIELD.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> AT THE PAR 9.
>> WE HAVE ALL LAND -- BAD LUCK
WE HAVE ALL LANDED IN A TAR PIT.
>> THAT AN EXTRA PENALTY.
>> Matt: CONTINUE TO PASS BY
CLUSTERS OF LEAFLESS TREES.
SOME ARE COMPLETELY BROKEN IN
THE CENTER, BURNED, CHARCOAL,
SOME JUST APPEAR TO BE
PEDESTRIAN IDENTIFIED OVERTIME.
IT’S LIKE WALKING THROUGH A
GRAVEYARD OF NATURE AT DIFFERENT
PLACES OCCASIONALLY YOU HEAR
DIFFERENT BIRDS THAT HAVE COME
OUT THIS FAR.
LARGELY SCAVENGING WISHES
VULTURE SIMILAR TO WHAT YOU HAVE
GIVEN A FORM.
YOU GET THROUGH ONE SESSION OF
BROKEN TREES AND A LARGE CHUNK
OF RUIN.
-- WHO IS AT FRONT?
\h-- WHO IS AT FRONT?
>> ME.
WE WERE CHECKING FOR -- WE MADE
IT FOR THE BARBS.
MY 20 PROBABLY WORE OFF.
>> Matt: WHO IS IN THE FRONT?
>>  I’LL BE WITH YOU JESTER.
YOU HAVE AT THE FRONT OF MOORE
BOUNDER YOU ARE MOVING THROUGH
THE AREA LEAPING QUICKLY BEFORE
YOUR MOUNT SUDDENLY KIND OF
STOPS FOR A SECOND..
>> WHAT IS IT, WHAT DO YOU
SMELL?
>> Matt: AND YOU CAN SEE THERE
IS A PERSON SITTING NEXT TOO ONE
OF THE TREES FACING AWAY FROM
YOU.
JUST KIND OF LEANING UP AGAINST
IT.
>> CALEB KILL THEM.
>> WHY ON DO WE WANT TO DO THAT,
WE DON’T KNOW ANYTHING.
>> Matt: EYES OF THE GRAVE.
OKAY.
NOTHING.
NOTHING CATCHES YOUR INTEREST.
>> COOL.
>> SHOULD WE CALL OUT TO THEM?
WHAT DO THEY -- WHAT DO THEY
LOOK LIKE --
>> Matt: PERCEPTION -- MAKE A
PERCEPTION CHECK.
>> OKAY.
8.
>> Matt: 8 IT’S HARD TO SEE
SINCE THE SUN IS GETTING CLOSE
TO SETTING AND THERE ARE NOW
LONG SHADOWS STRETCHING ACROSS
THE FIELD FROM WHAT YOU CAN SEE
KIND OF A PALE PERSON.
JUST KIND OF LEAN AGO WAY FROM
YOU, AGAINST THE TREE.
>> IN THE SHADE OR IS THERE
STILL LEAFLESS TREES?
>> Matt: LEAVELESS TREES.
>> THERE IS ONLY ONE OF THEM,
COME OFF.
AND THERE IS ALL OF US.
>> I AM LOOKING ALL AROUND.
>> THIS FEELS LIKE A HONEY POT.
>> I AM GETTING OFF THE MOORE
BOUNDER AND JUST SORT OF FLANK
RIGHT.
>> Matt: OKAY.
>> WEAPON DRAWN.
>> SHOULD I JUST CALL OUT THIS
THEM.
>> NOT YET.
>> CAN I SEND THEM A MESSAGE?
>> I AM GOING JUMP OFF THE MAR
BOUNDER JUST IN CASE.
>> Matt: OKAY.
>> WHAT IF I SEND MY BIRD TO
LOOK IN THAT TREE AND GET A
CLOSER LOOK.
>> THERE IS NOTHING FOR A VERY
LONG TIME THEY HAVE PROBABLY
HEARD US COME ARE COMING UP.
>> THAT PEEKS ME OUT.
>> MAYBE HE’S DEAD.
>> SEND TRUMP KIP OFF TO SEE IT
IN THE TREE.
>> YOU DON’T GET AN UNDEAD
PRESENCE.
>> Matt: THUMB KIN LANDS ON THE
BRANCH AND LOOKS DOWN, ARE YOU
LOOKING THROUGH HIS EYES?
>> YES.
>> Matt: YOU SEE WHAT LOOKS TO
BE A HUMANOID, KIND OF A PALE
GRAY SKIN NO HAIR.
>> Liam: BREATHING, SEEMINGLY
ALIVE?
>> Matt: MAKE A PERCEPTION
CHECK.
>> I WILL USE THIS DIE THAT HAS
BEEN FUCKING WITH ME.
>> DOES THE FUCKING CONTINUE?
>> I THINK SO.
>> 14.
>> Matt: HE APPEARS TO BE
BREATHE THE.
>> ARE HIS EYES OPEN OR CLOSED?
MA I CAN’T TELL.
>> DOES HE HAVE A MUSCULAR
BEARD.
>> ZONED OUT OR --
>> PLUS COULD YOU OR FIGURE ORIE
MACE 80 AND SLIM.
>> Marisha: IT’S LOOKS SLIPPER,
IT’S TARRED TO TELL YOU ARE 70
OR SO FEET FROM THAT FIGURE.
>> Liam: I AM GOING FROM THE
PRESEVENS THINKING HE’S DEAD
SEND FRUMPKIN TO GET SOME MINI
STEPS CLOSER.
>> HE’S LOOKING AT FOOD.
>> Matt: AS FRUMPKIN LANDS AND
LOOKS FORWARD THE FIGURE IS
STANDING THERE KIND OF LEGS
CROSSED THE PALE GRAY BODY
ITSELF, YOU CAN SEE KIND OF THE
SKIN PULLED TIGHT AGAINST THE
RIB CAGE.
>> RESISTENCE.
>> OKAY.
>> JUST CASTING RESISTENCE.
>> Matt: OKAY.
THE CREATURE’S YEAH IS OPEN A
BIT.
ITS EYES ARE CLOUDED OVER AND
WHITE.
YOU CAN SEE LIKE LAYERS OF
BROKEN JAGGED TEETH ON BOTH
SIDES OF ITS MOUTH.
IT’S --
>> Liam: FRUMPKIN JUST SQUAWKS
LOUDLY.
>> Matt: IT LOOKS UP AT IT.
THE.
>> TKHAOEPBGD.
>> Matt: IT LOOKS BACK OVER
TOWARDS YOU GUYS.
IS STANDS UP AND BRINGS ITS ARM
UP AGAINST THE TREE THE FOREARM
EXTENDS IN TO THIS LONG KIND OF
HOOKED POINT.
>> OH, MY GOD M.
>> Matt: IT GETS UP AND TURNS
AROUND.
AND YOU CAN NOW SEE ITS OTHER
ARM IS THE SAME AND THERE IS A
THIRD ARM COMING OUT OF ITS
STOMACH.
THAT ALSO COMES TO THIS POINTS
AND LOOKS TO YOU ALL AND KIND OF
AHHHH.
>> NO.
>> Matt: GIVES THIS LIKE LOW
MOURNFUL --
>> WHAT THE FUCK.
>> Matt: JUST WHALE.
AHHH.
[ SCREAMING ]
>> Matt: AND WE ARE GOING TAKE A
BREAK ON THAT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I DON’T LIKE IT WHEN YOU DO
THAT.
>> I KNEW IT.
I KNEW IT.
I KNEW IT WAS GOING TO BE 28
DAYS LATER.
>> THAT’S SO SCARY.
>> NO.
>> Matt: WELCOME BACK HERE.
IN JUST A FEW MINUTES TO PICK UP
FOR FROM ENCOUNTER.
>> NO.
>> CAN YOU HOLD THE BREAK WHILE
I FIND THE SWORD PAPER.
>> Matt: THAT’S WHAT I AM
GETTING NOW THE NOW.
>> I AM GOING TO THROW UP.
>> Matt: WE’LL CONSIDER IF IT’S
ANYTHING USEFUL.
ANYWAY, BACK IN EYE A FEW
MINUTES BEFORE WE HAVE DOE THAT
WE HAVE OUR GIVE AWAY FROM WORM
WOOD RIGHT HERE.
THIS IS THE -- YOU MAY RECOGNIZE
FROM CAMPAIGN ONE.
MADE FAMOUS BY THE SHORT HALT.
DICE TRAY IT’S SO PRETTY.
WITH WEATHER INTERIOR FROM OUR
FRIEND THE WORM WOOD THE CODE
WORD FOR TONIGHT’S GIVE AWAY IS
GENEROSITY.
>> OH.
>> Matt: SO GO AHEAD AND PUT IN
THE WORD GENEROSITY IN TO THE
CHAT ONCE, MORE THAN ONCE AND
YOU ARE DISQUALIFIED THIS IS FOR
THE U.S. AND CANADA AND QUEBEC,
WE’LL COME BACK AT THE BREAK
WITH A WINNERS AND WE’LL SEE YOU
GUYS IN A FEW MINUTES.
>> HAPPEN HAPPY RED NOSE DAY.
♪
♪ MUSIC PLAYING ♪
THIS WILL AIR FRIDAY MAY 31st.
IF YOU MISS THE LIVE BROADCAST.
THE VIDEO WILL BE AVAILABLE
IMMEDIATELY TO SUBDESCRIBERS OR
YOU CAN CATCH THE IT
TUBE.COM/CRITICALROLE SUNDAY
MORNING JUNE 2nd THINK.
I’LL SEE YOU THERE, EVERY PONY.
♪ MUSIC PLAYING ♪
>> HEY, EVERYBODY.
>> HAPPY RED NOSE DAY, WE WANT
TO SAY THANK YOU FOR THE FOLKS
SUPPORTING RED NOSE DAY AND THE
INCREDIBLE MISSION TO FIGHT
CHILDHOOD POVERTY.
IT’S BEEN INCREDIBLE.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH AND OF
COURSE THANKS TO STEPHEN COLBERT
FOR MAKING THE STEVEN MINI
ADVENTURE HAPPEN.
IT WAS SUCH A DELIGHTFUL AND
INCREDIBLE EXPERIENCE.
>> Matt: WE ARE STILL PROCESSING
IT.
>> WE ARE SO GLAD THAT WE GOT TO
TAKE YOU ALL WITH US ON THAT
CRAZY JOURNEY.
>> Matt: DEFINITELY.
AND DON’T FORGET, YOU CAN STILL
DONATE TO RED NOSE DAY AND HELP
BRING AN END TO CHILDHOOD
POVERTY AT CRITROLE.COM CLASH
RED NOSE DAY.
>> THAT’S RIGHT.
CRITROLE.COM/REDNOSEDAY.
>> DO IT FOR ERIC!
LOVE YOU GUYS.
>> BYE.
>>> ARE LAT TIME.
>> ARE WE ON THE INTERNET?
>> WE SURE TRY BRIAN.
NO.
TOP THE MIGHTY NINE GET UNNERVED
BY THE QUEEN AND LET THEIR
TARGET SLIP WAY, WE’LL BREAK IT
ALL DOWN WITH MY GUESTS SAM
REGAL, AND LIAM O’BRIEN.
ALL THAT AND MORE ON TONIGHT’S
TALKS MACHINA.
>> JAY IF YOU WANT TO KNOW THE
QUESTION THAT EVERYBODY IS
ASKING US THIS WEEK AFTER LAST
WEEK’S EVENT IS WHEN CAN EXPECT
FRUMPKIN TO BECOME A HORSE AS AN
APOLOGY FOR THE FANS .
>> I KNEW IT.
I NEED AN APOLOGY TO MYSELF.
THAT DID NOT FEEL GOOD.
I DID NOT KILL THE HORSE ON
PURPOSE.
I MEANT TO HURT IT.
AND GET IT THE HELL OUT OF THE
WAY.
>> JUST SAY THAT ONE MORE TIME
AS A COMPLETE SENTENCE TO
CAMERA.
I LIAM O’BRIEN PURPOSELY KILLED
AN ANIMAL.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> THAT WOULD HELP MY CAMPANA
LOT.
>> IF YOU COULD JUST REPEAT.
>> AS YOUR ATTORNEY I ADVISE NOW
THE TO LISTEN TO THAT MAN.
>> I LOVE ANIMALS, DO YOU KNOW
HOW MANY TIMES I HAVE GOTTEN
DOWN AND CUDDLED AND PET HEN
WRIT DOG.
DO YOU KNOW HOW MANY TIMES SAM
HAS PET HENRY THE DOG?
>> Sam: NEVER.
YOU HAVE NEVER TOUCH THAT’S DOG,
YOU KNOW WHY?
>> Sam: GERMS.
>> Liam: GERMS.
>> Sam: I DON’T WANT ANIMAL
GERMS.
>> Liam: YOU HAVE KIDS, KIDS ARE
A DISEASE.
PETRY DISH.
>> NOT GERMS FROM THE DOG.
GERMS FROM YOU, BRIAN BEING I
KNOW THAT YOU PET THAT DOG MORE
THAN ANYONE.
I DON’T WANT YOUR WHATEVER YOU
HAVE GOT SYPHILIS ON YOUR HANDS
TO TRANSFER SOMEHOW TO MY
PRECIOUS --
>> THE ONLY THING I WANT TO GET
TO TONIGHT I AM DONE WITH
QUESTIONS FOR YOU.
COSPLAY OF THE WEEK.
>> YES!
>> COSPLAY OF THE WEEK.
>> OH, COOL.
>> SO BEAUTIFUL.
>> THAT’S BEAUTIFUL.
>> WENTY DOODLES, OUR BELOVED
WENDY SULLIVAN DID THAT.
OUR FIRST WINNER FOR COSPLAY OF
THE WEEK WAS SENT IN BY ANDY
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> PERFECT.
>> AT ANDY UNDER SCORE THE THING
I JUST SAID.
PHOTO BY ALI MADDEN.
LET’S TAKE A LOOK.
THE FIRST WINNER.
COSPLAY OF THE WEEK.
>> WHOA.
>> HEY.
>> CHECK OUT THE BOMB.
IT’S THE SNARL THAT REALLY SALES
IT.
>> I WOULD NOT FIGHT THAT
PERSON.
>> THAT SCOWL.
>> I WOULD NOT FIGHT THAT
PERSON.
>> NO.
>> THAT SCOWL WOULD MAKE ME BACK
DOWN.
>> I LOVE ALL THE JADE TOO,.
>> AS SCARY A MARISHA RAY.
>> AND A WONDERFULLY TAKEN
PHOTOGRAPH AS WELL.
>> YEAH.
>> GOOD STUFF.
>> HIGH ROLLERS, DO YOU GET HIGH
AND PLAY?
>> HE’S GOT IT.
>> THAT’S THE GIMMICK.
>> HIGH ROLLERS.
>> YEAH.
DIFFERENT DRUG EVERY WEEK.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> OKAY.
I AM IN.
I WANT TO WATCH.
>> WE EXPERIMENT A BIT MAYBE MIX
A FEW THINGS UP.
BATH SAULTS ONE WEEK AND THEN
MAKE --
>> THE EPISODE WHAT HELL A WEIRD
BECAUSE THEY ALL TURNED IN TO
COWS.
GO BACK TO WHAT WE ARE TALKING
ABOUT WHAT DOES IT MEAN TO BE
GOOD IS THE QUESTION WE ARE
REALLY GETTING IN TO IN THIS
CAMPAIGN?
WHAT DOES IT MEAN TO BE GOOD AND
WHAT DOES THAT WEIRD GRAY AREA
LOOK LIKE BETWEEN -- BECAUSE
THERE IS THE ANTI-HERO
ARCHETYPE.
BUT NONE OF YOU ARE FITTING IN
TO THAT VERY WELL.
SO THERE IS -- IT’S A DEEPER
LAYER TO ME THAN THE ANTI-HERO
ARCHETYPE.
DOES THAT MAKE SENSE?
>> YEAH.
PART OF WHAT MAKES YOU GOOD OR
NOT GOOD IS YOUR OWN ASSESSMENT
OF YOUR OWN GOODNESS.
AND HOW COMFORTABLE YOU ARE WITH
THAT.
AND --
>> DOES THAT MAKE CALEB THE BIG
BAD?
>> I -- IF THAT WERE TRUE --
>> ARE YOU WILLING TO BE --
>> ARE YOU DRUNK ENOUGH TO LET
THAT SLIP ON THE AREA.
>> I WON’T ANSWER THAT QUESTION,
BUT I WILL SAY WE DID PLAYLISTS
FOR THESE CHARACTERS AND WE’LL
DO TWO OR THREE, I THINK WE’LL
DO THREE AGAIN AND I HAVE THIS
VAST BUCKET OF MUSIC AND IT’S
FULL OF SONGS THAT WOULD CHART
HIM TO LIKE THE WORST POSSIBLE
ENDING WHERE HE WOULD LEAVE, I
THINK IF HE WAS GOING TO HAVE
LEFT THE CAMPAIGN IT WOULD HAVE
HAPPENED ALREADY AND MATT AND I
HAVE TALKED ABOUT IT.
I HAVE SONGS THAT WOULD HAVE
CHART THAT’S ENDING FOR HIM AND
I STILL HAVE THEM BECAUSE I FEEL
LIKE THOSE ARE STILL ECHOS IN
THE BACK OF HIS HEAD WHETHER OR
NOT THEY BUBBLE TO THE
FOREFRONTS.
♪ MUSIC PLAYING ♪
>> Matt: WELCOME BACK, FIRST WE
HAVE OUR WINNER OF THE GIVE WAY.
THE PITCHER OF OUR FAN FANTASTIC
THERE IS A LOT GOING ON AROUND
HERE I AM EASILY DISTRACTED
TONIGHT.
I DIDN’T GET ENOUGH IRON, THE
WINNER OF OUR GIVE AWAY TONIGHT
IS CONGRATULATIONS.
WE’LL GET THIS TO YOU ACTUAL S.
IT.
A S.A.P.
\hA S.A.P.
BECAUSE I FOR THE TKPWER TO FORG
EARLIER.
>> THAT’S THE GREATEST NAME.
>> OH, MY GOOD.
CAN I SAY?
>> Matt: IT’S YOUR WEAPON.
>> TECHNICALLY CAPE ARE CALEB.
>> BECAUSE THE NAME.
IT’S CALLED THE SKIN GORGER.
>> WHAT IS IT?
>> SKIN GEORGER.
SKIN GORGER WHEELED BY ORPHAN
MAKER.
>> THIS MASSIVE RUST-COLORED
BLADE WAS ONCE WHEELED AS A SIM
BROLL OF DOMINANCE BY THE OERG
LORD.
THE PLUS ONE BONUS ATTACK AND
DAMAGE ROLES MADE WITH THIS
WEAPON YOU CANNIZE YOUR BONUS
ACTION AND TAKE A POINTS
EXHAUSTION TO EMPOWER THIS
PLAYED FOR ONE MINUTE ALL ATTACK
OF THIS GREAT SOARED DEAL ACID
DAMAGE AND CRIT CHICAGO HITS ON
A ROLE OF 19 OR 20.
BUT TO USE IT YOU CAN’T USE IT
UNTIL UNTIL THE NEXT INNING.
>> IT WOULD TAKE YOU A WHILE TO
I DON’T HAVE FROM THAT.
>> ONCE PER DAY YOU CAN USE
THAT?
>> Matt: YEAH.
>> THAT’S A ABOUT,.
>> THAT’S RIGHT.
>> THAT’S A DOUBLE-EDGED TOWARD
THERE.
>> THAT’S ALL YOU.
>> FOR ME.
>> I MEAN, -- THAT SWORD DOESN’T
HAVE THE SPELL OF MAGIC ON IT.
>> Matt: IT’S INTERESTING,
BUT --
>> CAN SOMEONE CARRY AROUND TWO
LONG SWORD ALL THE TIME AND JUST
LIKE --
>> Matt: YOU CAN KEEP A GREAT
SWORD WITH YOU BUT ONLY USE ONE
AT A TIME.
>> ARE THEY BOTH GREAT SWORD.
>> Matt: YOU COULD HAVE TWO A
TUNED BUT NOT USE THEM AT THE
SAME TIME.
>> YOU CAN PICK YOUR TOOL FOR
THE DAY.
>> GRIFF IT UP.
>> Matt: YOU DON’T GET IT.
>> IT FALLS TO A HOLE.
>> THATTHIS IS ALL TRYING NOT TO
THINK ABOUT WHAT GOING TO
HAPPEN.
>> OH, NO, THE CREEPIE GUY.
>> Matt: TODAY’S BAT IS BROUGHT
TO YOU BY THE GOOD FOLKS AT
DWARF EN FORGE.
THEY HAVE A FREE DOWNLOAD OF
THEIR 406 PAGE DUNGEON OF DOOM
MODULE AVAILABLE ON YOUR WEBSITE
RIGHT NOW.
BE SURE TO --
>> OH, SO CLOSE.
>> BE SURE TO DWARFEN IT UP.
>> ON, YEAH.
>> LOOK AT THAT.
>> THESE TREES ARE AN AWESOME
GIFT FROM MY FRIEND AT HIGH
PRIOR YENTA RAIN.
I HAVE BEEN TRYING HARD TO GET
DEAD TREES FOREVER.
THEY PRINTED THEM OUT.
>> THEY ARE BEAUTIFUL.
>> Matt: THANK YOU, GUYS.
>> THESE ARE THE MOORE BOUNDERS.
>> Matt: FOR THE TIME BEING
BECAUSE I DON’T HAVE MINIS.
>> BIG BOYS.
>> Matt: SO WE HAD JUST TURNED
FJORD ON THE FRONT FOOT.
NOTT HAD LEFT OFF AND GONE
AROUND THE SIDE.
YASHA WHO -- ALL RIGHT, SO WHO
ELSE GOT OFF OF THE MOORE
BOUNDERS?
>> I STEPPED DOWN.
>> I STAYED ON.
THE.
>> NOTT FLANKED RIGHT.
>> BOW YOU WOULD BE ON THIS ONE?
>> I AM RIDE THAT GO ONE BUT I
PREFER TO STAY ON.
WE’LL SAY YOU ARE ON AND OFF TO
THE SIDE THERE.
>> YASHA.
>> WHERE IS THE FELLA?
>> Matt: AND THE FELLA, BECAUSE
THERE IS NO MINI FOR THIS
PARTICULAR INDIVIDUAL, IS RIGHT
THERE.
AND BEGAN TO RUSH FORWARD TO
ABOUT THERE.
>> WHAT THE FUCK.
>> Matt: AS IT SHIMMIES TOWARDS
YOU QUICKLY, IT HAS THE THREE
ARMS AND YOU WATCH AS TWO MORE
KIND OF STICK OUT OF HIS BACK.
>> FUCK THAT.
>> Matt: FOR A TOTAL OF FIVE
APPENDAGES.
>> FIVE?
THAT’S THE WORST NUMBER.
>> Matt: LET’S GO ROLL SOME
ADDITIONAL.
>> DIDN’T YOU GET AN ADVANTAGE?
>> NO, I GOT A D.A.
NATURAL 20.
>> THAT’S TERRIBLE.
>> PLUS FOUR.
SO 24, 29.
>> DAMN.
>> GREAT.
>> Matt: OKAY.
SO TOP OF THE ROUND 25 TO 20.
>> 29.
>> JESUS.
>> WOW.
>> Matt: 25-20.
>> IS THAT THAT LOPELY ISLAND
VIDEO.
>> Matt: 2020-15.
>> 17, 18.
>> 15.
>> FUCK, MAN.
>> IT’S WEIRD HAVING ADVANTAGES.
>> Matt: 15-AT THE POINT.
>> 15-10.
>> Matt: ALL RIGHTY.
>> OH, GOD.
>> Matt: 10-5.
>> 9.
>> Matt: 9.
NOTT AND CALEB GOING TOGETHER.
ALL RIGHT.
AND WE HAVE FOR TO DO THIS --
OH, SORRY, BUDDY.
ALL RIGHTY.
SO TOP OF THE ROUND BEAUREGARD
YOU ARE UP AS THIS CREATURE
BEGINS TO RUSH TOWARD.
>> YOU AS SOON AS I SEE IT
TWITCH A TWITCH QUICKER THAN IT
BECAUSE I GOT THE ALACRITY AND I
GO KNOW NO AND JUST RUN.
>> AWAY.
NO.
>> Matt: UP TO THERE.
>> GO FOR IT.
>> I DART OVER TO IT AND I DO A
RUNNING BARREL KICK TO ITS FACE.
GOING FOR IT.
TWO ATTACKS, TWO ATTACKS.
FIRST TWO ATTACKS, THAT’S GOOD.
SHIT.
OH, THEY ARE BOTH THE SAME.
THEY ARE BOTH 23.
>> Matt: BOTH HIT.
>> THAT’S GOOD TOO.
12 DAMAGE FOR ONE.
AND 10 DAMAGE FOR THE OTHER.
SO 22 HIT.
POP, POP.
AND AFTER THAT FIRST ONE I DO A
STUNNING STRIKE.
>> Matt: ALL RIGHTY.
>> WHERE IS NOTT?
>> Matt: THAT’S A FINE.
>> BY THE BICK ROLLE ROCK OVER
THERE.
>> MY SAVE 15.
>> Matt: SO IT MAKES THE SAVE.
>> HOW DO I FIX THAT?
THAT’S PROBLEM.
DO IT AGAIN, I WILL DO IT AGAIN.
STUN THE FIRST TIME, TRY IT
AGAIN, STUN THE SECOND TIME.
>> Matt: ANOTHER POINT FOR THE
STUN.
>> TWO POINTS I AM TRYING TO
STUN THIS BITCH.
>> Matt: OKAY, THAT IS A FAIL.
>> HE IS STUNNED.
>> Matt: HE IS STUNNED.
>> YES.
AWESOME.
>> Matt: SO THE SECOND HIT.
>> WHERE IS THE RING OF SHAME?
>> Matt: ALL RIGHT.
>> OKAY.
AND THEN FUCK IT, LET’S GO BIG
OR GO HOME.
WE ARE AT FLURRY OF BLOWS.
>> Matt: THE STUN.
>> THAT’S RIGHT.
THE FIRST ONE ON A 14, THAT’S 24
TO HIT FOR THE FIRST ONE.
>> Matt: THAT HITS.
>> GIVING IT 9 DAMAGE.
THE SECOND ONE IS THE 16 TO HIT,
26.
10 DAMAGE.
>> Matt: ALL RIGHT.
>> Marisha: GOOD ROUND.
>> GOOD ROUND.
>> WHERE IS THE WIZARD?
>> Matt: ALL RIGHT.
SO AS THE SUN HAS BEEN SETTING
AND THE AREA HAS GROWN SLIGHTLY
DARKER AS THIS ENCOUNTER COMES
IN TO PLAY, THIS ENTITY, AS YOU
WERE UNLOAD ON THE GROUND IT,
YOUR BLOWS ARE GLANCING AND NOT
QUITE IMPACTING AS HARD AS YOU
WOULD HOPE.
>> Marisha: OKAY.
>> Matt: WITH EACH HIT.
BUT HE IS STUNNED.
>> Matt: HE IS STUNNED STILL.
>> Matt: JUST HELD IN PLACE, HIS
HID SWIMMING AND YOU CAN SEE ITS
EYES, IT’S WHITE PUPIL-LESS EYES
ROLLING FROM THE STUN.
>> Marisha: ALSO I HIT IT
WITH -- SORRY DID YOU WANT TO GO
AHEAD.
I HIT IT WITH MY -- GIVE ME
EXTRACT ASPECTS.
>> Matt: YES.
YES.
OKAY.
IT HAS RESISTANCES TO
BLUDGEONING, PIERCING AND
SLASHING WHILE IN DIM LIGHT OR
DARKNESS.
>> Marisha: OH, SHIT, THAT’S
COOL.
SO AS THE SUN SETTING WE ARE IN
DIM LIGHT.
>> Marisha: GOT IT.
SO I JUST QUICKLY SHOUT OUT THE
DARKNESS MAKES THIS GUY SLIPPY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> IS SLIPPY SLANG FOR
SOMETHING.
AND THAT ENDS MY TURN.
>> Matt: ALL RIGHT, YASHA YOU
ARE UP.
>> Ashley: OH, SHIFT, THAT’S
RIGHT, OKAY.
I AL GOING START -- I WOULD LIKE
TO RAGE.
SO I AM GOING TO START BOOKING
IT TOWARDS --
>> IS IT ALL BLUDGEONING BECAUSE
MY FIST ARE MAGICAL.
>> IS THERE A PLUS TO THAT?
>> IT.
>> Sam: THERE A PLUS AT THAT TO
THAT.
WHOEVER HAS THE MOORE BOUND
ERSTAD SHEET.
>> WOULD BE THE DEXTERITY?
I HAVE THE MOORE BOUNDER THING
IN THE --
>> OKAY.
DOES IT HAVE AN INITIATIVE PLUS.
>> DEXTERITY.
>> 12.
15 PER YARN BALL.
>> 17 FOR JANIK.
>> THEY ALL GO IN ONE WHATEVER
YOU ROLLED IS WHAT THEY GO AS.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> Matt: OTHERWISE WE HAVE OTHER
INITIATIVES TO WORRY ABOUT.
>> Matt: SORRY, YASHA YOU HAVE
RAGE AND THE WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
>> OKAY.
I WOULD LIKE TO START BOOKING IT
TOWARDS THIS CREATURE.
>> Matt: YOU LEAP OFF THE MOORE
BOUNDER I SAY TOGETHER.
THAT’S YOUR MOVEMENT THERE.
>> I GUESS I WILL TAKE THE REST
I’LL DASH THE REST OF IT.
I WANT TO GET TO THEM.
>> Matt: WITH YOUR DASHING YOU
COULD GET TO THE OTHER SIDE TO
FLANK THIS ONE.
SO YOU MOVE AROUND, BLADE AT THE
READY.
THE SKIN GORGE DOESN’T HAVE A
HILT.
IT’S ONE LARGE, SOLID LIKE KIND
OF RUST-COLORED BLADE WITH TWO
HANDLES ON THE BACK OF IT.
SO IT LOOKS LIKE -- IT’S NOT
LIKE A HANDS AND A HILT.
JUST LIKE YOU WERE CLUTCHING TWO
OPEN HANDLES ON THE BACK OF ONE
BIG SOLID BLADE.
>> COOL.
>> THAT’S SO COOL.
>> GNARLY.
>> Matt: YOUR ACTION BONUS.
YOUYOU ARE UP NEXT.
JESTER.
>> Laura: ALL RIGHT, GUIDING
BOLT THIS CREATURE.
>> Matt: GO FOR IT YOU HAVE AN
ADVANTAGE.
GO FOR IT.
WHOA.
>> Laura: THANK GOD I HAVE AN
ADVANTAGE, HOLY SHIT.
BOLT PLUS NINE IS 24.
>> Matt: 24 HITS, ROLL DAMAGE.
>> Laura: THAT’S FIVE AND SIX.
>> TOOK ME A SECOND.
18, 21, 23.
>> Matt: WHEW.
SLAMS IN TO THE CREATURE.
THE BURPING RADIANT ENERGY
COURSE AS CROSS ITS TORSO AND
HEAD THE SKIN PEELING BACK.
IT’S LOOKING HURT.
>> Laura: OKAY.
AND IN CASE HE NEEDS A DOUBLE
ADVANTAGE.
>> Matt: THERE YOU GO THAT,
FINISHES YOUR JOURNEY DO YOU
WANT TO MOVE OR STAY WHERE YOU
ARE?
>> Laura: I AM GOING SAY ON YARN
BALL.
>> Matt: JUST ON YARN BALL, ALL
RIGHT.
THAT BRINGS TO US FJORD.
>> Travis: I WILL USE MY 30 FEET
OF MOVEMENT TO RUN UP THE MATT.
>> Matt: YOU LEAP OFF MOORE
BOUNDER.
FIVE, 10, 15, 20.
>> Travis: NOT TOWARDS IT,
TOWARDS THE AREA IF I CAN,
SORRY.
>> Matt: ALL RIGHT.
THAT WILL BE 30 RIGHT THERE.
>> Travis: ANYTHING I SEE OVER
THERE BEFORE I TURN MY ATTENTION
TO BLADE HANDS?
>> Matt: YOU ARE USING YOUR
ACTION TO LOOK?
>> Travis: I DON’T WANT TO USE
MY ACTION TO LOOK I JUST SEND
TWO ELDREDGE BLASTS TOWARDS THAT
CREATURE BUT I WANT TO BE THERE.
>> Matt: LET ME SEE OVER HERE.
ACTUALLY, YES.
I SEE ANOTHER ONE OF THIS IS
CREATURES.
>> OH, NO.
>> Matt: JUST RESPITE END UP
FROM BEHIND LIKE --
>> YEP.
>> YOU DON’T NEED TO MAKE THE
NOISE EVERY TIME.
I WILL SEND TWO EL BRIDGE BLASTS
TOWARDS THAT WOULD NEW FRIEND.
>> Matt: ALL RIGHT GO FOR IT.
>> Travis: ONE IS A 26, AND 113.
>> Marisha: 13 MISSING.
THAT ONE GOES WIDE AND BLASTS
THE NEARBY ROCKS OUT TO THE
SIDE.
>> Travis: THAT’S ACCURATE.
THAT IS 13-POINTS OF ELDREDGE
BLAST.
>> Matt: YOU DO THE GOTT IT.
ALL RIGHTY.
>> Travis: I WILL USE MY BONUS
ACTION TO CAST A HEX ON THAT.
>> Matt: IS HEX AN ACTION OR --
>> Travis: HEX BLADE CURSE.
>> Matt: MECHANICS BLADE CURSE,
GOT IT.
>> DO WE HAVE TO ROLL MOORE
BOWNER INITIATIVE.
>> Matt: SHE DID.
>> Travis: I YELL.
>> Matt: OKAY.
DARK EARNED CORNER THAT HAVE
AREA OVER THERE, BLOCKED BY THE
LIGHT.
THE CURSE WRAPS ITSELF ALMOST
LIKE TENTACLES.
LIKE GUTS ACROSS THE CREATURE.
IT LOOKS -- AFTER BEING STRUCK
IT LOOKS BACK AT YOU.
AND IT’S NOT THEIR TURN.
FROM THIS NEARBY TREE, YOU START
HEARING DOZENS AND DOZENS OF
TINY SQUEAKS.
>> OH, NO.
>> Matt: YOU WATCH AS A SERIES
OF BATS, ALL DECENT FROM THE
TREE TOWARDS THE BRIGHTEST COLOR
IN THE VICINITY.
FROM THE TOP OF THIS TREE.
A SWARM OF BATS ARE DESCENDS ON
YOU FROM THE TOP.
THAT’S GOING TO BE 19 HIT.
THAT WOULD HITS.
THAT HITS.
IT ALL RIGHT.
SO YOU TAKE.
>> WOULD THE CREATURE THAT WE
ARE ATTACKING, THAT I HAVE HIT
WITH THE GUARDING BOLT, HE’S
GLITTERING WITH A MYSTICAL DIM
LIGHT NOW.
>> Matt: YEAH, MYSTICAL DIM
LIGHT.
HE’S IN DIM LIGHT.
TAKE FIVE-POINTS PIERCING
DAMAGE.
>> COOL, COOL.
>> Matt: AND THEY ARE SWARMING
AROUND YOU RIGHT NOW.
SQUEAKING AND SCRAPING AT YOU
AND BITING AT YOU AND YOU ARE
TRYING SHAKE THEM THEM OFF.
>> NOT COOL.
>> Matt: THAT GUY OVER THERE IS
STUNNED.
THIS GUY OVER HERE WHO IS BEHIND
THE ROCK.
AFTER BEING GLASSED IN THE CHEST
IS GOING TO CLIMB THROUGH THAT
OPENING AND TURNS AND GOES.
>> STOP, MAN.
>> WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS?
>> Matt: BECAUSE IT’S FUN.
RUNS PAST OVER HERE.
>> OH, GOD.
>> Matt: AND IS GOING TO TAKE
ITS MULTI ATTACK ARM SPIKES AT
YOU.
>> HE’S GOING OUT ON A LIMB.
>> OH, 18 HITS.
>> HITS.
>> Matt: INSTEAD THE ARM SPIKE
IT’S A BRACE.
>> OKAY.
>> Matt: SO INSTEAD IT COMES
FORWARD TOWARDS YOU, BOTH OF ITS
ARMS OUT.
AND PEERS THEM THROUGH YOUR BODY
AND PILL -LZ NEW TOWARD IT.
ALL THE ARMS ARE WRAPPING ARMED
I LIKE A SPIDER TRAPPING ITS
PRAY.
AND NOW YOU ARE IN UP AGAINST
IT, ALL YOU CAN SEE IS ITS
BRIGHT EYE AND MOUTH OPEN.
PULLING YOU AS CLOSE TO THE
CREATURE AS IT CAN.
THIS HORRIBLE WHALE.
YOU TAKE.
21 PIERCING DAMAGE AND YOU ARE
GRAPPLED.
>> 31-POINTS?
THAT’S THE LOVE DAMAGE.
>> WOW.
>> Matt: YOU ARE ALSO FRIGHT
ENDED.
WHILE YOU ARE IN ITS GRASP.
>> GRAPPLED AND FRIGHT ENDED,
DAMN.
>> Matt: WHILE IT’S HOLDING YOU
YOU CAN FEEL ITS MOURNFUL WHALE
JUST SHAKING YOUR SOUL AT ITS
DEEPEST LEVEL.
PULLING YOU CLOSER AND CLOSER
TOWARDS IT.
THAT ENDS ITS TURN THE ONE THAT
IS STUNNED REMAINS ZAUNED.
OUT FROM THIS SIDE.
>> OH, GOD.
HIGHER PITCH THIS WAY.
>> I AM ON THE MOORE BOUNDER.
IT’S NOW THE MOORE BOUNDER’S
TURN.
>> Matt: YOU CONTROL YOUR MOORE
BOUNDERS.
>> RIGHT.
DO WE HAVE TO ROLL FOR --
>> YOU CAN ONLY MAKE THEM SIT
AND STAY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> SHAKE.
>> I AM HAVING MIND MOORE BOUND
AIR TACK THE BATS.
>> IT CAN ATTACK WITH ITS HOOFS
IT SAYS.
IT’S A MODIFIED HORSE.
>> GOT IT.
>> IT’S A CLAW ATTACK.
>> IT DOESN’T HAVE LIKE A LARGE
ARRAY OF ATTACKS.
GO AHEAD AND ROLL AGAINST THE
BATS.
>> ALL RIGHT WHAT’S THE PLUS TO
ATTACK BY THE WAY?
>> PLUS SIX.
>> OH, THAT’S 24.
>> Matt: YEAH, GOOD ROLL DAMAGE.
THAT’S 2 24.
>> WHAT IS THAT CATEGORY, DO YOU
KNOW?
>> COMPANION.
>> SEVEN.
>> Matt: SEVEN-POINTS NICE.
IT TAKES NOT A WHOLE LOT OF
DAMAGE AS IT’S A STRIKING AT A
SWARM OF BATS, ONE OR TWO GET
KNOCKED TO THE GROUND IT’S STILL
JUST A LARGE CLOUD WILL TAKE
MORE CARVE THROUGH THEM.
IT’S YOUR MOORE BOUNDER’S TURN,
STAYING PUT?
>> THE MOORE BOUNDER.
YEAH, I THINK IT’S INTERESTED IN
THE BATS RIGHT NOW.
>> Matt: FOR YOURS JESTER.
>> Laura: MINE WILL TRY TO GET
THE ONE AT ATTACKING FJORD.
>> Matt: GO AHEAD AND ROLL AND
ATTACK.
>> SIX PLUS NINE,.
>> Matt: GO AHEAD AND ROLL
DAMAGE.
>> 11 POINTS.
>> Matt: NICE.
>> Matt: BECAUSE OF THE SHADED
SPACE THE DAMN DOESN’T DO AS
MUCH IMPACT AS YOU HOPEFUL AS A
REACTION IT USES ITS TIGHT
OWNING EMBRACE.
>> TIGHTENING EMBRACE.
>> Matt: AS IT GETS HIT IT WAILS
LOUDER AND CLASHES ONTO FJORD
LATER.
, TRUBISKY BAD MOVE.
>> YOU LOOK LIKE YOU NEED A HUG.
>> Matt: YOU TAKE 17 POINTS
SECOND DAMAGE.
>> Matt: IT’S PULLING NEW AND
SHAKING AND SCREAMING IN YOUR
BRAIN THE FEAR INSIDE IS YOU
GETTING MORE AND MORE PAINFUL.
>> THAT THING IS CRUSHING YOU ON
LIKE AN ELFIN PIRATE.
>> Matt: THERE YOU GO.
CALEB, YOU ARE LAST MOORE
BOUNDER.
>> Liam: I RANK THEIR HARNESS TO
THE RIGHT WHICH MEANS ATTACK.
>> PIERCING, BRIDGE INNING.
RESISTENT.
>> INCLUDING MAGICAL.
>> Liam: JUST SIX FOR THAT ONE.
>> I COULD BLOW SOMETHING CRAZY
AGAIN.
>> Matt: ALL RIGHT, YOU GOT IT.
STRIKES THROUGH AND CLAWS
DOESN’T DO AS MUCH DAMAGE AS YOU
HOPE AGAIN, THEY ARE IN THIS
KIND OF SHADED DUSK SPACE.
THEY ARE EMPOWERED BY THE NEARBY
SHADOW.
ALL RIGHT.
THAT ENDS YOUR TURN, CALEB.
>> Liam: THAT WAS THE MOORE
BOUNDER.
>> Matt: IS IT MOVING OR
STAYING?
>> Liam: IT’S STAYING.
>> Matt: THAT BRINGS US UP TO
NOTT AND CALEB.
>> IT SAYS I CAN LIGHT IT UP AND
SPEAK ANOTHER COMMAND WORK A IS
AN ACTION TO MAKE IT RISE, DOES
THAT 19 LYING IT UP AS A FREE
ACTION?
>> Matt: IT DOESN’T MENTION
ACTION ON THE FIRST PART OF
LIGHTING IT UP AND THEN SAYS YOU
CAN THEN DO AN ACTION TO MAKE IT
FLOAT.
>> Matt: SPEAK ITS COMMAND WORD.
I WOULD SAKE YOU CAN JUST SPEAK
THE WORD.
>> THEN I PULL THE DRIFT GLOBE
OUT AND HOLD IT UP IN THE AIR
AND SAY AND THERE IS DAYLIGHT
STREAMING ALL AROUND US.
>> Matt: ALL RIGHT.
SO --
>> 60 FEET IN EVERYONE
DIRECTION.
>> Matt: THAT ENCOMPASSES
EVERYTHING.
AS THE OR BE IS PULLED OUT BY
CALEB.
>> I DIDN’T MAKE IT UP IT WAS ON
THE CARD FOR MY ACTION --
>> Matt: THE GLOBE IS PUT A WAY.
TODAY YOU PULL IT OUT TO USE IT.
>> Liam: OKAY.
>> Matt: IF IT WASN’T AT THE
READY TODAY YOU REACH IT IN AND
PULL OUT I SAYING THAT’S AN
ACTION TO PULL OUT TO THAT’S USE
AN ACTION, DO YOU WANT MOVE OR
STAY WHERE YOU ARE?
>> Liam: I WANT TO STAY ON THE
MOORE BOUNDER.
>> Matt: OKAY, YOU WATCH AS THE
GLOBE BEGINS TO EMIT THIS
BRIGHT, BRIGHT LIGHT THAT
ENCOMPASSES THE AREA THE
REACHERS GIVEN TO SHRINK WAY
FROM IT.
AND PREVIOUSLY THE KIND OF
TOUGH, GRAY HIDE THAT THEY HAD
BEGINS TO CRACK ON THE EXTERIOR
SEEMINGLY AFFECTED BY THE
PRESENCE OF VERY, VERY BRIGHT
LIGHT.
SO THAT FINISHING YOUR TURN
THINK KAY LEX, NOTT WHAT ARE YOU
DOING?
>> Sam: I WILL GO WARPED THE
ACTION OF THE VOLUME.
>> Matt: THIS WAY?
>> Sam: YEP.
>> Matt: ALL RIGHT.
GETTING WITHIN 30 FEET OF THE
THING, THAT MUCH IT’S GOT FJORD
AND I WILL ATTACK.
>> Sam: WITH THE TINK TOP
CROSSBOW, 209 TO HIT.
>> Matt: THAT WILL HIT.
>> SNEAK ATTACK AND YOU’LL SORTS
OF SHIT UP IN MY --
>> Matt: VERY MUCH SNEAK ATTACK.
>> Sam: NOT GRATEROL BUT THAT’S
OKAY.
I WILL USE 21 FURY OF THE SMALL
AND ADD ANOTHER 9 POINTS, THAT’S
30-POINTS OF DAMAGE.
>> Matt: OF WHICH IT IS NOT
RESISTENT TO ANY I SINCE THE
LIGHT FROM THE GLOBE TAKE AS WAY
THEIR RESISTENCE THE BOLT TRIKES
THE BACK OF THE NET AND COMES
THROUGH THE CHIN CAUSING ITS
YEAH TO DISLODGE SLIGHTLY
LOOKING DOWN IN TO FJORD’S FACE.
>> TURTLES OF WORSE.
>> Matt: I WILL FIRE AGAIN.
GO FOR IT.
>> Sam: FIRE AGAIN, THAT’S IT
WASN’T FOUR TO HIT.
>> Matt: THAT’S THAT HITS.
>> Sam: ONLY SCORES -- THAT’S
NOT TERRIBLE.
WHERE IS MY SHIT.
10 MORE POINTS OF DAMAGE.
>> Matt: NICE, ALL RIGHT.
WILL STANDING, ITS LOOKING HURT.
>> Sam: IF I HAVE ANYMORE
MOVEMENT LEFT I SCHOOL BEHIND
THAT ROCK OR TREE OR ANY ROCK I
CAN GET TO TO GET --
>> Matt: BACK WHERE YOU WERE OR
BEHIND THIS TREE?
>> Sam: MAYBE BEHIND THIS ROCK.
>> Matt: ALL RIGHT.
>> Sam: SURE.
>> Matt: THAT’S YOUR TURN THAT
BRINGS US TO.
>> Caduceus: I AM GOING TO DO
SOMETHING SECOND LEVEL.
I AM GOING TO TRY A RAY OF
FEEBLE.
FOR FUNNY WILL HIT THE THING
TACK CALEB, I STILL STAY WHERE I
AM WITH THE BATS AND FIRE
THROUGH AND HIT THE FEATURE.
>> Matt: GO TO THE ATTACK.
>> Taliesin: IT’S A
CONSTITUTION -- IT’S ATTACK SAYS
CONSTITUTION.
>> Matt: THAT’S A 10.
>> NICE.
>> Matt: SO YOU DEAL ONLY HALF
DAMAGE.
OWE, IS IF WEAPON ATTACK?
>> Matt: THEY ARE CONSIDERED A
WEAPON, YES.
SO, YEAH, IT’S AT HALF DAMAGE NO
MATTER WHAT.
AND THEN, OH, DOW.
BIG SAVE AT THE END OF ITS TURN.
>> OKAY, I CAN MAKE IT SAVE
AGAINST THE SPELL.
>> GOT IT AND THEN, YEAH,
THAT’S -- I THINK THAT’S ALL I
CAN DO THA*EG THAT’S ALL I CAN D
JUST FOR FUNNY WILL BECOME
INVISIBLE.
>> Matt: YOU ARE VANISH ON TOP
OF YOUR MOORE WOUNDSER.
>> YEAH.
>> Matt: ALL RIGHT.
THAT FINISHES YOUR GO.
TOP OF THE ROUND, BEAU, YOU ARE
UP.
>> Marisha: DOES MY GUY LOOK
CRACKLY AS WELL.
>> Matt: YES, THE LIGHT RADIUS
IS AFFECTING THEM ALL THEY ARE
IN I BROUGHT GLOBE OF DAYLIGHT.
>> Marisha: I WILL DO TWO
MANAGER FITSES AND COME ACROSS
HIS FACE, NATURAL 19.
SEVEN DAMAGE.
FOR THE FIRST ONE.
ANOTHER NATURAL 19 FOR 29, WITH
6 DAMAGE.
SO 12 DAMAGE.
>> NICE, 16 DAMAGE YOU SAY?
>> 12 TOTAL.
>> Matt: 12 TOTAL GOT YOU.
>> Marisha: SELF DAMAGE FROM THE
FIRST 12 FROM THE SECOND.
HOW BAD IS HE LOOKING?
>> Matt: HE’S LOOKING PRETTY
HURT.
>> INSIDE CHECK.
I DON’T LAKE THE WAY HE SAID
THAT.
>> Marisha: HE’S LOOKING PRETTY
HURT.
FLURRY OF BLOWS AGAIN, TWO MORE
STRIKES.
28.
>> Matt: THAT HITS.
>> Marisha: 11 DAMAGE.
>> Matt: 11 POINTS OF DAMAGE,
ALL RIGHT.
>> Marisha: LAST ONE, COME ON.
26 TO HIT.
OH, PURRING.
FUCK.
\hFUCK.
WAIT, OKAY, 10 DAMAGE, HOW
DOCUMENT TO DO THIS?
SO I DID THE HAMMER PHYSICIAN AS
CROSS HIS FACE.
I WILL LACE MY FINGER AROUND HIS
NEXT.
KNEE FOR THE SECOND FULL TY THAI
CLINCH, I WILL LACK AROUND MY
ARMS AND BREAK HIM OVER MY KNEE.
>> Matt: AS THE PULL THE FINAL
BREAK THE KNEE COMES UP IN AN
ACTUAL AREA IN THE CENTER OF ITS
BODY AND BREAKS IN HALF.
YOU WATCH AS THE FLESH BURNS IN
TO ASH IN THE PROXIMITY AS IT
FALLS IN TO TWO PIECES YOU HEAR
THE EXHALE OF ITS LAST HORRIBLE
WAIL.
JUST SHRIVEL UP AS IT’S A BODY
TURNS TO THIS PAPER THIN
SKELETON.
>> Marisha: I JUST BRUSH OUT MY
HAIR.
AND LOOK AT YASHA.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Matt: SPEAKING OF WHICH IT’S
YOUR TURN, YASHA UNLESS YOU WANT
TO MOVE.
YOU STILL HAVE MOVEMENT ACTUALLY
ACTUALLY.
>> Ashley: I WILL MOVE TOWARDS
THE ONE THAT’S FUCKING WITH
CALEB.
>> Matt: EASY ENOUGH WITH YOUR
CRAZY MOVEMENT.
YASHA YOU ARE UP WHAT ARE YOU
DOING?
I STAND THERE STUTTERING.
OKAY, THAT ONE IS TAKEN CARE OF
BY B EAU.
I START WINNING TOWARDS THE ONE
WHO HAS FJORD ALL CAPTURED
BEHIND IT.
>> AS CLOSE AS YOU CAN GET.
>> Ashley: WITH I MAKE IT?
>> Matt: FOR THE NULL I FLANKING
IT.
>> Travis: HELP ME.
>> Ashley: I WILL ATTACK IT FROM
BEHIND.
>> WHY DO SO MANY FIGHTS END UP
LIKE THIS FOR YOU.
>> Ashley: 15 TOTAL.
>> Matt: 15 TO HIT.
THAT HITS.
DAMAGE.
>> Ashley: OKAY.
COME ON.
>> Travis: I AM NOT LAUGHING.
>> Ashley: SEE WHAT THE SCHEDULE
GORGER CAN DO.
LET’S SEE.
5, 6, I WILL DO SAVAGE ATTACKER
\h5, 6, I WILL DO SAVAGE ATTACKER
ROLL AGAIN.
>> Matt: OKAY.
>> Ashley: THAT’S BETTER.
7, 8.
OKAY.
15.
SORRY.
>> Marisha: 15 POINTS OF DAMAGE,
NICE.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU SLASH THROUGH WITH THE GIANT
BLADE IT SLAMS IN TO THE GROUND
IT’S HEAVIER THAN YOU ARE SUES
USED TO JUST GETTING USED TO IT.
YOU DID CARVE A CHUNK OF CHEST
OPEN THE SHOULDER IS EXPOSED.
THERE WOULD BE MUSCLE YOU SEE
BLACK SINEW TIGHT BETWEEN
BENEATH THE SKIN.
>> Ashley: SECOND ATTACK.
THAT IS 17.
>> Marisha: 17 HITS.
GOOD VOLUME.
>> Ashley: OKAY, YOU KNOW WHAT,
I WANT TO TRY THIS THIS POINT OF
EXHAUSTION, I WANT TO TRY THIS.
I WANT TO DO THE ONE EXTRA
DAMAGE.
>> Matt: BECAUSE YOU WERE NOT
TACKED LAST ROUND AND YOU WERE
NOT ATTACKED LAST ROUND YOU ARE
TECHNICALLY NOT RAINING.
LOSE YOUR RAGE BEFORE THIS
HAPPENS.
YOU COULD HAVE HAD TO USE THE
BONUS ACTION TO RAGE IT’S BEEN A
WHILE SINCE WE WERE BACK.
YOU WOULD HAVE TO USE YOUR BONUS
ACTION TO KEEP YOUR RAGE.
>> Ashley: SO I AM NOT ABLE TO
DO THAT.
SECOND ATTACK, 12-POINTS OF
DAMAGE.
AND THEN CAN I USE MY BONUS
ACTION THEN TO RAGE?
>> Matt: YES, YOU CAN.
>> Ashley: LET’S DO THAT.
>> Matt: LET’S SAY YOU DID THAT
AT THE TOP OF THE ROUND.
JESTER YOU ARE UP.
>> Liam: OKAY, THIS THING IS
STILL ATTACKING FJORD.
>> Matt: SAME ON FJORD ARE FJORD
ONE GOING BACK TOWARDS CALEB
THAT IS UNSCATHE AND THE A CLOUD
OF BATS.
>> Liam: AND THE GUY TACKING
FJORD LOOKS KIND OF ROUGH?
>> Matt: HE’S HURT.
>> Liam: OKAY, I AM GOING TO NOT
RISK IT, I WILL DO A GUIDING
BOLT ON THE ONE ATTACKING FJORD?
>> Matt: OKAY GO FOR IT.
>> IS FJORD WORTH SAVING.
>> Liam: I WILL DO IT AS A THIRD
LEVEL.
>> THAT’S LOVE.
>> Matt: ATTACK ROLL.
>> Liam: I WENT A AGREES I HAVE.
THAT’S 16.
>> Matt: 7 PLUS 6.
>> Liam: PLUS 6.
>> Laura: PLUS 9.
11, 19, 23 AGAIN.
I WILL HOLD UP MY SYMBOL OF THE
TRAVELER.
>> Reporter: AND THINK HARD
ABOUT MAKING FJORD SAFE AGAIN.
I DON’T WANT TO HIT FJORD I I’M
IT LOW UP LOU THE -- UP THROUGH
GUY AS HEAD WITH A PEOPLE OF
BINK ENERGY.
>> Matt: THE HEAD JUST DISSENT
GREATS AND THE DIVINE ENERGY
LEAVING A SMOKING CRATER WHERE
ITS NEXT AND HEAD ONCE WAS, ITS
BODY GOES LIMP AND CRUMBLE AS
WAY FROM ITS BODY.
>> Travis: THANK YOU.
>> Matt: WHAT’S THE RANGE ON
YOUR CURSE.
>> 14 HIT POINTS IF IT DIES, 14.
>> Matt: 30 FEET.
I DON’T KNOW WHAT ELSE YOU CAN
PUT IT ON THAN ONE OF YOUR
ALLIES.
>> I DON’T THINK YOU CAN
TRANSFER IT.
IT’S NOT LIKE REGULAR HEX.
>> Matt: RIGHT, RIGHT.
ARE YOU SURE?
>> Travis: YEAH, IT SAYS UNTIL
THE TARGET DIES YOU DIE OR ARE
INCAPACITATE TODAY ONE MINUTE.
>> Matt: YOU ARE RIGHT.
>> Travis: 14 HITS POINTS,
THANKS, JESSE.
>> Laura: YOU ARE WELCOME.
>> Matt: THAT FINISHES YOUR
TOURED.
FJORD YOU ARE UP.
>> Travis: I WANT TO SIT DOWN
AND HAVE A CRY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Travis: I WILL RUN UP AND
GIVE JESSE A LITTLE KISS ON THE
CHEEK SAYING THANKS AND STEP
AROUND HER AND FIRE TWO EL AGAIN
BLASTS AT THE ONE TACKING CALEB.
THOSE ARE BOTH NINES WHICH MEANS
18 MIT.
>> Matt: YEAH, BOTH HIT.
>> Travis: EVERYBODY POINTS OF
ELDREDGE BLAST DAMAGE.
AND 13.
>> Matt: NICE.
JUST GOT BLASTED WITH THE RAY
YOU WATCH EIGHTS HE BODY WHITHER
SLIGHTLY YOU CAN HEAR ITS WAIL
GET HIGHER PITCHED AS IT’S A
ACTUAL PHYSICAL SELF LOSES
STRENGTH.
AND THEN ALMOST BLOWN OVER IT
CATCHES ITSELF ON THE MOORE
BOUNDSER FROM THE IMPACT OF BOTH
OF YOUR BLASTS AND THEN PICKS
ITSELF BACK UP.
IT’S 22 KIND OF BACK SHOULDER
BLADE ARMS.
PREPARING FOR WHATEVER ITS NEXT
MANEUVER IS.
>> Travis: DOPE.
>> Matt: ARE YOU MOVING OR
STAYING PUT?
>> Travis: I WILL USE THE REST
OF MY MOVEMENT TO STEP BEHIND
THAT SPIRE OUTCROPPING RIGHT
THERE.
>> Matt: RIGHT HERE?
>> Travis: I LITTLE MORE TO YOUR
RIGHT.
YEAH, THERE YOU GO.
GREAT.
PERFECT.
>> Matt: OKAY, GREAT.
NOW IT COMES TO THE BATS TURN,
THEY HAVE LOST INTEREST IN
CADUCEUS, AS YOU TURN INVISIBLE.
AND INSTEAD MOVE OVER TO WARM
AROUND CALEB.
>> OH, YEARS.
>> NO.
>> DO I HAVE AN -- NEVER MIND.
>> Matt: YOU HAVEN’T
OPPORTUNITY, IF DO YOU WANT TAKE
IT.
>> NO, I’LL HOLD.
>> Matt: DO YOU HAVE A WAR
CASTER?
>> I DO HAVE WAR CASTER.
>> Matt: DOUBLE CHECK, I BELIEVE
THAT YOU CAN --
>> OH.
>> YOU CAN WHAT?
>> OH, WOW, ACTUALLY, I CAN,
ACTUALLY.
PRETTY SURE.
>> CAST A SPELL ON THEM LEAVING.
>> I CAN, ACTUALLY.
BUT YOU’LL LOSE INNING VISIT
BILL.
>> NOT THIS INVISIBILITY.
THIS IS WEIRD.
WHAT CAN I USE?
I CAN’T DO A LOT OF ANYTHING.
A SACRED FLAME ON THE BATS AS
THEY ARE ROLLING BY.
>> Matt: OKAY.
THAT IS A DEXTERITY SAVE.
>>> 17.
>> DAMN IT.
>> Matt: OR SORRY.
>> Matt: THEY SWARM TO YOU AND
ROLL A 22 TO HIT.
>> SORRY.
>> DID YOU YOUR BEST.
>> I DON’T HAVE A SHIELD
PREPARED TODAY.
PRETTY BLOW.
>> Matt: YOU TAKE AT THE ..S
PIERCING DAMAGE AS THE WARM IS
SWIRLING AROUND AND YOU BUYING
YOU FROM ALL SIDES.
YOUR MOORE BOUNDER IS STARTING
TO BACK AWAY LOOKING SPAO*P
SPOOKED BY THE -- NOT SPOOKED
BUT FRUSTRATED.
NOW IT’S THE CREATURE’S TURN.
THAT ONE IS GOING TO REACH UP
AND ATTEMPT TO EMBRACE YOU OFF
OF THE MOORE BOUNDER.
AND THAT’S A NATURAL 19.
>> Matt: 20 POINTS OF PIERCING
DAMAGE, SIRE, PLUS 3.
IT’S POLLED OF OFF THE MORE
BOUNDER NOW AND YOU ARE BEING
HELD AND YOU ARE FRIED ENDED IN
ITS GRASP.
>> Matt: BEAMS IT HAVE SHOOTING
OUT IN DIFFERENT DIRECTIONS.
>> IT’S ATTACKING CALEB, THE
THING FROM NOT OF ME.
>> Matt: EMBRACED HIM AND CALEB
IS BEING KILLED.
>> CAN I TAKE REACTION.
>> Matt: HALF THAT DAMAGE AS I
NOTE.
>> WHY?
>> Matt: IT DOES HALF DAMAGE
FROM THE SPELL.
SO 11.
>> 10 FROM THE BATS BUT THAT’S
NOT AFFECTED AFFECTED FROM 23 --
>> Matt: AND 11.
>> 11 TOTAL.
>> Matt: SO BETWEEN THE TWO OF
THEM 21.
>> THAT’S WAY BETTER.
>> Matt: REMEMBER YOUR SPELL.
>> THANK YOU, I HAD FORGOTTEN.
>> CENSURE A TACK?
>> Matt: YOU CAN, GO FOR.
>> DAMN.
WHERE WERE THESE ROLLS LIKE THE
PAST 10 WEEKS, 29.
>> Matt: 29 HITS, GOOD DAMAGE.
>> YEAH.
11.
>> Matt: OKAY.
>> WHACK.
>> 11.
>> Matt: 11-POINTS OF DAMAGE,
RIGHT.
BUT WHAT DAMAGE DID YOU SAY?
SO FOR THE RAY YOU DO.
DOES IT AFFECT WEAPON ATTACKS?
>> UH-HUH.
>> Matt: YOU GOT IT.
IT’S REACTION IS TIGHTENING THE
EMBRACE, AS YOU PUNCH THE CREEP
TER SQUEEZES ON CALEB AND YOU
HEAR ITS WAIL RESTLESS MADE
THROUGH YOUR ENTIRE BOD?
>> I.
>> OH, DID I DO THAT?
>> Matt: YEAH, YOU DO.
>> DID I DO THAT [.
>> Matt: YOU TALK 23 POINTS OF
SECOND DAMAGE.
>> NOT HALVED?
>> Matt: NOT HALVED.
>> I CAN’T SPEND A KEY POINT.
I CAN ONLY DO THAT ON MY TURN.
>> I FEEL LIKE HE’S JUST
RESPONDING.
>> Matt: LEAPING OFF THE RUIN,
FJORD, THIS HAS BEEN YOUR WORST
NIGHTMARE YOUR PLACEMENT HAS NOT
BEEN POSITIVE.
YOU HEAR THIS YOU GLAND UP AS
ONE FOULS OFF THE SIDE THAT
TRIES TO ATTEMPT TO DROP AND
GRAB YOU.
IT DOES TAKE -- THAT WOULD BE A
30-FOOT FALL.
THAT’S 36-POINTS DAMAGE.
AT THE ..S BLUDGEONED DAMAGE IT
TAKES RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
RIGHT OUT OF THE BAT IS A VERY
MESSY THING TO DO.
SO LAPS TAKES DAMAGE AND TRIES
TO EMBRACE YOU AGAIN.
>> Travis: FUCK.
>> Matt: THE 12.
DOES NOT HIT.
>> Travis: IT DOES NOT HIT.
THANK GOD.
>> Matt: OH, AT THE END OF THAT
ONE’S TURN IT WILL TRY TO ROLL
TO RESIST YOUR THING.
THERE IS GOING TO BE A 17.
WHAT’S YOUR --
>> Travis: 17.
>> Matt: JUST MANAGES TO REACH
THE RAY, IT’S NOT LONGER
AFFECTED AND GETS ITS STRENGTH
BACK.
THAT ONE HAS TAKEN SOME DAMAGE.
THAT ENDS THEIR TURN NOW IT’S
THE MOORBOUNDER’S TURN.
>> OKAY.
MOORBOUNDER PEOPLE WHAT,
DOCUMENT THEM TO DO?
>> MINE IS GOING TO RUN OVER AND
CLAW THE THING THAT JUST DROPPED
DOWN ON FUCKING FJORD.
>> OKAY.
RUSH OVER TO THAT SIDE.
GO AHEAD AND ROLL FOR AN ATTACK.
>> WAIT, PLUS 6, YEAH, 13.
>> Matt: 13, THAT DOES NOT HIT
UNFORTUNATELY.
IT GOES TO STRIKE AND HOLDING
FJORD   -- DIDN’T MANAGE TO GRAB
FJORD.
BUT IT’S NOT QUITE ABLE TO
FULLY -- ACTUALLY, INTERESTING
POINT OF ORDER IT WOULD NOT GET
CLOSE ENOUGH TO FJORD WITH THE
SPACE THERE TO THE CREATURE.
FJORD IS KIND OF BLOCKING THE
SPACE THERE.
OH, YEAH, AS PART OF THE
NARRATIVE THERE IT COULDN’T EVEN
GET UP TO STRIKE THE CREATURE.
>> OH, OKAY.
>> Matt: CALEB, ANYTHING WITH
YOUR MOORBOUNDER.
>> YEAH, KILL THIS THING.
>> Matt: GO AHEAD.
>> 25 TO HIT.
>> Matt: DAMAGE.
>> 7.
NO, WAIT.
IT’S 22.
>> 2D4 PLUS FOUR.
>> Marisha: NINE POINTS.
>> Matt: IT’S TAKING DAMAGE.
>> I WILL ROLL AROUND AND
ATTACK.
COME IN THERE.
ATTACKING THE ONE FROM CALEB
ALSO.
IF I CAN GET IN HERE.
>> Matt: IT’S A SWARM SO YOU CAN
GET UP AGAINST IT.
AND IT’S GOING TO ATTACK THE ONE
ATTACKING CALEB AND THAT’S 10.
>> Matt: 10 MISSES
UNFORTUNATELY.
>> AS IT JUMPS OFF THE ROCK AND
SWIPES OUT TOWARDS IT AND THE
CREATURE JUST JUTS OUT OF THE
WAY.
THAT FINISHED THE MORE BOUNDER’S
ROUNDS.
>> DOES THE BLAST REQUIRE ME TO
DO VERBAL SEMANTIC AND ALL OF
THAT OR DOES JUST WORK.
>> Matt: IF IT DOESN’T SPECIFY
YOU NEED WHAT’S REQUIRED FROM
THE SWELL.
>> IT DOESN’T SAY EITHER WAY.
YOU HAVE TO TAKE AND MOVE YOUR
HANDS.
>> I WILL JUST TRY TO WRESTLE
OUT OF THIS THING’S GRIP.
>> Marisha: YOU CAN STILL CAST
SPELLS WHILE YOU ARE GRAPPLED
WHICH MEANS YOU CAN’T MOVE.
>> A THINK NOT HELD TOO?
>> Matt: MA, YOU STILL CAST
SPELLS.
>> FUCK IT I WILL CAST MAGIC
MISSILE AT FIFTH LEVEL.
>> Matt: RIGHT IN TO ITS CHEST,
GO FOR IT.
ROLL DAMAGE.
>> I GOT IT THIS WRONG BECAUSE
IT’S NO THE MAIN NOTES.
IT ACTUALLY DOES 4D4 SLASHING
DAMN.
4D4 PLUS FOUR, BUT ONLY ADDS A
PLUS 6.
SO WE HAVE BEEN DOING IT WRONG
BASED ON YOUR NOTES ON IT JUST
SHOWED UP DIFFERENTLY.
>> Matt: GOTTA.
>> AND HE CAN JUMP 30 FEET FYI
GUYS.
>> FUCK.
>> Matt: GOOD ENOUGH.
THERE YOU GO.
>> Liam: 25 TOTAL.
>> Matt: 25 DAMAGE, NICE.
CALEB PUTS HIS HANDS UP TOWARDS
THE STERNUM OF THIS CREATURE HE
WATCHES A BLAST OF FORCE SHORT
WAVE OUT OF THE SIMMER WHERE
HE’S BEING PULLED UP WARD
LEAVING THIS CRATER HOLE IN ITS
TORSO.
JUST DRIP OUT BLACK LIQUID.
BUT IT’S STILL STANDING.
IT IS THAT THE END OF YOUR TURN.
>> Liam: YEAH, I CAN’T MOVE.
>> Matt: YOU TAKE 6D8 DAMAGE.
>> WHY?
>> Matt: TENDS OF CALEB’S TURN
BECAUSE YOU ARE STILL HELD IN
ITS SPACE, AT THE END OF A TURN
WHILE YOU ARE STILL BEING HELD
YOU ARE TAKE THE DAMAGE.
>> YOU ARE SURROUNDED BY BATS
AND SHIT.
>> Matt: 30 POINTS OF DAMAGE.
CALEB GOES LIMP IN ITS GRASP AND
BEGINS TO ALMOST LIKE IT’S
TRYING TO TUCK CALEB UP IN TO
THE WOUNDS THAT HE LEFT IN ITS
BODY.
>> OH, MY GOD.
>> Matt: HE’S --
>> HE’S TRYING DO WHAT?
>> Matt: TRYING TO STUFF HIM IN
THE WOULDN’T TRYING TO PULL IT
CLOSER TOWARDS IT.
AS IT GOES.
>> AM I BEING FJORDED.
>> ARE I DON’T THINK I CAN
EVERYBODY SEE ANY OF THAT.
I WILL RUN TOWARDS THE HOLE IN
THE ROCKS.
>> Matt: 30, YOU COME THROUGH
THE SPACE THERE AND YOU CAN SEE
RIGHT NOW THERE ARE THE MORE
BOUNDER AND CREATURE RIGHT ON
THE SIDE NEXT TO FJORD AND
ACROSS THE WAY
YOU HAVE A HARD TIME SEEING OVER
THERE.
>> I WILL DRAW ON THE ONE WITH
FJORD AND SAY FJORD, LOOKS LIKE
YOU COULD USE AN EXTRA HAND.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Matt: THERE IT GOES.
>> I FIRE AT THE THINGS LIKE
HAND.
>> Matt: GO FOR IT.
>> 22.
>> Matt: GO AHEAD AND ROLL
DAMAGE.
>> OKAY.
24.
>> Matt: 24 DAMAGE, NICE ITS ARM
SEVENS OFF AS ONE OF ITS LONG
LIMBS JUST HITS THE GROUND.
LACKS BACK TOWARDS YOU.
IT LOOKS SO SAD.
AND JUST SORROWFUL.
AND FUCKING FRIGHTENING.
>> WOW.
>> Matt: WHAT ELSE IS HE DOING?
>> I WILLOW, BOY, I WILL RELOAD
AND FIRE AGAIN.
NATURAL 20.
>> 12 MORE POINTS OF DAMAGE, SIX
PLUS SIX.
>> Matt: SIX TIMES TWO BECAUSE
HE DID A CRITICAL HIT.
>> THAT’S 18.
>> Matt: 18-POINTS OF DAMAGE.
>> PLUS IT FIRES AGAIN.
>> Matt: THAT’S RIGHT.
>> NATURAL 1.
SOMEBODY BAD HAPPENS TO ME.
YOU SHOOT YOURSELF.
>> I SHOOT MYSELF.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> AMAZING.
>> I SUFFER 4-POINTS OF PIERCING
DAMAGE.
>> THAT’S BAD ASS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Matt: PERFECT.
DOES THAT FINISH YOUR TURN?
>> THAT’S IT.
>> Matt: YOU COME BACK UNTIL TO
YOUR SPACE.
>> OKAY.
I AM GOING TO MOVE BEHIND, I AM
GOING TO MOVE NEXT TO CALEB.
>> Matt: THE MOORBOUNDER --
STEALTH MOVING NEXT TO HIM.
>> I WAIL HOP OFF THE WAR
BOUNDER AND MOVE NEXT TO CALEB.
>> CAST THIS AS FOURTH LEVEL.
>> Matt: GO FOR IT.
YOU ARE UP TO 37 HIT POINTS.
>> IS HE STILL IN THE GRASS WITH
THE DUDE?
>> Matt: NO, HE FELL OFF THE
MOORBOUNDER.
>> IS HE STILL CLUTCHED BY HIM?
>> Matt: HE IS NOT GRAPPLED
ANYMORE FROM.
A FLAVOR STAND POINT IT WAS
TRYING TO STUFF HIM IN TO HIS
BODY AND IF IN A REALLY FUCKED
UP WAY.
HE COMES BACK TO CONSCIOUSNESS.
YOU ARE NOT GRAPPLED UP.
>> I AM TAKING A DEFENSIVE
STANCE.
>> Matt: YOU GOT IT.
THAT FINISHES YOUR TURN
CADUCEUS.
BEAU YOU ARE UP.
>> Marisha: SEEING WHAT HE’S
TRYING TO DO TO CALEB I AM LIKE,
NO, SIR, I GRAB HIM BY HIS HEAD
AND DRANK HIM BACK.
AND JUST START FUCKING JABBING
HIM IN THE RIBS.
NATURAL 20.
>> I HAVE BEEN WAITING FOR THIS.
>> Marisha: I ROLLED A FIVE SO
THAT’S 10 PLUS 6, 16 DAMAGE ON
THAT ONE.
>> I WAS TRYING TO GET KAY
SKPHREB CALEB AND
IT WAS F A.J. AR A.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Marisha: ATTACK AGAINST.
12 DAMAGE.
>> Matt: HOW DOCUMENT DO THIS?
NCAA I HAVE HIM BY THE NEXT AND
JAB HIM IN THE RIBS AND JUST DO
A FULL NEXT SNAP.
>> Matt: YOU HEAR THIS SICKENING
BREAK NOISE AND IT’S HORRIBLE
MOAN GETS CUT OFF AS IT’S A WIND
PIPE IS PINCH AND THE CHANCES TO
THE GROUND AS CALEB PULLS HIS
HEAD OUT OF THE INTERIOR I HAVE
ITS ABDOMEN BLACK WITH GORE.
>> Marisha: YOU ARE ALMOST LIKE
RAVIOLI STUFFING.
>> Matt: YOU STILL HAVE A BONUS.
>> BEAU JUST INVENTED HALF RAVIO
>> Marisha: 1200 YEARS BEFORE
ITALY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Marisha: I CAN STILL MOVE.
>> Matt: YES, YOU CAN.
>> Marisha: CAN I GET TO THE ONE
THAT’S -- OH, BATS.
>> UP TO YOU.
>> Marisha: CAN I PUNCH BATS.
>> Matt: YEAH.
>> Matt: OF COURSE YOU CAN PUNCH
THEM.
>> Marisha: OKAY, I BREAK THAT
DOUCHE BAG’S NEXT AND I LOOK UP
AND SEE THE BATS AND I JUST PULL
OUT MY STAFF AND I START DOING
THE WHIRL WIND WALKING TOWARDS
THE BATS.
>> Matt: SO AS YOU MOVE THROUGH
WE’LL PUT YOU OVER HERE YOU GO
DIRECTLY THROUGH IT.
BONUS ACTION.
>> Marisha: I HIT HIM WITH MY
STICK.
20.
>> Matt: THAT HITS.
>> Marisha: OH, WAIT, I ROLLED
AN 8 FOR MY STICK.
>> Matt: YOU CAN’T USE YOUR
STICK AS A BONUS ACTION FOR
FLAVOR WE ARE SAYING IT’S YOUR
STICK.
>> Marisha: FLAVOR MY STICK.
12 DAMAGE.
>> Matt: 12 DAMAGE.
PLUS TONIGHT.
>> Matt: I TAKE ON THE OUR OR
FIVE MORE BATS, YOU COME UP THE
OTHER SIDE OF IT.
IT’S A SWARM.
IT’S HARD TO GET A GRASP O IT’S
TAKING SOME DAMAGE.
>> Marisha: OLD LADY WITH A
BROOM.
>> Matt: ESSENTIALLY.
YASHA YOU ARE UP.
>> Ashley: SO --
>> CROUCHING DOWN JUST IN CASE.
>> Ashley: SINCE I WAS NOT HIT I
HAVE TO RAGE GUN.
>> Matt: YOU ATTACKED LAST TIME.
>> Ashley: CAN I TRY TO MAKE MY
WAY TO THIS GUY OVER HERE.
>> Matt: YOU CAN TRY.
25, 30, 35, YOU CAN GET AROUND
IT THAT WAY BY MOVING THROUGH
FJORD.
>> YOUR NEW SWORD OR YOUR --
>> Ashley: IT’S THE SAME.
14.
>> Matt: 14 JUST MISSES.
>> Ashley: OKAY.
SECOND ATTACK.
>> Ashley: I JUST ROLLED A
NATURAL 19 FOR THE SECOND
ATTACK.
>> Matt: OKAY, GREAT.
BUT IT HITS.
>> Ashley: IT’S FOR THE SKIN
GORGER.
>> Matt: BUT YOU COULDN’T USE
THE WEAPON LAST TURN BECAUSE YOU
HAD TO USE YOUR BONUS ACTION.
>> YOU DIDN’T TAKE THE POINT OF
EXHAUSTION.
>> Matt: YOU HAD TO KEEP THE
RAGE GOING.
>> Ashley: I SEE, SO TO USE --
>> 19.
>> Ashley: IF I USE THE --
THAT’S IF I GET THE -- GOT IT.
>> Matt: IF YOU USE ABILITY FOR
THE NEXT MINUTE THAT’S WHERE
YOUR CHANCE GOES UP BY ONE.
>> IT’S LIKE THE WHOLE FIGHT.
>> Ashley: I SEE.
OKAY.
>> Matt: POINTS OF DAMAGE.
>> Ashley: 16 POINTS OF DAMAGE.
>> ON THE SECOND ATTACK.
>> Matt: RIGHT, OKAY.
>> Matt: YOU GOT IT.
HE’S LOOKING REAL HURT.
THE CAR -- THE BLADE AS YOU
BRING IT DOWN THE SECOND TIME.
IT IMMATERIAL BEDS ITSELF A GOOD
FOOT IN TO ITS CHEST AND IT
TRIED TO STOP IT WITH ITS CLAWS
AND YOU WATCH TWO OF ITS POINTED
ARMS JUST GET SEVERED AND NOW
THESE STUMPS ARE JUST BLEEDING
OUT AS IT GOES --
>> NO.
>> Matt: DOES THAT FINISH YOUR
TURN YASHA.
>> Ashley: IT DOES.
>> Matt: JESTER YOU ARE UP.
>> Laura: OKAY.
WHY NOT FOR SOME FLAVOR, I WILL
LEAP OFF THE MOORBOUNDER.
PULL OUT MY BATTLE ABDELKADER
AND BATTLE AX AND TRY TO
SLAP AT IT.
>> Matt: YOUR ATTACK.
, ROLL FOR IT.
>> Laura: OH, MAN.
I DON’T NEED TO DO THIS AX
THING.
8 PLUS 5 IS NOT ENOUGH, 13.
>> Matt: YOU JUMP IN THE AIR.
CATCHES NOTHING.
>> Laura: SHIFT.
I CAST SPIRTUAL WEAPON TO MAKE
UP FOR IT.
>> Matt: THERE YOU GO.
>> Laura: I’LL DO IT AT THIRD
LEVEL.
NO, THAT WOULD BE FOURTH LEVEL
TO MAKE IT.
>> THE TREES, THE TREES.
>> Laura: FOURTH LEVEL.
SPIRITUAL WEAPON.
>> Matt: ALL RIGHT.
>> Laura: BROKEN IT DOWN TO SLAM
ON HIS HEAD.
>> Matt: 2D8.
>> Laura: MY LOLLIPOP WITH
SERRATED EMS.
>> Matt: SERRATED LOLLIPOP GO
AHEAD AND ATTACK.
>> Laura: 17.
>> Laura: PLUS FIVE IS 12.
>> Matt: 12-POINTS HOW DOCUMENT
DO THIS?
[ CHEERING AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Laura: WITH MY AX AND I --
THE LOLLIPOP GOES DOWN AND SLAMS
IN TO ITS HEAD AND SMASHES ITS
HEAD IN TO ITS NECK.
>> Matt: AS YOU WHIFF IT TURNS.
IT GETS GROUNDED IN TO IT THE
GROUND.
JUST STOPS MOVING AND THEN IT
HITS AGAIN.
>> Laura: SEE THAT, THAT WAS THE
ART OF DISTRACTION.
>> WHOA.
>> THAT WAS GOOD.
>> Matt: SO YOU HAVE -- SO
JESTER THAT FINISHES YOUR TURN.
FJORD YOU ARE UP.
>> Travis: IF YOU CAN GO BATS.
HAMMER.
OH, THAT’S 19 AND 21.
>> Matt: BOTH HIT.
>> Travis: GREAT.
THAT IS FUCK, 6-POINTS 6-POINTS
BLAST DAMAGE AND 14-POINTS.
>> Matt: 6 AND A 14?
>> Travis: YES.
>> Matt: A TOTAL OF 20.
HOW DO YOU WANT TO DO THIS?
>> Travis: THE GIANT LOLLIPOP
COMES DOWN ON HIM WELL, LIKE
FUCK.
OVER TO THE BATS.
>> Marisha: AS THE BATS ARE
FLYING OVER CALEB’S NOW
CONSCIOUS BODY LOOKING UP.
>> SCOOT.
GO ON.
SCOOT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Travis: HE’S TRYING TO GET
OUT.
>> GET ON HERE.
>> GET GOING.
>> Matt: AS YOU SWING THROUGH
ONCE REQUEST YOUR STAFF SUDDENLY
A BURST, TWO BURST OF GREENISH
ENERGY AND THE BATS JUST GO
BROWN.
>> I DON’T CARE.
>> Travis: GOT ’EM FOR YOU.
>> TERMS NATER FORCE.
>> DID YOU JUST USE YOUR
FINGERSER?
>> I DID.
>> NOBODY CARED.
THAT.
>> THAT FIGHT COST US AN ARM AND
A --
>> NO.
NO.
>> SO NIGHTTIME HERE IS SUPER
BAD.
>> IT MAKES THEM STRONGER
WHATEVER IT IS.
>> YOU BUT, HEY, AS LONG AS WE
THE GO THE LITTLE GLOWING OR ORB
>> HOW LONG DOES THAT LAST?
>> I A LITTLE WHILE.
>> HOW ARE YOU FEELING
MR. CALEB.
>> Liam: IT’S AN HOUR I THINK.
LET ME LOOK AT THE SPELL.
>> I THOUGHT GROWTH BISECT FOR
YOU A SECOND.
>> OH, GUYS.
>> ONE HOUR.
>> I WILL INSPECT THE BODIES YOU
SAID THEY TURN TODAY PAPE OREGON
SOMETHING?
>> Matt: WHEN YOU SEE THEM DIE
IN THE LIGHT YOU CAN SEE HOW
FRIDGE YOU WOULD THE BODIES
BECOME.
IT LOOKS LIKE LONG DRIED PAPER
PA.
>> Marisha: SHEA THAT BEGINS TO
CRACK IS YOU CHECK THE BODY IT
BREAKS APART AND TURNS TO LIKE
THIN PAPER ASH.
>> THOUGH DON’T GOT ANYTHING.
>> Matt: YOU CAN ROLL AN
INVESTIGATION CHECK?
>> I WILL VERY GENTLY CHECK OUT
ONE OF THESE TREES.
>> 27.
>> Matt: NOT MUCH OF INTEREST.
YOU FIND SOME LIGHT KIND OF
PAPERY SKIN AND LOTS OF THICK
NASTY UP INNING INNARDS.
>> I AM LOOKING AT THIS TREE
THAT THE BATS CAME OUT OF AND
SEE IF THERE IS SOMETHING
INTERESTING THAT CAME OUT OF IT.
12.
>> Matt: IT LOOKS LIKE A TREE,
LOOKS LIKE A GOOD PLACE FOR BATS
TO LIVE.
>> OF MAYBE GRAB A QUIT OF
MUSHROOM AND PUT IT IN MY
POCKET.
>> Matt: IT’S A FUNGUS YOU VERY
MANY SEEN BEFORE IT AS A DULL
TURQUOISE COLORATION TO IT.
THE STALK ITSELF IS GRAY.
UNIQUE.
>> PUT IT IN MY SAMPLE BAG.
>> OKAY.
STARTING TO CRAWL THROUGH AROUND
ON THE GROUND AND PICKING UP
BATS.
AND SQUISHING OUT BAT SHIFT IN
TO A RAG THAT I KEEP HIDDEN.
>> Matt: ALL RIGHT.
>> CHECK AROUND THE ROCK
FORMATION TO SEE IF THERE WAS
ANYTHING THAT THEY HAD PULLED
FROM ANYBODY THAT HAD COME
THROUGH HERE BEFORE.
>> Matt: MAKING AN INVESTIGATION
CHECK.
>> 16.
>> Matt: A LOT OF BONES.
A LOT OF CORPSES THAT HAVE BEEN
GROWN OTHER WITH DRY BRUSH AND
VERY LOWLANDS VEGETATION, YOU
LOOK AT THIS, YOU CAN SEE THE
FORMATIONS THERE SEEMS TO BE A
NUMBER OF INDIVIDUAL TAKE THAT
LIVE AND THRIVED HERE BUT THEY
FLESH WITH THE REST OF THE COLOR
AND STICK AROUND OTHER
FORMATIONS THAT COLLECT WATER.
BUT, YEAH, A NUMBER OF CREATURES
HAVE FALLEN AND BEEN DRAG TODAY
THE SPACE.
>> WE ARE NOT IN THE WILD LANDS
RIGHT?
THAT’S ANOTHER PLACE.
>> YEAH, NO, WE ARE IN THE --
>> Matt: THE CHILD LANDS THAT’S
NORTH.
YOU ARE FAR EAST.
>> IT’S ONLY GETTING DARKER,
RIGHT?
>> Matt: YEAH, ARE YOU DONE
SEARCHING THE SUN IS DOWN.
AND YOU ARE LOOKING AT
NIGHTTIME.
>> CAN I LOOK AT THE AREA OF THE
GROUND THAT THE CREATURE CAME UP
OUT OF BEHIND THE FORMATION AND
SEE DOES IT LOOK -- DIDN’T IT
COME UP OUT OF THE GROUND AT ALL
OR WAS IT JUST CHILLING.
>> Matt: IT WAS SITTING AND
RESTING.
>> GOT IT.
>> Matt: THEY SEEM TO BE CALLED
BY YOUR PRESENCE.
>> OKAY.
>> ARE THERE ANY OF THE BARBS
SPIRES CLOSE BY THAT WERE COMING
OUT OF THE GROUND.
>> Matt: NO.
DO A SYSTEM CHECK.
>> NO.
>> Matt: DISADVANTAGE BECAUSE IT
IS -- YOU HAVE DARK VISION?
>> YEAH.
>> Matt: WHAT DID YOU ROLL?
>> 22.
>> Matt: 22.
>> SHIT.
>> Matt: IT’S HARD TO SEE AND
THE ONLY REASON YOU CAN SEE IS
MOONLIGHT THAT’S PEEKING THROUGH
SOME OF THE CLOUDS THE SKIES
OPENED UP FOR THE NIGHTTIME BIT
AND A LITTLE BEST THE WHITE
MOONLIGHT YOU CAN SEE THE OUTER
SHAPE OF WHAT LOOKS TO BE TWO
LARGE ARE SPIRES ON THE HORIZON,
YOU ARE NOT SURE OF THE
DISTANCE.
BUT YOU CAN SEE THAT THERE ARE A
FEW KIND OF IN THE DIRECTION
THAT YOU ARE TRAVELING.
>> OKAY.
>> WERE THESE CREEP I WAS
ANYTHING LIKE WE WOULD HAVE
HEARD OF BEFORE?
IN STORY BOOKS OR --
>> Matt: YOU CAN MAKE A RELIGION
OR A [ INAUDIBLE ] CHECK.
>> ON BEING.
10.
>> Matt: 10.
I AM NOT SURE WHAT THESE THINGS
ARE BUT THERE IS SOMETHING ABOUT
THAT’S THAT THEY DON’T SEEM TO
BE FROM ALEXANDRIA.
THEIR ESSENCE ISN’T SOMETHING
THAT WOULD NATURAL EXIST ON THIS
PLAIN.
>> THAT LIGHT SENSITIVITY.
>> THEY SEEMED SO SAD.
>> SHOULD WE DOME UP FOR THE
NIGHT.
>> ONE MINUTE.
I AM FEEDING BATS FOR JANIK.
>> MAYBE IT’S TIME TO HAVE A
COUPLE OF THESE CONVERSATIONS.
>> RIGHT.
>> ALL OF THE CLERIC STUFF THAT
YOU CAN ONLY DO AFTER 7:00 P.M.
>> YEAH.
>> COOL.
>> THAT STUFF.
I WOULD RATHER DO IT IN THE
TENT, THE DOME, WHATEVER.
I DON’T LIKE THIS PLACE.
>> I DO THE BEDTIME ROUTINE AND
PUT UP THE DOME.
>> I GATHER DRY BRUSH AND MAKE A
BIT OF FIRE FOR WARMTH AND
LIGHT.
>> WHICH ONE FIRST?
>> WHAT ARE WE CALLING?
>> THE HOBB GOBLIN FIRST.
>> OH, WE ARE TALKING TO THE
DEAD.
>> FIVE QUESTIONS.
>> OKAY.
SO YOU HAVE THE BALL STILL
GIVING OFF DAYLIGHT AS WELL.
>> IT HAS AN HOUR TOTE.
SO WE ARE LIKE FIVE MINUTES IN,
10 MINUTES IN.
>> OKAY.
ALSO A REALLY GOOD BEACON FOR
WHERE WE ARE.
>> WE ARE IN THE DOME WE CAN
OKAY.
>> CAN LIGHT ESCAPE THE DOME?
>> IS THE FIRE IN THE DOME?
>> THAT WAS MY THINKING.
BUT I DON’T KNOW IF -- YEAH.
>> THE DOME DOESN’T TRAP IN
SMOKE OR ANYTHING.
IT JUST DOESN’T LET THINGS IN.
IT ALSO CAN ILLUMINATE FROM THE
INSIDE.
ITSELF.
AND THAT DOESN’T GO OUT OF THE
DOME.
>> OKAY, THAT’S COOL.
>> SO IT KEEPS LIGHT IN?
>> IT GENERATES ITS OWN LIGHT I
BELIEVE SO.
LET ME CHECK THE SPELL.
>> MEANING CREATURES CAN’T SEE
WHAT’S INSIDE THE DOME.
>> COOL.
>> SHOULD WE ASK HIM?
>> WE SHOULD.
>> IF WE TALK TO THIS DEAD HOBB
GONE
GOBLIN, WE THINK MAYBE YOU
SHOULD MAKE YOURSELF LOOK LIKE
THE GUY THAT HE WAS WITH BECAUSE
YOU CAN SOUNDS LIKE HIM, YEAH?
>> OH, YEAH.
>> YOU ARE REALLY GOOD AT
IMPERSONATING PEOPLE AFTER ALL.
>> SOUNDED KIND OF LIKE.
HIGHER CRUST, RIGHT?
>> OKAY.
>> CAN YOU WEAR HIS FACE AS
WELL?
>> SURE.
I REMEMBER.
AND I WILL USE MASK FACES TO
LOOK LIKE EL D R.A. L DUDE.
>> EL DRAL BLAST.
KRKIC HOW DOES THIS LOOK.
>> VERY IMPRESSIVE.
>> I WILL GIVE YOU GROUND RULES
YOU ONLY GET FIVE QUESTIONS.
THIS PERSON WHO ARE THEY ARE
THEY ARE GONE YOU ARE NOT
TALKING TO THEM IT’S A ECHO
THERE IS KNOWLEDGE ANYTHING THAT
CAN BE BARGAINED WITH, NOTHING
THAT CAN BE TRICKED.
THIS IS JUST A REFLECTION.
>> CAN IT LIE?
>> Matt: YES IT, CAN LIE.
>> OKAY.
>> THAT’S WHY WE ARE MAKING HIM
LOOK LIKE HIS BOSS.
>> HE WILL HAVE NO REASON TO
THINK THAT YOU ARE NOT WHO YOU
ARE, BUT YOU HAVE TO REMEMBER
THAT IT ALSO THINKS YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU KNOW.
SO WHEN YOU ASK A QUESTION, YOU
HAVE TO DO SO IN A WAY THAT IS
FAMILIAR AND OPEN AND WITH THE
UNDERSTANDING THAT YOU TWO HAVE
A BOND.
>> WE DIDN’T CATCH THIS GUY’S
NAME, DID WE?
>> Matt: IT WON’T MATTER IF DO
YOU IT RIGHT.
>> WELL WHAT DO WE WANT TO ASK
HIM?
>> HEY, WHAT WAS THE NAME THAT
HAVE HOBB GOBLIN THAT YOU WERE
WITH.
>> WHAT WAS YOUR NAME?
>> ALSO WHAT WAS YOUR NAME, I
CAN FIT IT ALL IN.
>> MAYBE JUST STICK TO WHATEVER
WE WANT TO ASK HIM.
>> I REMEMBER FRIEND AS ALWAYS.
>> OR AS IS LITTLE AS POSSIBLE.
THIS IS JUST A BODIES NOW.
>> HE DIDN’T SEEM LIKE THE TYPE
OF PERSON THAT WOULD SAY FRIEND,
FYI WHEN I HAD THE LITTLE TALK
WITH HIM BEFORE.
>> MAYBE JUST HEY.
>> DO WE HAVE A REQUEST FOR
QUESTIONS?
>> THAT’S GOOD.
>> WHAT DO WE WANT TO KNOW?
WHAT THEY WERE HANDING OFF.
WHAT THEY BOUT WITH THEIR 50
PLATINUM.
>> ALSO WHERE IN BOZO -- BASEL
STANDS, BOZO, EXXON, DO THEY
RESIDE?
IN.
>> JUST SAY THAT YOU NEED THEIR
HELP.
>> HELP FOLLOW WHAT?
>> ANSWERING THESE QUESTIONS.
YOUR MIND IS HAZY.
>> THE SPELL SPEAK WITH DEAD IS
YOU ASKING THE QUESTIONS.
I HAVE TO DO IT.
>> I WAS LOOKING I THINK IT SAID
THAT ANYONE COULD.
I CAN POINT THEM TO YOU.
>> THAT IS WHAT CAN BE DONE.
AS IT SAYS YOU CAN ASK THE
CORPORATION CORPS
THE FIVE QUESTIONS.
>> IF WE WAIT ANOTHER DAY, YOU
CAN MAKE YOU LOOK LIKE THIS
FELLOW.
>> I HAVE AN IDEA.
>> HE CAN LOOK LIKE IT TOO BUT
FJORD CAN SOUND LIKE IT.
>> I WILL MAKE MYSELF LOOK LIKE
BLONDY BEAR.
>> SO I LOOK LIKE THE DRAL AND
YOU LOOK LIKE THE BLONDES.
>> GREG.
GREG BLONDE HEAD.
>> OKAY.
DO YOU SOUNDS LIKE THE BLONDES
HAIRED GUY?
>> NO.
>> I WILL MAKE MYSELF LOOK LIAR
MORROW.
>> I WILL LOOK LIKE THE BUG BEAR
THAT WAS INVISIBLE.
>> I AM ACTUALLY, DID I HAVE A
WEIRD QUESTION WITH THIS.
CAN I DECIDES EVERYBODY THE
STATE OF MYSELF.
>> YEAH.
>> I WILL BE TOP UP A BIT.
I WILL HAVE SOME DAMAGE, I WILL
LOOK LIKE I HAVE BEEN IF A FIGHT
AND LIKE THROAT AND CHEST
DAMAGE.
>> THE REST OF YOU GUYS DOING
ANYTHING.
>> INVISIBILITY.
>> A THINK GOING STEP WAY.
>> BEHIND SO IT DOESN’T SEE.
>> STEP BY MIND.
>> START ROLLING THIS.
>> LET’S DO NUMBER ONE.
>> YOU BURN THE INNOCENCE.
YOU REACH OUT AND TOUCH THE
DISEMBODIED HEAD OF THE HOBB
GONE LYNN THAT YOU HAD SLAIN THE
DAY BEFORE.
YOU HEAR THIS WEIRD SUCKING
SOUND AS IT TRIES TO DRAW AIR
THROUGH A SEVERED NECK.
IT’S EYES FLICKER OPEN.
AND LOOK OUT.
MOVING IN THEIR SOCKETS DRYLY
ACROSS THE SOMEWHAT CONGEALED
MOISTURE IN THE OKAY HE HADS
TOWARDS YOU CADUCEUS.
>> I STEP BEHIND CADUCEUS’
SHOULDER AND SAY, MY FRIEND, IT
IS SO GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
DO ME A FAVOR, TIME IS VERY
SHORT.
ANSWER MY FRIEND’S QUESTIONS
HERE AS QUICKLY AS YOU CAN.
I HAVE PRESSING BUSINESS
ELSEWHERE.
AND I WALK AWAY.
>> Matt: DECEPTION CHECK.
>> DON’T FUCK ME, YOU SON OF A
BITCH.
13.
14.
>> Matt: OKAY.
DID YOU COMPLETE YOUR MISSION?
>> YES.
>> REPEAT YOUR MISSION.
>> KEEP [ INAUDIBLE ] SAFE.
>> MORE SPECIFIC, WHOM, PROVE
YOURSELF.
>> OPEN.
OWEOBAN.
>> 12 YEARS.
>> WHERE WERE YOU GOING TO MEET
UP NORTH, SPECIFIC LOCATION?
>> MAKE A DECEPTION CHECK.
>> GOING FOR IT.
>> 20.
>> YES!
>> THAT THE 20.
>> 17 PLUS 3.
>> NOT A NATURAL 20.
>> STILL GOOD.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> 200.
>> WHAT IS THE NAME OF OUR
ORGANIZATION?
PROVE YOUR IDENTITY.
THE ANGEL OF IRONS.
>> THE ANGEL OF IRONS.
>> A 5.
>> OH, SHIT.
>> THAT WAS SO FUCKING, SICK,
YOU GUYS.
>> THE ANGEL OF IRONS.
>> DOES THAT SOUNDS RIGHT.
THE ANGEL OF IRONS.
>> THE NAME OF THEIR
ORGANIZATION IS THE ANGEL OF
IRONS.
>> THEY FOLLOW THE ANGEL OF
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> OH, MY GOSH.
>> YOU HAVE 90 MORE DECIBELS
BEFORE YOU ARE THERE.
>> I HAVE NEVER DONE THAT THAT
WAY.
THAT WAS INTERESTING.
>> IT WORKED REALLY WELL.
YOU TOTALLY FELL FOR THAT.
THAT HEAD WAS SO STUPID.
>> ONE MOREHEAD.
>> WE FOLLOW THE ANGEL OF IRONS.
WE FOLLOW THE ANGELS OF IRONS.
>> WHAT FUCK IS THAT.
I HAVE NEVER HEARD OF AN ANGEL
OF IRONS.
>> MAKE A RELIGION CHECK.
19.
>> ANYONE THAT WANTS TO MAKE IT,
SURE.
>> YEAH.
>> 13.
>> LET ME MAKE SURE THAT’S A 16,
RIGHT?
>> 22.
>> SO 22.
>> 16.
>> 19.
>> NONE OF YOU HAVE HEARD OF IT.
>> OH.
>> FUCK.
>> ANGEL OF IRONS.
>> THAT WAS A RELIGION CHECK.
>> OKAY.
>> IRONS.
IRONS.
>> WHAT IS OUR OTHER PERSON, THE
DRAGON BORN.
>> WE CAN SEE WHAT SHE WAS
DELIVERING.
>> YEAH.
>> GOOD ASK.
>> DOES THE NAME OBAN MEAN
ANYTHING TO ME.
>> MAKE A HISTORY CHECK.
>> FALSE.
>> 14.
NOPE.
>> BUT IF THIS WAS -- THIS IS A
ARE D R.A. DRAW.
THE DRAW IN THIS AREA FOLLOW
LUXON.
WHAT’S THEIR RELIGION.
>> THE DYNASTY FOLLOW THE LUXON.
>> HE’S NOT PART OF THE DYNASTY.
>> I KNOW, THERE ARE SOME
COMPETING GOD IN THIS.
>> MAYBE.
>> LOTS OF COMPETE THE GOT.
>> THE MAYBE THE ANGEL OF IRONS
ISN’T A GOD MAYBE IT’S LIKE.
>> A LOT OF THINGS.
>> IT COULD JUST BE A BAD DUDE.
>> IT COULD BE A DEMIGOD.
>> DO WE NEED TO TALK TO THE
DRAGON BOARD.
>> I AM GOING TO.
>> YOU COULD LOOK AT THE BLONDE
GUY FOR THIS ONE.
>> I DON’T THINK IT’S NECESSARY.
NOT WITH THIS ONE.
>> OKAY.
>> I AM JUST GOING TO BE MYSELF
FOR THIS ONE.
>> OKAY.
SO YOU DISPEL YOUR DISGUISE.
>> DO YOU WANT ME OVER YOUR
STKPWHROERLD
SHOULDER?
>> NO.
>> I STILL LOOK LIKE THE GUY SHE
WAS MEETING.
>> SHE DID DO THE HAND OFF.
>> OH, SORRY, YEAH.
>> UP TO YOU, THIS IS YOUR CALL.
>> I’LL STAND OVER YOUR
SHOULDER, IT DOESN’T HURT.
>>  I’LL STILL LOOK.
>> YOU POUT THE PULL OUT THE DRA
HEAD.
>> ONE MORE TIME.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> THEY ARE NOT AS GROSS AS THEY
COULD BE.
THAT’S WHAT I AM GOING SAY.
>> LIKE DEADWOOD.
>> AND GO, 10 MINUTES, GETS IT
GOING.
>> IT FALLS ON ITS SIDE AND ITS
YEAH OPENS TO TRY DRAW BREATH.
>> THIS IS SO SANTA CLARITA
TYPE.
>> OH, YEAH.
>> WHAT WAS YOUR ASSIGNMENT
TODAY?
>> THE YEAH OPEN EXAMINES THE
HEAD FALLS TO THE SIDE AGAIN.
BECAUSE IT OPENS THE YEAH IT HAS
TO.
THE DRAGON HEAD.
>> I AM GOING TO HOLD.
THIS IS NOT CIVILIZED.
>> THE ASSIGNMENT YOU GAVE ME.
>> OH, SHIT.
>> THE ASSIGNMENT THAT YOU GAVE
ME.
>> SHIT, THAT’S RIGHT.
>> REPEAT IT TO ME, PLEASE.
>> WHAT WAS THE ASSIGNMENT
SPECIFICALLY.
>> MAKE A DECEPTION CHECK.
COME ON.
>> 13.
>> OH, YOU ARE NOT ON THE GUY.
>> WHICH IS WHY I WOULD LIKE --
THEY DON’T KNOW WHO I AM.
>> I FORGOT ABOUT THAT.
ANSWER THE FIRST QUESTION.
>> I WAS DELIVERING OUR CREST.
>> OUR CREST.
>> DELIVERING A CREST.
OUR CREST.
>> A CREST.
>> THE ANGEL OF IRONS.
>> IS THAT A QUESTION.
>> WHICH CREST, WHOSE CREST I
SUPPOSE WOULD BE THE BETTER
QUESTION.
>> I DON’T KNOW.
WHO IS THE ANGEL OF IRONS?
>> ASK WHO HIS BOSS IS, WHO HE
WAS MEETING.
WHO DO YOU WORK FOR?
>> WHO DID YOU WORK FOR?
WHO DO YOU SERVE?
>> I SERVE NO ONE.
I WORK FOR THOSE WHO PAY ME.
>> OH, DAMN IT.
>> WHO WAS YOUR LAST EMPLOYER?
>> I DON’T KNOW HIS NAME.
>> I THINK THAT’S ALL OF THEM
ACTUALLY.
>> IS THAT IT?
>> KNOWLEDGE MORE DETAILS.
>> A WHOLE BUNCH OF NOTHING.
>> TELL ME WHAT YOU KNOW.
>> WAS THAT OUR CREST.
>> I THINK THAT WAS FIVE.
>> I FEEL LIKE IT MAY HAVE BEEN
FOUR.
>> I FEEL LIKE IT WAS FIVE.
>> I THINK IT WAS FIVE.
>> I GUESS YOU CAN ASK ANYMORE
DETAILS ABOUT WHO --
>> WHERE DID YOU MEET HIM?
>> WHERE DID YOU MEET YOUR LAST
EMPLOYER?
>> STALIN STOCK.
>> TAL INS STADE.
>> TAL INSTADE.
>> DO I KNOW THAT?
>> YOU DO IT’S AN EMPIRE.
>> WHERE IS OUR EMPIRE MAP?
>> HAVE WE BEEN NEAR THAT?
>> NO.
NOT PART OF MY HISTORY.
>> IT’S ON THE OTHER SIDE OF
THE --
>> BOTH BEAUREGARD AND CALEB CAN
MAKE HISTORY CHECKS IF YOU WOULD
LIKE.
>> I LIVE RIGHT NEXT OF THAT.
>> BUT YOU DIDN’T TRAVEL MUCH.
>> NO.
>> YOU CAN MAKE A HISTORY CHECK
TWO TOO.
>> 21.
>> 12.
>> 15.
>> OKAY.
YOU PICK UP A BIT.
>> TALINSTADE IS ESSENTIALLY A
REFUGEE AT THE PRESENT TIME CITY
FOR ABOUT 20 OR SO YEARS OF A
NUMBER OF RAFN ICE THAT FLED THE
DESTRUCTION OF DRAW CONE REQUEST
AND THE EMPIRE WELCOMED THEM IN
BUT DEALT THEM IN THIS AREA AS
THEY WERE PROCESSED AND GIVEN A
PLACE TO STAY AND BECAME A
SETTLEMENT MOAN ASTILLINSTADE.
>> IT’S TEMPORARY.
>> BUT MORE PERMANENT.
>> KPWHAOSZ THE UMPIRE PROPER
FEELINGS ABOUT THEM ARE THEY
JUST TOLERATED?
>> THEY ARE NOT DISCRIMINATED
AGAINST PER SE.
ESPECIALLY WITH WHAT HAPPENED IN
PREVIOUS POLITICAL
RELATIONSHIPSES VARIED DEPEND ON
THE GROUNDS INDIVIDUAL.
THEY ARE MEMBERS OF -- PEOPLE
WHO LIVE IN TALINSTAYED THAT ARE
WORRIED THAT THERE ABOUT BEEN
SURVIVING DRACONIAN NOBLES
HIDING WITHIN THE POLITICAL
STRUCTURE OF THE EMPIRE AND FEEL
LIKE THEY ARE WORKING TO
ELIMINATE THE RAFN OUTS
EXISTENCE OF THE EMPIRE.
AND PERCEIVED FROM THE FAIL OF
DRACONIAN, BUT, YEAH, THAT’S
WHAT THAT CITY IS.
AND IT’S CLOSE TO THE BORDER.
IT’S SOUTH OF BLADE GARDEN.
>> I AM GOING TO GATHER UP THE
HEADS AND PUT THEM BACK IN THE
BAG.
>> OKAY.
>> WHO IS IT YOU WANTED KNEE
SEND MESSAGES TO AGAIN?
>> WELL, SHOULD WE -- SHOULD WE
MESSAGE THE BRIGHT QUEEN AND
JUST SAY MISSION IS CONTINUING.
ALMOST TO THE END.
>> JUST AS PLANNED.
FOLLOWING OUR GUYS.
>> I THINK WE SHOULD KEEP HER IN
THE DARK FOR THE TIME BEING.
>> NO NEWS IS GOOD NEWS.
>> YEAH.
>> AGREED.
>> CERTAINLY SHE HEARD OF THE
ACTION AROUND HER TOWN TODAY.
>> THAT’S MUDDY.
>> DO YOU WANT TO TRY AND
MESSAGE THE ONE THAT WE ARE
CHASING AND PRETEND TO THROW HIM
OFF THE TRAIL AND IF HE IS
KEEPING TABS ON US, HE’LL LET US
KNOW?
>> OR CHECK IN WITH YOUR FAMILY.
>> I HAVE THREE SENDINGS I CAN
SEND MULTIPLE THINGS.
>> WE CAN ALSO CHECK WITH NBA
WITH MORROW AND SEE IF ANYONE
SHOWED UP.
>> MORROW, I WILL START WITH
MORROW.
>> OKAY.
>> HEY, MORROW, ANY OTHER PEOPLE
SHOW UP THERE, THIS IS THE BLUE
GIRL?  REMEMBER WE’LL KILL YOU
IF YOU ARE LYING.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> ALSO, YOU ARE SUPER CUTE.
THANKS FOR THE HAIR STUFF.
>> PERFECT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> YEAH.
>> IT’S A LITTLE WEIRD, YEAH, I
AM FINE.
NOBODY ELSE REALLY SHOWED UP.
A COUPLE OF CUSTOMERS.
JUST BUYING THE USUAL.
DON’T KILL ME!
>> MORROW IS FINE, EVERYTHING IS
FINE.
EVERYTHING IS GOOD.
WHO ELSE SHOULD I TALK TO?
>> I WOULD LOVE TO CHECK IN JUST
TELL YAZ WE ARE STILL OKAY, BUT
I DON’T.
TO WASTE A SPELL.
>> HOLE YAZA.
>> THERE’S TWO, WE ARE ALL SAFE,
DON’T WORRY ABOUT US.
WE FOUGHT THESE GUYS WITH LIKE
FIVE ARMS, WHOA, WE ALMOST DIED.
BUT NO, WE ARE GOOD, WE ARE
GOOD.
ALSO --
>> THAT’S IT.
>> OH, OKAY.
WELL, I -- I AM GLAD TO HEAR YOU
ARE GOOD.
I WILL PROBABLY JUST CLEAN UP A
LITTLE BIT.
>> BUT NO, WE ARE GOOD.
>> IT’S COLD.
>> YOU SHOULD HAVE BOUGHT HUM A
COAT OR SOMETHING BEFORE WE
LEFT.
>> THERE IS A HOT TUB.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> BUT HE HAS TO BOIL THE WATER
HIMSELF NOW.
>> THAT’S TRUE.
>> TELL BETH I LOVE HER.
>> HE LOVES YOU SO MUCH.
>> LAST PERSON.
>> I THINK IT’S WORSE.
>> I AM THINKING A LOT ABOUT
YOUR CHILD AND YOUR MOTHER’S
HOUSE AND I AM NOT SURE THAT
YOUR MOTHER’S HOUSE IS BEST
PLACE TO SEND YOUR CHILD AFTER
ALL PERHAPS.
>> WHY?
>> WELL, WHAT IF THE LETTER THAT
YOU TWO SENT HAS BROUGHT
ATTENTION THERE.
>> BUT HERE IS THE THING, CALEB,
YOU KNOW, MOST PEOPLE DON’T KNOW
MY MOM’S LAST NAME.
YOU KNOW, SHE’S THE RUBY OF THE
SEA.
SO THEY WOULD HAVE TO REALLY DO
SOME RESEARCH AND I DON’T KNOW
HOW LIKE SMART THE PEOPLE ARE
THAT ARE IN YOUR ORGANIZATION.
BUT THEY PROBABLY WOULDN’T BE
ABLE TO FIGURE IT OUT, RIGHT?
>> MY POINT STILL STANDS.
>> OKAY.
WHAT IF I SEND A MESSAGE TO THE
OWNER OF THE [ INAUDIBLE ]
>> AND SAY?
>> AND SAY WHAT?
ACCIDENTALLY MIGHT HAVE ALERTED
THE WORST PEOPLE IN THE WORLD.
>> HEY --
>> BE CAREFUL.
>> IF THE PERSON THAT --
>> I THINK FOR NOW, YOU KNOW,
YOUR MOTHER IS PROBABLY ALL
RIGHT -- MAYBE NOTHING IS
HAPPENING, BUT IF THEY HAVE BEEN
ALERTED TO HER.
MAYBE THEY ARE WATCHING AND IF
THE CHILD SHOWS UP, I -- IT
SEEMS LIKE AN UNNECESSARY RISK.
>> THERE IS NOWHERE ELSE FOR HIM
TO GO.
IT’S REALLY SAFE.
AND THEN AT THE LEAST MY MOM CAN
FIND SOMEWHERE ELSE TO GO.
>> DOES YOUR MOM HAVE SAVE
HOUSES ARE ANYTHING.
>> OF COURSE SHE DOES SHE KNOWS
A LOT OF PEOPLE.
>> SHOULD SHE GO THERE NOW?
>> THAT WOULD BE KIND OF HARD
TO.
>> SHE WOULD JUST BE GOING TO A
SAFE HOUSE FOR NO REASON.
>> IT’S JUST SHE DOESN’T LIKE
TO, YOU KNOW, LEAVE.
SO IT WOULD BE HARD FOR HER TO
GO TO THE.
>> SHE DOESN’T LIKE TO LEAVE HER
HOUSE?
BECAUSE OF WORK?
>> YES, NO.
SHE JUST DOESN’T FEEL
COMFORTABLE, YOU KNOW.
>> IS SHE SCARED OF THE OUTSIDE
OR SOMETHING?
>> A LITTLE.
THAT’S THE IMPRESSION I GOT.
IT MAKES HER ANXIOUS, YOU KNOW.
>> OH.
>> SHE FEELS SAFE.
IN THE SHADOW.
>> MAYBE IT’S WORTH USING THAT
LAST MESSAGE BALL TO JUST CHECK
IN WITH HER?
>> MAKE SURE SHE’S OKAY.
>> YEAH.
SEE IF ANY RUFFIANS OR WEIRDOES
HAVE BEEN HANGING OUT.
>> DIFFERENT CLIENTELE THAN
USUAL.
>> WHAT DOES ASTRID LOOK LIKE?
>> WELL, SHE’S -- WELL, SHE WAS
ON THE SHORT SIDE.
>> PROBABLY STILL SHORT.
>> ABOUT YOUR HEIGHT.
>> I AM NOT SHORT.
>> HOW TALL ARE YOU?
>> 5’3".
>> ABOUT THERE.
>> OKAY.
>> WHEN I KNEW HER SHE HAD VERY
SHORT HAIR.
IT WAS DARK BROWN.
>> OKAY.
>> THIS WAS A LONG TIME AGO.
>> WHAT COLOR WERE HER EYES.
>> THEY WERE BROWN.
>> BROWN EYES.
>> DID SHE HAVE ANY SCARS OR
ANY, YOU KNOW, FEATURES THAT
WERE SUPER PROMINENT.
>> SCARS ON OUR HER ARMS, JUST L
YOURS.
>> I COULD BE WORRIED ABOUT
NOTHING, BUT IF YOUR MOTHER HAS
BEEN COMPROMISED IN SOME WAY, IT
IS TO LATE.
BUT IT IS NOT TOO LATE FOR YOUR
CHILD.
IT SEEMS LIKE A BAD IDEA TO SEND
HIM THERE.
IT PAINS ME TO SAY THAT.
>> I TRUST YOU.
>> NOT GOING TO BE THERE FOR
SOMETIME.
>> THAT’S TRUE.
IT WOULD TAKE MORE WEEKS FOR
THEM TO TRAVEL.
MAYBE WE SHOULD TELL THEM TO
HOLD UNTIL WE KNOW MORE.
>> MAYBE HE CAN GO FOR THE
WIZARDS’ TOWER.
I DON’T KNOW WHAT THE WIZARDS
FEELS ABOUT THIS RIGHT NOW.
>> I WOULD LIKE TO MAYBE BRING
YOUR CHILD TO.
>> LET’S CHECK IN WE ARE MAKING
A LOT OF ASSUMPTIONS ON
INFORMATION WE DON’T FULLY KNOW
YET.
>> NO.
>> IT’S A VERY US THING TO DO.
BUT --
>> I SEND THE MESSAGE TO MY MOM.
>> OKAY.
>> HI.
LITTLE WORRIED SOMEONE MAY BE
COMING TO THE CHATEAU.
IF YOU SEE A GIRL.
>> I AM WORRIED FROM THE TONE OF
YOUR VOICE I WILL KEEP A LOOK
OUT.
I HOPE EVERYTHING IS OKAY.
COME BACK SOON.
I MISS YOU.
THAT’S ALL.
>> SHE MISSES ME.
I DON’T HAVE ANY OTHER SPELLS.
>> IF YOU TALK TO HER AGAIN, I
MEAN THEY COULD SEND ANYONE I
SUPPOSE, BUT THE OTHER BOY, THAT
I WAS WITH, HE WAS LARGE, HIS
HAIR WAS CROPPED VERY CLOSELY
LIKE MINE WAS, BUT, I MEAN, MY
HAIR IS LONG NOW SO THAT MEANS
NOTHING, HIS HAIR WAS BLACK, HIS
EYES WERE BLUE.
HE WAS MUSCULAR.
HE WAS STRONG.
IN ADDITION TO BEING TALENTED.
FOR THE FUTURE.
>> TALENTED AT --
>> THE ARCING.
>> YEAH, OKAY.
>> SO HERE IS BUFF -- SO HE WAS
BUFF AND HE CAN CAST SPELLS?
WELL, THAT’S NOT FAIR.
>> I WILL LET MY MOM KNOW THAT
THE NEXT TIME I TALK TO HER.
>> SHALL WE TURN IN.
>> I BELIEVE SO.
>> JUST TO MAKE LIFE EASIER I
WILL SPEND THE LAST 10 MINUTES
BEFORE WE GO TO SLEEP CASTING A
PRAYER OF HEALING FOR ANYBODY
THAT NEEDS HP BEFORE THEY
RESTORE THEIR OWN STUFF.
>> I WILL NOT TURN THAT DOWN.
>> THESE PRIDE I GOOD.
>> HE WILL WICK ME IF HE
SEASONING.
>> ROLL POSSESSION CHECK.
>> BUS ART.
>> NATURAL.
OKAY.
>> WE ARE SAFE.
>> I HAVE TROUBLE SLEEPING
TONIGHT.
>> SO THE NIGHT DRAWS ON.
SOMEWHAT RESTFUL SLEEP FINDS
MOST OF YOU.
THE MORE THAN MORNING COMES BACK
OF THE SUN SURPRISES THE STY
CLOUDED THAT WAS THE DAY BEFORE.
NOT QUE ACE THE MORNING GREETS
YOU, GATHERING YOUR THINGS.
AND CONTINUES ON FOR YOUR THIRD
DAY.
TO GET THERE, THERE WAS A LITTLE
BIT OF SLOWING AT CERTAIN
POINTS, YOU TOOK A BREAK RIGHT
AS YOU REACHED THE EDGE.
YOU HAVE THREE DAYS OF TRAVEL.
>> WELL MAKE UP THERE.
>> DAMN IN.
>> I WANTED TO KEEP PLAYING.
>> ONE MORE.
>> ONE MORE DAY.
>> JUST ONE MORE DAY.
>> IT’S 10:30 WE CAN KEEP GOING
UNTIL LEVEL ARE 11.
>> IT’S UP TO YOU GUYS.
>> I WANT TO READ SOME -- I WANT
TO READ SOME STUFF.
>> I WANT TO READ SOME STUFF
BEFORE I GO.
>> OKAY.
>> I HAVE SOME STUFF TO READ.
>> I GOTTA GET HOME AND PUMP.
>> YOU UP.
>> PUMP, YOU UP.
>> ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT THEN WE’LL PICK IT UP
NEXT THURSDAY.
>> ONE MORE.
LIKE OLD TIMES, YEAH, EIGHT HOUR
GAMES.
>> YEAH.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> A PUMP MACHINE.
>> SIT ON A THROWN.
>> I KNOW.
ALL RIGHT, WELL, TAKE IT UP NEXT
WEEK IN THE 19 TIME, GUYS, HAVE
A WONDERFUL WEEK.
WE’LL SEE YOU SOON, LOVE YOU
VERY MUCH.
>> HAPPY RED NOSE DAY.
>> WE RACED $100,000.
>> NO SHIT, ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
>> YOU ARE FUCKING KIDDING.
>> WHAT?
>> THE CRITTERS ARE INSANE.
>> YOU GUYS, ARE NUTS.
>> TAKE THAT CHILD POVERTY.
>> YEAH.
THAT’S SO COOL YOU ARE AMAZING.
I GUESS THURSDAY.
>> ONE MORE HOUR.
♪ MUSIC PLAYING ♪