(no audible dialogue)
MATT: My name is Matthew Mercer,
Dungeon Master for the show.
Welcome to the
chaos of this evening.
Before we get into
our actual game story,
and the thread of what has
transpired in recent events,
we're gonna go through
our quick announcements.
First and foremost, tonight's
episode is sponsored by us!
Sponsored by the new year.
Sponsored by, hopefully,
have our sponsor
contracts finalized soon,
and we can have an
actual sponsor soon,
but until then,
we are sponsored
by you awesome people who
come and watch the show.
I think Sam had
prepared a bit.
SAM: What-- I, yeah,
I prepared a bit.
That's pretty much it.
Now, I'm gonna need
a little quiet,
because we've gotten a
lot of feedback from fans,
and so, this new feature
we're gonna roll out.
We're gonna have
a telephone number
that people can call
and complain to,
so I just wanted to--
I think I can use this mic
if everyone can be quiet.
I'm gonna just record our
outgoing message for the--
the new phone line that
we're setting up right now.
So stand by.
Thank you for calling
Critical Role customer support.
We value from your feedback and
want to improve your experience.
If you're calling
to argue against
one of Matthew Mercer's many,
many rule violations, press one.
If you're calling to cry
because Ashley Johnson
isn't on this episode,
mash your forehead into
your number pad repeatedly.
If you're calling to lodge a
complaint about Marisha Ray
or the character of Keyleth,
or how nothing she
ever does is cool,
press three.
You will be given five minutes
to rant and don't worry.
Your message will make Marisha
feel like shit within 24 hours.
Quiet, guys.
If you would
like to complain about
the technical
aspects of the Twitch stream,
please hang up and
call 1-800-hashtag
W-E-K-N-O-W.
If you are offended by something
Sam Riegel said on the stream,
you can go
fuck yourself.
Thank you for
your support.
Okay, that's it.
MATT: Good, good.
(laughter, applause)
(talking over each other)
LIAM: Pick up.
Can I just, on behalf
on all of us?
(humming)
MATT: We miss you, Ashley.
We miss you.
LAURA: Always, always.
TRAVIS: Start crying before
the show starts.
MARISHA: I look forward to
all the voicemails.
-SAM: Uh-huh.
-LAURA: Yeah, so many.
LIAM: It's already full.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
It's like our very own
This American Life episode.
-I'm so excited.
-MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: Thank you, Sam, for
that fantastic message.
LIAM: Wow!
MATT: We have some-- I think,
some merch updates
if you want to
take that, Laura.
LAURA: Oh, yes, we do!
So if you guys check
the store right now,
there should be some Strongjaw
Ale shirts available.
I was getting some tweets
about it, that, you know,
we hadn't put those in
store for a long time,
so, we made some more
and put them in the store.
Along with the
Gilmore shirts, and the
How do you want
to do this?
and the regular
logo shirt.
All of those things
available plus there are some
How do you want to
do this? hoodies left
from the pre-order stock
that we had a long time ago,
so, there's a few of those
left in the store, and...
(ding)
I have a tweet.
Sorry.
Sorry about that, and
we also have these new,
wait, where'd I put it?
-LIAM: On the back of your book.
-LAURA: Where's my book?
-LIAM: This is it.
-LAURA: Oh, I have it out.
We have vinyl stickers now,
you guys.
Aren't they so spiffy?
TRAVIS: Oh, yeah, look at it.
LAURA: Yeah, I'm excited
about those, so those are--
Those are here.
Those are in the
store for you.
-SAM: For sale?
-LAURA: For sale, Sam!
TRAVIS: Do we get them for free,
do we get them?
LAURA: You get-- you get--
you want one?
-LIAM: Heavily discounted.
-LAURA: Here you go.
-LAURA: Do you guys want some?
MARISHA: Yeah!
I'll put it on
my white car.
(laughter)
LAURA: So, yeah, there's
all that stuff.
SAM: Amazing.
-TRAVIS: Those are awesome.
-LAURA: Yeah.
And we have
more hats too.
There's hats again.
All these things, you guys.
Just so many things.
-TALIESIN: Loot!
-MATT: We're trying to keep up.
LAURA: Yeah, we're trying to do away
with, like, the whole, you know,
pre-order and wait a really
long time to get your stuff,
so, now we're trying
to keep things in stock
so you can
actually buy it.
TRAVIS: Yeah, trying to get
it to you sooner.
LAURA: Yeah!
MATT: Alright, thank you, Laura.
Also want to mention for those
who want to check it out.
We've been running it
for a few months now,
but we have our
Talks Machina
Critical Role after-show
Tuesday nights,
7:00PM Pacific time
here on Twitch.
And Alpha.
It's hosted by our amazing Brian Foster.
TRAVIS: He's a dick!
MATT: He is a dick, and
that's part of his charm.
But yeah, so if you
haven't checked it out,
you can come and watch us
answer your community questions
or ask questions to
the @TalksMachina Twitter
and watch us fumble
our way through
trying to explain
our inane actions
in the dice
role-playing RPG
we play
every week.
Anyway, check that out.
Anybody else have anything
else they want to talk about
or mention or--
or say something?
TRAVIS: Say-- say something?
MATT: Say something?
MARISHA: You guys want
to say anything?
You didn't say
anything this time.
Do you want to say how
much you love everybody?
-SAM: Huh?
-LAURA: Oh, man.
MATT: Alright, let's go ahead and get
us down to tonight's episode.
SAM: Bring on the catharsis!
MATT: Of Critical Role!
(yelling)
LAURA: Oh God, I got to--
SAM: We're not out,
we're not out.
TRAVIS: We're not--
(screaming)
♪
(electricity crackling)
MATT: Hello everyone
and welcome back.
So, get you up to speed
with what's recently
happened in our game.
Vox Machina, our
band of adventurers,
have been traveling
across Tal'Dorei,
continents and planes
of existence beyond,
in search of the
Vestiges of Divergence.
Magical artifacts that
can help outfit them
for their coming struggle
against the Chroma Conclave,
a group of chromatic
dragons that had terrorized
and conquered the
Tal'Dorei countryside
for quite some time now.
At the end of
this venture,
you've all, acquiring
your relics of power,
your levels of experience,
and the allies you've amassed
through this journey,
converged upon the central
capitol city of Emon
in hopes of
finally defeating
and destroying
Thordak, The Cinder King.
You made a tenuous
relationship
with a member
of the Conclave,
Raishan, the Diseased
Deceiver, the green dragon,
and after killing the other
three members of the Conclave,
you went in with
armies at your back,
Ashari in the sky,
who laid siege to the city
as you snuck beneath
the streets of Emon,
emerging on the outskirts
of the Cloudtop district
through the help of your two
allies: Zahra and Kashaw.
You managed to bypass
two waiting fire giants,
push straight into the center
of the mostly ruined
cloud topped district
where you confronted
Thordak, The Cinder King,
in his large, swollen powerful,
primordial red dragon form.
(shivers)
LAURA: Sorry.
-TALIESIN: I was with you.
-TRAVIS: Gross.
MATT: It's a favored
enemy, right?
Just checking.
You came prepared with--
with allies at your sides
and full power
you tore into Thordak
and while many
blows were sustained
on both sides
of the fray,
Thordak fell on
the battlefield.
In those moments,
as Thordak attempted
to retreat into his lair,
you, Vax, gave chase
and slew the dragon
using Whisper
in your grasp.
As a few of you came up
behind, Raishan, as well,
asked as part of the
accord you had made
to be given some time
with the corpse of Thordak.
It was decided that
this was not to be allowed.
She was not to be trusted,
and an attack was made on Raishan.
Though Raishan
also had made
a few unique choices of
her own leading up to it.
This led to a confrontation in
Thordak's lair beneath the city
where you
all nearly got
your asses
handed to you.
By-- by a
well-prepared Raishan.
However, in the midst
of this battle,
you did summon your
ally, J'Mon Sa Ord.
They're the leader
of Ank'Harel,
the distant city on the
continent of Marquet,
and a brass dragon, who
upon arriving in this fray,
full health and
ready to fight,
was enough of a threat
to drive Raishan off
in her damaged form before
she could finish you off
in your-- the
state you were in.
SAM: So, it was worth it.
TALIESIN: Yeah, it was
definitely worth it.
LAURA: Yeah!
TALIESIN: Yeah, it was worth it.
MATT: However, you were
then kept at bay
by a wall of force
as Raishan took two
of Thordak's strangely
existing eggs
and flew into a tunnel
towards the corpse of Thordak
and then disappeared in
a flash of purple energy
before the wall dropped
and you all just arrived
halfway through the tunnel
where the corpse
of Thordak once lay
to find it missing
along with Raishan
and the eggs that
she had gathered.
And that was where
we had left off.
So, as the rest of your
party begins running up,
winded, bloodied
and still reeling
from the intensity of the
battle you just fought,
you have the intense
heat of a nearby cavern,
the hints of-- of cracked
red-hot Earth and rock
that are kind of protruding
in small sections.
The sweat just
pouring down your face.
You run up and
you can see the trail.
The pool of blood that once
was driven by the wounds
left by your blade at the side
of Thordak's corpse-- missing.
The impact crater
of Thordak's landing
still carved into the
side of this curved tunnel.
You see, as
Kima rushes up.
Out of breath,
you see Gilmore rush up
and push his hair
out of his face
and there's a
moment of silence
as you all kind of take
in what has just transpired.
What do you want to do?
TRAVIS: Using my magic,
can I detect
which direction
the beast fled?
-MATT: No.
-TRAVIS: Okay.
I don't know anything.
LAURA: Should we get,
I don't know,
does it matter to
get any of his blood?
Maybe we can
track him easier?
-MARISHA: Yeah.
-LAURA: The body?
SAM: Thordak's blood?
LAURA: Yeah, Thordak's blood.
MATT: Okay, so you go
ahead and you pull--
Do you have empty
vials currently?
LAURA: I took a lot of potions,
so I'm assuming so.
MATT: Yes, you would
actually, so yeah.
So you take some
of the-- the mostly
or completely emptied healing
potion vials and collect--
LAURA: I lick,
I lick the bottle
for all the
remaining healing.
-MATT: Little straw.
-LAURA: Like a Capri-Sun.
MATT: Yeah, exactly.
Okay.
MARISHA: I head back
into the chamber
and see if I can
find any of, like,
Raishan's scales or,
like, Raishan blood or...
LAURA: Maybe give it a moment
just to let the lair actions
die down a little bit.
LIAM: What?
LAURA: The-- you know, all the lava
stuff happening in there.
MARISHA: I'll watch from a distance
and make sure that, you know,
it's not boiling over.
-LAURA: It's safe?
-MARISHA: Yeah.
LIAM: I'm gonna limp up to you.
You're burnt all over.
-MARISHA: Yeah.
-LIAM: Hold still for a second.
MARISHA: That really sucks.
I want to assume
that was karma.
-Yeah.
-LIAM: Alright.
I do have--
MARISHA: I feel really bad
for that duergar now.
That sucks.
That's a
rough way to go.
(laughter)
LIAM: I cover her mouth with
my hand for a second
and use the last of
Lay on Hands and I--
I checked with CritRoleStats,
I do have ten left.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: So I'm gonna use
eight, eight of those
to heal you up a bit.
-MARISHA: Okay.
-LAURA: Eight whole points.
-LIAM: I only got ten.
-LAURA: Romeo.
What do you do
with those last two?
TALIESIN: I just imagine
like light slapping
in the face
just eight times.
Pow, hit point, hit point.
MARISHA: Lay on Hands,
Lay on Hands.
LIAM: One, two, three,
four, five, six.
MATT: The Oath of Annoyance Paladin.
Coming soon in the
Tal'Dorei campaign book.
LIAM: Thordak died like this.
(laughter)
MATT: Alright, so as
Vax heals you up
with some of the remnants
of his divine power still--
still in his body.
Kima's kind of walking
up to Keyleth
and Gilmore goes over
and starts helping you
gather and
separate some of the--
What little blood you can.
A lot of its kind
of just dug into the--
the rock and the dust
but there are a little bit
that you can kind
of pull into it.
It's not too
clustered and filled
with the equivalent
of coffee grinds.
What else are
you guys doing?
TALIESIN: Once the lair is safe, I want to
get in and start examining it.
-MARISHA: Same.
-LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: Okay.
It takes, I'd say,
probably a good two minutes
or so before the--
the general tremors of
the lair begin to subside.
The presence of Thordak
being long enough removed
that the volcanic
activity begins
to come to a
small, gentle end.
LAURA: Actually, before
we go back in,
can I peek up on
the surface level
and see if it looks like
the fighting has died down?
LIAM: I was just about
to say the same.
MATT: Uh, okay, you
guys go up there?
-LAURA: Yeah.
-LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: Okay.
Everyone else staying down?
-TRAVIS: Yep.
-(Same) Yeah.
MATT: Okay, while you
guys are waiting,
the two of you
rush up to the surface.
The outside of the opening
to Thordak's lair.
Both of you guys
make perception checks.
TRAVIS: Don't die.
-LAURA: Twenty-seven.
-LIAM: Twenty-nine.
MATT: Okay.
As you both
peek through the--
the heated clouds
of soot and ash
that are billowing
out from inside,
your vision clarifies and
you can see up into the sky
the thunderstorm that
has been encompassing
the vicinity of Emon.
It's still rolling
and firing off
bolts of lightning
and thunder.
(imitates thunder clap)
In the distance.
It is beginning
to slowly subside
to the size that it began,
but you also notice
that the wyvern riders
that once rapidly
swung through the air
are all retreating en masse.
The few that still remain
into the southwest end of,
now maybe, about a
half mile off Emon,
and a number of
them are fleeing
and catching up with them.
It looks like they're
being fended off
and the tides, at least,
have turned somewhat
from where they
began here in Emon.
You also do
notice that the--
the two doors that you
guys originally entered,
that you pushed through?
One of the doors is now
pushed off of its hinges
and has fallen
to the ground.
The other is kind
of partway off that--
that giant gate doorway,
and just beyond it,
you see what looks
to be battle still ensuing.
You hear the muffled screams
echoing from outside that gate
and streets beyond in Emon
of hundreds of soldiers
shouting into battle.
Large heaving war cries
of deep voiced giant-kin.
You see bursts of
flame in the distance
and what looks
to be bodies
occasionally flung
through the air
to disappear past the
horizon beyond the gate top.
This-- there is still
warfare raging in this city.
LIAM: Can we see through that gate to
where we parted with Kashaw?
MATT: From this distance, you
cannot get that much more.
You can just
see the motion of--
You have to get closer.
LAURA: So, we can't-- can
I reach into my shirt
and grab out that note
that was on the arrow?
I never read it.
-MATT: Oh, yeah.
-LAURA: What is it?
MATT: It says, My gift to you,
darling, use it well.
LAURA: Oh, I knew it!
We have to find them.
LIAM: Let's go look.
-Just a look.
-LAURA: Just stealth.
To see if it looks
like the giant is gone,
and if Zahra and
Kash are around.
LIAM: Why don't we just cover
like half the distance?
-See what we can see from there.
-LAURA: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
MATT: Okay, stealth
check both you guys.
♪
LIAM: Twenty-eight.
LAURA: Twelve.
-MATT: Wow.
-LAURA: I know.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: I'm-- you know, I've--
I'm injured grievously.
MATT: You are.
You snatched from the
jaws of death temporarily,
you find yourself
physically affected
more than you
would have expected
and what seemed to you as
just an instant of darkness,
and as you begin to try and
follow after your brother,
you find yourself stumbling
and falling to one knee
and trying
best to keep up.
LAURA: Oh, shit.
MATT: At this time, you
notice two figures
running from the opening in
that gate in your direction.
You see it first, but you
see it for a moment after him.
You see bloodied, bruised,
but still in a full sprint
both Kashaw and Zahra
rushing in your direction
and you hear Kash
just yelling out,
"Vox Machina!
You're alive, right?"
LAURA: Keep it down, you fuck!
Come on, come on
into this hole.
MATT: "Hole?"
"Yes, the hole, darling."
"Right."
And they both rush up
and as you guys are
catching up with them,
you notice, by the gate,
pushing through
what looks to be
another fire giant
wielding a sword
kind of dragged behind,
kind of pour through.
(yells)
And just begins
going into a--
a large bounding
sprint in your direction.
-LAURA: Oh, God.
-LIAM: Running.
LAURA: Giants, giants at the door.
-Giants!
-TALIESIN: I am moving towards it.
TRAVIS: Yeah, now we're all going
on up towards the hole.
-MATT: Okay.
-LAURA: Can I shoot an arrow at him?
MATT: As you're saying "giants"
into your ear,
you watch as two
crossbow bolts kinda...
into the back of the head
of the giant and giant goes...
and stops and looks
over the shoulder
and you see a flash
of light behind him.
An impact into the back of the
black ironed giant's armor.
Like a sudden impact of a fiery
meteor just slams into it.
(yells)
And the giant
stumbles to one knee
before another blow
hits him right across
the back of the head
and the fire giant
just falls on face first
unconscious onto the ground.
Little cloud of dust and dirt
kind of billows up to the sides.
There you see, by
the front of the gate,
you see Jarret with crossbow
right there and standing,
and now stepping up onto the
back of the giant's armor
and slamming a flashing
bright radiant war hammer
into the back of its neck.
You see,
in chain mail,
long beard,
white streaked,
billowing war torn
hair pulled into
a tight ponytail
towards the back,
a familiar face.
You see Kerrek,
currently of white--
of Westruun standing,
wipes his brow
and looks up and takes notice
of your presence immediately.
Patrick, if you want
to come on the stage.
LAURA: What the fuck?
(applause, cheers)
SAM: Geez, Louise!
Patrick Rothfuss.
LAURA: Scooch on by since it's
so easy to make your way.
(laughing)
MATT: Our set is so conducive
to movement.
TRAVIS: Oh!
I didn't break it.
-LAURA: The whole set falls down.
-MATT: I know!
LAURA: Kerrek, you can fight!
PATRICK: I get to sit
next to my besty.
MARISHA: Yeah!
My new besty.
-LIAM: What in the fuck?
-LAURA: I thought you were--
I thought--
you can fight?
PATRICK: Uh.
LAURA: Uh, yeah, you just brought
down a giant, no big deal.
PATRICK: Uh, team effort.
Like is everything cool now?
Like is this
the last of them?
MATT: For one, I think you might
want to move a little bit over
to get into the camera.
TRAVIS: Yes, come on over.
MATT: Just a smidge
for the audience.
-LAURA: Yeah.
-LIAM: Yeah, yeah.
MATT: There you go,
and as you've been in this
fray for quite some time
and the exhaustion's starting
to mount on you a bit,
and the--
the two individuals
that you and your--
your allies have come upon,
being the smaller unit,
you manage to penetrate
further into the city
then the main armies that were
pushing towards the gates.
You saw the
golden-armored human
and the Tiefling
currently struggling with,
what looked to be,
five fire giants.
Three that had come up behind
the two that they had ensnared,
and after minutes of battle
and tearing through them
it looks like you
finally gain the upper hand.
You've lost a number
of allies through this--
this incursion, however,
these are the really, really
familiar welcome faces
given the perpetual
onslaught that you've seen
since you first
arrived in Emon.
PATRICK: He--he probably just says,
"Is it done?"
LAURA: Is it?
PATRICK: That's his--
that's his opener.
LAURA: I mean, eh.
LIAM: Ish.
LAURA: Thordak was killed.
MATT: Kashaw pipes up and says,
"So you killed the thing?
You killed it,
it's dead, right?"
LAURA: Mm-hmm.
MATT: "Please tell me
you killed the thing."
LAURA: Yes, the thing is dead.
-LIAM: We killed thing.
-LAURA: And gone.
Literally, gone.
-MATT: "Great."
-LAURA: Stolen.
MATT: "Fantastic, that's--
that's wonderful, great."
-"We can go home."
-PATRICK: Stolen?
LAURA: Can I hug Zahra?
MATT: Yeah, she-- she
eagerly puts her arms out
and as you guys kind
of embrace real fast,
she kind of-- both of you
almost, from the impact,
stop, the bruising sets in.
-MATT: "Darling, careful."
-LAURA: Yeah, yeah, I know, darling.
Injured.
PATRICK: How-- how do
these guys look?
MATT: You don't see them yet,
you just see these two.
And after a moment
of these hugs happen,
you kind of
catch your breath.
You notice a few
more figures appear
from out of this large
craterous hole in the ground
in the center of
this ruined district,
and from there you watch
as the familiar Percival,
Scanlan, oh no,
you stay behind?
Grog and Keyleth all
emerge from the hole.
PATRICK: How's she look?
SAM: Whoo!
MATT: A little-- a little
singed, a little burned.
A little worse
for wear, but alive.
Can't say that
much different
from the rest of
her allies as well.
PATRICK: Okay.
I might actually kind of lumber
a little bit in that direction
as if I were going in for a hug,
and then stop when I remember
that maybe I'm not
that sort of person.
(laughter)
It looks-- it looks
actually very awkward.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Oh, good.
This is-- this is a face
I would like to see.
MARISHA: Kerr?
LAURA: He just killed
a giant with his
giant hammer of
blazing white--
MARISHA: Keyleth just
closes the distance
and runs up and
just hugs Kerr.
PATRICK: Big bear hug,
big bear hug.
MARISHA: What are you doing here?
PATRICK: Same as everyone.
Been doing-- doing as
much as a person can do.
MARISHA: I got your gift.
PATRICK: I'm so glad of that.
-MARISHA: It meant everything.
-PATRICK: Oh.
MARISHA: Maybe even a little
too literally, like--
like 20 minutes ago.
A lot of passing through
fire here lately.
PATRICK: Yeah.
TALIESIN: To break the
awkward briefly, dear.
TRAVIS: Yeah, much
war still happening.
-LAURA: Maybe we should go down.
-TALIESIN: Wait!
MARISHA: I sky write up in the air,
is there like a--
like a sigil of Emon?
Like a--
MATT: I mean, there is a
crest for the city.
You can do a simplified
version of it, if you like.
MARISHA: I do that into the
sky with Sky Write.
MATT: Okay, so the storm,
which is still raging,
but it's moving itself
southwest to almost follow the--
the wyvern riders that have
survived this battle so far
and are fleeing
from the scene.
The clouds then begin
to shift and shape
and the darkness separates
into what looks like
little plumes of white
that spell out a very basic
rendition of the symbol of Emon.
♪
What else you wanna do?
TRAVIS: Is Kash there?
MATT: Kash is there
with you guys.
-TRAVIS: How's he look?
-TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: He looks pretty messed up.
There are a few large
sections of armor
that have been
just cloven through
and you see a number
of flesh wounds sustained
but nothing mortal, but he--
He holds himself
with a kind of a
knowing confidence
with his arms crossed,
but as soon as any sort
of physical movement,
there is a little
bit of a wheeze
and a trying to cover
for the physical impact
of the battle
he's just sustained.
TRAVIS: You look a little
worse for the wear there.
MATT: "I don't know what
you mean, I'm sorry."
TRAVIS: Oh, I'm sorry.
Z, did he go unconscious?
MATT: "Actually, no, he
fought quite bravely."
-TRAVIS: Are you lying?
-MATT: "No."
-TRAVIS: Shit.
-MARISHA: She's lying.
TRAVIS: Good job,
I guess, Kash.
MATT: He goes, "You didn't
too bad yourself, big man."
Smacks you on the
shoulder and goes...
(whimpering)
TRAVIS: No, that would
never hurt me.
LIAM: I'm gonna walk up
to him as well,
cause he looks
fucked up and say,
"Hey, thank you for
the assist, Spanky."
And I'm gonna give
him two slaps of the cheek
and leave a couple of
black feathers stuck there
with sweat and use the last
of my Lay on Hands on him.
TALIESIN: Now that-- now that we've
sent the word, maybe now--
(indistinct talking)
The conversation's
underground.
MARISHA: Okay.
LIAM: Everything hurts.
MATT: What's your
armor class?
LIAM: Twenty-one.
MATT: He knees you gently
enough in the nuts
to get you to
drop to one knee.
TRAVIS: "Gently enough."
MATT: "That's two."
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Yes, good
throwback!
LIAM: I laugh through it.
TRAVIS: Good callback.
TALIESIN: Are there-- are
there any soldiers
running around
by the way?
Right now, any
of our people?
MATT: Right now, some soldiers
are beginning to pour in
through the gate
that they emerged from.
Some of your allies,
some from other armies
that are starting
to find their way
towards the center
core of the city.
Not everyone's been
made aware that the--
the center of this battle
has already been
won, essentially.
TRAVIS: Damn it.
MATT: So, people are
starting to come in
and calm down a bit
and then rush back out
to see what else is there.
You watch as a few wyvern riders
try and scoot through the sky
to catch up with the rest of
them as a bolt of lightning...
Slams into one
and you see it...
(yells)
Streak and tumble
and then crash somewhere
on the outside
of the district.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna fire a couple
of times into the air
just to get some
attention and just,
"Spread the word,
Thordak has fallen!
Spread the word!"
Now, we can go down.
MATT: You see some of the
soldiers immediately
kind of look at each other
and you can hear the--
sound of the shouting and
whispering back and forth.
Voices are shouting, "Thordak
has fallen! Thordak has fallen!
Thordak has fallen!"
It starts just carrying
throughout the city and echoing.
MARISHA: Call the locksmith!
MATT: Everyone goes, "What?"
"Sorry, Thordak has fallen!"
(laughter)
So, as you--
you follow them
and gather into the
area, or you want to--
PATRICK: I'd say, just as--
and I have to go talk.
I'm like,
"Samantha, it's you.
Circle everyone up.
Make sure the people
are taken care of."
MATT: "Yes."
PATRICK: And it's just
like, 30--
SAM: Another campaign going on.
lots of campaigns have
just briefly touched.
PATRICK: It's a couple--
a couple dozen
moderately well armored,
but you know, like...
These-- these are not
maybe crack troops.
They have a
lot of heart.
LIAM: Do they have
any hit points?
PATRICK: More than you
might expect.
Yeah, and so I just,
I square them away.
They can take care
of themselves by now,
at least for a bit.
MATT: Yeah, they set
up a small perimeter
to the entrance ways
to the district
and are awaiting
other forces to arrive
and inform them
of what's going on
and still stay alert for any
stragglers of the battle.
LIAM: What a world,
what a world.
MATT: As you--
What'd you do?
MARISHA: I just-- I grab Kerr and I start
ushering him down into the hole.
PATRICK: Okay.
MARISHA: Into the hole!
MATT: Laura.
LAURA: I'm so sorry!
MATT: You are-- you're my
favorite 13 year old.
PATRICK: It's-- it's
a lovely hole.
(laughter)
-LIAM: That's what they tell me.
-MATT: There's room for everyone.
PATRICK: It's been a long
time for me, you know.
I haven't done
this recently.
LIAM: I'm in here
all the time.
All the time.
MATT: While this is
happening, Scanlan,
you stayed down there
with Kima and Gilmore.
SAM: Yeah, I sort of moseyed my
way back to the beginning--
to the opening
of the lair,
like, where I had
tossed the flute.
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: And I pick it up,
and I carefully divide
my sachet of Suude
into three parts.
Three thirds.
And I'm going to
snort one third of it.
MATT: Okay.
The large brass dragon
that has currently
-been heading at the end--
-SAM: He can watch.
They can watch, they
can watch, they can watch.
MATT: At the end of the
tunnel, Devo'ssa,
they've slowly brought down
to their hands and knees
after travelling through
and scoping out
the interior
of the lair.
Approaches you as you're pulling
out your stash and you know,
Gilmore and Kima
approaching as well.
"What have you there?"
SAM: I've had a...
Not a great
day, Devo'ssa.
Thank you for coming.
For answering our call.
I just need a second to
myself if you don't mind.
LAURA: Isn't Pike
still down there?
MATT: Technically, Pike would
still be down there with him.
SAM: Maybe just
turn a wing?
(laughter)
MATT: They give a
curious glance
as Gilmore
kind of walks up
and brushes
his hair back,
which it catches
your eye interestingly.
There is like a glowing
rune of some kind
in the center of
Gilmore's forehead.
He kind of brushes the hair
out of the way and he goes,
"If a man wants some privacy,
give him some privacy.
I just want to ask
you a few questions.
It's not very often
I get to talk to...
J'Mon."
And Gilmore walks up
as the dragon sits back up
and puts out a claw and kind
of lifts Gilmore into his claw.
They both begin having a
conversation back and forth,
which, at this point
Pike is also curious
and begins to
pay attention
and sidles
up next to you
as you begin
divvying out and goes--
SAM: Are they talking
in their language,
the Marquet
language or--
MATT: If you want
to listen in--
SAM: No, no, I'm just curious.
MATT: Marquesian, and
yes, they are.
-SAM: Exciting.
-TALIESIN: I don't speak that.
MATT: As you begin
taking it out
and you're getting ready to go
ahead and snort one portion.
SAM: One third.
MATT: One third of
your Suude.
Pike approaches
from behind
and claps her gauntlet
onto your shoulder and says,
"Scanlan, you okay?"
SAM: Oh, yeah, I just--
This is some, some
healing herbs that I got.
MATT: "Okay, well, if I--
I'm trained in--
in medicinal applications
if you need my help."
(laughter)
SAM: I put it away.
TRAVIS: Pike cures all.
MATT: She looks over towards Kima
and Kima is now
approaching the rest of you guys
and walking into the lair
and they're feeling
out the vicinity
to see if the lair actions
have come to a halt,
and made it safe.
And so Pike begins
shouting out orders, like,
"Alright, we have
to make a perimeter!
Make sure there's
no other exits!
Make sure there's no--
nothing else waiting
for us in this cavern!
I'm giving
orders to a dragon.
You, dragon!
Help us do a
perimeter, please!"
And kind of interrupting
the conversation
between Devo'ssa
and Gilmore.
The brass dragon
turns the head down.
"Well, if you
insist, small one."
And sets Gilmore back down
onto the center of
the lair floor and...
They just begin
to walk perimeter
as Pike joins up and you are
still left alone in the tunnel,
should you be so inclined.
SAM: Alright, I'll
whip it out again.
(laughter)
MATT: Make an intelligence
check if you don't mind.
Just add your
intelligence.
-SAM: Oh, not good.
-TALIESIN: Wow.
LAURA: You're gonna put
it in your butt.
(laughter)
-SAM: Six!
-MATT: Six!
TRAVIS: Six total?
MATT: Okay.
This looks exactly like
the kind of substance
you should be
snorting for use.
So, you-- you take a bit
of the Suude, and this--
this particular Suude,
taking a closer look at it,
the grains of it,
and it's like--
almost like a--
like a brown sugar
type texture to it.
It is a dark
brown color to it.
It looks like a
crystallized dirt almost
and you kind of like take--
take a second, look around.
(sniffs)
It burns!
It burns.
Oh, man,
does it burn!
It burns a lot,
and you're like...
(groaning)
SAM: No effect?
MATT: It burns,
that's an effect.
SAM: Okay.
I take out
the flute.
I pack some in
the front of it.
(laughter)
MATT: This is how you
treat relics
that were gifted to you by the
leader of a foreign nation
by turning the expended energy
into a makeshift pipe.
SAM: I'm taking another third
and I'm packing it in
the front of the flute.
TRAVIS: Oh, please let it be--
(talking over each other)
Free basing, so!
SAM: I will dip a torch into
a bit of lava to light it.
(laughter)
And I am going
to bong rip
from this ancient
brass flute.
(laughter)
MATT: Alrighty.
I need you to make a
constitution saving throw.
LAURA: What are you doing?!
-SAM: Constitution saving--
-MATT: Constitution saving.
-LAURA: Constitution saving throw!
-MATT: Constitution saving throw.
SAM: Not good.
(laughter)
-Eight.
-MATT: Eight.
Roll 1d4.
SAM: Here we go,
here we go.
Three.
MATT: As you inhale deeply,
as opposed to the
burning sensation
from when you decided
to snort the granules,
the smoke and
mist that emerges
as it fills your
lungs, actually has a--
a very fine herbal taste
to it almost and it is warm,
and there's a head rush
immediately that hits you.
You feel for a moment your
vision kind of crystallize
and clarify
all of a sudden.
All the colors become
briefly brighter
and you feel this
slight pulse of--
of energy whenever
you cast a spell,
like the fingers
kind of warm at the tips
and you
feel the immediate need
to just practice something.
Right before your vision
gets blurry, and dark.
As--
Yeah, that's it,
the rest of you guys--
The rest of you guys come
walking down the tunnel,
being careful,
you know,
weapons out,
but talking,
kind of getting up to speed
with what's transpired.
You look in the distance and
you can see within the lair
and you're seeing
this, it's a down--
A decline into this
large heavy tunnel
that is just made
of volcanic rock
and blackened stone with
occasional cracks of--
of melting rock that
are just spilling through
and these small
orange glowing pockets
into this large central
underground cavern
that has an entire
pool of molten rock
that is kind of spiraling
through portions of the floor.
There is a large
brass dragon
just casually strolling
around the opposite side.
Huge, gargantuan in
size, strolling around
and a few other
humanoid individuals,
and you guys watch as
a singular male gnome ally
is face down on
the ground not moving.
TRAVIS: Oh, there was
no one even in here!
LAURA: Can I run up to him?
-MATT: Yeah.
-LAURA: Scanlan?
Smack him a couple times,
does he wake up?
MATT: Nope.
LAURA: Can I roll him over?
PATRICK: Probably get over
there pretty quick too.
It's not that I don't
think that these guys
can take of their
own wounded, but--
-MATT: Yeah.
-PATRICK: Yeah.
MATT: So, you rush up and
have both of you
make a medicine
check right now.
LAURA: Oh my God.
SAM: This is everything.
(laughter)
MARISHA: Great time for
a personal crisis.
Great timing!
LIAM: ♪ I'll do anything
for Suude ♪♪
-LAURA: Only eight.
-TALIESIN: That's the end of his turn.
MARISHA: Yes, that was his turn.
-Yeah.
-TALIESIN: Fair.
LAURA: But I've got a Cure Wounds
potion I can--
a Cure Wounds
spell I can use.
MATT: But what'd you roll
your medicine check?
-LAURA: Eight.
-MATT: Eight.
PATRICK: Not great, like,
is he gushing blood?
MATT: No, there is no blood
from his wounds.
PATRICK: (sniffing)
Do I know what
that smell is?
MATT: What'd you roll for
your medicine check?
PATRICK: Not worth speaking of.
Like 6.
MATT: Okay, okay.
So you're not sure
exactly what happened.
You do smell this
strange kind of herbal,
almost like an
incense scent
that is centered
around his area
and he is breathing.
But he is not conscious.
-LIAM: Pike!
-PATRICK: Can I check for poison?
LAURA: Can I do a nature check to
see if I recognize the scent?
MATT: Sure, make a nature check.
LAURA: I'm gonna cast Cure Wounds
on him, just to try it.
LIAM: And I'm just shouting
out Pike's name.
MARISHA: Ooh, I rolled
a natural 19.
-MATT: Okay.
-MARISHA: So that's 29-- no 30 total.
MATT: Okay, best that you can make,
strangely enough, there's--
the scent is
medicinal almost,
but it's also synthetic
in a way that's not natural.
This-- whatever
this smell is,
it's not a natural incense.
SAM: PCP.
It was laced.
TRAVIS: Anyone check to see if
the pipe's still packed?
MARISHA: Yeah, are there any
signs around Scanlan as--
MATT: Well, yeah, there is--
There is
the tarnished brass flute
that was gifted
to him by the leader
of the foreign city
of Ank'Harel
that is currently tarnished
by the use of its magic
and it is jammed pack with a
black ashy crystalline substance
with a trail of smoke
that is kind of lazily
drizzling off the tip.
TRAVIS: What did J'Mon do to him?
(laughter)
LAURA: Well, regardless of what's going
on, you healed 13 points.
SAM: Oh, that's nice.
MARISHA: Okay, I pick up the pipe,
since I recognize what--
that's where the
scent is coming from.
Can I like, do an investigation
check or something?
LAURA: Can I smack him across
the face as hard as I can?
-MATT: You can.
-LAURA: Even though I just healed him.
MARISHA: If I can put together
what's going on.
PATRICK: This obviously-- if
he's not gushing blood.
Some sort of
poison going on.
MATT: Okay, so-- so--
SAM: Am I having any sort
of dream, Matt?
MATT: No, darkness.
TRAVIS: Darkness.
MATT: You utilize Detect Poison
and you don't--
you don't sense anything
that is clarified toxin
to the point where it would
register as a poison,
so at least,
you're calm--
you're calmed
to know that
there isn't something coursing
through his system right now
that is in danger
of killing him.
-PATRICK: Okay.
-MARISHA: Fifteen.
-MATT: Fifteen on investigation?
-MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: Yeah, he smoked
something out of this.
(laughter)
MARISHA: Guys.
I feel like this was
a classic Scanlan.
In terms of choices, I don't
think anyone did this.
LAURA: I don't understand.
MARISHA: I'm gonna start kind
of, like, like kinda,
can I start seeing if I can find
whatever he put in this pipe?
MATT: Make an investigation check
as you start rummaging
through his stuff.
MARISHA: Eleven.
MATT: Alright, you're pulling
through pockets.
He has a lot more pockets
than you'd expect.
LAURA: Can I do investigation check?
Cause I'm good at hiding
things on my person.
MARISHA: Hey, Vex--
Vex, look.
I-- I think he
did something.
I think he--
he tried something.
Look and see if you
can find what might be--
what he might have
put in this pipe.
MATT: So they're starting to go
the rest of his pockets.
Make an investigation check.
What'd you get here, Vex?
LAURA: Goddammit, I'm
rolling like shit!
Ten.
MATT: Okay, you both
start pulling
through the pockets
before Scanlan--
SAM: I have a porn book
that they might find.
MATT: And you do, you find a fantastic
small pocket sized tome
that manages to contain
a lot of very, very detailed
pieces of artwork about
male and female anatomy.
TRAVIS: I'll take that.
MARISHA: I take the pipe.
Sorry, the flute.
MATT: You also, you watch
as Scanlan begins to shift
and his eyes begin to
flutter open and you--
you come back to consciousness
with a mild headache
with all of your
friends gathered around
and Keyleth and Vax with
their hands in your pockets.
LAURA: I'm Vex, hi.
-MATT: Vex.
-LAURA: Hi.
SAM: Get your hands
out of my pockets.
LAURA: What the fuck
did you do?
SAM: Wait, first.
Are you real?
(laughter)
TALIESIN: No.
SAM: Is this a hallucination?
-TRAVIS: Yep.
-TALIESIN: Yes.
MARISHA: Scanlan, why
would you be asking
if this is a
hallucination?
Just curious.
SAM: We've had a
very rough day.
How do I feel, Matt?
MATT: I mean, you feel
like there was--
there was something
to the rush,
but your body
rejected it.
SAM: Rejected it.
-Hmm, interesting.
-MARISHA: Huh.
TRAVIS: Are you tired?
You were asleep
when we found you.
LAURA: Face down.
SAM: I was shaken
by today's events
and there was a lair action
that knocked me unconscious.
-TRAVIS: Holy shit.
-LAURA: What's a lair action?
SAM: I mean, there was
a trap set by Thordak
previously to his death that
knocked me unconscious?
LAURA: What's in this flute,
you piece of shit?
What's in the flute?
SAM: Herbs, give it to me!
MARISHA: No, no, no.
LAURA: No, you're too short,
you can't even reach.
MARISHA: I'm too--
TALIESIN: Angry T-Rex.
MARISHA: Can I do an
insight check on him?
MATT: Sure.
Scanlan, make a
deception check.
SAM: Thirty-two.
(laughter)
MATT: What'd you get,
Keyleth?
MARISHA: Twenty-two.
MATT: Legitimately, like, aw,
I guess a misunderstanding.
SAM: I'm shaken,
guys, I'm sorry.
I'm-- I'm not myself.
TRAVIS: Was it like poison gas
or like lava or did a
rock fall on your head?
SAM: I appreciate your concern
but what the fuck, Vax?
Why did you just charge
in after Raishan like that?
See how I did that?
(laughter)
TALIESIN: This is the
best thing ever.
SAM: Next time, will
you please tell us?
LAURA: There wasn't a lot
of time there, Scanlan.
LIAM: She was casting.
She was reaching
for whatever it is
she's been angling
for for months.
SAM: Well, you almost got me
fucking killed, alright?
TRAVIS: Actually, you--
you did get killed.
LAURA: You died, so did I.
SAM: That's even worse
than almost being killed.
LIAM: I reach out and I do
this thing to his eye.
Like that (indistinguishable).
What did you think we
were coming here to do?
We're here to-- the
fucking world is on fire.
SAM: Yeah, but we're
your backup.
You don't go in
without your backup.
You've done this so
many times at this point.
You've got to wait
for your backup to go.
-LIAM: I do--
-SAM: Listen!
I will do anything
that you want me to do.
I will kill Kerr right--
hi, Kerr, by the way.
I will kill him dead right
now if you want me to.
That's how much
you are my brother.
You need to trust us and
tell us what you're doing.
Kerr, no offense.
PATRICK: None taken.
LIAM: I hear what
you're saying.
She was reaching
for whatever power
she has been
working towards
and I wasn't going
to freely let her take it,
and you weren't there.
Fate didn't place you there,
and when we ran in that cave,
you were ten seconds behind me.
SAM: I have little legs.
LIAM: Listen.
-We failed.
-SAM: I know.
LIAM: Hard.
It doesn't mean it
was wrong to try.
SAM: That's true.
Man, we really
did fail though.
LIAM: If not now, when?
If not us, who?
♪
LAURA: Well, it's not
now, so, when?
MARISHA: And it is us, so.
TALIESIN: And I'm not calling
this a failure.
MARISHA: You're not calling
this a failure?
TALIESIN: I'm not calling
this a failure.
-SAM: Well, it is.
-TALIESIN: We bought time.
-MARISHA: What?
-TALIESIN: What?
TRAVIS: Yeah, we shit
the bed on that.
It was a complete failure.
-LAURA: Truly, here's the thing.
-TALIESIN: Two dragons!
LAURA: If she had succeeded,
if we hadn't attacked
her when we did,
and she had
succeeded in
whatever she's about
to do with Thordak,
you know, we probably
would have had to fight
a much more powerful
Raishan or Thordak again
or whatever the fuck
she's doing.
LIAM: We don't know
what it was.
TRAVIS: Yep.
LIAM: And I wasn't
about to stand back
and listen to her
Scooby Doo monologue.
I wanted to put
an end to it.
SAM: What's Scooby Doo, man?
TRAVIS: Don't know, folk tale.
LIAM: It's an island far away
in the next campaign.
SAM: Listen, I get it, I know.
I know why you acted
and I probably
would have done the same
thing had I been closer,
but just next time,
give us some sort
of a heads up, alright?
We have a code word
and everything.
LIAM: HolyshitI'mthrowingthedagger.
LAURA: Jenga, I think it's jenga.
LIAM: It doesn't apply
to this situation.
I'm sorry, you
weren't there.
She was moving.
The only thing I regret
is that she got away.
I'm sorry, Scanlan.
SAM: I'm sorry too.
LIAM: I reach out and I pick
him up by the scruff
and I walk off to
a far end of the cave.
Away from everybody else.
I shove him down
in a corner.
Sit still,
don't say anything.
Really, don't
say anything.
This is gonna
take a minute.
And I start to
unbuckle armor.
-LAURA: Oh, no!
-LIAM: Shush!
I start to unbuckle armor,
and it takes awhile as we
learned with that fucking wolf.
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: And I reach down
into my bag--
MATT: As you're in the
middle of unbuckling,
Kima has kind of approached from
the side of the wall and goes,
-like, What--
-LIAM: Sup girl?
MATT: You know what, keep going.
And she kind of just leans
back and crosses her arms
with her sword sheathed
behind her back
and there's a little part of
her looking at you, Scanlan,
as this is happening
that says, very silently,
Remember that
phantom dick circumstance
that happened back
in the Underdark?
I'm gonna enjoy
watching this.
With her eyes.
Reach, reach, reach and I pull
out a piece of paper, yeah?
I shove it into your chest.
That was for if I died.
If you're gonna
die, don't do it
with a fucking flute
up your ass, alright?
And I storm off.
♪
SAM: I have a piece of paper?
Can I read it?
Does it exist?
-MATT: Yeah, yeah.
-SAM: What is it?
♪
TALIESIN: It's a Critical Role sticker.
-PATRICK: Vinyl sticker.
-TALIESIN: Vinyl sticker.
MATT: Pardon me while I pull
up the actual information
that this has.
TRAVIS: While you're
pulling that up,
is there anything
shiny in the cave
that I can walk towards?
Cause I'm bored.
LAURA: Oh my God,
if I roll poorly
on a perception check
for loot, I'm gonna be so sad.
MATT: Alright, let me pull up--
TRAVIS: All this like
lava and gold,
there's got to
be gold, right?
Platinum.
LIAM: Melted together
in big hunks.
TRAVIS: Yeah, like cheese,
if we're lucky.
What?
You don't dream of cheese
in your treasure?
LIAM: That's not what she means
when she says cheddar.
TRAVIS: Oh!
What--
I cannot keep up.
MATT: Was it in text
or an email?
(laughter)
I didn't have it
at the ready.
LIAM: Fairly short, it says,
You were right.
SAM: To me?
LAURA: About what?
SAM: Alright.
LAURA: I know, but--
SAM: And I just fold it up and
put it one of my pockets
that seem to have
been messed with.
Well, I'll just sit there
and think for a while.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: As Vax walks back,
I kind of pull
him aside and I say...
You ran in after me.
This is--
Partially on
me as well.
Us, all of us, I guess.
♪
LIAM: We're not mercenaries.
We didn't come here
looking for a fight
we knew would
be easy to win.
♪
We do what we have to do.
When we landed on the
shores at Glintshore,
we fought and
we kept going
because it's what
needed to be done.
♪
MARISHA: Kerr.
I--I tried to
be the hammer
that you said
I needed to be,
and I don't know--
I don't know.
PATRICK: Oh, no.
I-- I might not be great
at writing letters.
This is not my--
MARISHA: Oh no, that was a
pretty great letter.
PATRICK: You don't need
to be anything,
and you certainly
don't need to be anything
other than what you are.
But he has--
he has a good point.
I mean, you--
In situations
like this,
you do what
you have to do.
Everyone does
what they can do
and you can't do anymore.
MARISHA: I feel like I focus so much
on just my want for revenge
and justice against Raishan
that I made it so personal
that I forgot that
this isn't about me.
It's ultimately not
about any of us.
There's something so much
bigger going on here and...
♪
Maybe my onus
and guilt was,
in some way, selfish.
I don't--
I don't know.
♪
PATRICK: Well, congratulations,
you're a person
like the rest of us.
No, and I mean no offense,
but we all do it.
And if you think
it was wrong,
then you can do it a little
different next time.
(sighs)
MARISHA: I admire your wisdom.
-PATRICK: No, no, no, no.
-MARISHA: I do!
PATRICK: No, don't.
Don't do that.
MARISHA: Would you be willing
to lend, at least,
a little bit
of your knowledge
to help us maybe
find Raishan?
PATRICK: If, for what it's worth.
It seems like you won,
you didn't win,
you failed, someone was
killed, but they're lost?
MARISHA: Well, you know,
that was a pretty good
summary actually, yeah.
LIAM: Killed one dragon, picked
a fight with another.
LAURA: Got our asses kicked.
LIAM: Didn't go as
well as the first,
and the second made
off with the first.
PATRICK: Sounds like you maybe got
sandbagged a little bit?
-TRAVIS: Yeah.
-LAURA: Yeah.
PATRICK: Okay, that's
always the worst.
LAURA: Yeah.
PATRICK: And you can't expect
to win that fight.
MARISHA: She knew far more
about us the whole time
than we ever knew about her,
and that's still the case.
LIAM: Almost did.
-PATRICK: I see that you're alive.
-MARISHA: Yes.
PATRICK: And if you get caught
unawares by a dragon
who has been gathering
intelligence on you
and you walk away,
that is not nothing.
TALIESIN: She downright ran.
LIAM: She did.
TRAVIS: I thought
she teleported.
TALIESIN: I'll miss you.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Where am I going?
MATT: As this conversation's
happening,
in the intensity
of the emotions,
you notice
that Gilmore,
Kima,
and Devo'ssa,
the brass dragon,
are all just kind of
sitting watching.
Devo'ssa has their
hands kind of clasped
in front with their
jaw resting on the edge
and just kind of watching,
and the-- the dragon's voice
kind of billows up forth.
"Ah, the drama of
such short lives.
It's heartwarming for us
who don't get the chance
to see it often enough.
It's lonely in the tower."
LAURA: You know, you can come down
and join us whenever you like.
MATT: "I appreciate
the offer,
however, the longer
I'm away from my city,
the more in danger
I leave it.
I have many enemies,
as does Ank'Harel,
and I can guarantee you
the moment that I absconded
with your magic to aid you,
that's the opening
they've been waiting for,
so I have to return
to my city and my people,
but I believe our
debt is collected.
Your victory against
Thordak complete
from where
I once left it.
I wish you luck."
SAM: Would you--
would you like--
You lent me this symbol,
this necklace.
Necklace? Symbol.
Would you
like it back?
MATT: The large brass dragon
face kind of shifts down
right up to you and the
immensity to distance
is already intimidating,
but when the front
of the snarling jaws,
the immensity of
the nostrils flare
right at the presence of
a gnome sized individual...
You've grown up fighting the
sensation of feeling small
in comparison to
the world around you.
You feel truly
small this close
to the front of
the dragon's maw.
The teeth curl into a grin
and the voice
kinda billows out,
like, a slow rolling
landslide into your face
with the warmth
of its breath.
"Nah, keep it."
MARISHA: J'Mon!
MATT: And just steps
over and starts
making its way
up the hall--
the cavern
towards the district.
MARISHA: Before you leave?
If you were fighting
a green dragon
named the Diseased Deceiver,
who wanted ultimate
power over her domain,
where would you start?
MATT: "In my opinion,
entities that are
this intelligent,
you never want
to wait for them
to fight on
their terms."
-TRAVIS: Good answer.
-LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: And the slow
rolling impacts
of the dragon's feet
grow quieter and quieter
before you hear eventually...
The wings lifting
up and you see
as a cloud of
smoke and ash
kind of pulls forth
into the tunnel,
showing the lift off
as you can only ascertain
J'Mon Sa Ord,
leader of Ank'Harel,
the brass dragon begins flight
back towards their home.
LAURA: Oh, shit, did J'Mon
fly here that entire way?
SAM: No, I don't
I don't think so.
TRAVIS: Flash.
SAM: Maybe.
LAURA: I was joking,
I was joking.
SAM: As terrible as
this day has been,
there is some gold at
the end of the tunnel.
TRAVIS: Which is probably
rigged to explode.
TALIESIN: I think it's
probably-- well--
SAM: Want to go
check it out?
LAURA: Kind of feel like,
we should, you know--
Heal up a bit.
I've been here before.
It didn't go so well.
PATRICK: Yeah, how knocked
about are they?
I mean, obviously, singes
and abrasions and--
LAURA: Like really, really
knocked to shit.
TRAVIS: Raise your hand if you have
less than 30 hit points.
MARISHA: I'm at 30.
PATRICK: I could probably take
out the whole group.
(laughter)
-TALIESIN: Wow, that would be--
-MATT: Plot twist!
LAURA: Oh my God,
are you Raishan?
LIAM: Rothfuss!
PATRICK: I was sent here
by Acquisitions.
MATT: Assassination mission.
-I love it.
-PATRICK: You sons of bitches.
(laughter)
SAM: You befriended us!
PATRICK: Next time you pay
your protection money.
SAM: Just like us to do this,
we trust everybody!
God, we're idiots!
LAURA: Oh, shit.
MATT: The last thing you
hear is the laughter
of a one-armed man in
the distance echoing.
LIAM: Clarota, Asum, Rothfuss.
Never ends!
PATRICK: But no, if
people are that--
are that bad,
like, I'll--
You know.
How are you?
You're obviously, like,
it's gonna be, like,
are you like visibly
like knocked about?
-LAURA: I mean she's--
-MARISHA: I kinda fell in a pit of lava.
LAURA: She's basically black
cinder right now.
PATRICK: Oh, really?
-Okay.
-LAURA: She face planted into lava.
LIAM: She's burned,
she's burned.
PATRICK: I'm like, Do you really want to
go looking for gold right now?
Because you--
♪
Would you like to come
over here and sit down?
I can take a look at--
TRAVIS: As they discuss, can I
just walk over to a pile of--
LAURA: Kash, how low are
you on healing?
Can you heal us?
MATT: Kash and Zahra, who
just kind of sitting off
of the edge of the cavern,
kind of taking a breather.
"Um, well, I got a
little bit, I guess."
Zahra, by the way,
is like healed to full.
TRAVIS: Of course.
MARISHA: Yeah, I just--
Keyleth just
bursts into tears.
She just start--
I'm so tired!
I'm so tired.
PATRICK: I'll kinda just kinda
usher her off a little bit
wherever, like, is a little less
in the middle of everything.
And I've got
my little pack
and we can lay
it on the blanket.
And she needs to get
some of these charred,
smoldering clothes off of her.
And so I can
look at these burns
and start, um, you know...
LAURA: I nudge Vax.
I think that guy's puttin'
moves on your woman.
-Okay.
-TRAVIS: Super worried.
MARISHA: I do the same to Kerr,
I just...my eyes.
MATT: Kash kind of walks up and
slaps you on your shoulder,
Vex, and kind of a jolt
and you heal 14 points.
Cure wounds a little too,
but as a bit of a
jolt through your body.
LAURA: It's good, it's good.
-Thank you.
-MATT: "You're welcome."
He turns back around and
walks back to Zahra.
PATRICK: And I just kind of
do the slow talk.
You know, we're kind of like,
it's like, oh,
this isn't as bad
as it looks
at first, you know.
And, 'cause this
was the old thing
that I did in town for years.
Somebody would come to
me hurt and I'd be like,
oh, it's like--nobody
knew who I was in town
for 20 years.
So I do the gentlest, least
obtrusive laying on of hands.
You know, where it's like,
oh, you know,
this probably stung
like the dickens,
but, you know--
Look at this,
look at this,
it's just rubbing,
this is just--
TRAVIS: Oh, you skinned your knees,
let me blow on that.
(cross talk)
LAURA: And I'm hugging you.
MARISHA: Why am I so cold?
LAURA: I heal Vax 12 points
while I'm hugging him.
SAM: I take a little potion.
TALIESIN: Try and clear
my guns in the hopes
that they're
actually gonna work.
So proficiency?
PATRICK: Uh, so down, like you can soak
up another 30, I'm assuming?
MARISHA: Yeah, I have 118 max, so.
PATRICK: Then, yeah,
soak up a full 35.
TALIESIN: Whoa, there you go.
Are we calling
this a short rest?
Is that what's
happening right now?
Are we having, like, some sort
of spontaneous short rest?
MATT: If you would like
to take a short rest--
TALIESIN: Oh, my God.
LIAM: I got 16 hit dice, man.
MARISHA: Yeah, I'm gonna burn
a few hit dice as well.
TRAVIS: So there is a full blown war
happening up on--
SAM: Oh, shit, that's true.
TALIESIN: Yeah, you know,
we just fought two dragons,
they can handle this.
MATT: Okay, so you're all
taking a short rest before
or your going to
the gold and not taking--
-TRAVIS: Gold.
-MATT: Okay.
So as you all take a moment--
TRAVIS: There's a lot
of talking happening,
I just wandered off.
MATT: So as you guys begin
to take the rests,
tend to your wounds,
take a breather,
and begin to mentally
prepare yourself
for whatever the next stage
of your journey is.
Grog, you step out
into the cavern,
now without the
red in your eyes
that normally calls to
combat where your focus is on
what you can hurt and
kill as soon as possible.
Now it's what can loot and
keep as soon as possible.
And make an
investigation check.
TRAVIS: Okay, gonna be high.
Oh, 17 plus, minus 2.
-Fifteen.
-MATT: Fifteen.
Uh, doesn't matter too much
as you walk in and begin
taking in the surroundings,
you can see there
are edges of the cavern
that are just crammed
with gold and platinum
and art fixtures and vases,
and golden, brass, and silver
keepsakes and knick-knacks
and decorations.
You can see chains
and candelabras
You can see all sorts--
it looks like
and you kind of--
some of you gleaned this
as you went in here.
This is more wealth
than you've ever seen
in your entire life.
This...this is probably
a majority of the wealth
of Emon that has been slowly
brought to Thordak
and forced into his lair
as part of the tyranny
that he took over the city.
So, all the money
here has been amassed
from the guilds,
from the villagers,
from the townsfolk,
from the temples,
from the shops,
from the Cloudtop.
This is the economy of Emon
crammed into, at least
a majority of it,
into a singular cavern.
TRAVIS: I feel overwhelmed by
the sheer amount of stuff.
Are there any, like,
unique looking knick-knacks
or really lovely or
dangerous looking weapons
that grab my eye?
Because it's just
a lot of shit.
MATT: Well, as based on your
investigation check,
which is a 15, um, you do
find a couple of fun things.
You find a...
TRAVIS: I love it when he
reaches for stuff.
LAURA: I know.
MATT: You find a somewhat familiar
looking metallic rod
about that long, cylindrical.
Looks to have a couple of small,
almost ring divots on it.
You're pretty
sure you have one of these.
LAURA: Immovable rod.
TRAVIS: What?
SAM: Immovable rod.
-TRAVIS: Yeah.
-SAM: Who has ours?
-LAURA: I think I have it.
-MATT: You've seen it?
SAM: Why don't we use that more?
TRAVIS: Oh, no, no, it's
not the same thing.
LAURA: Ooh.
MARISHA: Oh, yeah,
you'd be like climbing.
TRAVIS: This is different,
this is a movable rod.
SAM: Oh, it's a movable one,
not an immovable one?
PATRICK: Just, which means
it's just a rod.
MATT: It's just a rod, basically.
TALIESIN: It's a shake weight,
it's a shake weight,
(laughing)
It can't stop moving.
LIAM: You sullied
Dungeons and Dragons.
TALIESIN: I would hope so.
MATT: Mind you, that fighter's
forearms look amazing.
So you pick that up
and you start glancing through
and you're just kind
of pushing through
some of the art objects--
a large painting that
just breaks in half.
TRAVIS: If there's a vase I
would totally smash that.
MATT: You smash a
few vases, actually.
TALIESIN: Ironically, there are
two gold coins inside.
(laughing)
MATT: Um, you also do
see to the side
a...what looks to be a
wooden box about that big
that is latched shut.
It has beautiful
engraving all across it.
And what looks to
be almost like gold leaf
with little gems
of blue and red
kind of toward the corners.
It's a really beautiful artisan
wooden box about that big.
And then there is a large, looks
like a beautiful tapestry
that is rolled up and bound.
TRAVIS: Okay, that's boring.
The box, like does it look
like it's simple to open?
MATT: Uh, you pick
it up and look at it.
It has a little latch on it.
-TRAVIS: What would--
-MATT: Make an intelligence check.
TRAVIS: What would that guy that's
always sneaking around do?
Intelligence check
two minus--yeah two, okay.
-So, zero.
-MATT: Zero.
You shake it, there's something
inside it, rattles around.
It's got a little heft to it.
TALIESIN: Oh, boy.
MATT: You look at it, try
and pry open the side.
Nothing.
TRAVIS: Even with the
titanstone knuckles,
it doesn't open?
MATT: You want to
use your strength?
Go and roll
a strength check.
-TRAVIS: Yeah.
-MATT: Force it open.
LIAM: You're going to break
a wonderful item.
TRAVIS: Dammit.
Eleven.
MATT: Eleven, okay.
TRAVIS: That was a low roll.
MATT: Uh, you crssshh and the wooden
case just breaks in half.
And as it does,
you see what looks to be
a small leather sleeve,
similar shape kind
of pfff and land.
-TRAVIS: I'll go get it.
-MATT: Pick it up.
And it's a leather pouch,
it has a little top,
it's buttoned shut.
And it looks like there's
something inside,
almost like cards.
MARISHA: No, no.
TRAVIS: Yeah, yeah, open the sleeve,
the leather sleeve.
PATRICK: No.
MATT: What are you gonna pull out?
MARISHA: You wish.
MATT: You open it
and you can see inside
what looks to
be about 13 cards,
tarot looking cards.
-TRAVIS: Little cards.
-MATT: Cards, yeah.
TRAVIS: Do they smell
like anything?
MATT: Uh, they smell
clean and fresh.
TRAVIS: How far away is the lava?
MATT: Um, maybe from where you are
right now in this portion,
I'd say 25 feet.
-TRAVIS: Who the hell uses--
-LAURA: No, Travis!
(laughing)
-TRAVIS: What?
-LAURA: What are you even doing?
TRAVIS: I'm going through the loot,
you all are fucking
healing and shit,
I'm trying to find
something useful here.
TALIESIN: Did you find
anything useful?
LIAM: Laura Bailey manifested.
(laughing)
Oh, harp please, poof!
MATT: As you guys have
been resting, to be fair,
as you're all sitting there
in the tunnel kind of talking,
you hear in the distance
an occasional like
ting, ting, ting, clunk.
You look in the distance
and you see Grog
just like rummaging through
the loot and throwing shit.
-TRAVIS: Pretty much.
-LAURA: What are you doing?
TRAVIS: What, I'm trying
to find something.
There's a giant rolled
up carpet over here.
LAURA: A carpet?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I mean some people call
it a telafaphy or whatever.
LAURA: I go over to Grog.
What do you
have in your hand?
TRAVIS: Uh, I don't know, it looks
like a bunch of cards.
LAURA: Can I see them?
TRAVIS: No, they're mine,
I found them.
You have all of this stuff
to choose from, have at it.
LAURA: What's that tapestry
he's talking about?
MATT: Uh, the tapestry
that's bound up?
-LAURA: Yeah.
-MATT: Go and make
an investigation check.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna start
wandering into this mess.
This is exciting.
LAURA: Twenty four.
MATT: Okay, as you quickly go over,
you find--there are a
number of what look to be
types of decoration,
wall tapestries.
And there one
that Grog caught
that it's a very,
very fine material,
it looks like it's
probably expensive.
Made of a very deep
dyed navy blue silk
with looks to be a very, very
light tan pattern across it.
As you unravel it, it's
roughly six foot by nine foot.
Um, it rolls out
in front of you.
LAURA: Do you fly, fly?
Try to fly right now.
Go up in the air.
(spit)
-TRAVIS: No.
-PATRICK: Did you just spit on it?
LAURA: Well, that's my code word
for my flying broom.
MATT: Chuck on it, you'll fly.
Which sounds like chat-oo!
MARISHA: Naturally.
MATT: What do you want to do,
do you want to spend
some time with the tapestry?
LAURA: No, I'm gonna roll it up
and save it for later
and look around
for other cool stuff.
MATT: Okay, so you grab
the tapestry and roll it up
and toss it to the side.
TRAVIS: There's really
no way around this,
I've got to pull a card
out of the
leather sleeve, right?
LIAM: Are you gonna take
this fucking tapestry
or you're gonna
look around the room?
MATT: All right, so you
pull one card out?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'll pull one card out,
but I want to pull
the one in the middle
because I remember
magicians be like,
choose a card, any card.
LIAM: Travis, you could
destroy the world.
TALIESIN: I'm so excited.
TRAVIS: I mean, on any day, but you're
lucky I'm really in control.
LAURA: I don't know what can
come out of that thing,
but like, really
bad things can come out.
TRAVIS: What is that, I don't
even know what that is.
MATT: Ryan, do we have a
deck of cards anywhere?
MARISHA: Jesus Christ.
TRAVIS: What is this?
PATRICK: I probably...
MATT: Just regular playing cards.
(Ryan) I'm going to look for some.
TRAVIS: Is it fair to say that everyone
knows what this is but me?
SAM: I don't know what it is.
TRAVIS: Sam doesn't know.
LAURA: I've heard that--oh, God,
there's cards right there.
They had 'em right there!
MATT: Thank you.
TRAVIS: Scanlan doesn't
know what this is.
Do you know what this is?
LIAM: Yes.
TRAVIS: Laura, do you know?
LAURA: I know it's really--
it can be really bad.
TRAVIS: Patrick, do you
know what this is?
LAURA: Didn't they pull this out
during one of the charity games?
LIAM: Amazing and great or it
could be totally destructive.
TRAVIS: I'm feeling amazing
and great right now.
LAURA: Oh, God, oh, God.
LIAM: Aren't you glad you're here?
PATRICK: I'm so--there's nothing
I'd rather be here for.
TRAVIS: Oh really, just straight up?
MATT: All righty, so.
TRAVIS: That's unfortunate.
(cross talk)
LIAM: I'm sweating harder than the
dragon fight right now.
(cross talk)
MATT: Be patient here
for a second, folks,
as I have to pull out the
proper deck here so I know--
(cross talk)
As Travis now currently
pulling a card out of
some sort of enchanted deck.
TRAVIS: It's called
an enchanted deck?
LIAM: If he wins, he can win big.
TRAVIS: Is there a name for it,
whatever this is?
-PATRICK: Oh, yes.
-TRAVIS: What's the name?
TALIESIN: Idiocy.
LIAM: Yes.
LIAM: We'll tell you later.
(cross talk)
'Cause we're all
out of character.
TRAVIS: I genuinely
am only doing this
because I don't know
what the hell it is.
PATRICK: Which is perfect,
it's perfect, perfect.
This could not be better.
Although honestly, they're
like--and into the lava
would also be perfect, yeah.
MARISHA: That would be perfect, yeah.
TRAVIS: Would that have activated
all of them and then...?
LAURA: I don't know.
MARISHA: You can't really destroy
magical items though, right?
TALIESIN: No, they would have just
put them into the rock.
TRAVIS: Oh, they're magical...
MATT: In my rush to
get everything ready,
-I did not...
-SAM: How dare you.
LAURA: How dare you not prepare?
MATT: Well, there was that too,
but you know.
I learn lessons
the hard way sometimes.
LAURA: If Travis gets
a hold of it...
LIAM: Not ready for eSports, Matt.
(laughing)
MATT: I hate you so much.
TRAVIS: Not ready for...
-MATT: Okay.
-TALIESIN: So excited.
LAURA: Oh, God, I'm terrified.
I don't know what all the
things are that they can do.
TALIESIN: I don't think I would
have the guts to do it.
I think--'cause I would know,
I would not have the guts.
TRAVIS: 'Cause you know what it is.
Well, there's like 13 cards,
how bad can it be?
What's the percentage
of bad cards to good cards?
LIAM: It's mostly bad.
TRAVIS: It's mostly bad?
LAURA: Do you know, you know,
you know all the cards.
LIAM: But the goods are amazing.
MATT: Shuffle these
here for a minute.
LAURA: Oh, God, oh, God!
Oh, my God, what if
we're all about to die?
'Cause it could
be world ending, right?
It could just...
MARISHA: I'm with Kerr
in the hall, right?
MATT: You guys are all just resting.
And Vax is asleep.
SAM: I'm checking to see if
there's any more in the flute
that didn't get burned.
-MATT: Uh...
-LIAM: Now is the time.
TALIESIN: Smoke 'em if you got 'em.
MATT: Literally.
As you check the flute,
what you put in the flute
has been expended, yes.
All right, so I want you
to just pull one of these--
I'll turn them around, shuffle.
TRAVIS: How many pulls do I get?
MATT: You said you were
just pulling one card,
so you pull one card.
TALIESIN: Only Travis,
Travis is the only one.
MATT: What's it say?
MARISHA: You have this
conviction to your voice
that's just--I believe you.
PATRICK: I'm very calming.
MATT: All right, good to know.
SAM: Good to know.
Oh, good to know,
you all die.
LAURA: It's a giant...
TALIESIN: No, don't look at the screen,
don't look at the screen.
That's not gonna
make anyone feel better.
(cross talk)
MARISHA: 50 gold, 50--
50,000 gold.
LIAM: No whammies, no whammies.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: He's turning more pages, why?
Why more pages?
PATRICK: I'm actually sweating.
SAM: You should only
be on one page.
Why would he need to be
on multiple pages?
(cross talk)
TALIESIN: It's a centerfold.
LIAM: It's the most powerful
thing in the book.
MATT: Okay, hold on, I have
to go back for a--
SAM: Why are there
more pages, Matt?
MATT: You'll find out,
you'll find out.
TRAVIS: Why would you give me that?!
(laughing)
MARISHA: I was asking
the same question.
TRAVIS: You give me
like chastity belts or--
MATT: Look, man, the last
thing I expected was Grog
to be the first to loot
for magical items.
And roll a decent
investigation check.
And yet, here you are,
discovering this deck.
All right, so...
With this...
You pull the card out and it
looks like this beautiful
tarot like design of what
looks like a metallic key
that is currently
held aloft in space
behind what looks
like almost like the stars
converging into some sort of
a pattern in the night sky.
TRAVIS: That's good, stars are nice.
MATT: At this point--
TRAVIS: Orion wouldn't fuck us.
LIAM: Nope.
PATRICK: That's not a
sword on his belt.
MATT: As you pull the card
and look at it,
the card bursts into flames,
and you feel this slight
tingling in the hand
that held the card.
Suddenly, you watch as
there's a flash of light
within your grasp with
what looks to be extending
from where the card once was.
You immediately feel
something steel in your hand
and as you clutch your fingers
instinctually around it,
and try to crush
whatever it is,
you look and watch as this
beautiful looking scimitar
like blade is now
in your grasp.
TRAVIS: Oooh!
Whoa.
MATT: It's beautifully made,
an ornate hilt and hand guard.
And it has like a chain dangling
from the bottom of the pommel
that has, looks like
a small blue gem.
It's a beautiful
looking piece of weaponry.
And as you whip
it back and forth,
it's perfectly balanced.
TRAVIS: Does it make any noise
when I swing it?
LAURA: A card turned into a sword?
SAM: We should pull the other cards
to see what swords they'll make.
PATRICK: You can do that 12 more times!
TRAVIS: I'm apparently the
most powerful sorcerer
that has ever lived.
SAM: This is a deck
of weapon cards.
LAURA: I mean seriously, though.
TRAVIS: I have to hit
something with it.
LAURA: Well, go hit
TRAVIS: Is there like a tall
statue around or anything?
MATT: I mean, you can see
there are a few marble busts
and things that have been
collected from the more--
TRAVIS: A marble bust is good,
that's perfect.
TALIESIN: Please don't
decimate the antiquities.
TRAVIS: Can I pick it up?
Lob it--
LAURA: Grog, also don't forget
this is property of Emon.
TRAVIS: It just broke because
you distracted me.
(laughing)
I've got to go
find another bust.
Is there another?
MATT: There are a few, yeah.
TRAVIS: Thank God there's another.
MATT: You need to recognize,
some of these used to exist
in the Alabaster Lyceum.
These are actually busts
of old heralded teachers
within the arcane halls
of the lyceum.
-TRAVIS: They wrote on stuff, right?
-MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Okay, then nobody cares
what they looked like, cool.
Take it and lob it
in the air, big swing.
-MATT: Make an attack roll.
-TRAVIS: Okay.
Can I make this
a reckless attack?
MATT: You can.
TALIESIN: Is it a strength
or dex weapon?
MATT: It's a strength weapon.
TALIESIN: Ah.
TRAVIS: Twenty seven.
MATT: Twenty seven.
Um, roll damage.
It is considered a scimitar.
TRAVIS: Okay.
LAURA: A scimitar.
MATT: It's a d8, I believe.
MARISHA: It's considered a scimitar.
TALIESIN: But really.
PATRICK: It looks exactly
like a scimitar.
TALIESIN: It's a meal.
(cross talk)
TRAVIS: I'm kind of doing it
off of the blood axe, so like 16?
No necrotic no--
MATT: No, no magical bonus on it.
-TRAVIS: Just 16.
-MATT: 16, okay.
And with your gauntlets
you have siege,
which means you
do double damage
against objects and structures.
So as you take the sword back
you strike the
edge of this bust
and watch it just
turn to gravel and dust.
Pshhh, it just shatters
and explodes out the side
with one singular swing
and you watch as
the small chunks of rock
that still somewhat
resemble any sort of, you know,
sculptured structure go
scattering across the black,
you know, lava and magma
encrusted darkened floor
of the cavern.
Blade is untouched.
TRAVIS: It is really
well balanced, that is,
and I just hold
it up to my ear.
(laughing)
MATT: A moment passes.
A second moment passes.
-TRAVIS: We're good.
-LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: We're totally good.
SAM: It's a cool weapon.
TRAVIS: It is, yeah.
And I stealthily try
and pocket the other cards.
LAURA: What are you doing?
TRAVIS: But I haven't showered in
a few days and my bum itches.
MATT: Make a slight of
hand check, Grog.
(laughing)
TRAVIS: Shit, that's a natural 1!
God damn it!
MATT: You watch as Grog so
discreetly takes the cards
and just kind of throws them.
(laughing)
Somehow throws
them closer to you
and in between
him and you guys,
trying to hide them
and just go thdummp.
LAURA: I pick them up.
SAM: Does anyone know
what these are?
LAURA: Grog just made a sword
out of one of these cards.
Do we know what this is?
TRAVIS: They only activate
under my magical touch.
SAM: I'm gonna look at it
and just see if I happen
to know anything about it.
MATT: Roll an arcana check.
SAM: I don't know
anything about it.
I rolled a 12, do I
know anything about it?
MATT: Mmm, they're
apparently magical.
TALIESIN: Twenty three.
MATT: Twenty three.
You, being a studious child
and reading many things,
you've heard rumors,
you have heard myths,
you have heard
legends of glory and woe
based around an
artifact referred to
as the Deck of Many Things.
LAURA: I start to open it up and--
TALIESIN: No, no, no, no.
No, oh, he looks--
LAURA: I think these made weapons.
TALIESIN: They can make
a lot of things.
SAM: Can they make bad things?
TALIESIN: They can make a
lot of bad things.
SAM: And do you know
what activates them,
just looking at a card?
TALIESIN: If I recall,
it doesn't take much.
LAURA: I just shut the little
case and stuff it in my...
SAM: Let's keep it.
TALIESIN: I was going to say
let's put it somewhere
where no one will
ever find it,
but that will
be fine for now.
TRAVIS: May, may I--I actually,
I found that.
LAURA: Oh, Grog, that's sweet.
TRAVIS: But I don't, I want to
hold on to it, it's mine.
LAURA: No.
TRAVIS: You can keep
all the other gold.
LAURA: Yeah, no, I don't
trust you with it.
TRAVIS: Why not?
LAURA: Because you do stupid things.
TRAVIS: Look what I made.
LAURA: You made a beautiful sword
and I'm proud of you.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'm sure it's like
reactive its user--
LAURA: Maybe there's another set
in here, we should find it!
TRAVIS: And then you can have it.
LAURA: No, if we find another set,
you can have it.
LIAM: That's a bad deal, too.
TRAVIS: I go to look for
another Deck of Many Things
and nothing else.
(laughing)
MATT: For all the gold
that is in this cavern,
none of it has any
luster or shine to you
as your singularly focused
on finding another one
of these deck of cards.
You are throwing handfuls of
platinum over your shoulder.
TRAVIS: Garbage.
Rubbish, filth.
(laughing)
Life has no luster
to it anymore.
You wretched...
MATT: All right, so continuing off of
your investigation check--
-LIAM: What a heart attack.
-TALIESIN: Wow.
MATT: So you do have the
Deck of Many Things
which now has
12 cards in it.
LAURA: Oh, my God.
TALIESIN: Ah!
MATT: I'm gonna hand that to Laura.
SAM: Next time I go back to casino,
I'm taking that with me.
MATT: You do--you
have that tapestry.
You have--you find what
looks to be a pair of very fine
crafted dark
green leather boots
that have almost a silver
or platinum scrolling
along the edges
of the leather,
almost like
leaves and branches
that tangle in towards
the front of the foot.
LAURA: Do they look Elvish?
MATT: It looks Elvish in design.
And you find
what looks to be
a very, very well
crafted war hammer.
It has--its shape
and its design is--
and only because you've seen
this type of handle before--
it appears to be
Dwarven in make.
And it has a
series of runes and glyphs
along the sides of
the war hammer head itself
that seem to
give you the sense
that this is a very expensive,
or at least a very, very
elegantly crafted weapon.
LAURA: Okay.
Sweet.
I can't, can I see if
they're magic, I can't can I?
MATT: I mean, you can take
the rest of your short rest
with one of the objects
to see if you can
ascertain any sort of magic
or information about it.
LAURA: I'm gonna do that
on the tapestry.
MATT: Okay.
-TALIESIN: I'm with you.
-LAURA: Fly, fly for me.
MATT: All right,
the rest of you guys,
is there anything else should
rest, just healing up?
TALIESIN: Healing up,
fixing my guns,
and then sort of
trying to navigate
some of this crazy in here
and then eventually
looking around the cavern
to see if there's anything.
MATT: Has everyone
spent their hit dice?
What are we at
in point totals here?
SAM: Sixty eight.
TALIESIN: I've got 102.
MARISHA: Seventy nine.
MATT: I think you're still full.
LIAM: Ninety nine.
LAURA: One hundred.
TRAVIS: I didn't roll any 'cause
I was looking through this
Deck of Many Things!
90.
MATT: Ninety, okay.
At the end
of the short rest,
Vex, you've taken the
time with the tapestry,
looking at it.
Its design kind of
hurts your heart a little bit
'cause it reminds you of the
flying carpet that you once had
and you're like
hoping and praying.
And as it--as you're
concentrating on it,
and hoping that
something comes to you,
you're like, "Fly,"
you know, "Go."
"Traverse, carry."
You're just throwing
all these words out.
And as you're just getting
more and more exhausted,
and the rest of your
party kind of look over
with this, "Oh, give it up,
girl," kind of look
and shaking their head,
a sudden hit of
inspiration hits your mind
and clarifies--the word "lift."
You say lift and the tapestry
goes fll fll fll.
LAURA: Shut the fucking--!
You guys!
VAX: (snoring)
TRAVIS: It's a flying telefaphy.
LAURA: Lift higher.
♪ High up in love ♪♪
SAM: Another flying carpet.
LAURA: Oh, you guys,
this is wonderful.
TALIESIN: I legitimately think this
is the one she tried to replace
the one we stole.
TRAVIS: Wwwaahhhhhhh.
LAURA: Waahhhhhh.
LIAM: It's Allura's other carpet.
TALIESIN: It's her other carpet.
-LAURA: Oh, shit.
-MARISHA: She collects magical carpets.
TALIESIN: Well, she should
only ever needs one,
we just keep taking it.
SAM: Does it say
how much weight it can hold?
TRAVIS: Eight hundred.
LAURA: Eight hundred pounds, it can
carry more than the last one.
SAM: How big is Grog?
MARISHA: Ah, is it a bigger tapestry?
LAURA: It's six by nine.
TRAVIS: Like three hundred.
LAURA: This is like the
California king version.
MATT: Bigger than the one
you had before, yeah.
MARISHA: It's a California
king version.
SAM: Grog can get on that
and go hit things.
TRAVIS: Yeah flying speed of 30,
I can run faster than that.
MARISHA: Can you be like a
Silver Surfer thing?
TRAVIS: Blaaaaah, yeah.
MARISHA: Ya!
LAURA: What's my carrying
capacity on my broom?
MATT: Uh...
LAURA: I should probably know this.
MATT: Your broom can carry, uh,
it can carry 400 pounds
at a flying speed of 30.
LAURA: Well good, so...
MATT: Sorry, it can
carry 400 pounds,
but its flying
speed becomes 30
while carrying
over 200 pounds.
LAURA: Okay.
Oh, this is amazing.
SAM: That's a good find.
-TALIESIN: That's a very useful find.
-LAURA: This is some good stuff.
MARISHA: Vex, does it look
like our old carpet?
LAURA: I mean, it looks similar,
it's a bit bigger.
MARISHA: Does it looks like they were
maybe in the same family?
-LAURA: Definitely, Keyleth.
-MARISHA: Yeah?
LAURA: Hey, look at
these boots,
I throw them down to you.
They look kind of Druidish.
MARISHA: They do look Druidish.
Do they look Druidish?
-MATT: Roll an arcana check.
-MARISHA: Okay.
♪
Five.
MATT: They look pretty.
-MARISHA: These are so pretty!
-LAURA: I know, right?
MARISHA: Oh, my gosh.
LAURA: I think the color looks nice,
it would look good
with your dress.
MARISHA: Okay, I'll
look at these later.
MATT: They're nicer than
the boots you have on.
TRAVIS: Ooh, that's a diss
on your boots, dog.
MARISHA: I, well...
MATT: They don't necessarily
match the ensemble, per se,
but they're nice boots.
MARISHA: The soles are
a little melted now.
LAURA: I mean basically Keyleth
would be naked this whole time
'cause all of her clothes would
have burned off in the lava.
MATT: This is the magical
world of fantasy
in which characters don't
suddenly lose all their clothing
or facial hair or body hair
because of magical spells.
LAURA: All right, sure, whatever.
MARISHA: Sounds like that Japanese RPG.
(cross talk)
MATT: I'm sure there
are RPGs out there
that let you do that.
I'm sure Lamentations
of the Flame Princess
lets you do that.
I think there's
actually some exalted
expansions that let you do that.
Not this game.
The fan artists take
care of that for us.
TALIESIN: And with that, yeah, I'd love
to take a look around the room,
see if anything
captures my eye.
MARISHA: I think also,
I think Keyleth's hair
would probably
be shorter now again,
thanks to the fire, again.
MATT: Yeah, sure.
LAURA: Ooh, can I fly
up on the carpet
and see if anything
catches my eye from above?
MATT: Sure, you can
jump up on the carpet
and get an aerial view.
And as you get up towards the
top if the cavern, look over.
LAURA: Not that I couldn't have
done that on my broom,
but I feel a little safer
'cause there's
stuff all around me.
MATT: Yeah, it's a nice big
square patch just for you.
LAURA: I'm gonna lay down and...
LIAM: Is there room for
your broom on your carpet?
LAURA: Yes.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna run on up there
and get a vantage point 'cause
I still have some spider walk--
MATT: You do, yeah.
LAURA: Hop on over, Perc.
MATT: So you watch as Percy
kind of walks upside down
from on the cavern
and kind of gets
a similar perspective as you.
Make an
investigation check.
-SAM: Not great.
-MARISHA: That's real bad.
-TALIESIN: I can't pretend,
-I can't pretend that that's--
-SAM: Real, real bad.
MARISHA: That's pretty bad.
TALIESIN: Why am I even bothering?
Six.
MATT: Yeah. In all the
time you spent here,
most anything that catches
your eye beyond just value,
you've managed to scavenge
and glean from the horde.
Everything else seems
to be just collections
of expensive or
valuable knick-knacks,
collectibles, museum pieces.
You know, silverware,
furniture, art pieces.
Gem collections, and
then gold, silver, platinum.
It's...you knowing
good amounts of money,
you can't even
fathom the scope of this.
Like this is...
TRAVIS: Vex, you're drooling.
MATT: Like millions of gold pieces.
LAURA: That's a lot.
TRAVIS: I feel like this
is too much for anyone--
LAURA: No, no, no, it is.
We need to return this
to the people of Emon,
I mean, that's who
this money came from.
TRAVIS: Yeah, but how do we do that?
-LAURA: Yeah?
-MARISHA: Do you see anything
from Greyskull in there?
LAURA: Oh, do I see
anything from our keep?
MATT: Nothing that stands out
or you would recognize.
LAURA: Not that I can see.
MARISHA: All right.
TALIESIN: Now we'll, we'll take
a tithing for ourselves
to help rebuild and then
everything we're gonna
have to post guards and someone
is gonna have to take charge
of all this, put it to a use
rebuilding the city,
make sure that the antiquities
get back to the proper owners
and that the money is used
to just rebuild everything.
LAURA: People will have to put in
papers with the counsel.
MARISHA: I was gonna say people
are gonna have to pull papers.
TALIESIN: I think they're probably not
gonna get their money back,
but they're at least
gonna get their--
LAURA: Something.
TRAVIS: Should we reward Kerr?
Kerr, do you want
some of this bling?
PATRICK: Actually Kerr, after
you're okay and kind of
up and about yourself,
probably very casually
like kind of wanders around
and like when he gets
to the jewelry and the gems,
like very matter
of factly fills up a sack.
MARISHA: Very matter of factly.
PATRICK: You know like, no like,
ooh, I'm a---I feel a little
awkward about this,
just like, like this is really
not my first rodeo and money.
And money,
money does some--
this is more
than they can carry.
And, um, I have some
uses for this money.
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: I did give
20 pounds of gems
when we were down
in the city of Brass,
maybe I can find
some more gems.
MATT: Okay, yeah.
TALIESIN: No, this is, we are
taking our tithing.
You know taking it, we have work
that needs to be done.
MATT: How much are you taking?
I mean, it's your choice
really at this point.
How much do you want to
and how much can you carry?
Do you feel
comfortable doing?
LAURA: We do have a lot of, we do
have a lot of money right now.
TALIESIN: We're going to be rebuilding.
We need gems and platinum.
Let's not take anything that
isn't gems and platinum
and let's not
take a ton of it.
TRAVIS: What about like big
diamonds or rubies
for like important
spells and stuff?
TALIESIN: A few of those
would be good.
MARISHA: Gems, yeah--gems for
heroes feasts are always good.
LAURA: Oh yeah, smart, smart.
TALIESIN: We did burn a bunch
of them for this.
LAURA: Smart, Grog.
TRAVIS: I pass out
from the smartness.
(laughing)
MATT: As Grog falls asleep
cuddling with the gold coins.
Like a slow rolling
Scrooge McDuck.
(yawn)
Vex, you do find--with
eight of your friends, too--
there are two diamonds roughly
worth about 1,000 gold pieces
that you can put off
to the side as component.
You do find gems,
but really I mean,
how much do you
want to take, really?
This isn't how
much did you find,
there's enough
here to take
pretty much anything
you can carry.
There's no way you can carry
even but a fraction of this,
so, what do you want to take?
SAM: Platinum is worth ten gold?
LAURA: Yeah, so like we have--
SAM: I'm taking
200 platinum for myself.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: I think I would
actually honestly say
at least 1,000
platinum in general
just for general
use for the group.
-MARISHA: Yeah.
-LAURA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: And then ten of each
gem that we can find.
LAURA: 1,000 platinum
for the group then?
-MATT: Sure.
-LAURA: Okay.
TALIESIN: That seems reasonable.
LAURA: Yeah, totally.
TALIESIN: We're also gonna need to put
somebody in charge of all this.
MARISHA: Yes, someone trustworthy.
PATRICK: (snoring)
(laughing)
TALIESIN: Oh, we know you have
things to do.
TRAVIS: The guilt of it.
(laughing)
MARISHA: I see Kerr hesitate,
and I bend down
and I pick up like
a handful of gold and say...
PATRICK: No, it's more like,
it's like am I gonna
be in charge of another city?
LAURA: No, no, no, not
unless you want to be.
PATRICK: It's, uh, but no, I grab mostly
not big gems, nothing flashy,
but light, portable,
and stuff that
can be converted into cash.
Like, I've got troops
who are going to--
and a city back home, yeah.
TALIESIN: And you did come here, so.
SAM: Vex, there are six,
there are seven of us.
Maybe we should
take a bit more.
MARISHA: I'm taking a little bit
of gold for myself
just 'cause I'm low.
LAURA: Yeah, if you guys want
to grab stuff yourself.
MATT: Kima's abstained, by the way.
Kima's not taking anything.
While Gilmore is currently
filling up a small satchel,
he's like, "Well, I have
to rebuild some way."
Shoveling in small amounts,
but you know, not too much.
LAURA: Same.
I'll take...so hard.
TRAVIS: I'm taking 184 gold pieces.
MATT: Good job, Grog.
LAURA: Nice, Grog.
(laughing)
TALIESIN: I'm just gonna
put 500 gold pieces.
SAM: Dude, that's
a million dollars.
MARISHA: That's what I did
with 500.
TALIESIN: 500 gold pieces.
TRAVIS: Like candy or something.
Jellybeans in a jar.
LAURA: Fifty platinum,
so it's lighter.
TALIESIN: We're going to have
to seal this cave for now.
SAM: Why, the city is secured.
TALIESIN: The city is secured, the
city is about to become a riot
once they finish getting
-everything out of here.
-LAURA: And looters will come down here
and take far
more than we did.
TRAVIS: No, really?
SAM: Wait a second.
Don't we owe The
Clasp half of this?
LAURA: We owe The Clasp
half of our loot.
SAM: What does that mean?
MARISHA: But that's our loot,
that's not the city's.
LAURA: If we don't take as much,
then we don't give them as much.
SAM: I don't think they
would view it that way.
TALIESIN: That's the deal they made.
This is not our loot
we just looted.
LAURA: It's not our money,
it's Emon's.
MARISHA: The Clasp should
be aware of that.
SAM: I think we're going
to make an enemy
out of them by doing this.
TALIESIN: I think we're going to
keep an enemy out of them
is really more likely.
LAURA: How do we even
know who we told?
It could have
been two underlings,
nobody would believe
what they said anyway.
TRAVIS: Sure would be a gesture in
the right direction, though.
MARISHA: Well we can, I'm sure
we can still throw them
a little bit
of platinum, but...
I mean, Percy--
SAM: What like 5,000,
is that what you're saying,
half of, half
of what we take?
How does this work?
That's nothing to them.
We promised them
untold riches.
LAURA: We took 1,000 platinum
for ourselves.
If we took another 1,000
and gave it to The Clasp,
that's a lot of money.
TRAVIS: How about we don't
give them anything
and we just let them know
it's clear to come down here
and deal with it as they will.
SAM: They'll take everything.
TALIESIN: I don't know if they'll
take everything, actually.
MARISHA: Well, Percy, you once
said that every good city
needs a good underbelly.
TALIESIN: That's true.
MARISHA: I imagine that
the underbelly would also
have a vested interest
in a having good city,
I imagine it
works both ways, right?
TALIESIN: I'm so proud
of you right now.
MARISHA: Yeah, thank you.
TALIESIN: Oh my God.
MARISHA: I'm learning from you,
just like a little,
-where it's appropriate.
-TALIESIN: I'm so sorry,
-but I'm so proud.
-MARISHA: Only where it's appropriate.
TRAVIS: So what is it,
we hand deliver it
or we just let them know
it's clear to come down?
SAM: Hand deliver, we don't want
them coming here at all.
TRAVIS: I agree, it's more personal.
You write the limerick and
we give them two platinum.
(laughing)
What was the number you said?
LAURA: That two is what I said, yes.
PATRICK: Send them an envelope
with half of the deck in it.
(gasps)
TRAVIS: It just turns into swords--
TALIESIN: How are you the cruelest
human I've ever--oh, my.
That's amazing.
LAURA: I don't know what
the deck can do.
Could it, could it cause
the entire city to crumble?
Potentially?
Ooh.
PATRICK: That, I do not know.
TALIESIN: We can give them the deck.
LIAM: Vax just woke up.
MATT: Hi, Vax, welcome back.
TRAVIS: So, what, five
thousand platinum?
SAM: Five thousand platinum.
LAURA: Why five tho--where are you
coming up with these numbers?
MARISHA: You literally said
different numbers every time.
TRAVIS: We could give them like
three pizza platinum,
it doesn't
really matter to me,
I just want to go.
-LIAM: Hey, big man?
-TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: That's a nice sword,
where did you get that?
TRAVIS: I took out a card
of this little pouch
and it turned into this thing.
LIAM: What are you talking about?
TRAVIS: Yeah, it was like a little card
in like a leather pouch
and then Vex took it from me
'cause apparently
I make too many weapons.
SAM: If we want them
to be our allies,
and not hate us
and try to kill us,
we have to give them
a good amount of money.
LIAM: What, The Clasp?
SAM: Yes.
LIAM: We're talking about payment.
LAURA: We give them 1,000 platinum and
say that's half of what we took.
LIAM: Oh, they're a crime syndicate,
they're gonna laugh at that.
SAM: I agree.
PATRICK: And they know when someone's
running a game on them.
LAURA: But we didn't take any more,
that's our loot.
SAM: That's not how
they're gonna see this.
LIAM: That's a letter
of the law argument,
they're gonna want
to go spirit.
MARISHA: We also just saved their
city from utter destruction.
TRAVIS: Honestly, are we
gonna stay around
and really regulate what happens
here, we're not, right?
We've got shit to do.
TALIESIN: I would honestly say,
and I cannot believe
that I'm agreeing to this,
but I think just
if we run into them,
we let them know
that the dragon's dead
and that's where it is.
TRAVIS: I'm with Percy.
TALIESIN: They're not gonna
bankrupt the city,
it's not in
their best interests.
They're gonna
take a look at it
and they're gonna get
what they can carry.
SAM: So we're turning over the city
and the city's treasury
to a bunch of thieves.
TALIESIN: We turned over the city
to a bunch of thieves,
they've basically
been running the place
for the past few months.
PATRICK: How small town am I?
Do I know about these folks?
MATT: You've never dealt
with them directly
other than scaring off a
couple of younger cutthroats
you caught in like
an alleyway here or there.
But you're aware of The Clasp.
The Clasp, while
largely centered in Emon,
is a syndicate that is
across all Tal'Dorei
and has some hand in every
village no matter how small.
PATRICK: Right.
LAURA: Maybe we let them
know that it's there,
but that the
guards are coming.
They won't have
a lot of time.
MARISHA: Why don't we just hand
this over to someone else
and let them handle it?
PATRICK: If you hand it
over to someone else,
and send them a letter, it
will take a while to get there.
SAM: The Clasp?
They're down the hallway.
PATRICK: Which one?
TRAVIS: Over yonder.
SAM: They're in the sewers
1,000 meters from here.
PATRICK: Oh.
MARISHA: Regardless,
I agree with Grog.
We have more important things
to worry about right now.
TRAVIS: I'm running for office.
SAM: T-shirt: Regardless,
I agree with Grog.
(laughing)
MARISHA: Things never
been said before.
PATRICK: Is there any of
the people collected,
the generals or whatever,
have you worked
with them as well?
LAURA: The Clasp or the--
PATRICK: No, the former
leaders of this city,
any of the people
that you've--
SAM: The military, we can put
them in charge of this.
TALIESIN: There's not
really any military.
SAM: There's a visiting army.
Yeah, we can put
them in charge of it,
at least temporarily.
They can be trusted.
TALIESIN: Can they?
LIAM: Kima, do you feel
like keeping an eye
on a small group of
soldiers from Syngorn?
Protecting this?
A few days?
MATT: "I could probably run it,
I'd probably have to go
and check in with Allie.
I'm sure she'd be interested
in knowing about this
since she's, you know,
part of the council."
LAURA: Right, we need to tell her.
MATT: "We have Asum--I mean
we still have a number
of standing council members
and there's a few we still
haven't accounted for."
LIAM: This is your home.
TALIESIN: That would be better.
MATT: "My home is Westruun,
to be honest,
but I've kind of taken
this as a second home."
TALIESIN: Far more stories of treasures
being looted by foreigners.
LAURA: Honestly, we need to get to
Whitestone, speaking of.
TRAVIS: Yeah, don't we need
to like get a hand
and plant it under a tree
or something like that?
LAURA: Yes.
Yes.
SAM: Forgot about that.
TALIESIN: We have a hand.
MARISHA: We have a hand.
LAURA: We have ashes to
bury in Vasselheim.
MARISHA: We have a lot to do.
LAURA: We have to find out
where the fuck Raishan is.
Can we see if maybe
she went to Whitestone
and the whole city's decimated?
MARISHA: I can try and scry
with the scrying eye,
but that's it.
TRAVIS: How about we go to
Whitestone and then scry?
SAM: Well, we won't need
to if we're there.
MARISHA: Yeah.
LAURA: Just find out
if it's all right.
TALIESIN: Let's crawl upstairs.
Let's keep some
people on this, Kima,
and we'll crawl upstairs.
MARISHA: I can try to scry on Rai--
Did I find a little, like a
scale of hers, by the way?
MATT: Glancing about, uh...
roll an investigation check
specifically
looking for the scale.
As opposed to looking for
other things about the room.
TALIESIN: That's crock, that's--
yeah, I know.
MARISHA: That's slightly better.
Uh, ten total.
MATT: Ten total? It takes
you about ten minutes
and because the
shifting low light in here
the rocky formations
of the ground itself,
you're having a hard time
finding any scales of Raishan's.
MARISHA: Anything, blood?
MATT: It takes you about
15 or 20 minutes
before you actually
find a small cluster.
From one of the wounds
left behind by Grog.
MARISHA: Yeah, that'll do it, yeah.
TALIESIN: I'm gonna
grab the bag of colding
and take samples of the
dragon eggs that we cracked,
the fluid, the bodies, like I'll
put the whole thing in there.
We need that.
PATRICK: They intend?
-They took the body--
-LAURA: Raishan?
LIAM: She, uh, no, no, she's been
playing us for a long time.
We were in a loose
agreement with her
to get to today
and we've never felt
like she's told us
the whole picture.
Uh, we have watched her
gas scores of people
in front of us.
She's killed many
of your friends.
She's not good.
But no, we don't ultimately
know what her next move is.
MARISHA: I can try to scry on her
and maybe get lucky
or I can try and
scry on Whitestone.
The problem is
is she's smart,
so even if I try
and scry on her,
there's a possibility
that she'll resist it.
TALIESIN: She's exhausted still,
I would assume.
MARISHA: She did burn all of her
legendary resistance,
-didn't she?
-MATT: She did.
TALIESIN: And she's
probably been running.
LIAM: What could it hurt?
MARISHA: I'm gonna try
and scry on Raishan.
MATT: Okay, casting the spell?
MARISHA: Scrying eye.
MATT: Scrying eye, okay the reason,
the item's DC,
not your spell DC.
MARISHA: I guess so, but I
don't know if you ever put
the scrying eye DC on here,
it doesn't have a DC.
MATT: It doesn't--then, uh, then
we'll use your spell DC,
that's fine, okay, so.
So as you guys
begin situating,
Kima walks up at the surface.
Gilmore's still kind
of rummaging through
and trying to find some
interesting things.
And there's a few moments when
you hear Gilmore across from you
like, "Hah, hah,
this is mine."
Starting to find things left
over from his destroyed shop
that have been
scavenged by looters
and brought back to
Thordak as, you know,
paying homage to
their new ruler.
Um, Kima begins to head up
and you can hear now people
have begun to gather en masse
into the Cloudtop
it sounds like other--
the rest of your soldiers
along with Zahra and Kashaw
are walking up with her
and begin to organize
and find whoever's been
fighting through the city
and figuring out how to set up a
perimeter to defend the center
which essentially the entire
economy of the city
lies underground.
You begin to pull
out the scrying eye
and set up the small
space for the ritual.
You concentrate on it and
kind of thrust your vision
towards the center
of the artifact.
What's the spell DC?
MARISHA: My spell save DC is 20.
MATT: All right.
So as you focus, you feel
your vision kind of lift up
into the dark clouds
as the storm is drifting
south--south east of the city
towards where the wyvern
riders have been escaping.
Into the clouds and the dark,
the moisture, the rain,
you feel the humidity
almost oppressive against you
and you feel your
essence being tugged,
being pulled rapidly
in a direction.
Amidst the cloud, you don't
know which direction it is,
but it's pulled you quickly
and suddenly you
emerge from the clouds
and you're over ocean.
Um, over ocean you
see in the distance
just open waves,
no signs of land, just water.
And then a singular island,
isolated, distant,
far from everything.
Your vision suddenly jumps,
scats upright to the outside
of this cavern opening.
You see--
skips, I meant to say.
Nothing escapes Laura's mind.
She is our
resident 13-year-old.
-LIAM: It was me that time.
-LAURA: It was actually him.
-It was him that time.
-MATT: You're twins, that's fine.
LIAM: Poopy.
MATT: Yes.
Skips ahead to the
exterior of some sort of
a mountain based cavern
that dips deep into the ground
in the center of this very,
very thick jungle-like terrain.
You can see portions
of the cavern here
have been ruined
and broken down
and there appears to be some
sort of geothermal activity
in the vicinity.
Your vision skips again
and you can see
a deep series
of winding caverns
that lead to what
looks to be like a stone--
a very, very old
stone laboratory.
You see cages.
You see wooden furniture.
You see what look to
be portions of bookshelves
that are toppled over.
And out of the blurry peripheral
of this one focal point
where the spell
has taken you,
you can see what looks
to be just out of sight,
a large deep red crimson mass
that is just resting still.
You also see what appear to be
to your other peripheral,
two ovoid-like red shapes that
are kind of resting in the edge.
And there at one
of the bookshelves
you see a woman
with long dark green hair.
Um, wounded and bleeding.
Currently pulling books out
of the shelf and opening them
and looking through and slamming
it closed and throwing it down
and pulling another
book and going through.
♪
The vision recedes and your eyes
blink and come back to you
and you're back
in the cavern of the lair.
MARISHA: She's not in Whitestone.
SAM: She was looking for the
third book of the trilogy
of Patrick Rothfuss--
(laughing)
It couldn't be
found anywhere!
Why can't I find
this fucking book?
(laughing)
MATT: And with that
we'll take our break.
(cheering)
That's your break, we'll--
(laughing)
Alright, we'll be back
here in a few minutes,
take a restroom break
and a snack break,
we'll see you
guys here shortly.
Stay tuned.
(laughing)
♪
Welcome back, ladies and
gentlemen, to Critical Role.
(laughing)
Well done, Liam, well done.
(indistinct remarks)
So welcome back.
Jumping back into our adventure.
(laughing)
So as the armies
begin to filter in,
word begins to spread
throughout the city that
every Fire Giant that
stood beneath Thordak
in the city has been slain.
A multitude of the lizardfolk
that were under Thordak
and the Conclaves barrier
have also been slain
or have fled the city.
The storm of the Ashari
has wandered and dissipated
as the immediate threat
of the wyvern riding horde
has fled towards the Stormcrest
Mountains to the Southeast,
and are now out of sight.
The armies have converged
and have begun
searching for survivors
and putting them
under their care.
Members of the Clasp
have begun to rise up
and meet with the
remaining armies
in discussions of how to bring
most of the survivors out
as the Clasp has actually been--
as they discussed before--
taking many of the survivors
that aren't already bound
to Thordak and keeping
them underground,
and kind of building small
underground tent cities
for them to live in while they
try and figure out what to do.
It's very interesting
with those of you
who've lived in Emon
for enough time
to see so many different people
and so many different
racial backgrounds,
cultural decrees
all coming to one point
and all working together
so quickly and so strongly
just for the sake
of recovery, for aid and
there is an air of relief.
Some people are gathering
the dead and identifying them,
bringing them out into portions
of the streets to make sure
that they are properly buried
and the families are
given notification.
You can see a lot of the
fires are being put out
and people are doing the
best they can to salvage
as much of the city
that still stands.
And a lot of the city
still stands untouched.
I'd say a good third
of it is gonna need
some serious reconstruction
and rebuilding.
And being one of the largest--
if not the largest city
on the continent, it's
gonna take some time.
You guys have begun
to speak with the Warmaster
as he approaches with his army,
and kind of trade stories
on what has transpired
on their end and yours.
And as this is happening,
a familiar face steps
into the district
with a small group
of cloaked figures.
LAURA: Oh shit.
MATT: Standing before you,
you see a tall,
scaled female Dragonborn,
tailless, armored,
Tofor Brotorus,
looking harried and exhausted.
She steps up and you
see what looks to be
the cusp of a toothy grin
at the edge of her mouth as
she catches your attention,
raises one hand.
"You have no idea how happy I am
to see that you all live.
So, if I'm to be told,
you are the ones
that took down the Cinder King?"
-TRAVIS: Yeah.
-TALIESIN: Yes.
MARISHA: Us and with the aid of
many others, of course.
MATT: "Then this is indeed
the turning point.
Do you have access to any
of the members of the council?
We've been cut off in
the Lyceum for months."
-TRAVIS: Aye.
-LAURA: Yes.
MARISHA: Allura is safe is
Whitestone currently.
We can say Whitestone now right?
-TALIESIN: We can say Whitestone now, yes.
-MARISHA: Okay.
-She's safe in Whitestone.
-TRAVIS: Whitestone.
-Sorry, are we not saying it?
-MARISHA: Whitestone, yeah.
It's kinda nice saying it again.
LAURA: Emperor Uriel's
wife and children
are in Whitestone as well.
MATT: "This is good to know,
I was worried about them
after the initial attack.
Okay, all right."
MARISHA: Asum should still be
here as well, right?
-TALIESIN: Back in Whitestone as well.
-MARISHA: Also back in Whitestone?
SAM: Mhm, Whitestone.
I think--wait,
Raishan was supposed
to take Asum somewhere.
Did we ever--
did that ever happen?
TRAVIS: I thought Asum came
down to the Ziggurat.
-MARISHA: Yeah.
-SAM: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
MARISHA: Raishan brought Asum back to us.
-LAURA: Yeah, that.
-LIAM: Sound of confidence.
-TALIESIN: It was like a month ago.
-MATT: "Very well.
With Warmaster's aid, and
any of you who are able to,
we'll begin to do
the best we can
to restructure some semblance
of law and order
here within the city."
MARISHA: And Kima's in there,
she's kind of guarding
the treasury, if you will.
-SAM: Solo.
-MARISHA: Solo, by herself.
LIAM: We were hoping to peel
off some of the troops,
maybe some of Syngorn's
troops to help
keep an eye on things in there.
MATT: "Well, master, could
you make that happen?"
You see Mikael Daxio
who is currently
in the midst of giving orders
to a few of his soldiers
kind of puts his hand
up and walks over.
"I'm sorry, what?"
"Mikael, if you would be able
to offer some aid or
strength of your troops
to guard what remains
of the city's economy."
And Mikael nods.
"Should not be a worry.
Of course, I'll uh--"
and he begins to
talk with Tofor,
and they begin to break
down and structure
how people are gonna
go here and there.
So the longer this progresses,
the more it gets
into more logistical
conversations.
What do you guys wanna do?
MARISHA: I fill them in on
what I saw in scrying.
More importantly, what
this means is that she
is on this plane of existence.
I can't scry if she's on
another plane, so she's here.
LIAM: Do you know where
that island is?
♪
MARISHA: I could attempt to think
really hard about it.
I could attempt to think.
SAM: The Marisha Ray Story.
LIAM: Scrying doesn't
give any direction.
MATT: I mean even the
visuals I'm giving
from a narrative standpoint
are like a little more
than the spell should,
but it's for fun.
MARISHA: Can I do like a--can
I do a roll to see--
-MATT: Make an intelligence check.
-MARISHA: Oh, geez.
Thanks for your vote
of confidence, Sam.
That's not good,
that's not good.
-SAM: For the dice.
-MARISHA: This is your fault.
-It's a five total.
-SAM: Yeah, it is.
MARISHA: Wait, wait, wait, no, just a
straight intelligence check?
-MATT: Yup, intelligence modifier.
-MARISHA: Yeah, it's five.
MATT: Yeah, you've--you,
for lack of a better term,
are the homeschooled
one of the bunch,
and you only recently left the--
well, before meeting the
rest of these adventurers,
you know, left Zephra to go
and see what the
world was about.
So, unfortunately, you don't
have as much worldly experience
as other people
on your team would.
So the visuals you
have clear in your mind,
you have no personal life
experience or any place
that you've seen that you
can connect the dots to.
MARISHA: I turned to Pike and asked--
and tell her of the island,
and ask if she has
encountered anything
like this in her travels.
MATT: She closes her eyes for a second
and kinda winces a little bit,
her tongue kinda peaks outside
her mouth for a second.
"Uh, no.
Wide ocean, you said, right?"
MARISHA: Big, nothing but ocean, except
for that one singular island.
It looked like there was
geothermal activity going on,
so it must be near a
volcano or something.
MATT: "Most of my sailing was
done in the Ozmit Sea."
MARISHA: Nothing like that?
MATT: "Nothing that I've seen.
Sorry."
MARISHA: It's okay, Pikey.
PATRICK: I'll throw a Hail Mary,
like how wide-ranging
was I back in the day
when I was doing
this for my career?
Any of this sound
familiar to me?
-MATT: Roll an intelligence check.
-LAURA: Come on!
(mixed remarks)
Natural 20!
-PATRICK: Eighteen.
-MATT: Eighteen?
Plus your intelligence modifier?
PATRICK: Eighteen.
No negative modifiers.
MATT: That's good.
Must be nice.
(laughing)
As Keyleth is going over
the description again,
you're thinking about it,
and you did a bit of sailing.
Sailing in the Lucidian
Ocean is difficult.
That's why Wildmount...
-Take it outside, Liam.
-LAURA: He's good, he's good.
-MARISHA: Don't die.
-LIAM: I pulled the wrong card
from the deck.
MATT: The glass of many drinks.
You've done a bit of
sailing out of necessity,
and the Lucidian Ocean is known
for being the more treacherous
of the large bodies
of water, which is why
between Wildmount and
the other continents
there isn't a whole lot
of trade, or the trade
that's out there is generally
considered very expensive
and for rarer items
and resources.
What catches your
mind is the idea
of geothermal activity.
And while you haven't
specifically been
to a place like that,
the islands you know
that usually contain
that type of
subvolcanic activity
to expel that type of, you know,
region based terrain,
those usually are in
the southern region,
south of Tal'Dorei.
♪
More like southern,
southern Ozmit Sea.
Close, but not specifically
to the Hespit Archipelago,
but somewhere in that
similar type region.
♪
SAM: Hespit Archipelago?
TRAVIS: I believe it's archipela-jo.
MATT: I'm gonna throw every
dice at you, Travis.
(laughing)
MARISHA: Southern southern Ozmit Sea.
PATRICK: This lair did not seem to
be the bookish sort of lair,
like the sort of dragon
who collects a lot of lore,
and would have like,
stuff like that, no.
MATT: No, not this one, this--the--
Thordak in particular
has been interesting too,
and as people have been
discussing it here--
once a very intelligent
and cunning Red Dragon.
You don't know the
full details of it,
but there was something
about his return
to this realm after being sealed
on the Fire Elemental plane,
his return involved harboring
an enchanted gem within
his chest that kind of held
and carried the essence of
the Fire plane with him,
and the longer it
resided within Thordak,
it caused him to mutate
and swell into this, like,
primordial beast dragon,
but it also drove him insane.
And so everything
you've seen in the lair,
it seems to be a natural
chaotic formation
of a more feral
type dragon mentality
than what you've heard
about in your travels.
PATRICK: Right, um, the only other thing
I can think of from
what you've described
is if she was there, and she--
and this place was obviously
in ruin and abandoned,
and she was tossing at
looking for information--
it wasn't hers,
but it's abandoned--
the only thing I can think
of that she would want
would be some sort
of lore or magic,
which means this is the lab
of someone powerful,
which means those people
show up in stories.
And so, that might be
a way to find out where this is.
In this area, if you find out
who was doing terrible things--
'cause you said cages, right?
-MARISHA: Yes.
-PATRICK: Nothing good comes from cages.
So whoever was doing terrible
things in that area--
LAURA: Maybe a necromancer
of some sort?
PATRICK: Well, if she stole
a dead dragon...
LAURA: Hm, all right.
TALIESIN: Can I make a lore roll
for Booky McBookerson?
MATT: Make a history check.
TALIESIN: Natural twenty.
(cheering)
PATRICK: The look of incredulity
on his face!
TALIESIN: That's a 29.
MATT: Literally was like,
If he's...
he better roll
a natural-- okay.
TALIESIN: You're just gonna hand me your
notebook and I can just read.
-MATT: No.
-TRAVIS: Well done, man.
MARISHA: Holy shit, holy shit!
TALIESIN: Knew there was one
in there somewhere.
MARISHA: Oh my god, you just saved
us a trip to the library.
-MATT: Don't say that yet.
-TALIESIN: I was about to say,
no, we're going to the library.
Use these places or
they disappear.
MATT: You have always had
a mild fascination
with the macabre.
And since the Age of
Arcanum was also referred
to as the Age of
Wanton Necromancy,
because at the time,
there was no law against it.
While necromancy exists
in modern day Tal'Dorei--
more so in Wildmount,
but it's generally
heavily regulated.
There are very few necromancers
that weren't sanctioned
or part of a government
system so that
it could be very
closely watched,
and any sort of research or
development could be made,
you know, made sure
that it didn't turn into
the usual classic, you know--
My power's greater
than everything, I'm gonna
go off and do my own thing.
The den that she's
describing is very much
that type of a necromancer.
And there are only a handful
that catch your attention.
One, uh,
is an entity that you're
very familiar with.
That is what was once
a great mage, necromancer,
that began to pursue
ascension to god-dom,
known as the Whispered One,
or the very familiar
name of Vecna.
However, however,
the acknowledgement
of Vecna's history
was heavily tied into Wildmount,
and what little bit
of research you've done
into the back history
of the Briarwoods
says that wherever Vecna's old,
forgotten laboratory was,
it most likely existed on
the continent of Wildmount.
The only other individual
you can think of
that is known historically
was an individual
known as Opash.
Opash was a
sanctioned necromancer
during the Age of Arcanum
on the continent of Marquet,
and then after being
discovered to be
delving into his own
experimentations,
largely in the idea of
crafting and sculpting flesh
and undead flesh into
whatever form it wishes,
as well as the prolonging of
life to pursue this endeavor,
was set to be,
was set to be executed.
Through some very,
very clever conversations
and favors that were owed
to Opash, it was agreed instead
to just banish the
necromancer out to sea.
-SAM: Well, that could be it too.
-MARISHA: Wait, what was that last part?
That was really important,
banish the necromancer
-out to sea?
-MATT: Banished out to sea.
-MARISHA: Who was banished to sea?
-MATT: Opash.
SAM: So those are two different
stories, two different--
MATT: Those are the only two, like,
famous necromancers that--
-SAM: Are a-sea.
-LAURA: You're brilliant.
MARISHA: You guys--you're all--
we have such smart friends.
Oh my goodness.
TALIESIN: Well, we need to, in theory,
find the last resting
place of Opash.
MARISHA: Well, you know, we have--
TALIESIN: Can't be harder than
killing a Red Dragon.
MARISHA: We have a paladin
of the Raven Queen,
and from what I remember, the
Raven Queen hates necromancers.
LAURA: Vecna is one of
her sworn enemies.
MARISHA: Maybe she knows, maybe
you could talk to her.
TALIESIN: We can do that
back at Whitestone.
PATRICK: What do I know about
the Raven Queen?
(laughing)
Because that one's,
that one's new to me.
MATT: So yes, it catches
your attention.
The Raven Queen,
the mother of ravens
is, um, is a fairly
prominent member
of the Pantheon of Exandria,
the entire world.
Once immortal,
ascended to take on
the mantle of death and winter
as her domains of influence.
She presides not
over the afterlife,
but the moment in transition
from life to death.
She is the keeper of fate,
and keeps watch over
the destinies of those
who walk the prime
and beyond planes,
and occasionally takes
interest in those
that tend to bend the
threads around them.
Um, you know,
resurrection, healing magic,
things that maintain
life naturally
or a natural life, per se,
are not infractions
upon her belief
as destiny is stronger and
if an entity is meant to live
to fulfill his destiny,
then that is how
it's meant to be.
It's the creatures
that pervert destiny,
creatures that bypassed
the natural predestined
and essentially, balk what,
in her sphere,
says is supposed to be
your way, your path,
your timeline.
Those are her fervent enemies.
Largely feared because
of what she represents.
Largely misunderstood because
Generally, worship of the
Raven Queen is pretty rare
from the circles
you've run into.
You've generally
walked in a lot of--
especially in recent years--
more, um--
for lack of a better term--
-not urban--
-LAURA: Rural.
MATT: Rural, thank you,
more rural environments
Raven Queen worship
is acknowledged,
but generally there's
no temples to her.
-PATRICK: Right, okay.
-TALIESIN: I love the notion of
cornfield Raven Queen worship.
LAURA: So creepy.
TALIESIN: Ohh, I'm damned for that.
(laughing)
MATT: Oh, don't worry, you'll
get to Wildmount eventually.
-MARISHA: I'm sure they're out there.
-TALIESIN: The harvest is good this year.
LAURA: You know, Raishan did say--
I mean, I know she's
prone to lying,
but she did say she
was from Wildmount.
That's where she wanted
to go back to she said.
TALIESIN: We have two very clean paths.
LAURA: Maybe she's studying necromancy,
maybe she's been studying Vecna,
maybe she's been studying Opash.
TALIESIN: Maybe she's been studying a
lot of things, but one of them
would probably be how to
resurrect a red dragon.
MARISHA: And she's also very
familiar with, I'm sure,
whatever the Briarwoods were
doing, and with whatever
the Ziggurat is on
the bottom of Whitestone
that we still don't know
what it's technically for.
-LAURA: She knows what it is.
-MARISHA: I bet she does.
LAURA: She knows what
the orb of death is.
-MARISHA: Is Gilmore still around?
-MATT: Gilmore is.
Gilmore's kind of listening
to the conversation
while finishing closing off
the satchels that he's filled
with coin, and is currently
kind of thinking to himself
with his, you know,
fingers crossed, his chin
kind of perched upon his hands,
and himself, trying to see
if there's anything he knows
out of the conversation.
You do notice that also at
this point there's a very faint
glowing glyph on his forehead.
-MARISHA: Yeah.
-SAM: What is that thing?
-MATT: Do you say that?
-LAURA: Yeah.
-What's going on there?
-TALIESIN: What's on your face?
MARISHA: You've got a little, you've
got a little something.
SAM: You always look dashing,
but you have a new added
dashing feature to your
forehead right now.
-LAURA: Gold, right up--
-MATT: Oh, and he kinda waves a hand
briefly, and it kind of
fades back into his skin
and it's like there's
no glow there.
"Ha, it's a, it's a,
just a thing."
SAM: Oh, that seems fine, okay.
(laughing)
-LAURA: No, seriously.
-MARISHA: Hopefully a good thing.
MATT: "Everyone has their
magical specialties.
I, um, I carry,
I carry power in my bloodline."
SAM: What power?
MATT: He looks back,
'cause there's people
kind of in the vicinity,
and he--
LAURA: Just mouth it, I can read lips.
MATT: He kinda goes,
"I'm what they refer
to as a runechild.
LAURA: What does that,
what does that mean?
-MATT: You don't know.
-LAURA: I know, what does it mean?
-MATT: Go and make a history check.
-LAURA: Okay.
♪
-Oh no, I don't know.
-TRAVIS: You don't know shit.
-You know less than me.
-TALIESIN: What's a child?
(laughing)
MATT: Who are you, who am I?
TRAVIS: I've got a new weapon
down in the, in the lair.
Can you identify this?
-MATT: "I can."
-TRAVIS: Just take a look at it.
MATT: "I've got a few low level spells
still available, certainly.
Oh, this is quite
a fancy endeavor."
TRAVIS: It's really pretty.
MATT: "Oh, it's not just pretty,
it'll perform for you.
This, my friend,
is a dancing sword."
SAM: A dancing sword?
-MARISHA: How does it work?
-LAURA: How do you make it work?
TRAVIS: I throw it on the ground.
SAM: I start playing a ditty.
(imitating instrument playing)
-MATT: Okay, what'd you do, Grog?
-TRAVIS: I threw it on the ground.
I throw it on the ground!
I don't need your dancing!
MATT: My weapon's not a sword!
TRAVIS: Duh!
(laughing)
MATT: I'm not part of
your feudal system!
All right, so you throw
the sword on the ground.
-TRAVIS: Yeah.
-MATT: Okay.
-TRAVIS: It's gonna kill me.
-LIAM: Clang-a-lang-a-lang.
-TRAVIS: Clang-a-lang-a-lang.
-MATT: Here we go.
(humming)
The sword goes clang-clang.
The music's playing,
sword just stays there.
LAURA: I don't think that's
how it works, Grog.
SAM: ♪ Dancing sword ♪
♪ Feel the-- ♪♪
TRAVIS: I feel moved by Scanlan's
tunes, and I go over
and I pick up the sword and...
(singing gibberish)
SAM: Maybe it has to lead, Grog.
(crosstalk)
(laughing)
SAM: ♪ I know this much is true ♪♪
MATT: As Grog slowly rotates,
caressing the back
of this ornate scimitar,
the music emanating
from Scanlan's fantastic shaum.
A number of nearby military
begin to slowly turn
and just kind of cock
their heads and watch
as an unexpected
display presents itself
amongst the Cloudtop ruins.
♪
TRAVIS: Perverts.
MATT: Gilmore leans in,
"You might wanna spend
some time with it first.
I don't think it
trusts you yet."
-SAM: Take it to dinner.
-TRAVIS: Yeah, but it's very sharp.
LAURA: Sit down and
compliment it a lot.
LIAM: I think you have to hang out in
the shitter with it for a while.
TRAVIS: Oh right, shitter, compliments,
take it to dinner.
MARISHA: Conjure some wine in your jug.
-LAURA: Oh, good call.
-TRAVIS: For it or for me?
-LAURA: Both, both.
-TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: "Once it likes you it'll
tell you a magic word.
Use the word and that
sword fights on its own."
-SAM: On its own?
-TRAVIS: Really?
-TALIESIN: Like a Warner Brothers cartoon.
-LAURA: So you can fight--
it can fight and he can
fight with another thing?
(gasping and laughing)
-You should give it to Scanlan.
-TRAVIS: What?
LAURA: I'm sorry.
TRAVIS: She forgets herself
sometimes, it's all right.
Thank you, Gilmore.
MATT: "Of course, anything
else you need?"
MARISHA: Back to the runechild thing.
-MATT: "Yes?"
-MARISHA: What's that about?
LIAM: What's a runechild, Shaun?
LAURA: You don't have to tell us if
you don't want to, but please.
MATT: "Well, I just--
it's, um,
it's a natural thing that
some people are born with.
It's a gift, it's, um--"
MARISHA: Like scoliosis?
-MATT: "Adjacent."
-LIAM: That means I had it.
MATT: "But no, it's--there
aren't many of us,
and let's just say,
in times past, we were--
runechildren
were sought after.
Not always by the
best of intentions.
So I'd like to keep
this information--"
-MARISHA: Sure.
-LAURA: Of course.
LIAM: Was that a problem even in Emon
or just where you hail from?
TALIESIN: Another threat we need to
deal with at some point.
MATT: "It pervaded the
entire Age of Arcanum,
but, um, it's not that it's--
it's just not well
understood, and, uh,
um, just please."
TRAVIS: Your word is safe with
us because I don't know
what you're talking about.
MATT: "That's why I like you, Grog.
The details go nowhere."
MARISHA: Gilmore, in your time
in growing up on Marquet,
did you ever hear any tale
of someone named Opesh?
-LAURA: Opash.
-MATT: "Opash?"
-MARISHA: He's a necromancer.
-LAURA: Terrible necromancer.
-MATT: "Hmm."
-TRAVIS: Don't tell him.
MATT: "Can't say I have, I'm sorry.
I wasn't really a
history buff, sorry."
LAURA: Damn, I bet J'Mon
would've known.
TALIESIN: We have to go back anyway.
-LAURA: We have a hand to deliver.
-TALIESIN: We do, we have many things.
If anything else, the next order
of business is to make a list.
SAM: That's what I'm doing right now.
TALIESIN: I'm not actually
going to build a list,
we're just gonna make--
MARISHA: How much longer do you think
Raishan will stay there?
Especially if she's not finding
what she's looking for.
-TRAVIS: Not long.
-TALIESIN: I think it'll be a base
of operations, that's
what I would do.
If I thought that I was
going to be safe somewhere,
I would stay there
and simply hunt out,
much as we did with Whitestone.
Safe until it's not.
LAURA: Do you think she knew
you were scrying on her?
MARISHA: She didn't seem to notice.
A lot of times
you can kinda tell.
-LAURA: Yeah.
-MARISHA: She seemed distracted.
-TALIESIN: She's been beaten pretty badly.
-MARISHA: Yeah.
LAURA: We should get to Whitestone.
SAM: Is here taken care of?
And do we need to stop
in on our home, our keep,
and do anything there
before we leave?
LIAM: I mean, can--aren't
we all tapped out?
Can you get us
to Whitestone now?
LAURA: Maybe we spend the
night in the keep
-for old time's sake.
-SAM: For old time's sake.
-TRAVIS: The old hangout!
-MARISHA: I could get us to--
back to Whitestone using
my last seventh level spell,
and then that's it,
I'm done, done, done.
-TALIESIN: We could go home.
-SAM: You couldn't get all of us,
-right, I mean--
-MARISHA: No, transport via plants.
SAM: But like Jarrett,
and Kima, and Gilmore--
-MARISHA: It lasts six seconds.
-MATT: "If we all go quickly, yeah."
-LIAM: We could get in a line.
-MARISHA: I think my record was like
25 people when we were
moving refugees through.
Yeah, it was pretty good,
still trying to break that.
MATT: "I would recommend not
really trying to break it."
PATRICK: We don't wanna
get 25 and a half.
(laughing)
MATT: "You've seen it
happen, I can tell."
(mixed remarks)
"Well, I'm glad I'm alive,
I'm glad you're all alive."
-LAURA: Thank you for helping.
-LIAM: Thank you, Shaun.
MATT: "It's the least I could do,
and if anything, it's really--
this experience has helped me
come to terms with the fact
that I should not be
on the battlefield.
I need to stay in
the shop, and I--"
TRAVIS: That is not true, that finger
of yours is very powerful.
MATT: "Yes, and I was
also on fire a lot.
-I want to avoid that."
-TRAVIS: That's true.
TALIESIN: Are you gonna be
rebuilding your shop here
or are we gonna see you
in Whitestone as well?
MATT: "You know, my intent
a while back
was to start a franchise.
We'll see how the winds carry
me, after all, I think--"
And he kinda tugs open this
large heavy sack and satchel
that's on his side now,
and to the other side you see
a small compact bag of
holding, and he goes,
"I think I've got
it taken care of."
(laughing)
-LAURA: Nice.
-TRAVIS: Brilliant.
We wish you well, Gilmore.
MATT: "Well, I mean, if you're
going to Whitestone,
-I'm coming with you."
-TRAVIS: No, you gotta stay.
I'm just kidding, you can come.
(laughing)
LAURA: Ker, are you gonna come
to Whitestone with us?
♪
LIAM: Stay the night and
have a drink with us.
-SAM: Are we going now?
-LAURA: We can bounce you back.
SAM: We're not even gonna go to
our keep for a little bit.
-Did we go there?
-TALIESIN: We did, we came in.
-Stopped by the ruins.
-SAM: All right.
TRAVIS: Heyo, heyo, Ker, heyo.
PATRICK: I could use a drink,
I would love to.
I would love to,
give me just a moment,
and I head back to the troops
and I talk to, like,
the couple of them
that have kind
of like risen up--
-LAURA: Samantha.
-PATRICK: Samantha, yeah,
like fucking runs the
whole thing right now.
-LIAM: Sam's pretty legit.
-PATRICK: Yeah.
And so--and I also
kind of circumspectly--
I sort of distribute
a little bit of money.
I give Samantha some,
and this is like--
it's like if something happens,
if I don't come back,
here's how long you stay,
here's what to do
among the populous.
Like--and I don't need to
give them the talk of like,
No looting, 'cause they've
already had Daddy Ker
like constantly lecturing them
about how to not be dicks.
MATT: The kind of people that would
follow you into battle for this,
as small as your group was,
the kind of people that you know
you can trust this, and
Samantha with her like,
kind of, you know, graying
hair that's pulled into
this kind of hard topknot
on top, and her darker skin
with the scar across her cheek,
and her breastplate of armor,
she comes up and kind of
grabs your hand and goes,
"Don't worry, I've got it
taken care of, it's fine."
PATRICK: Right, yeah, it's right,
you've done it before.
MATT: "We've gathered the dead, we'll
make sure with what you've given
that we'll get it back to
the families that remain."
PATRICK: Right, this is gonna be
a tricky place for
a couple of weeks,
and not only could our
people maybe use a rest,
but maybe it would benefit from
30 or 40 level-handed
people with swords
maybe keeping an eye out,
maybe traveling in
pairs around the city
making sure nobody's
houses get broken into.
Just--you can't take
care of everything,
but it would not be bad to
camp out maybe for a week.
Wait for me, and I'll be back,
and if I'm not,
you know where to go.
MATT: "Hey, I'm always down to
rough up some ruffians."
PATRICK: It's--yeah, okay.
-MATT: "Ker, go with your friends."
-PATRICK: Okay.
TRAVIS: Is Samantha attractive?
LAURA: Should we--just ignore.
She has that breastplate.
MATT: Yeah, I mean, she
looks like she could
definitely bruise you in
the face with a left hook.
So, for you, yeah.
TRAVIS: Awesome, hey, Ker, Ker.
-PATRICK: Hm?
-TRAVIS: Put in a good word.
PATRICK: I--she--I...
(laughing)
TRAVIS: Hey.
♪
MATT: "He's going with you, right?"
-PATRICK: Yeah.
-MATT: "Great, okay."
LAURA: Does Kima wanna come with us?
MATT: Yeah, Kima's ready
to go, she's like,
"All right, we're going
back to Whitestone?"
LAURA: Does everything look
like it's in order
with Daxio, with everyone here?
-MATT: "Sure."
-LAURA: Are we good to leave?
MATT: "I don't do the
whole council thing,
but they assure me it's fine,
Allie's gonna know what to do.
I just--this is
really depressing me."
LAURA: I look at Daxio, is everything
okay, can we cut out--
MATT: He's in the middle
of a conversation.
"Yes, yes, we've got it covered.
Let Allura know
as soon as she can,
come to us, we have
a lot to discuss."
-LAURA: Will do.
-MATT: "Everyone, thank you."
-LAURA: Thank you.
-MATT: "And from me,
from all the civilians
of the city,
from Tal'Dorei proper,
we all owe you a great
debt of gratitude."
LAURA: Thank you for having our back.
MATT: "Thank you for having ours.
Now, off with you, you
know where to find us."
LIAM: Kima, come on, let's
get you back to Allie.
-MARISHA: We gotta find a tree.
-SAM: Might I just--
-TALIESIN: We have a tree at the keep.
-MARISHA: We do have a tree at the keep
if we wanted to make
a stop at the keep.
SAM: So we are now
stiffing The Clasp.
-LAURA: No.
-TALIESIN: No.
LAURA: By the way, Daxio...
(laughing)
I'm sure you're aware, but--
and we'll let Allura
know as well--The Clasp
was instrumental in keeping
survivors alive here in Emon.
-They definitely deserve a bit of the pot.
-TALIESIN: Compensation.
-SAM: Handsome reward.
-MATT: "We'll discuss with them.
I do believe that we've already
had a few conversations
with a few operatives during
our arrival within the city,
and they've been
very forthcoming
with information,
and willing to aid us.
So, yes, I appreciate
the acknowledgement."
LAURA: We wouldn't have made
it here without them.
SAM: Please let them know
that we vouched for them.
LIAM: They've at least earned
the old status quo.
-TRAVIS: What is that?
-MATT: "Very well."
LAURA: I have no idea.
PATRICK: And just to mention,
if you take people like that
and give them, in a place
in your town,
you can keep an eye on them.
MATT: He eyes kinda narrow a little
bit, he nods towards you.
"Indeed.
Well, I'll take it from here.
Return when you can.
Get Allura back to us,
and stay safe."
And he turns back to
handle some more business.
What do you guys wanna do?
-TRAVIS: Make for Greyskull Keep--
-LAURA: Where our giant tree is
so we can go to
our other giant tree.
-MATT: Okay.
-MARISHA: What they said.
MATT: You guys make your
way walking southward
through Emon, and--
LAURA: Just loot everything
along the way, like--
-MARISHA: Just like decking children.
-LAURA: Every person you see.
(crosstalk)
LIAM: Matt starts rolling
random encounters.
MATT: Six episodes just
getting out of Emon.
(laughing)
TRAVIS: Why the hell did we walk?
MATT: You guys make your way
through, and as you do,
it's, it's an emotional journey,
because as you walk through
the city that became your home
as you all became a family,
you can see familiar sights,
you can see familiar
thoroughfares,
and streetsides, and taverns,
many of which have
sustained severe damage,
many that have been reduced
to nothing but rubble and ash.
And some that still
stand defiantly
versus all the
difficulty, and stress,
and strenuous struggle
that has existed
for weeks and weeks
and weeks here.
You see people slowly
emerging from the shadows
to try and reclaim what
remains of their life,
but you also see them
helping each other.
You also see a comparison
between the busy bustle
and kind of general
selfish lifestyle
that most people in a well-off
capital city exist in
replaced with a newly
understood sense of kinship
and looking out for each other.
You see the guards
themselves beginning
to really understand,
in their lifetime,
the first true,
large-scale victory
for the betterment
of their people and
what that means to them.
And there's kinda
a sense of pride
through the sadness that
many of the armed soldiers
you've come across
probably never had.
♪
It gives you hope,
though to see it in
such a state in itself
is harrowing in its own right.
You can already begin to
see through this energy
and through the
slow crawling return
to life that you've
helped ensure
that Emon still has a future,
let alone Tal'Dorei itself.
No one catches your
attention as you leave,
but a number of eyes train
onto you as you exit.
And many of them flash
with recognition,
their face going bright,
and then with just a solemn nod
of, "Thank you."
Eventually you find yourself
to the southern gates of Emon
exiting out into the charred
fields that once were green
and lush with grain and grass.
Eventually coming upon the
exterior of Greyskull Keep,
the home of Vox Machina.
Just as you left it, abandoned,
the front gate partially ajar.
There stands the keep.
Mighty, defiant,
and somewhere there is a jar
of no-longer-magical poop.
(laughing)
Making your way inside, there
is the garden that you left
within the Temple to Sarenrae
and the large central
tree that you use
for most of your transport
to and from, Keyleth.
-MARISHA: How's the garden look?
-MATT: Looks as good as you left it.
It was far enough from
the battle to where
it didn't seem to suffer
any sort of blows or issues.
You guys managed to basically
focus everything within
the city's walls, so,
good on you for that.
MARISHA: Okay, anybody need anything?
SAM: Not gonna go through the--
need anything from
your rooms or anything?
-LAURA: We'll be back here.
-SAM: Change of underwear?
-TRAVIS: What's that?
-LAURA: It's all at Whitestone.
We have everyone with us.
Jarrett, Kash, Zahra.
MATT: They've all kinda
walked along with you.
LIAM: I'm just gonna
pluck another flower
and tuck it behind my ear.
MATT: Okay.
As Keyleth steps forward
and places her hands
across the base of
the tree, she focuses
and it's almost like
grasping two ends of a bag
and then pulling it open
with alternating zippers.
You watch the bark split,
and as it opens up
and crawls from floor
to the seven-foot apex,
a doorway is opened temporarily,
and on the other side
you immediately see the,
the slow morning sun
beginning to rise
in Whitestone across the city.
-SAM: Jump in.
-MARISHA: Six seconds, go, go, go!
MATT: You all go charging through
as fast as you can,
all emerging into the center
of Whitestone's central area,
the twilight being slowly
cast away by the rising sun.
The Sun Tree at your back as
the doorway closes behind you,
and the cold air
immediately catches your lungs.
You've been amongst
the heat and the clouds
of smoke and soot
of Emon for so long
amongst the struggle,
the cold crisp air is almost
a welcome moment of respite
from that experience.
You look around you and
the little bits of grass
have broken the cobblestone
and floor of the open area,
have bits of frozen dew
across their surface,
and it's this beautiful
crystal moment
of peace that you didn't realize
you've been seeking
for quite some time.
You can see the gentle bit
of light beginning to crest
over the mountains, hitting
Castle Whitestone ahead of you.
You've returned.
What do you wanna do?
LAURA: Well, I thought it would a
be a nightcap, but it seems
like it's a morning cap instead.
-LIAM: That's our specialty.
-TALIESIN: It's night somewhere.
LIAM: That is our specialty.
LAURA: Head to the castle,
have a drink,
-tell Allura what's going on.
-MARISHA: Should find Allura.
And Cassandra.
TALIESIN: Yes, let's head to the castle.
♪
-LAURA: Hey, Ker.
-PATRICK: Hm?
LAURA: Wanna see where we live?
PATRICK: I will admit to a
passing curiosity.
TALIESIN: Let's give him a tour.
LIAM: This place was full
of fucking vampires.
They were everywhere,
they were giants.
It was terrible,
we've renovated, yeah.
SAM: We led a rebellion and I was
the general, it was amazing.
-TALIESIN: We let him say that.
-LAURA: He was a dinosaur.
LIAM: Any beret you see one
someone's head right now
is because of this
man right here.
LAURA: Oh, and that flat part
of land, that's mine.
(laughing)
TRAVIS: I thought they said
that was the wastelands.
LAURA: No, it's mine.
TRAVIS: Isn't that where
they bury all the shit?
-SAM: Yup.
-TRAVIS: Yup.
(laughing)
♪
MATT: As you guys walk your way up
the path to Castle Whitestone,
the Pale Guard morning shift
has already begun to
walk across the grounds.
They greet you, you're
let into the castle,
and from your perspective,
this hillside,
this small mountain that
marks the northern side
of Whitestone, the city that
sits in the central valley
surrounded by the
thick Parchwood Forest,
you see this beautiful castle.
Not too large, but enough
to have once housed
a very respectable royal family,
if you will, of at least
lord and lady blood.
Made of a dull pale gray.
You've never been to Whitestone,
you've heard about it,
and you immediately assume that,
Well, this is what they call it
'cause the castle itself
has a little bit of white.
Entering inside, it's
slowly beginning to rouse.
You sense some energy
with the sunrise.
People begin to make breakfast
and guards begin to walk past.
Eventually, with you guys
taking a moment to kind of rest
and even grab a
little bit of food,
as early as it is,
Cassandra enters.
You watch as a woman in her--
what you can only imagine
to be late teens,
early twenties physically,
but her eyes carry
the wisdom that only
years of trauma
and survival can hold.
Her dark brunette hair with
a single shock of white
that kind of curls to the back.
Walks in, consciousness--
as much as you could
expect from a girl
that early in the morning.
Has her hands kinda
clasped at her chest.
"Well, um, back
so soon, are we?"
MARISHA: Is it soon?
It feels like we've been--
at least two weeks.
(sighing)
(laughing)
LIAM: More like five.
MARISHA: That's true.
Like a holiday break happened.
LAURA: Thordak is dead.
MATT: "Then it is done,
I'm proud of you all."
-LAURA: It's not done.
-LIAM: It's not done.
TALIESIN: But it's a victory.
-We've had a good day.
-MARISHA: We're not dead.
MATT: "I can see that,
and I'm quite thankful.
Um, your friend, I don't
believe I've had the honor."
-MARISHA: Oh yeah, this is Ker.
-PATRICK: Am I still like--
do I look like Brian Blessed
who's just been through,
like, a bloody fucking massacre?
-Am I still like--
-MATT: All of you do.
All of you right now
are just wrecked.
-PATRICK: Okay.
-MATT: Like still,
still shiny from
like oils and sweat.
There's still like
smeared ash and--
PATRICK: It's probably not until
right then where I'm like,
I am, I am a fucking mess.
I'm like up to
elbows bloody, yeah.
-TALIESIN: You fit right in here.
-PATRICK: Yeah, okay.
MATT: "I've not had the pleasure."
PATRICK: Ker, it's a pleasure
to meet you.
LAURA: How did you know we
were here, Cassandra?
MATT: "The guards went
and summoned me.
To be perfectly honest,
I don't usually rouse
so early in the morning,
but this is good news.
And to be perfectly honest,
the last few times
the guards have summoned
me with your arrival,
they've been with
a bit of a scare.
So, um, it's an absolute
pleasure to make
your acquaintance, Ker,
you are welcome here.
Any friends of my friends
are a friend of mine."
LAURA: Can we roll an insight check
to see if it's really her?
-LIAM: Sure.
-MATT: Sure, roll an insight check.
-LAURA: I don't trust anybody now.
-TRAVIS: Me too, it was my idea.
LIAM: You've burned us too
many times, Matt.
-LAURA: Twenty-five.
-LIAM: She's a beholder.
TRAVIS: Four.
(laughing)
-LAURA: This is just a ruse.
-SAM: Secrets!
LAURA: It's not gonna be Raishan.
(laughing)
Go team.
MATT: Suddenly suffers how much psychic damage?
-SAM: Vex.
-LAURA: Huh?
Do you think this would be my
reaction if it was Raishan?
(laughing)
MATT: "Well, rest."
TALIESIN: Have a bit a of drink,
we're going to rest, and then--
MATT: "Well, you know where
we keep the wine."
LAURA: ♪ Bloody Marys ♪
♪ Mimosas ♪♪
MATT: "Are we expecting more
or is it just you?"
-TALIESIN: Did Vex just do that?
-SAM: It's just us for now.
-I think--
-TRAVIS: It's just us, yeah.
SAM: They never gave our
airship any instructions.
I guess it's just
roaming the countryside.
TRAVIS: It's just us this time, I know
we usually have a lot in tow--
SAM: Oh, and we don't need to--
well, do we need to keep
the force field up
around the city anymore?
TALIESIN: No, everything's--we can
stand down at this point.
It's time for everything
to rest briefly.
-LAURA: We need to wake Allura.
-TALIESIN: We do need to wake Allura.
MATT: "All right, I'll
have her roused.
The rest of you, if you wish,
I could have baths drawn.
I think you could use it."
-TALIESIN: What are you trying to imply?
-MATT: "Brother."
TALIESIN: I know, I know,
you owe me--I owe one.
LIAM: You don't like
Dragon Age splatter?
(laughing)
TRAVIS: Paintbrush of gore.
MATT: "I mean no disrespect,
but as a lady
of esteemed blood, you
are all a terrible mess."
TALIESIN: I am going to walk right up
to her, give her a big hug.
MATT: "No, no, no, no!"
And for a second, for
a second you see a glimmer
of the young sister
that grew up with Percy
fighting him off,
and she pushes him off.
(laughing)
"Thank you."
TALIESIN: I am going to be owed for much
more than that, I'm well aware.
MATT: "Yes, yes, you are.
-I'm glad you're back."
-TALIESIN: It's good to be home.
MATT: "All right, I'll have
Allura brought to you.
Rest well, should you
require anything, I'll be
in my chambers
waking properly."
She leaves the room.
♪
Though you had--brought
little scraps of food
as they were available,
a full breakfast meal
is properly prepared
for you, warm food.
LAURA: This is post bath
and we're clean?
MATT: Yeah, you guys take time
just being cleaned properly.
TALIESIN: We're spying, we're spying.
MARISHA: My hair is still
singed short again.
SAM: Before we part
ways with Jarrett,
I'd like to pull him
aside a little bit.
MATT: As you pull Jarrett aside,
you get but a few steps away
and he goes, "I'm
not doing it again."
SAM: I know, I know.
I just wanted to thank
you for your efforts,
and, you know, it really
meant a lot to me,
and I'm gonna cast
an eighth level
modify memory on you.
(laughing)
-TALIESIN: What?
-TRAVIS: I love him so much.
MARISHA: You still have an
eighth level spell?
(laughing)
LAURA: You have an eighth
level spell left?
SAM: Yeah.
(crosstalk)
MATT: Okay, okay.
LAURA: I don't even feel
bad that he died now.
MATT: Is this through the hand cone,
because that's a whole--
-that's not subtle.
-SAM: No, it would not be subtle,
-so I cannot do the hand cone.
-MATT: That's okay, he rolled a five.
So, what are you modifying?
SAM: When he delivered
the suude to me,
I thanked him for it
and I went into a--
I'm implanting this
memory in his head.
I told him why I
needed it so badly,
and it was a very sad tale
of how a goblin killed my
mother and the image haunts me
to this day and I can't
get through a night--
I can't function without
some sort of sustenance.
He felt terrible for me and
vowed to get me more, much more.
(laughing)
And at that time,
I gave him 50 platinum.
TRAVIS: Holy shit, you're
turning into a drug lord.
SAM: Which he finds in his pocket
now, because I gave it to him.
TALIESIN: We have met the
enemy, oh my god.
-MARISHA: You're going full Heisenberg.
-SAM: And he feels for me.
-TRAVIS: He is Heisenberg.
-TALIESIN: He is the one that knocks.
(laughing)
(crosstalk)
SAM: I broke down and he's never
seen me break down like that.
-MATT: No, he hasn't.
-SAM: In his mind anyway.
-MATT: He hasn't, and--
-TALIESIN: Wow!
-TRAVIS: Outstanding.
-TALIESIN: I can't--what?
-MATT: Okay.
-SAM: That's that.
MATT: All right, and at which
point you watch as his eyes
kind of glaze over for a moment.
He was about to make his way
towards getting his own shower.
He let everybody else go first,
and he kinda stops for a second
and his eyes glaze over, and
he kinda blinks for a second.
"Well, I understand these
have been very trying days.
If there's anything I can
do to help, let me know."
SAM: You know how to help.
(laughing)
MATT: And you see the look in his
eyes that you've seen before,
which is the, I don't do this,
I barely know how to do this,
and the connections I have,
it's, it's gonna be hard.
And you see this look, but
as opposed--where previously
it was, I can't
do this anymore.
He goes--he reaches up,
touches your shoulder and goes,
"I'll do what I can."
SAM: That's all I ask.
LIAM: Yeah, Mr. Shorthalt, yeah.
-TRAVIS: Meat man coming.
-MARISHA: What the fuck?
SAM: Rest well, Jarrett, thank
you for your brave battle.
MARISHA: Oh my god, oh my god.
MATT: "Just so you know, I'm
expecting a raise, 'cause, uh,
I kinda almost died like twice.
It's ridiculous."
SAM: You should've seen me.
I did.
MATT: "I'll see what I can do."
Then he goes and
leaves to take a bath.
LIAM: We were all taking baths, right?
And they're like big royal baths
'cause this is Whitestone?
MATT: Yeah, there's maybe four
at any given point in time.
So you guys still have
to kinda take turns.
LIAM: Excellent, I take
mine very quickly,
and walk in the buck, and
I find Percival's bath,
and silently walk
in while he's bathing,
and I sit in the bath
on the other side,
and just stare for a minute.
TALIESIN: You know you're getting weirder.
(laughing)
LIAM: Um...
♪
You and I are very different.
TALIESIN: I would agree, although,
again, I'm in a bath
at the moment...
Cut to it, I think,
I was really
working on something.
(laughing)
LIAM: I didn't think you were,
uh, so meek.
Umm...
Anyway, I still plan
to honor your request,
but, um...
I want you to know...
that you are like
a brother to me.
♪
Now I have a sister,
and we fight constantly,
so I expect to do that with you.
TALIESIN: I'd hope so.
♪
LIAM: I'm glad I have you
around still.
TALIESIN: Me as well, I--
I like this family,
I'd like to keep it.
♪
LIAM: Don't say another word.
I show him my ass
and I leave.
LAURA: As soon as he leaves,
I come up from the water
and go, Ugh!
(laughing)
I thought he'd never leave!
TRAVIS: Amazing!
Amazing!
TALIESIN: I was so hoping
you were gonna do that.
MARISHA: How big are
these fucking bathtubs!
-TALIESIN: They're big bathtubs!
-LIAM: That is so gross!
That was like a minute long!
TALIESIN: I love you,
that was wonderful.
LIAM: So gross!
(laughing continues)
Oh, my--
My opinion of you has changed!
LAURA: You don't know!
You don't know, you're gone!
TALIESIN: She was just tickling
on the back of my knee
the entire time.
LIAM: I'm not talking about Vex!
Vex can pork him all she wants,
I don't give a fuck!
That is a twisted
D&amp;D choice, man!
MATT: That is--that is
an amazing D&amp;D choice.
LIAM: That is crazier--
that shit is crazier
than the broom to me, Laura.
Holy shit.
Boosh!
-Hit me up top!
-MATT: Hey, Laura--
TRAVIS: I'm working on something here,
cut to the chase.
MARISHA: I'm working on something.
SAM: We gotta speed this up!
(laughing)
MATT: In hindsight,
that changes everything.
-Wow.
-LIAM: Yes, yes and!
(laughing)
MARISHA: Is that where those
water-breathing potions
-have gone to?
-TALIESIN: Literally--
we are actually
bathing in them, ironically.
In the water flow.
MATT: It's like The Abyss.
(laughing)
LIAM: Percy, what is that
really cheesy music
that's playing in here?
MATT: All right, so...
unless you have
any more particular
bath-based shenanigans
to encounter...
TALIESIN: I will leave that
to peoples' imaginations.
LIAM: I need a shower with lye, man!
(laughing)
TRAVIS: Amazing.
MATT: ...and that might work better.
TALIESIN: ...while that was happening.
Let me remind you of that.
LIAM: It looks just like us.
PATRICK: I heard somebody
has alter-memory spells,
if you can hit me with that.
MATT: No, he only does it to people
that don't deserve it.
LIAM: Oh, man!
I can barely remember
those dragons right now.
MATT: So, after you've all come--
finished bathing, come down
to get your breakfast,
and you've all kinda
gathered around the table
and there's, you know, chatter,
that sort of,
the release after
so many nerves built up
even though there is
still things to tackle,
there is a moment
of kinship and respite
and, honestly, Ker,
it's a little strange
for you at first.
You--such jovial atmosphere
in the face of such...
you know, recent tragedy
and trauma
reminds you of back
when you used to do this.
And it's weirdly welcome.
You know, it's very humanizing,
and there's a brotherhood
that comes after battle
that you can only describe
if you've been there.
And it's been a while
since you've had
this type of brotherhood.
And even though you're quiet
amongst their chatter,
and they are a family
that you're outside of,
you can't fight the smile.
PATRICK: Oh, no, it's--this is--
and actually it's, you know,
it's very nice to watch
like, you know--
It did not stay
like this for me,
and it's obviously
staying like this for them.
And so, yeah, I'm very happy.
And honestly,
if there is liquor here,
I probably do not stay
very quiet for long.
(laughing)
LAURA: So much liquor.
MATT: Breakfast wine!
TALIESIN: One of my Brit friends--
actually, were you at
that breakfast at Comic Con
where we went to the pub
and he said, Do you have
any breakfast beer?
What do you have on
the breakfast beer menu?
TRAVIS: Yeah, if Ker
is with the liquor
and not being quiet,
-I'm probably with him.
-MATT: All right, well,
you watch as Ker comes back
with two bottles
after being given directions
as to where the...
(bottle pops)
Just like that.
(laughing)
A bottle in each hand,
and each of you grab a bottle,
and kinda toast
the bottle itself.
You're gonna drink.
Is there anything
you guys wanna discuss
while you're having breakfast?
TRAVIS: We're not worried
about the spinning
dirt button of death, right?
It's fine down there,
like it's--
TALIESIN: I think it's on the list,
but we have a list,
we can slow down a bit.
SAM: What is our list,
'cause, I mean--
so here's what
I got on my list.
It's not very long.
Bury a hand in Vasselheim.
LAURA: No, bury ashes in Vasselheim.
SAM: Oh, what was the hand?
LAURA: The hand was return the hand.
SAM: Oh, return the hand to Marquet.
MARISHA: Marquet, yeah.
-SAM: Return hand...Marquet.
-PATRICK: An actual hand.
I don't need to know,
I just wanted to see
-if I was doing it right.
-SAM: Bury ashes in Vasselheim.
-Find Opash, go to--
-TALIESIN: Island of Opash.
-SAM: Go to Wildmount.
-LAURA: Both, yes.
-SAM: Is that the same thing?
-LAURA: No.
SAM: Well, what--which one do we do?
LAURA: Well, Vasselheim is--
is Vasselheim north--
close to Wildmount?
-TALIESIN:Nothing is north--
-MATT: No, opposite side.
-LAURA: Oh, well, shit.
-MATT: Vasselheim's to the northwest.
Wildmount is the east--
northeast of Tal'Dorei.
TRAVIS: We may find more
about Opash in Wildmount.
LAURA: Zahra's from Wildmount.
MATT: Uhh.
-TRAVIS: Is she?
-LAURA: Originally, I think.
MATT: Maybe--you'd have
to check with Zahra.
LAURA: I think she is--when she told me
her history, I think it was.
MATT: Sure, there we go.
TRAVIS: What else is on your list?
-SAM: Uh--
-LAURA: Ooh, and the boys!
The boys.
SAM: Oh, the little boys!
LAURA: Yeah, the little angel babies,
they're from Wildmount.
SAM: Where are they--
where did we leave them?
-LAURA: They're here.
-SAM: Oh, okay.
TRAVIS: Where did we leave them?
TALIESIN: On the side of the road.
SAM: Any other to-do list items?
TALIESIN: We have a demon.
LAURA: Oh, God, we have Hotis,
and the other demon that
we fought in the City of Brass.
LIAM: We've got time on that--
how long has it been Hotis-wise?
MATT: Hotis-wise,
it's been a few weeks.
-LIAM: We've got time.
-SAM: Is there another one?
-TALIESIN: No.
-LAURA: The ambassador
to the Nine Hells
was in the City of Brass,
and we killed him,
and he's gonna hate us.
-SAM: Wait, he can come back?
-LAURA: I think so!
-TRAVIS: Hotis, oh, yeah.
-SAM: Well, we can't do anything
about that.
MATT: Make an arcana check, Sam.
SAM: Uh, more than 20--23.
MATT: Twenty-three.
Umm, best that you know,
as far as like hierarchies
and devils in that plane,
a devil as high-ranking as
the one that you guys fought
that got its ass handed to it
by a bunch of random people
in the City of Brass
is considered such a slight
in the eyes of the hierarchy
of the Nine Hells,
that devil probably
has been punished
stripped of its power,
and is not something you
probably need to worry about.
LAURA: Oh, shit!
(cross talk)
Nice!
TALIESIN: He does not get
to come back next week.
SAM: We've done something
on our to-do list.
TALIESIN: I have a bit of...
I have a bit of work to do
around the house, so to speak.
There's a few matters
that have to be tended to here
that we should at least
get up and started, but...
-MARISHA: I mean, I feel like...
-TALIESIN: ...nothing's urgent.
MARISHA: I feel like the giant
green dragon in the room
is pretty urgent.
TALIESIN: It's the top of the list,
but it's not something
that's going to be
solved tomorrow.
It's not something
that's necessarily
going to bite us tomorrow.
I think it's going
to bite us, honestly--
if we left it alone,
I think we would be
reaping the damage of it
in six months.
MATT: "Preferably no biting at all."
As you look,
you see at the table,
her hair kinda pulled up
into these small circles
at the bottom of her head--
you see Allura, um,
with just kinda
like a nightrobe on.
LAURA: She has fun buns.
MATT: She steps in...
you see a woman standing
with blondish, light hair
that's been braided
into long braids
and then curled up into
these small little balls
underneath
with like a dark blue--
almost shimmering materials
are her robe.
She steps in a sits down
across from you guys
at the other end of the table
and begins taking them out
and begins kind of
rebraiding them.
"I'm very happy to see
that you're all safe.
From what I've also been told,
that there is no need
to maintain the illusory barrier
over Whitestone,
which is of great relief to me
as that's been draining.
I have also heard
that Thordak has fallen,
so congratulations
are in order."
SAM: We also found you
a replacement flying carpet.
(laughing)
If you'd like it.
LAURA: Scanlan, you're on my list.
SAM: Although we could use it
in our battles to come.
MATT: "I'll tell you what--
when I have my tower rebuilt,
then perhaps we'll find
the right place for it
where it matches the rest
of the furniture.
Until then, hold onto it."
SAM: It's really
a tacky color, though.
-MATT: "I can change that."
-LIAM: We won't let it come
anywhere near acid at all.
MATT: "Please, I would
appreciate that.
In fact, any of my things
that you may've stolen
or taken over
the past few years,
keep them away from acid
in general, thank you."
LAURA: Really the rug
was the only thing.
TRAVIS: I took a couple pictures
while I was in that...
(whistling and laughing)
MARISHA: Um...
Raishan is still at large,
and we have discovered
that we think she is
on the island of Opash.
TALIESIN: The island that Opash
was banished to, that is.
LIAM: Dude what's name was Opash had an island.
LAURA: Do you know anything of him?
♪
MATT: She thinks for a second.
TALIESIN: They will probably be
in ... we'll check.
MATT: "Do you remember
the name of the island
that apparently
Thordak was ruling over
when he was thought
lost at sea?"
-LAURA: Do you?
-SAM: Notes--there's some notes
to go through.
MARISHA: When did you tell us
that information?
MATT: "Uh, this was information
that Raishan gave you."
LAURA: Right!
(cross talk)
...200 years ago.
TALIESIN: Just think if we had some device
that would make it searchable...
LAURA: Could I--would I remember this?
'Cause this was
remembering information
based on a dragon.
MATT: I would say yes for you.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: Well lawyered.
(laughing)
LIAM: Because you are
so de-stressed right now,
-your mind is so focused.
-LAURA: It's so clear.
MATT: Yes, there was something--
after Thordak
was long thought dead,
Thordak seemingly
reemerged after spending
a few--as far as you know--
years, decades,
centuries, possibly,
rebuilding his domain
on what was called
the island of Viscon.
MARISHA: Of Viscon?
MATT: Viscon in the south
of the Lucidian Ocean.
MARISHA: Lucidian Ocean.
MATT: And so as you say--
as it comes to your mind,
you're like--You say Viscon?
Allura goes, "Viscon.
Now, I know this island is--
it was part of our research
when Thordak first
began to attack
and assail the seven regions
of Tal'Dorei
back when, you know,
me and Kima were adventuring.
Um...I don't know much
about this Opash figure
you speak of."
LAURA: Did you find a laboratory
on the island?
An abandoned one?
MATT: "We did not go
to the actual island,
we just had to discover
that was the--
the historical creep
of Thordak's domain."
LAURA: Right.
MATT: "It was fiercely guarded,
and at the time,
our focus was more
to banish the creature
as opposed to trying to walk
into the center of its home,
and none of us would be alive.
That would be
a place to look."
LAURA: Thank you.
PATRICK: Um, from the religion angle,
do I know anything about Opash?
Like necromancer working
against the natural order?
MATT: Role a religion check.
TALIESIN: It's in Tolkien's Spirit Guide.
PATRICK: Yeah.
Uhh, 17.
MATT: Seventeen.
I mean, you've--
you've come across
a modicum of necromancy
in your years--
your younger years, at least.
Usually, low level,
employed by various tribal sages
and wandering,
marauding hordes of orcs
or knolls that were, you know,
given positions of power
within their small cultures,
because they had
begun to harness
some of the powers
of life and death,
but nothing that really
left a lasting impression.
There was one tomb
that you excavated
that it was beyond
the southern lands
of the Stormcrest Mountains.
It was in
the Reifenmist Peninsula,
which is the thick
jungles that exist
on the southern peninsula
of Tal'Dorei,
below the countryside,
below the actual
political structure.
It's a free land,
it is beyond the rule
of Tal'Dorei or Syngorn,
and it is where refugees
flee from society.
It's where folks that want
to live beyond the law
go and build their own place,
but south of that
into the jungle,
there are many lost
and ancient places
that were either
forgotten intentionally,
or buried through time
as the founding
to the age of Arcanum
in these eons past and past.
There is one tomb
that you went to
that was steeped
in heavy necromancy
and even just
a short journey in,
you lost two friends,
watching the life sucked
from their corpses,
left behind just these
dust-skinned skeletal memories,
and you fled--you
and the remaining members
of your team.
Since then, you've
been keenly aware
of the awful effects
of necromancy,
and it honestly scares you,
and so the more
this discussion continues,
the more and more just uneasy
you become with the discussion.
Um, as far as the essence
of what Opash may have in store,
uh, you're not
particularly sure,
but, um, I mean, the domain
of necromancy is life and death.
Um, and that central theme
keeps reemerging
with Thordak, with Raishan,
with whatever this dynamic is,
there's something
about life and death
that is cyclical
in this conversation
that keeps you connected.
♪
PATRICK: Was that island
that you mentioned volcamic?
LAURA: The island of Viscon?
PATRICK: Volcanic.
MATT: You should slow down on
the breakfast wine, friend.
PATRICK: Kerrek is pronouncing
very deliberately at this point.
(laughing)
MATT: "The island of Viscon--
it would be in a zone
that does see quite a bit
of activity of that kind.
There are a number of places
in the ocean that are known
to just perpetually spire forth
sulfur and other terrible fumes."
TALIESIN: I wonder if a red dragon
had been living there.
MATT: "Long before he came."
TALIESIN: He would've certainly
encouraged it, though.
MATT: "I'm--I don't doubt that.
There is something
to be said for that, so--"
SAM: More Lava, Keyleth.
MARISHA: My favorite.
TALIESIN: One day we're going
to meet a lava door.
TRAVIS: Don't you put that evil on us.
Don't even put it out there.
LIAM: Matt hadn't even
thought of that!
TALIESIN: Three times,
you say it three times.
SAM: Door made of lava.
MATT: "If you do decide to inquire,
this island of Viscon,
carefully, slowly, methodically,
whether or not this has a tie
or this is specifically
where the deceiver lives
at the moment, who knows
how long they'll stay.
You say she's seeking
something there?"
LAURA: That's what Keyleth
said it seemed like.
MARISHA: She seemed to be poring
through tomes and books
looking for something.
She seemed very frustrated.
Question--oh, go ahead.
MATT: "Let's just say,
what happens if she finds
what she's looking for?"
MARISHA: Exactly.
PATRICK: Oh, she brings the dragon
back from the dead.
TALIESIN: Or transfers her consciousness
into the dragon's body,
reanimates an undead red dragon.
LAURA: I don't know what necromancy
is capable of.
TALIESIN: ...create some unholy monster.
-PATRICK: You...
-SAM: There's also dragon babies.
PATRICK: ...put into the--
into the eggs...
LAURA: Hey, K, you remember when
I said you were really smart?
(laughing)
SAM: He makes wagon hitches,
all right?
-Listen!
-LIAM: I like this guy.
SAM: He's a simple man!
He's a great wagon hitch maker.
PATRICK: Well, I mean,
why do you take a body?
I mean, well,
and you're all like,
"Well, I died Tuesday,
I died Thursday!"
Like, and then you killed--
how bad did you kill the dragon?
Because if you didn't
kill it real bad--
LAURA: It could be brought back.
PATRICK: Like Tuesday, right?
LAURA: At least
the gem was shattered--
the gem was shattered.
-MATT: "It was?"
-LAURA: Yes.
MATT: "You destroyed the Soul Anchor?"
LAURA: Yeah, and Thordak shrunk!
He was huge, and then
he was like normal after that.
MATT: "Well, that's something at least."
TRAVIS: Yeah, it's something.
SAM: I don't think that she's trying
to reanimate Thordak.
I think she's
trying to probe him
for knowledge of some sort.
-TRAVIS: Probe.
-TALIESIN: I think she's attempting--
SAM: She's trying to probe
his dead body.
TRAVIS: Probe.
MARISHA: Allura, if we scried
on this island,
if you saw it again,
would you recognize it?
MATT: "I'm--I haven't been there,
-but if I were to scry..."
-MARISHA: Oh, I thought you said...
MATT: "...what would you require--
what would you need?"
MARISHA: I wanna confirm
if she actually is
on the island
of Viscar--Viscon.
MATT: "Well, I mean, I can attempt to.
I've only heard of it, so..."
SAM: Do you--what if we--
would it help you to scry
if we gave you some blood
of the thing that
we're scrying on?
LAURA: Thordak?
MARISHA: But she would still see
the same thing that I would--
that I would've seen.
-It wouldn't confirm the island.
-LAURA: Oh, right.
TALIESIN: It also might mean
that we would be discovered.
SAM: Keyleth, don't you have some spell
where you say
the name of a place
and it shows you
the way there or something?
LIAM: Well, can you look
for trees on that island?
MARISHA: I could try and scry...
on Viscar--Viscon.
Right? If I know
enough about Viscon,
I could try and scry
on a location, correct?
SAM: No, you can only scry
on a person.
MATT: Yup, you can scry
on a location.
That was my fault
in the past, by the way.
I completely--I--
very into the spell.
SAM: But no, don't you have
like a directions spell?
-MARISHA: Find the path, yeah.
-SAM: What does that do?
MATT: Yeah, if you have
secondhand knowledge,
and you've heard of the target,
you can still scry to it,
it just has a modifier--
if it's a target.
If it's a location, um...
LAURA: But, 'cause I--will it--
I mean, we lucked out
the first time
that she didn't catch on.
What if she realizes?
MARISHA: If I scry on the island,
she won't notice.
-LAURA: Okay.
-MARISHA: It's only if I scry on her.
SAM: ...you're looking
at some leaves and trees.
TALIESIN: But we'll get an idea
of where to go.
-MARISHA: I could look--
-LIAM: You saw it once already,
and you would know it--
you'd probably recognize it
-a second time.
-MARISHA: Would I?
-TRAVIS: Would you?
-LIAM: It's worth a fucking shot.
MARISHA: If I--if I scried on Viscon,
could I recognize, yeah,
this looks like
the similar island?
MATT: You could try, yeah.
LAURA: Yeah, you could certainly try.
MATT: You can certainly try.
Thank you, Laura.
I needed a little goose.
-MARISHA: All right.
-MATT: Needed a little ...
MARISHA: Last fifth-level
spell of the day.
(cross talk)
LAURA: Ker, you should try this wine
that Grog got from--
-TRAVIS: Yes!
-MARISHA: You should try it!
-TRAVIS: Oh, it's really good!
-MARISHA: It's so tasty!
-TRAVIS: ...sand dunes of terribleness.
-LIAM: I mean, you don't want to--
I haven't tried it either.
You don't want
to finish your life
without trying this bug juice.
It's the nickname
we have for it.
TRAVIS: I pop the top,
and I hand the bottle to him.
LAURA: Just small--small amounts.
TRAVIS: What is it, sand keg, sand...
-LIAM: Bug juice.
-TRAVIS: Yeah, that stuff.
(cross talk)
LIAM: I take the bottle,
and I put my thumb over it
and pretend like
I'm drinking--go--
MATT: Sleight-of-hand.
LIAM: That's great, sure.
LIAM: Sure, sure, sure.
LIAM: That is a 26.
MATT: For the hell of it, Kerrek,
go ahead and roll--
roll a perception check.
PATRICK: Uh, no, not by--
not by a country mile.
MATT: He took a mighty swig.
PATRICK: Yeah, well, it's--
-LAURA: Don't take a swig that big.
-PATRICK: It's that good?
-LIAM: It's smooth.
-TRAVIS: It has really got
-some balls on it.
-LIAM: It goes down smooth.
PATRICK: You gotta shake the flavor in.
(laughing)
'Cause the flavor goes
slowly to the bottom.
-LAURA: Oh, God, oh, no.
-PATRICK: It's 'cause of the gravity.
LAURA: What if he realized
something we didn't?
MARISHA: See, I told you see was wise.
LIAM: I wish it could be
my first time again.
MATT: So as the liquid hits
your lips, it's thick.
It's like...
(laughing)
PATRICK: Too much flavor.
MATT: It doesn't pour
like wine or liquor,
it pours more like a--
like a light honey.
But it has
a very acrid, um...
pungent, immediate flavor
as it hits your tongue.
I need you to roll
a constitution saving throw.
PATRICK: So is this like when I left
that glass of Surge out
for so long that it
evaporated in the cup down?
-TRAVIS: Just, like, ...
-MATT: Kind of, yeah.
PATRICK: And then because there
was no mold growing on it,
and I am a scientist at heart...
TRAVIS: It's all clear.
TALIESIN: You went where mold
feared to tread.
PATRICK: I, uh--I thought,
when will I ever have
this opportunity again?
MATT: When the most basic
forms of life
eschew existing on a substance,
that's when you
have to drink it.
TRAVIS: Agreed.
TALIESIN: Yes, yes!
PATRICK: That's gonna be
my best role all year.
MATT: So--so--
LIAM: Wait, can I point out
that this is the best game
in existence?
(laughing)
MATT: You may.
As it fills your gullet,
the warm, burning sensation
you're used to
with fine,
heavy liquors is surpassed
by the ever-burning sensation
of fire within your lungs,
and as the heartburn
begins to kick in,
you stop for a second and
realize that the burn goes away
and everything goes numb.
Everything goes numb.
Your tongue...your jaw...
LAURA: How do you feel, Ker?
(indistinct speech)
(laughing)
LIAM: One more time?
SAM: Beard got in the way.
(indistinct speech)
(laughing)
LAURA: He likes it--
I think he likes it.
LIAM: I would've thought that as well.
TALIESIN: Ladies and gentlemen,
Burning Man,
ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to Burning Man.
TRAVIS: That is good shit.
MARISHA: The fire has passed through you.
(laughing)
It's gonna go
all the way through you.
So be careful when it
comes out the other end.
LIAM: Good reincorporation!
(laughing)
TALIESIN: I remember this.
LAURA: But you're still conscious,
and that is saying something.
TRAVIS: Really impressive.
LAURA: I wouldn't drink
any more of it, though.
TRAVIS: No, no, no, yeah,
you gotta warm up
-and then take another one.
-LIAM: No, no, no,
I mean, that's all fun
and games, but come on.
MATT: As this is happening,
you all look over
and glance that, as Allura
has cleared the table
and begun to set a space
for the scry ritual,
-is just staring at you all.
-LAURA: Oh, shit, right.
MARISHA: Thanks for setting
this up for us, Allura.
-MATT: "Oh, please, keep going."
-TRAVIS: We didn't mean to be rude.
MATT: "This is the most fun
I've had in days."
TRAVIS: Do you want some?
TALIESIN: After!
(yelling)
LIAM: No, that's a bad idea,
don't do it!
-TRAVIS: Do it.
-SAM: She needs to do the spell!
LIAM: Do it later--
that shit's fucked up.
TRAVIS: Don't listen to him.
MARISHA: Wait, I thought
I was doing the spell.
We could do it together.
TRAVIS: We're trustworthy.
Open the bottle.
-Down the hatch.
-MATT: She pops it off, and goes,
"Look, it's morning,
we're all alive.
What's the point if
we're not celebrating?"
-TRAVIS: That's what I'm saying!
-LIAM: That will turn
your blonde hair green!
TALIESIN: No!
MATT: Ah.
"Not my favorite flavor."
(gasping)
-LIAM: She's got magic.
-SAM: She's so strong!
LAURA: Constitutions for days!
LIAM: She's so cool.
TRAVIS: Will you teach me
your sorcerous ways?
LAURA: Keep talking, keep talking.
TRAVIS: How do you feel?
MATT: "I feel fine."
TRAVIS: I don't--I don't
know what to say.
-LIAM: Fucking magic.
-SAM: She's amazing.
MARISHA: You're awesome.
LIAM: Can you say red leather,
yellow leather?
What about--
(laughing)
What about--try saying
three times in a row
can you say Irish wristwatch?
(laughing)
PATRICK: Three times in a row.
LIAM: This is to Ker or Patrick--
Irish wristwatch
as fast as you can
three times in a row.
I have faith in you.
PATRICK: Irish wr--
(laughing)
Irish wr--
Irish wish--
LIAM: You know, thank you for playing.
That was a valiant effort.
Hey, let's scry on a dragon!
MATT: "All right."
(laughing)
TRAVIS: Were you in a motorcycle gang?
How did she do that?
-LIAM: Warrior!
-SAM: She's immune to alcohol.
MATT: She sits across the table
from you and puts her hands out.
SAM: Oh, yeah, let's do this.
MARISHA: Oh, man, it just feels
like old days, Allura!
MATT: "That it does--simpler times."
MARISHA: Yes, it was.
MATT: As you both close your eyes
and you all watch as Allura
and Keyleth close their eyes.
A moment passes,
a second moment,
and across the smooth,
polished wood table surface
of which you've been
having breakfast,
you watch as the grain
begins to shift.
Almost these small lines
of light blue and white
sparkling, tiny arcane ley lines
begin to just curl
a circle around the table.
In the center,
their arms are clenched.
You watch as it
carves two circles--
one smaller one
within the other--
and then begin to form
these various, rigid,
star-like patterns within,
and as soon as the two points
eventually connect
in the center,
there's a flash,
and both Keyleth and Allura
open their eyes,
but there is no pupil,
there is no iris,
it is just white.
-TRAVIS: Creepy.
-PATRICK: Fuck.
(laughing)
TALIESIN: That was the most Brian Blessed
fuck I've ever...
It was amazing.
(laughter continues)
MATT: The two of you share a vision--
a vision of water,
a vision of endless ocean--
a familiar vision
of endless ocean.
You see small pillars of steam
rising out of the center
of this expanse,
clusters of them in places,
occasionally a few rocks
breaking the surface,
and beyond that,
you see an island
isolated out in the ocean,
covered with green.
You see a large mountain
set across one side
as your vision flashes inward
to an overhead view,
you see a familiar island.
SAM: ♪ And the line where
the sea meets the sky ♪
♪ It's blinding ♪♪
(laughing)
MATT: The vision fades,
you both return,
the circular glyphs
on the table
kind of sparkle out
leaving the smooth surface
untouched.
Both of their eyes clarify,
their irises
and pupils returning,
and they both take
a simultaneous breath,
and then release
each other's hands.
MARISHA: Holy shit.
-LAURA: So yeah?
-MARISHA: Yeah.
We know where she is.
(gasping)
It's the island.
LAURA: Do we know how to get
to the island?
MARISHA: I can tree stride us there.
I saw a tree--did I see
a tree big enough?
-MATT: There were a number of trees.
-LAURA: Oh, geez!
SAM: Palm trees?
LAURA: Oh, my God, we need
to rest and get there.
-MARISHA: We need to rest and get there.
-LIAM: We need to go the fuck to bed.
PATRICK: Let's go right now!
(cross talk)
That was a joke.
(laughing)
LAURA: Shit, we need to rest!
MARISHA: Oh, my God, yeah.
-LAURA: And go!
-MARISHA: We need to rest and go.
LIAM: We should go right away.
What a to-do to die today
at a minute or two 'til two.
SAM: Trippingly off the tongue.
-MATT: "You get two options."
-LAURA: Okay.
MATT: "And I defer to
your judgment on this.
You rest and prepare,
that leaves her
to rest and prepare."
-LAURA: Yes.
-MATT: "You don't rest,
she doesn't rest.
The choice is yours
as to which you think
leaves you in the more
advantageous position.
MARISHA: I--I--I cannot...
get us there.
-LAURA: We need to rest.
-LIAM: Can you get us there?
MATT: "I've unfortunately
already used my spell
to get you to..."
LIAM: But you're say--I understand
what you're saying.
-She's got nothing--
-MATT: She stops and goes,
"I've seen it, actually,
with the vision.
And I did rest--I do--I could.
I could get you there."
SAM: To what end?
-MATT: "The choice is yours."
-SAM: I have nothing.
LIAM: But Scanlan, pluses and minuses.
She has nothing.
SAM: I can't die, Vax.
I've already died once today,
I can't do it again.
LAURA: We don't have any healing.
If anybody dies,
we can't come back.
TRAVIS: I've got two healing potions.
MARISHA: Okay, all right.
(humming)
Is there a way, do you know,
where we can maybe, like,
restore ourselves faster?
(laughing)
MATT: "I wouldn't recommend that."
TRAVIS: Oh?
LAURA: Oh!
MATT: "But nevertheleth..."
(laughing)
TRAVIS: Amazing.
PATRICK: Say, Irish wr--wr--
(laughing)
TALIESIN: Hard, isn't it?
MATT: She goes back to
braiding her hair.
(laughing)
MARISHA: What is the minimum amount
of time we could sleep?
MATT: Eight hours.
(grumbling)
TRAVIS: Let's do it, let's sleep.
LIAM: So if we rest,
she gets her meteors,
she gets her everything.
-LAURA: She gets it all back.
-SAM: And she could leave.
LIAM: She's gonna rest, too,
to get all her shit back.
If we go now,
having had a breather
with this drunk guy...
-LAURA: No!
-LIAM: I'm not saying what we do.
You can decide what we do
because you're the smart one,
but I'm just talking it out.
She--it would be
a physical fight
with none of her magic.
TALIESIN: If we had--if we had
a dragon with us, I'd say yes.
LIAM: You two brainiacs
can make the decision,
but she's got no meteors,
she's got a lot less.
LAURA: Look, we took on Thordak
with full health,
and we made it out pretty well.
MARISHA: I mean, once again,
unless we do this--
unless we get to the island,
try and scout out--
find Raishan...
...island,
that way if she moves...
we won't let her leave?
What Grog, what?
SAM: I can't camp on the island,
I don't have the mansion.
MARISHA: We can camp like we did
old school style.
TALIESIN: She would know
that we were there--
LAURA: Wait a minute,
you said you had it left.
TALIESIN: And if we go there...
LAURA: Scanlan, you said you
still had the spell left
-so we could--
-MARISHA: No, he used it
to change Jarrett's mind, right?
MATT: Well, you don't know that.
MARISHA: Well.
LAURA: Oh, well, shit.
SAM: I used it in the battle,
fuck off.
(laughing)
TALIESIN: If--if we were to go right now,
I would almost recommend
that Scanlan
and Keyleth stay behind
because they would be
nothing but targets.
TRAVIS: Ooh, how does that feel?
LIAM: Well, then, we won't do that.
TALIESIN: Which is why we shouldn't go,
because if we go, it is...
the four of us.
TRAVIS: Strangely, I agree with Percy.
TALIESIN: And if we wait a day?
It's six--it's at least
six, seven, eight of us--
however many was can bring,
but every magic user
right now is--
-LAURA: Tapped.
-LIAM: Allura.
-MATT: "Yes."
-LAURA: Except for her.
LIAM: I kinda wanted to bring you
in the beginning.
Are you willing to come with us?
MATT: "There's no need for me
to maintain the illutho--
-the illusory barrier on the thity."
-PATRICK: Wristwatch.
(laughing)
MARISHA: You did it!
MATT: "That's rather imprethive."
MARISHA: Okay, well, look,
if we wanted to go now,
I still have my beast shaping back.
TALIESIN: That's a bit...
MARISHA: I have one first-level spell,
two third-level spells,
and one fourth-level spell.
-LAURA: Oh, my God.
-SAM: That's enough to kill a dragon.
LIAM: Do we have--here's a question.
Do we have some
healing potions banked
-at Whitestone right now?
-TRAVIS: No.
-LAURA: We took them all.
-MATT: "To be perfectly honetht,
we've given you
everything we have."
(laughing)
-LAURA: Are there any--
-MATT: "Don't laugh at me, Vex'thahlia."
LAURA: I'm not, darling, I'm not.
MARISHA: I haven't used any of my health.
LAURA: Are there any steal-- heal--(stammering)
LAURA: Are there any healers
within the castle?
PATRICK: I am relatively fresh
in terms of healing.
I could heal some.
-LAURA: Would you wanna go with us?
-LIAM: Yes, but are you
in Burbank next week, though?
(laughing)
SAM: Pike is out!
LAURA: Pike is done.
She's got two
first-level spells left.
That's it.
SAM: I have one fifth and one fourth.
No, two fourths.
LAURA: I think I've got two
first-levels spells left,
-but that's it.
-TALIESIN: It's--
TRAVIS: Let's be honest.
We're not quite at our best,
and it's one diseased
deceiver in a cave
with another
dead dragon that might
or might not come back to life,
and two baby little eggs.
We rest, and then
we give 'em hell!
PATRICK: The brass dragon, I feel,
made a great point
that if you let
someone of that...
-SAM: Power.
-PATRICK: ...power choose
the rules of engagement...
-LAURA: Right.
-LIAM: That's a good point,
and Allura makes a good point.
TRAVIS: Plus she doesn't know
that we know where she is.
She thinks she's got
all the time in the world.
SAM: You wanna go now?
TRAVIS: No, I wanna wait.
TALIESIN: Go tomorrow.
LAURA: I think we rest
and we go tonight.
We sleep eight hours,
it's only in the morning--
we go as soon as we're rested.
LIAM: She's gonna have
everything tomorrow.
MARISHA: Can we, like, do,
like, six hours...
SAM: She won't be
expecting us at all.
MARISHA: ...and chug some coffee?
MATT: Nope, need a full
eight hour rest.
SAM: She won't be
expecting us at all.
We'll still have
the element of surprise,
she won't have a lair to defend.
She won't have any other
fire giants to protect her.
TALIESIN: There might be a lair.
TRAVIS: Maybe, but we are fucking tits
against lairs, come on.
SAM: You have a dancing
fucking sword.
LAURA: That's right.
LIAM: Percy, what do you think?
TALIESIN: I think we--honestly,
I think that we--
I think if we go
right now, we win,
and at least one of us dies.
And if we go tomorrow,
we're probably going to win,
and probably most of us
are going to survive.
PATRICK: Unless she is merely
scrounging there.
TALIESIN: I think she might be scrounging,
but I think if she's scrounging,
that's a lot to look through.
I think that
she thinks she's safe.
LAURA: Did it look like there was
a lot of books there, Keyleth?
MATT: There were quite a number.
Probably 100 at the very least.
SAM: We don't even know what she is.
-Didn't you see a woman?
-LIAM: But that was her.
MARISHA: That's Raishan
in her female form.
LIAM: So she can look at books so
she doesn't fucking mangle them.
TRAVIS: Keyleth, are you worried
if we wait,
you're going to lose
the chance to kill Raishan?
MARISHA: I don't think we're gonna lose
the chance to kill Raishan,
it's just a matter
of who's killing who first.
TALIESIN: I say that we take
eight hours' sleep,
and we go there immediately.
TRAVIS: She thinks she's got cover,
but she doesn't.
TALIESIN: It will have
only been ten hours at best
by the time we get there.
MARISHA: Allura, since you know
of the island,
and we know where she is,
is there any way
where we can keep an eye
on the island
magically from afar?
If Raishan moves, we know?
MATT: "I mean, I can incrementally
scry on an island
and keep an eye on the vicinity,
but if I scry
directly on Raishan--"
-MARISHA: She could sense it.
-TALIESIN: She'll sense it.
MATT: "Well, there's a chance."
MARISHA: Yeah, let's not do that.
TRAVIS: Don't you wanna be at your best?
Don't you wanna be some fucking
wicked badass from the sky?
Or do you wanna limp in?
-LAURA: Right?
-TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: Plus, if she's got
100 books to go through,
that's gonna take
more than two hours.
TALIESIN: She may not--it's possible
she may not even rest.
She might just be
so angry that she's--
LAURA: She might not be fully rested
by the time we get there.
TRAVIS: I know it feels like
an advantage to press,
but we were five down
at one point.
LAURA: I can't die again.
TRAVIS: You can, but it's not advisable.
TALIESIN: Let's not let that happen.
MARISHA: She has none of her legendary
resistances right now.
TRAVIS: No, I'm not worried about those.
TALIESIN: She--we may
interrupt her mid-slumber.
MARISHA: How long did it take when, um,
we injured...was that Vorugal?
Who retreated
and started healing?
-LIAM: Umbrasyl.
-MARISHA: Umbrasyl.
-TRAVIS: In his lair.
-MARISHA: In his lair.
Doing nothing
but sleeping right?
MATT: Well, you came upon
a number of empty potions--
things that were part
of Umbrasyl's hoard.
LAURA: So Raishan might not have that.
TALIESIN: Or she might.
LIAM: But we're gonna get--
if we wait till tomorrow--
TALIESIN: Which, if she does have it,
she's already taken them.
LIAM: You all can decide,
but if we go tomorrow,
she's fully stacked,
she's in her lair.
If we go tonight--I'm just--
LAURA: I don't wanna
fucking go tonight.
I don't wanna go tonight.
-I don't wanna die again.
-TALIESIN: It's the morning,
we sleep through the day,
we go tonight.
LIAM: Well then, there's
nothing to talk about.
-TALIESIN: I think that's the way to go.
-TRAVIS: Agreed.
LAURA: We sleep, we go tonight.
TALIESIN: We sleep, we go tonight.
She may spend all of today
going through those books,
and then sleep tonight.
TRAVIS: Keyleth, we know
what we're asking of you.
We're asking you to wait, again.
(chuckling)
MARISHA: I...
I think in recent events,
I can wait.
-SAM: Then at dusk...
-TRAVIS: We plan.
SAM: Yes.
(mixed remarks)
TRAVIS: It's actually dawn--sorry.
MARISHA: How much do you...
how much do you heal up
overnight, generally?
MATT: At night, you get full points,
and you get back half of your--
half of your hit dice
that were spent.
MARISHA: Okay.
TRAVIS: Make the call, Keyleth.
MARISHA: We'd better get sleeping,
I guess.
LAURA: Let's go to bed.
SAM: Instead of fighting,
we're going to sleep.
MARISHA: Well, what do you want, Scanlan?
-TALIESIN: You can go.
-MARISHA: You have been devil's advocate
this whole time--
"I don't wanna die again,
but she could kill us!"
What do you want, Scanlan?
SAM: I don't wanna die.
-LAURA: Then let's sleep.
-TALIESIN: Then sleep.
MARISHA: I don't wanna die either,
and I don't wanna watch
any of you die again.
TALIESIN: But if we go right now,
you're going to die.
LAURA: We need your spells
to protect us--
you're clutch in a fight--
and without them,
you're kind of just a--
a dude.
TALIESIN: Who's very good
at becoming a target.
SAM: I'm so much more than a dude.
(laughing)
TALIESIN: One day you may be a bro.
SAM: Someday.
MATT: And on that note,
you begin to put
your things together,
your plots, your preparations
for getting to rest...
Did you have
something you wanna do?
LIAM: It feels like you're
going to wind down.
Before we do that,
if everyone's going to bed...
back in your room, I plunk down
a bottle of whatever,
and I take out Whisper--
have a seat.
-MARISHA: Okay.
-LIAM: I take Whisper,
and I just start
gently cutting away
burnt edges of hair
on your already shorter hair
so that the ends are clean.
LAURA: Aww.
MARISHA: Do you like it shorter?
LIAM: I like you.
♪
And I see you doubting yourself.
I see it, Kiki.
♪
I have no doubts in you.
I've known you
for a long time now...
♪
and I have seen
the strength in you growing.
♪
And I'm a fan.
You're gonna make
a great leader some day.
♪
MARISHA: I just feel like
there's so many people
I could easily disappoint.
I don't want to.
♪
LIAM: You are doing
the very best you can
with what you've been given,
and I've seen you rise
again and again
and not stop and not back down.
♪
And you fucking blow me away
with the things
you can do out there.
You are beautiful,
and you are talented,
and you are strong as fuck.
♪
And I can't take
the doubt away--
I can't do that.
♪
But mix in with that
my faith in you...
Percy's faith in you...
Grog's faith in you...
Ker's...
Vex'ahlia's, Scanlan's,
Allura's...
all of ours.
♪
We are all behind you,
and we all believe in you.
And we all love you.
And obviously, I love you.
MARISHA: I love you.
You know...
everyone comes
from these backgrounds
of having all
these well-ventured
and traveled pasts.
You were the first people
that I knew and met...
so not only are you the longest,
I don't really have
any other friends.
You are my family.
♪
I'll try not to let you down.
LIAM: I have no worries.
Look at you.
Don't you look like royalty.
♪
MARISHA: I'm not a princess, remember?
LIAM: That's kinda what
I like about you.
(laughing)
Would you do me a favor?
Down the line,
once all this is behind us...
will you go back
to the theater with me?
MARISHA: What is it with you
and the theater?
(laughing)
Why?
LIAM: I don't understand it either.
♪
MARISHA: As long as you go back
to Zephra with me, maybe?
LIAM: You don't have to ask.
MARISHA: Does my hair look okay?
LIAM: Are you kidding me?
MARISHA: Does the short thing kinda work?
Does it work with
my bone structure?
The antlers aren't
overpowering it, right?
The length kind of
balanced out this, you know?
SAM: Bangs!
MARISHA: Bangs.
LAURA: Don't do it, don't do it,
you'll regret it.
MARISHA: No bangs.
LIAM: I shut her up with a kiss.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: (stammering)
I'm in my room...
♪
I am taking Vax's letter
and ripping it in half
and burning it.
And I'm packing my pipe
for the morning.
(mixed remarks)
LAURA: This is for real, you guys.
-LIAM: Wow.
-MATT: Alrighty.
Prepared and ready to go.
You have your next dose
of brown suude prepared.
MARISHA: I pass out
from sheer exhaustion.
MATT: Okay.
PATRICK: I am noisily sick.
(laughing)
And honestly...
it took every ounce
of willpower I had
to not do it in
the middle of your scene.
(laughing)
I feel like I've really grown
as a human being.
TALIESIN: I think we've all
learned something tonight.
MATT: The whole time, just like
slowly cut past the wall,
and there's Ker just going--
holding it.
(groaning)
(laughing)
-LIAM: We've all been there.
-LAURA: Before we go to bed,
Allura, any chance
you'd be able to join us?
I know you didn't get
to come the last time.
MATT: "Oh, I'm there, don't worry."
LAURA: Thank you.
MATT: "So, you all get your rest.
I'm honored, really.
I was proud of you all for going
into that fray as you did.
And you had many great
compatriots at your side.
I was a little jealous."
LAURA: Kima did wonderfully.
MATT: "I'm sure she did."
LAURA: I'm sure she'll want
to join us again.
MATT: "I'm sure she'll
continue to complain
about things that fly.
It's never been her strong suit.
But I'll be there with you,
do not worry.
Rest well.
I've had a full night's sleep,
I'm just gonna keep vigil
and no longer drink things
you procure from your bags
without inquiring."
MARISHA: And we all set our alarms
for exactly eight hours.
LAURA: No sleeping in, and just go.
LIAM: Siri, wake me up
before Raishan wakes.
(laughing)
SAM: (barking)
MATT: "I'm sorry, I didn't
understand that, Vax'ildan!"
-TRAVIS: That stupid dog alarm.
-SAM: I love the dog alarm!
MATT: All right, so as you all
find evening's rest,
we'll go ahead and end
tonight's session there.
(cheering)
Preparing for whatever chaos
the next endeavor unfurls.
LAURA: Oh, geez.
-MARISHA: That was a good game.
-LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: Well done, guys, it's fun.
MARISHA: Yay, Kerr-bear!
TRAVIS: Yeah, Patrick!
PATRICK: It's such a treat--
such a treat to be able
to come back.
LIAM: Is there any chance
you'll be here next week?
PATRICK: Honestly, I was already
trying to figure
that out in my head.
Like, it's--I mean,
I've flown places
for dumber reasons.
(laughing)
You know, so I'll maybe
email with you a little bit
to see how you feel about that.
MATT: Let me know, I mean,
we'd love to have you.
LIAM: Get you in some combat!
-LAURA: Yeah!
-PATRICK: I will admit I've never--
LAURA: You had a pretty
awesome hammer there!
PATRICK: I, uh--I have yet
to actually take him
for a test drive
in that way, so...
LIAM: ♪ I'm just looking
for one divine hammer ♪♪
(laughing)
Breeders--that's
The Breeder's, man,
-that's the '90s.
-MATT: We'll try and coordinate
for that--hopefully
it works out,
'cause that would be great.
Otherwise, thank you guys
for kicking ass.
Uhh...it's a great--
it's a great episode.
Thank you guys for watching,
thank you again for all
your amazing support.
We're--we're taking
all the positivity
we can force-feed into 2017.
Um, but we love you guys.
We'll see you in a week,
and is it Thursday yet?
Take care, guys.
♪