You know what I mean?
I don't know.
I don't think--
this is a bad idea.
Why can't I just--
Vex, Vax, and Keyleth--
as you guys are having this
conversation, something
catches the corner of your eye,
and you watch something just go
[WHOOSHING NOISE] and just whiz
past.
Oh, shit.
Like from in the bottom
of the ravine to the top.
Just--
Like what?
We saw that.
You saw something
quickly just go by.
Can I get a better look?
Can I look and see--
Can we, after the fact--
--if I see it again?
--try to figure
out what we see?
Do we roll alone?
Yeah.
The three of you guys
make a perception check,
as you kind of come up
to the edge and look.
Oh, shit.
26.
14.
Is this related to dragons?
This is not
related to dragons.
Ha, ha, ha.
That is a 21.
26.
OK.
Best we got.
All right.
So you're kind of
seeing little things--
just right out of the
middle of the light,
you can see just something
shifting above and below you.
You guys have a
little better view.
You still can't quite see.
The length of your
darkvision is too far for you
to see what is below you,
or initially what's above.
But you--
Can I-- as a quick reaction--
grab the rope bridge?
Yeah.
OK.
So you're still
off to the side,
just holding on to the bridge?
Grasping, yeah.
OK.
You are being watched.
[BLOWING NOISE] What
looks to be figures--
humanoid bodies.
Oh, I have a theory.
Are those spirits?
They're just kind
of tumbling past.
One of them kind of hits
the edge of the bridge--
[CRACKING NOISE] and
keeps spinning off,
and just disappears
in the darkness above.
I have a weird theory.
Awesome.
I'm to grab--
what do I have that
I can do this with?
Yes, Percy?
But they look like
spirits floating upwards?
Or do they look like bodies?
You watch a few more.
You watch a couple more go by,
and they are nearly-skeletal
bodies--
Falling upward.
--falling upward.
But, as they watch a
couple of more go by,
they're limp,
somewhat, but still
moving as they scoot past.
Oh, no.
Oh, Jesus.
Let's just get
across here, shall we?
I'm going to use
divine sense now--
OK.
--just to confirm.
You have to wait
about a minute or so
before one comes close
enough to hit the sense,
but there is an undead
energy that passes past.
And both you and Kerr
kind of have this moment
from across the ravine from
each other seeing this.
I'm going to try and--
Kerr will throw up the horns.
[LAUGHS]
That's me to you, man.
Try and clock them.
See if it's the same bodies
over and over again--
if it's in that loop of falling.
Oh, interesting.
An infinite loop of falling?
OK, so I want to
get a good look at--
Oh, it's a gif.
--one of them as
they go by and see.
OK.
It's a gif.
Six seconds.
So I'm just-- aw, aw!
Three or four
more stumble past.
[CRACKING NOISE] And they're
getting more and more--
More and more frequent.
--rapid.
And they're--
We should probably go.
They're different sizes.
They do not appear to
be the same bodies.
Go, go, go, go, go, go.
I pick up Pike and try
to barrel roll across.
OK.
You got it.
You barrel roll across.
As you're making it
across, three more
come tumbling up-- two of them
too far away, but one of them
does kind of reach out with his
arms as it tumbles past you,
and kind of swats out
to try and grab you.
What?
I need you to make
an acrobatics check.
You've got this.
Oh, you've got such a bonus.
Come on, girl.
I know, I know, I know.
Such a bonus, huh?
Such a bonus.
Oh, no.
Look at Matt's face.
Look at his face.
Oh, fuck, no.
But, what?
But he--
No.
Come on.
Such a bonus.
No, come on.
Such a bonus
Did they both make that roll?
She's the one
driving the broom.
She's having to try
and maneuver it.
She's the one in the air.
I was about to
interject, and I
know that I didn't
make that fast enough.
No.
But at some point,
I would already
like to be moving to
interject in this.
Right.
As you're watching
them start across,
you get a step out
onto the bridge--
I'm not going onto the--
I'm pulling out my
gun, and trying to--
and like, I see the--
Oh, wait!
Doesn't Pike have a thing that--
she can help people with their--
War god's blessing?
--war god's blessing?
That's an attack roll.
Damn it!
That's all right.
War gods don't help you survive.
They help you kill shit.
They do.
Do what you were going to do.
So--
I was going to start skeet
shooting at some point.
Well, I rolled a 1.
I understood, but
before we get to that--
Yeah, finish it.
So the creature grabs you,
and essentially grapples you
in the moment.
Yeah.
And as that happens, the
momentum of pulling you
up causes the broom to
kind of shift out of whack,
and you begin to careen
at a slight circle.
I need you and Pike to both
make strength saving throws.
Oh.
How far away is this from--
Do you want help with this?
They're about
30 feet from you.
Or do you want to do it?
And what about from Keyleth?
That's OK.
About the same, because
your guys are about--
whereas they're on the
other side of the ravine.
You do this?
I'll do hers.
She's got a plus
4 on strength.
Plus 4 on strength?
Correct.
My foot is asleep.
9 for me.
9 for you.
13 for Pike.
So-- OK.
So Pike's on the broom with you.
Yeah.
You get grabbed and
yanked off the broom.
Oh shit.
Pike--
I am tethered.
--manages to hold the broom.
But currently, Pike was not
the current driver of it.
And so she's
clutching a broom that
is just floating to gravity.
You watch as both
Pike and Vex go
from careening off to tumbling
upward into the darkness above.
Are they both
attached to the broom?
No.
Vex is pulled off the broom.
But she's still tethered.
She's still tethered, yeah.
Vex has a tether.
So both of them are trying to
like [SPUTTERING NOISES] kind
of spinning.
It's a slingshot-- bola.
--to get your motion upward.
Does Keyleth have an action?
Right now, the two of
you can make an action.
All right, my first action--
I was just pulling
to try and skeet
shoot, and do a sharp shoot
with Bad News to hit that the--
The undead?
--undead that
had grappled her--
Go for it.
--and try and--
I assume I have to spend a
grit to get him to let go--
to shove him off.
To shove him off?
OK.
You are, because of the
nature of the rapid movement,
you have disadvantage
on this attack.
OK.
You have that
inspiration, right?
I still have that
d12 inspiration.
Oh!
Hey, can we have like
Bigby's hand go voomp?
Matt?
Yes.
Watching this, I'm going
to pull Whisper out, and wait
and watch to see my sister
falling through the air.
And if I see her
falling, I'm going
to throw the dagger at her.
OK.
She's falling.
Jessie?
Down or up?
Up.
I'm watching him,
and I'm watching her.
And if she goes--
OK.
That doesn't--
How far away is she from me?
Right now, she's about--
because she was up 30
feet out from the ravine,
and now tilting upwards,
she's about 50 feet from you.
50 feet from me?
50 feet from you.
Because he's on the
other side, correct?
If you bamf out--
Oh, for fuck sake, really?
--don't do it.
Because then you really--
Nothing?
Worse than nothing. --won't
be able to do anything.
Misfire?
Misfire.
That's not true.
Keyleth's going to go.
Seeing Percy misfire, Keyleth is
going to grab a grasping vine--
Fucking cleric
right now while this--
--on the side of the wall,
and she's going to go for that
broom.
OK.
Because both Pike and her are
still grabbing on to the broom,
yeah?
And I'm throwing Whisper Vex.
OK.
I'm doing it.
The vine, unfortunately,
only has a range of 30 feet.
She's not-- you said
she was 30 feet away!
She's 30 feet out-- like
in the center of the ravine,
and is now 15, 20
feet up in the air.
Can she not hit the wall--
get a vine off the
side of the wall?
On the opposite side?
Maybe.
I am holding--
I've got like a 60-foot
range for this spell--
--the tether.
--plus the 30 feet from
the grasping vine, right?
You're holding--
oh, are they tethered?
Or is it 30 and 30?
No, we're not
tethered to that.
They just fucking went for it.
I thought you
were still grabbing
on to the tether to the--
I'm tethered to the broom.
--to the broom.
To the broom?
Oh, you're tethered
to the broom?
And Pike is still grabbing
on to the broom, yeah?
Yeah, that's what I mean.
Don't Whisper, because
the broom won't
be able to support
me, you, and Pike.
I'm going for the broom.
You've roped the broom.
All right, never mind.
Ah!
Come on, man!
All right.
[LAUGHS]
Look, I'm trying
to work over the--
I'm letting you guys do a
lot of things really fast.
That's insane.
(SCREAMING) Ah!
I'm trying--
I have six more moves
I want to make right now.
I'm working with you.
So please bear with me on this.
Fuck yes.
Yes.
Grasping vine!
What?
You're like a loan officer.
I wouldn't
recommend doing that.
I won't give you a
chance to even do it.
No lincolning.
Oh no!
Don't taunt the DM.
I want to sell you
this house, but there's
some things we need to go over.
Shh!
So I'm going to
ask you, Keyleth--
Yeah?
--to go ahead and make just
a general dexterity check.
Oh shit.
Just general dex?
Yes.
What?
This is how fast you're
able to chant a spell, which
requires an incantation and the
release of the spell's effect,
thus summoning the vine
and causing it to lash out.
This is just a base DC.
I need you to go ahead
and just roll and add
your dexterity modifier.
You got it.
You got this.
I love you.
Ooh!
That was a natural 18.
So that is plus my dex,
which is plus 2, so 21.
Ha!
OK.
With that, a vine--
Don't ha!
Don't taunt the GM!
What are you doing?
Stop rubbing it in his face--
Shu-- I mean, huh!
--for fuck's sake!
Huh!
So as Bad News misfires.
You watch as the front of it
just [EXPLOSION NOISE] --this
burst of black smoke
bursts outward,
and this look of utter
horror on Percy's face--
Keyleth rushes out, and grabbing
the edge of the end of the rope
bridge to get enough
of a reach out there,
you watch as her hair lifts
up and part of her body
begins to just drift upward.
But she holds on, and
reaches out with the staff,
using the strength
of her force of will.
The edge of the stone above
the ravine cracks open--
[CRACKING NOISE]
And suddenly, you
watch where there
is no life, a piercing flash
of dark green shoots outward.
A vine, freshly grown from
the edge of the stonework,
reaches out and grabs, wrapping
around the broom itself
and holding it taught.
You watch as the vine and the
entire group kind of fwooshes
upward.
You're suddenly pulled!
You're still grappled by this
undead zombie-like corpse.
And Pike is currently clutching
onto the broom as hard
as you can, as you
both impact at the end.