MATT: Welcome to tonight's episode
of Critical Role,
where a bunch of us
nerdy-ass voice actors
battle traffic from E3
to get here
in time to roll dice
and play Dungeons and Dragons.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we do.
SAM: Video games!
MARISHA: All the video games.
MATT: Thank you for being patient
and waiting for us
with a couple of tech issues
and generally battling
living in Los Angeles and having a car.
Anyway, before we kick the night off,
real fast,
I just want to take a moment
to acknowledge--
and I feel
it's important to acknowledge
there's been a lot of difficulty
and a lot of terrible things
happening in the world
and in our country in particular
this past week or so.
And us as Critical Role
and this community around,
I'm sure many of you agree,
we just wanted
to take a moment to express
that we stand with the families
of those that are currently dealing
with this difficulty,
who have lost those,
and stand with the community
that this was aimed at.
And everybody who has come together
as part of this,
we are in full support of this whole
wonderful gathering of people
in light of this darkness,
and I think it's
not just myself when I say
that everything
this community stands for
is to perpetually spread love,
community, positivity,
acceptance,
and everything in between.
So we just wanted
to bring that to you guys
and let you know that we're thinking
about you all out there.
And we have a wonderful community
of Critters out there as well.
If anyone needs any help,
assistance, or guidance,
or even just a happy word
to pick them up during this rough time,
we're all there for you.
So, anyway.
(blows kiss, sighs)
Then, to kick off this evening
of announcements and such,
we are kicking into the second day
of our renewed
Loot Crate sponsorship.
(cheering)
MATT: We wanted to reinforce
that their current theme is Dystopia,
which is an awesome theme box
that deals with all sorts of things
of post-apocalypse and dystopian-type
films, games, the whole thing.
They have Fallout,
RoboCop, BioShock,
a whole bunch
of really, really cool things,
so if you guys want to go
to lootcrate.com/criticalrole,
you can go ahead and get $3 off
your subscription
and get a whole bunch
of that cool stuff.
We also have the Dystopia DX,
which is their big collector's box--
TRAVIS: So awesome.
MATT: which we showed last week.
LAURA: Oh, is that
what this one was from?
MARISHA: Yeah, your sweet shirt.
ASHLEY: I love that shirt.
LAURA: Yeah, Skeletor!
MATT: (laughs) That's pretty slick.
If you guys have a chance
to check it out,
go see if it's
something you'd be interested in,
and make sure you put in
the criticalrole-- all one word-- code
to go ahead and get
your subscription discount,
which is fantastic.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: We're happy to present that
(funny accent) and are happy
that they like our show enough
to come and sponsor,
which is awesome.
(normal voice) So check that out.
You have until
the 19th at 9pm Pacific
to subscribe
and receive the Dystopia theme,
otherwise it switches over
to the next theme,
so if you're gonna get
under the wire for that one,
(funny accent) do it soon.
It's like a-- yeah! We have a--
TRAVIS: We’re giving out crates
in a chat room thing, don't we?
MATT: You think so?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
SAM: Giving out crates?
LAURA: We are?
ASHLEY: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Are we?
MARISHA: Are we?
LAURA: (gasps) That's exciting!
ASHLEY: It's going to be one at the break?
It's going to be a giveaway at the break?
MATT: Oh, snap.
ASHLEY: I'm just going
to start making stuff up.
TRAVIS: Is that--
did you just point and--
ASHLEY: Point, shoot.
SAM: Loot Crate has donated
two Loot Crate DX boxes
to give away to you.
We will be doing this at the break
and at the end of the night,
random in chat.
You must be active!
Stay tuned for that!
Exclamation point!
MARISHA: I'm so glad
someone wrote that down for us!
TALIESIN: Yeah, I'm so glad
they wrote out
the exclamation point.
TRAVIS: I'm in the chat right now.
LAURA: (laughing) Yeah.
TRAVIS: Totally.
SAM: Remind you, gotta stay active.
MARISHA: You're active? Stay active.
MATT: Stay active, Travis.
In the game! (snaps fingers)
Eyes up here, Grog.
(laughter)
MATT: All right,
so the next couple of things
we want to mention
to you guys real fast:
We have, it started up today,
a Critical Role t-shirt contest
that went up.
LAURA: Yeah!
MATT: We're doing this with Woobox.
The link should be in the chat room
for you guys to check out,
but we have currently,
until June 24th at midnight,
the cut-off date,
but if anyone wants
to submit any designs,
all the rules for the contest
are there.
When all those designs
have been submitted,
we ourselves,
the cast of Critical Role,
are going to pore through
and pick our favorite.
LAURA: Top three.
MATT: Top three?
LAURA: Yes.
TRAVIS: Top three faves.
MATT: (funny accent) And we will have
designs incoming forward
for official Critical Role
shirt stuffs, which is nice.
TRAVIS: (similar accent) Critter.
LAURA: (similar accent) Critter,
it's a Critter shirt.
MARISHA: Critter shirt.
TRAVIS: (similar accent) Critter
community t-shirt.
SAM: Are they all going to be like
Boaty McBoatface or something?
(laughter)
LAURA: What's Boaty McBoatface?
SAM: Boaty McBoatface is
like an online "name our boat."
(all say Boaty McBoatface)
MATT: Say Boaty McBoatface
so we can get into this,
and I'll be happy.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Do your worst.
Show us your best. Yes!
MARISHA: All right,
who did we send to Alaska?
Who was that? Was that Flo Rida?
MATT: No. Oh, Alaska? That was...
Redman. Bulldog.
MARISHA: Bulldog!
TALIESIN: Pitbull.
MARISHA: Pitbull! Pitbull!
MATT: I mess up his name
intentionally all the time.
TRAVIS: Bullman?
TALIESIN: (groans)
MARISHA: (laughing) Pitbull.
ASHLEY: Bulldog. Shih tzu.
MARISHA: He played in,
like, a Wal-Mart in Anchorage.
LAURA: But it was like
a joke for publicity, right?
MATT: He went ahead and did it!
The online poll
for his next performance,
the internet trolled him and made it
to this far Alaska performance.
MARISHA: A Wal-Mart in Anchorage,
or something like that.
LAURA: And he did it
MATT: And he did it! I was like,
"respect to you, man. Well done."
MARISHA: Yeah, respect.
Like 50 people showed up.
LAURA: That's awesome!
MARISHA: And got a private--
LAURA: Concert.
MARISHA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: You know what,
I've done a con in Anchorage.
It's nice. I like it.
TRAVIS: Yeah, man. Anchorage moose.
TALIESIN: They've got moose.
LAURA: Can we talk about our next thing
because I'm so excited about it.
SAM: Yeah.
TALIESIN: What's the next thing?
MARISHA: Yeah.
SAM: Do we get to show it, or no?
LAURA: YES.
TALIESIN: Oh, yes, that!
LIAM: (frustrated noises)
LAURA: Wait, okay,
so Liam gets to say it.
MATT: So, you are technically DM.
LIAM: So some of you
might remember us
talking about Joe Madureira
and his Kickstarter game,
Darksiders Night War,
which he successfully Kickstarted.
We talked about it a bunch
on this show--
MATT: Battle War, you mean?
LIAM: Hm?
MATT: Darksiders was--
LIAM: Excuse me. Battle Chasers.
LAURA: Battle Chasers.
LIAM: Excuse me,
I was going to be here
for a half hour and settle down
and go over my talking points.
LIAM: Battle Chasers.
SAM: You're wearing the shirt.
I'm wearing the damn shirt.
(laughter)
LIAM: Sorry.
Hour and a half in L.A. traffic.
Anyway.
He successfully Kickstarted,
they're working on it,
I just saw him at E3,
I saw him a couple of days ago.
If you don't know Joe's work,
he is a comic book artist rock star.
He has worked on X-men,
he's worked on Avenging Spider-Man,
Inhumans, Ultimates 3,
and his own comic, Battle Chasers,
which I fell in love with
when I was a teenager.
He does gorgeous artwork.
He's only gotten better with time.
SAM: Pitbull Chasers.
MARISHA: (laughs)
LIAM: Pitbull Chasers, Flo Rida,
and Joe collaborating together.
Anyway, that game's coming out.
You should check it out,
this is it.
But I bring that up because
while Joe is a busy, busy guy,
he somehow found the time--
I'm so excited--
to create an exclusive art piece
for Critical Role.
ASHLEY: Can we bring it in?
MARISHA: So gorgeous.
LAURA: Okay, okay, okay.
(noises of awe)
LIAM: Look at that business.
So right now--
LAURA: It's blocking my face,
but I want to see it.
MARISHA: Well, we've seen it tiny.
LIAM: Guys, if you go over
to the Geek and Sundry shop
right now,
this is on pre-order, so--
I'm going over my script--
signed versions of this
will be available for pre-order
for 2 weeks only.
TRAVIS: Yeah, limited 2-week run, y'all.
Get it.
LIAM: 2-week pre-order.
And then unsigned for 3 weeks.
LAURA: 3 weeks.
LIAM: So this is now or never.
ASHLEY: It's so badass!
MARISHA: Now or never
and then it goes away forever.
LAURA: Forever!
LIAM: And it's too gorgeous, too.
Oh my lord.
MARISHA: It's so gorgeous.
ASHLEY: I wonder if we should show
a close-up or something.
LAURA: So yeah, keep in mind
when you order it on pre-order
that you have to wait
for it to be fully pre-ordered
before we can send it out.
I don't know if that was on camera
because I'm above the poster.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: It's so sexy.
MARISHA: You're so sexy.
LIAM: It's all right.
Vex is on the paper, so.
LAURA: That's right.
MARISHA: Pike in that
three-point landing!
LAURA: Oh no, don't take it away.
ASHLEY: (singing) Goodbye, my love!
TRAVIS: There's an image
on the website, right?
MARISHA: And they are
movie-poster size.
They are that size.
LAURA: Yeah, they're that full-on--
LIAM: They're 24 x 36. Gorgeous.
MARISHA: 24 x 36.
SAM: And there's a place to click
on the page where you are
right now watching this.
MATT: Those are my eyes.
I'm on a poster!
MARISHA: If you scroll down,
there'll be a button.
LIAM: Scroll down
to the bottom of the page,
there's a button for that.
MARISHA: Scroll down,
there's a button.
LIAM: Thank you, Joe.
Thank you. It's gorgeous.
LAURA AND MARISHA: Thank you, Joe!
MATT: Thank you, Joe. It's amazing.
ASHLEY: Thanks, Joe!
TALIESIN: That's amazing.
LAURA: It's beautiful.
ASHLEY: I love it so much.
MATT: It is getting framed
and becoming a centerpiece of our home.
LIAM: And Battle Chasers Night War.
You should check it out today.
(laughter)
MATT: All righty.
SAM: Signed, by the way,
signed by us, not by the artist.
LIAM: Us. By us.
MARISHA: Yeah, by us.
TALIESIN: You could find him.
Hunt him down if you wanted to.
MARISHA: Yes. (laughs)
MATT: (in a funny accent)
Taliesin, you are going to be
somewhere this weekend,
are you not?
TALIESIN: Oh, god, I am.
As soon as we're done here,
I go home and pack
and get on an airplane.
I will be at Amazing Comic Con
in Vegas all weekend.
TRAVIS: You bastard.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
Sleep is never gonna happen.
LAURA, ASHLEY, AND MARISHA: No.
TALIESIN: Never.
ASHLEY: What is that.
TRAVIS: Sleep.
TALIESIN: You can meet me,
slightly deranged,
all weekend at Amazing Comic Con
with a bunch of other
Street Fighter kids,
and it's going to be a great time,
and be right next to the Library Bards.
Bonnie Gordon, yeah yeah.
MATT: Yes, yes.
TALIESIN: Yeah, be hanging with them.
MARISHA: Oh, yeah, Library Bards. Nice.
MATT: Glorious.
TALIESIN: Good times.
MATT: And if I recall,
there was also
a recent announcement
of a cool Telltale game
that went up this week.
LAURA: Oh, man!
Batman the Telltale series!
TRAVIS: It's sweet.
They announced the Batman cast
and Laura is playing
Catwoman Selina Kyle.
LAURA: Yeah.
MARISHA: Yeah, man.
TRAVIS: I play District Attorney
LAURA AND TRAVIS: Harvey Dent.
ASHLEY: Ohhh.
LAURA: It's pretty exciting.
TRAVIS: We're gonna
turn Gotham around.
LAURA: And at E3 today,
we went and checked out the demo
and it's pretty frickin' cool.
ASHLEY: It's so good.
I saw it yesterday and today
because I just couldn't not
watch it again.
TRAVIS: It's gonna be fun.
MATT: All righty,
anyone else have anything
they want to talk about?
(southern drawl) Or shall we dive into
the rest of tonight's story?
TRAVIS: Let's dive into the story.
MARISHA: Let's dive.
MATT: (southern drawl) All righty.
Let's go ahead and bring it down
as we all prepare ourselves
to begin to kick off
tonight's episode of Critical Role.
(spooky ethereal music)
(heavy breathing)
(roaring)
(dramatic music)
(gun firing)
(crackling flames)
MATT: Welcome back.
So, picking up
where we last left off last week.
Vox Machina,
the growing troop of heroic misfits,
having recently felled
their first recent member
of the Chroma Conclave,
Umbrasyl the Hope Devourer,
as well as destroying
the current incursion
of the Herd of Storms
in the city of Westruun.
You met with
the remaining people of the town
and began to decide a plan
for its continued existence
and the recovery of those
that were displaced
in these recent conflicts.
Part of this process was meeting
an individual named Kerrek,
who was a blacksmith
who had been in the town for a while,
who unwittingly
became part of this discussion--
MARISHA: My best friend.
MATT: (laughs)
Grog had spoken with
the remnants of the Herd of Storms
that had essentially
been disbanding from the name
and moving west
to join with the Rivermaw,
which had stepped off
from the herd not too long ago.
You guys had a hot springs episode
in the mansion.
SAM: (laughs)
MATT: Scanlan,
you had made your way back to Kymal,
in which you, along with the aid
of a few of your friends,
figured out a plan in which the people
who had been displaced
could eventually return to Westruun,
and also found Kaylie
and spoke with her,
had your somewhat-tearful
reunion there.
You guys began to construct
a subterranean portion of Westruun
that would be protected
from future dragon incursion,
renovating and restructuring
within the sewer system
beneath the city.
After this process was complete,
you decided the next level
of your trek,
the next direction you would travel
would be towards the far western,
northwestern continent of Othanzia.
Specifically, the city of Vasselheim
that you all know so well.
All of you guys stepping through
a tree portal presented by Keyleth,
you immediately step out
into the snowy exterior
of what seems like the outside
of the Quad Roads in Vasselheim.
And now, we see what
your next plan of action is.
What do you guys want to do?
SAM: (sighs) Light a fire.
LAURA: What time is it? (laughs)
MARISHA: Yeah, what time is it?
MATT: It's hard to tell right now
with the cloud cover so thick in the sky,
but you envision at this point in time,
it's probably mid-afternoon or so.
The general omniscient glow
through the clouds,
kind of diffused light,
but based on the time that you--
where you were
and how far you traveled,
you gather it's probably
early to mid-afternoon.
SAM: Well, you're the one
who brought us here, Vax.
Where would you like to go?
LIAM: I need to go
to the temple of the Raven Queen.
SAM: We'll come with you.
LAURA: Let's go.
TALIESIN: I know where that is.
LIAM: I know that you all
have a lot of errands to do.
I don't need everyone to come.
TRAVIS: We have a lot of errands to do?
LIAM: I thought so. You mentioned...
LAURA: My only errand
is to keep my eyes on you.
TALIESIN: I have some errands,
if that makes anybody feel better.
I have some errands to run.
TRAVIS: Do you need any help
with your errands?
TALIESIN: Sure. Actually, yes.
I would love some help with my errands.
LAURA: Don't let him shop, Percy.
Do not let him shop.
TALIESIN: That shouldn't be a problem.
TRAVIS: I don't know what that means,
but I'm sure I take great offense.
LAURA: (laughs)
TALIESIN: You're getting smarter.
TRAVIS: How effin' dare you.
LAURA: That eagle form
really made a difference.
TRAVIS: I spit out a feather.
(pthh)
MATT: So. Who's off to where?
LAURA: Where is this
Raven Queen's temple?
LIAM: (sighs)
We've not been here many times.
Are we surrounded by people?
Are there people walking about?
MATT: It is quite a busy time
in the afternoon.
There is actually a bit
of hustle and bustle.
Looking around,
just a quick glance
at your vicinity in Vasselheim,
you can see a lot of the bastions
are out in force.
Many of them are in process
of helping construct
what looks like
reinforced dragon-headed ballistae.
Some of the ones you had seen
towards the outside walls of the city.
There are more being installed
upon the inner walls,
and the ones in the distance
appear to be
under some form of construction.
TALIESIN: We have rooms.
Why don't we go claim our rooms
and I'm sure they can lead us
to everywhere we need to go.
LIAM: That makes sense.
MARISHA: Want to go check in
at the Slayer's Take?
TALIESIN: And we can meet back there
when everything is done.
MARISHA: All right.
LAURA: Do you need
to check in at your temple,
or should we pretend
you're not here
so they don't try
to make you stay?
ASHLEY: Let's just pretend
for a little bit.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MARISHA: Okay.
ASHLEY: And then I'll check in later.
There's no rush to get there.
At least, that I know of right now.
SAM: God will wait
for a long time.
TRAVIS: All right.
To the Slayer's Take, then?
LAURA: Let's do it.
TALIESIN: To the Slayer's Take.
MATT: All right. You guys continue
further south into the Quad Roads
until eventually you find yourselves
at the Slayer's Take guildhall.
The door is partially ajar already.
It appears that somebody
had left it open,
but it is warm on the inside.
You can see a fireplace hearth
on the far back and to the right
is already kind of filling the area
with this subtle musty smoke smell,
and the crackling of wood
in the distance
is a very welcoming sensation
from the cold exterior
of the city streets.
As you enter,
you do not see anybody
at the front desk at the moment,
but you do see a few other
random individuals of the guild
that have taken certain tables.
Some are eating,
and some are in the process
of playing cards or passing the time.
It seems to be
a relatively casual day
here at the Slayer's Take.
But your rooms are still available,
best as you need.
Anything you specifically require
in this place?
LAURA: Can I grab one of the people
that are here and ask him,
What's all
the hustle about outside?
I see them installing more.
MATT: Okay. You go ahead and--
one of the guys closest to you,
you've met him briefly in passing,
his name is Loran.
He has a completely bald head
with a single stripe tattoo
down the center.
He has a very, very pointed long chin.
Human, but he's probably
been busted in the face a few times.
You can see there's just scars
and what appears to be bone structure
that may have been reformed at times
due to blunt trauma.
But he's just sitting there,
sharpening his weapons,
just kind of doing good upon his own self,
being prepared for anything.
But as you come over
to ask him the question,
he looks up to you and goes,
"Word's gone
around the town recently
"that there's some wandering
dragon horde
"tearing through Tal'Dorei,
"so they're just upping security
around these places, just in case."
LAURA: Smart.
MATT: "I hope so.
Hope they make their way here."
LAURA: Nobody's sighted the dragons,
though, over here?
MATT: "Not to my knowledge, but
"(chuckles) I'd love to get my hand
on some of them scales."
(blade scrapes)
MARISHA: What's your name?
MATT: "Loran."
MARISHA and SAM: What?
MARISHA: Oran? What?
MATT: "Loran."
MARISHA: Loran.
MATT: Because... that's what I remember.
LIAM: Thought so.
(laughter)
LIAM: It took over 50 episodes
for that to happen.
LAURA: I'm sorry,
what was the question?
MATT: Well, when you don't take notes
when I give you
a character's name originally,
and they come back around
and it's weird
when you suddenly take damage
and your character starts hemorrhaging.
LAURA: Oh no. Loran.
Loran was his name.
LIAM: I was just eating an apple.
Why am I dying?
MATT: (laughs)
TRAVIS: Veiled threat.
ASHLEY: I'm just sitting by the fire, so.
LAURA: Slayer's Take.
MARISHA: So we have seen
this guy before?
MATT: Some of you
may have seen him in passing.
You haven't really
had a conversation with him.
He just exists within the guild.
There's many members
that you've come across in the past.
MARISHA: Sure, that exist.
TRAVIS: Probably a dragon.
LAURA: Pointy chin. Got it.
ASHLEY: Stripe on his head.
TRAVIS: Nothing wrong with those.
LIAM: How are the people doing?
Is there a sense of worry,
or do you guys feel pretty secure?
MATT: "As far as this town is concerned,
"it takes a lot more than a couple dragons
to drop these walls.
"It's the reason it's been around
for a long time,
"and I'd like to see them try."
MARISHA: Have you ever
encountered a dragon personally, Loran?
MATT: "I mean, I've come across
a few small ilk in my days."
MARISHA: Uh-huh. Sure. Yeah. Yep.
SAM: (laughs) Are you hazing Loran?
MARISHA: Nope.
LAURA: Keyleth is proud of herself
because we've just killed our third,
actually.
MATT: "Oh, that's fantastic.
I love to hear it.
"You half-elves are a humble bunch."
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Fire! Put the flames out!
MARISHA: Yeah, Team Half-Elf. Yeah!
TRAVIS: Such a good burn.
LAURA: Liam, I don't want
to ask Matt this,
but the chick
that runs the Slayer's Take,
her name's Vanessa?
ALL: Vanessa.
SAM: Cyndrian.
LIAM: And her husband Merkin.
SAM: Mertin.
MATT: (laughs)
LAURA: Are Vanessa
and Merkin around?
SAM: Mertin.
LAURA: Mertin.
SAM: Merkin is a different thing.
MATT: (laughs) Yeah,
a very different thing.
I guess it depends on
if he shaved recently.
He looks toward the back room,
where her main office is, and he goes,
"You're welcome to go ahead
and knock on the door
"if you're feeling frisky."
LAURA: Should we try to sell Vanessa
some of our dragon bits?
TRAVIS: We should sell to a merchant?
LAURA: Well, they tend to be in the--
TALIESIN: They may have a buyer.
LAURA and MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Love that you
asked me that question.
LAURA: I know, right?
What was I thinking?
TRAVIS: I don't know. (laughs)
TALIESIN: Keep a few of the scales, obviously.
TRAVIS: We can tell
what my place in the party is.
LAURA: Of course. Grog, come with me.
MARISHA: Oh, wait, keep the teeth.
Keep enough teeth for us.
TALIESIN: We'll talk
about the cold bag for now
and see if there's anything else
they want to talk about.
MARISHA: I have an idea for teeth.
LAURA: Can I go find Vanessa?
MATT: You go
and knock on the door. (knocks)
There's a brief pause.
Knock again. (knocks)
LAURA: (sing-song) Vanessa?
Vox Machina here-- oh, hi.
MATT: The door (whoosh) swings open.
You have to duck backwards.
It (thump) slams onto
the other side of the wall there,
knocking a few knick-knacks
that were on a nearby shelf over.
And Vanessa swings out.
"What? Who's calling-- ah.
It has been some time.
"How nice of you to come and visit.
"May I... be of service to you?"
LAURA: Oh, well, we were wondering
if we could be of service to you.
We happen to have acquired
a great many dragon bits
and we thought you might be in need of
buying them for your sellers-- buyers.
Your people.
SAM: Fencing them.
LAURA: Fence-- you know.
TALIESIN: I really thought
you'd be better at this.
MATT: "There is no fencing."
LAURA: No fencing, no. No, you're--
MATT: "We run a legitimate business."
LAURA: Legal buyers.
MATT: "Good.
As was I hoping to hear this.
"Let me check my ledger."
She turns around
and goes back to her desk.
Her tail flicks behind her as she steps
over to her table, leans over.
"(muttering) Ah!"
Pulls one of the books. (blows)
Starts thumbing through it.
(mutters) "What color dragon?"
LAURA: Black.
MATT: "Chromatic."
SAM: (quietly) Ancient.
LAURA: Ancient black dragon.
MARISHA: Yeah, you might have heard
about him. Umbrasyl... (chuckles)
SAM: You're super salty today.
TRAVIS: Tone it down two notches.
MATT: "There is currently
no contract for a black dragon.
"I do have one up for a bronze
or perhaps a white, but..."
LAURA: Oh, white!
Do we have any white bits left?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
ASHLEY: We should have white
from back in the day.
LAURA: What, do you want scales or...
MATT: "Specifically hide.
If there is white dragonhide?"
TRAVIS: We have 60 pounds of--
LAURA: That was the dragon
we killed for you before,
because we didn't bring the--
TALIESIN: No, it was before that one.
LAURA: No, but we killed one with Zahra.
We killed a white dragon.
MATT: "That was
for a different contract.
"This is for a newer one I came by."
LAURA: We've killed four dragons?!
Four fucking dragons. Go us.
MARISHA: Yes, we have. Yes.
TRAVIS: Excuse us
while we reminisce, apparently.
MATT: "(deadpan) Yes, it is amazing.
"The things you've accomplished.
I am blown away.
"But in light of your capabilities,
"I do not require anything black dragon.
"However, if a contract comes in,
I know who to call.
"Hold onto that,
because that would save you a trip."
LAURA and MARISHA: All right.
TALIESIN: We do have
some white scales left over, don't we?
LAURA: Yes, I think so.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we do.
We have 60 pounds of scales.
MATT: "Is this hide or scales?"
TRAVIS: Just scales.
No hide, unfortunately.
MATT: "Well, I could definitely do
"a bit of business for you there.
"The hide would fetch more, but--
60 pounds, you said?"
TRAVIS: Yeah. 64, to be exact.
LAURA: Of white dragon scales.
MATT: "64 of white dragon scales, okay."
MATT: "I would be willing to continue
at least part of this contract
"for this applicant for...
let's say... 4,500 gold pieces."
LAURA: 5,000 gold pieces,
I think is a fair price.
MATT: "This is not about bartering.
"This is what the contract says, my dear.
"This is beyond
a situation of conversation.
"The paperwork is already signed."
LAURA: What if we gave you
less dragon scales?
Would you have said less money?
SAM: That's typically how it works.
TALIESIN and MARISHA: (laugh)
MATT: "Vex'ahlia. My dear.
"My delightful little
dragon-hating half-elf.
"We've been good to you.
"We've done many great things for you.
You've done great things for us.
"This is a fantastic arrangement."
(thud) She slams the book shut
and sets it down.
"But you have signed on with us,
"and the deal is to fulfill contracts
"as they are signed, as they are written,
"as they are agreed upon by the person.
"If you wish not to accept this contract,
"we can just wait
until somebody else picks it up
"and goes out and fulfills this need
"at the price
at which they are requesting for this.
"You're welcome to keep the scales."
LAURA: I think we'll keep them
and we'll sell them to other vendors, then.
SAM: Haven't we had them for years?
TALIESIN: I have a thing
I'm thinking about.
MATT: "See? Then it's easy
for you to get rid of them.
"If they've been a problem for you,
then I'm sure this would be easy."
SAM: Where are we going to sell these?
The world's on fire!
MARISHA: Okay, hang on.
We know it's here.
There aren't that many
white dragons walking around--
TALIESIN: Certainly not anymore.
MARISHA: Certainly not anymore.
We know it's here.
Why don't we sleep on it.
Think about it.
If we're ever in a pinch for money,
we can come back.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Sounds good.
LAURA: Vanessa, you're so kind.
TRAVIS: Besides, I've been working
on that dragon immunity potion.
LAURA: I'm so sorry.
MATT: "That is all right. Goodbye."
And she shoos you out.
MARISHA: Oh, wait, Vanessa. Wait.
MATT: "Yes, other female half-elf?"
MARISHA: That's me.
Where's the temple of the Raven Queen?
MATT: "Oh, you're looking for
the Duskmeadow. Raven's Crest."
She points loosely outward,
kind of southeast of the direction
of the Slayer's Take guildhall.
"It's kind of hard to miss.
It's giant, black, ominous.
"(chuckles) You'll see it."
And she bops your nose
a little bit with her finger.
"Now, please. Out of my office.
I have work to get done."
LAURA: Thank you, Vanessa.
MARISHA: Okay, bye.
SAM: Thank you.
Kord's strength to you.
MATT: "That does nothing for me."
(slamming) Slams the door shut.
LAURA: They were worth a lot more
than what she was offering,
just for the record.
They are worth so much more.
SAM: To whom?
We haven't ever sold them
or come across anyone
who wanted them before.
TALIESIN: This is no reason
to get rid of something for wholesale.
LAURA: Well, we've not really tried.
That doesn't mean
we should just give them away.
SAM: We also are almost full
in our Bag of Holding,
might I remind you,
and 64 pounds
would free up quite some--
LAURA: It's not 64 pounds.
SAM: It's 64 pounds.
TRAVIS: It's 64.
LAURA: Oh, it was 64 pounds. (groans)
MATT: (laughs)
TRAVIS: Like I just told you.
ASHLEY: 64 pounds of scales.
TRAVIS: But I could
get rid of some other stuff.
LAURA: Well, they're worth
like 20,000 gold.
SAM: To whom?
LAURA: You don't care.
TRAVIS: We also have 15 cases
of expensive-ass bottles of wine.
TALIESIN: I'm just going
to point out, since--
LIAM, LAURA, AND MARISHA:
We should drink those.
TALIESIN: We should drink those,
first of all.
That is the only thing that makes sense.
And I feel-- and I apologize
if it seems like I say this a lot,
but I do have a castle
that we can drop things at,
and we can leave them there,
perhaps get back to them at a later date.
MARISHA: To be fair, Percy,
you do a lot to remind us
to try not to forget that you're titled.
SAM: To be fair, have we ever
gone back for something before, ever,
in our entire travels?
TALIESIN: Yes.
SAM: What?
LIAM: We needn't stay here long.
I don't think what I'm here for
is going to take too long.
I hope.
We could go to Whitestone next.
TALIESIN: Yes, drop everything off,
create a little nest of what we need.
LAURA: All right.
Let's go find your queen.
TRAVIS: (quietly)
There is some gross shit in this bag.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: You found the troll dick,
didn't you?
LAURA: What do you have in there?
TRAVIS: There are six basilisk eggs.
LAURA: Are they still good?
MARISHA: Those are probably bad.
TALIESIN: Oh, I bet those
have gone really bad.
TRAVIS: I reach into the Bag of Holding
and think about one basilisk egg.
LIAM: I'm sure they smell like Grog.
MATT: You pull out a basilisk egg.
TALIESIN: Do they just turn to stone?
MATT: It's roughly that size.
It's a dull grayish-blue hint.
LIAM: Sulfuric?
TRAVIS: Can I get the smell?
MATT: It has a somewhat, very vague
sulfurous scent on the outside of the egg.
TRAVIS: I'll put it back in the bag.
ASHLEY: Oh, Vanessa!
LAURA: We could make stink-bombs with it.
MARISHA AND TALIESIN: Ooh.
LIAM: Yeah, we could.
MARISHA: Good idea. I like that.
TRAVIS: All right. So what's next?
LAURA: We go see the Raven Queen.
You go see the Raven Queen
and we wait outside.
LIAM: I didn't say anything.
LAURA: Uselessly.
LIAM: I didn't say anything!
TALIESIN: Is it in the direction
where I have to go?
MATT: Where are you heading?
TALIESIN: I need to resupply everything.
MATT: That's the opposite direction.
TALIESIN: Okay.
MATT: You're heading
to the Braving Grounds.
They're heading to the Duskmeadow.
TRAVIS: Oh! I like the sound of that.
I'll go with you.
TALIESIN: Yes, you will.
SAM: I'll come with you, as well.
TRAVIS: Yeah, three! Who else?
Any other takers
while Vax goes and gets a tattoo?
MATT: (laughs)
LIAM: Another tattoo?
TRAVIS: Well, I thought that--
is that not what you're doing?
LAURA: That's what he's doing, Grog.
LIAM: It is. I'm getting a tattoo.
ASHLEY: Close. Something like that.
LIAM: It will say "Phillip the Brave".
TRAVIS: (gasps)
LIAM: Across the small of my back.
TRAVIS: Phillip. Full name, Phillip.
TALIESIN: This is out of--
I don't know if this is going to be
any help or anything,
by the way, Vax, but just in case.
I'm going to reach in
and pull out the mask
and hand it to Vax.
Just in case.
LIAM: (slowly) I don't know.
Thank you.
MARISHA: Percy?
TALIESIN: Yes?
MARISHA: Do you still have
that raven's skull I gave you?
TALIESIN: I do. We'll talk about that.
MARISHA: All right.
TALIESIN: But I've found in moments
when I was feeling less than brave
that pretending to be
somebody else on occasion,
even afterwards, can be helpful.
LIAM: Is there anything left
inside of this?
TALIESIN: Just some spit.
LIAM: That's wonderful.
LAURA: (laughs)
TALIESIN: And something that smells nice
in the front that will help.
It helps cleanse the air.
LIAM: All right, Percival.
TALIESIN: I don't know why.
I'm feeling... what would be the word?
Superstitious.
MARISHA: Oh, I was
going to say "giving."
LAURA: She's ornery today.
MARISHA: Sorry. Angry.
TALIESIN: You know,
I kind of like it.
LIAM: You know. Enough chit-chat.
Let's get this shit done.
MATT AND TRAVIS: All right.
MATT: So you three
are going to the Braving Grounds.
You four are going to the Duskmeadow.
LAURA: We are.
MATT: Okay. All right, so.
You three are making your way
towards the Braving Grounds.
Following suit after Percival,
you make your way up
not quite to the Trial Forge,
which is where you had
your last discussion
and brief showdown
with Earthbreaker Groon.
Still seeing the large statue of Kord
looming over the entirety of the realm.
You can still see the large columns
of dark smoke and soot
coming out of the various forges,
the various mining encampments,
and a lot of the folks there
that are working on different pieces
of iron and metal.
You, I assume, make your way
to a very familiar abode. (laughs)
TALIESIN: Of all the options of the world
that you've given me...
MATT: All right.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: This is really your fault
as much as it's mine.
MATT: You come up to the outside
of a familiar hovel.
Previously damaged,
missing part of its roof.
The roof is mostly repaired.
You actually see two individuals
are over the top of it,
hammering pieces of wood into it.
Not a very fine job,
but definitely enough patchwork
to keep the rain and snow
from pouring in.
The door is partially open
as you approach.
TALIESIN: (sighs heavily)
SAM: You might be blown up
if you go in there.
TALIESIN: I know.
TRAVIS: Should we wait outside?
TALIESIN: Let's just all be ginger.
(louder) Hello? Victor, are you home?
It's Percy.
MATT: Silence.
SAM: Want me to go in
and investigate?
TALIESIN: Hold on.
(louder) Hello, you up there? Hello?
MATT: (hammering noises)
"What?"
TALIESIN: Where is the owner
of this domicile?
MATT: "I don't know.
I haven't seen him."
TALIESIN: How long has he been gone for?
MATT: "(mutters)
(louder) Couple of hours."
SAM: Oh, good. Not dead, then.
TRAVIS: He's dead.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Do you have any idea
where he's been off to?
MATT: "I haven't seen him leave."
(hammering noises)
TALIESIN: Well, I'm going to pop in
and check really quickly,
just letting you know.
MATT: "Your funeral."
(hammering noises)
TALIESIN: I gingerly open the door.
Can I check for traps?
TRAVIS: Attaboy.
MATT: You may.
Make an investigation check.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we're standing right here.
TALIESIN: Oh, yay, that's not that bad.
Investigation? I never use that.
11. No, 12. 12.
MATT: 12, okay.
(creak) You move the door open
and kind of search the ground
and the area before it
and the actual frame of the door itself.
No traps.
TALIESIN: All right.
MATT: Glancing inside, though,
you can see a little bit of light.
It looks like there's
a hooded lantern across the way
and just a little bit of light is flickering
and it's kind of
going against the wall nearest to you,
to your right, as you enter.
The same familiar smell of fresh earth,
really, really, really dry dust
and a very familiar smell
of explosive black powder material.
TALIESIN: Oh, dear.
SAM: Is Victor in there?
TALIESIN: No, I don't see anybody in here.
SAM: Well, should we just
purchase what you need
via the honor system
and leave some coin behind?
TALIESIN: He's not necessarily
always a believer in coin.
Sometimes he just wants some trade.
Also, I need to talk to him
about some personal issues.
MATT: (thud) You see off to the side,
what you didn't initially notice
as you entered,
what appears to be a wooden trapdoor
in the far corner that (thud).
TALIESIN: Oh, sweet gods of Pelor!
MATT: (repeated thuds)
And you notice
that apparently something--
a large sack
of some heavy material
has rolled off a nearby table
and is now currently
holding the door down.
TALIESIN: Okay.
MATT: You hear a muffled,
"I'm inside!"
TALIESIN: I'm going to go
try and lift it.
TALIESIN: (grunts)
MATT: You lift it up,
set it off to the side. (boosh)
"(coughing) What's going on?
You trying to kill me?"
TALIESIN: (laughs) No! Hello, Victor.
I was just to give you money.
You were stuck--
you had gotten stuck down--
what is down there?
MATT: "This is my mining building."
SAM: Your mine?
TALIESIN: His Mayan building.
Can you not
understand simple English?
MATT: "Don't put things
on top of the door.
"It makes it hard to get out!"
SAM: (whispering)
Something's happened to him.
TALIESIN: Are you all right?
MATT: "I'm okay!"
TALIESIN: Are you sure?
MATT: "No, I've been locked
down here for hours!"
ASHLEY: Oh no.
TALIESIN: Grog, Scanlan?
(stutters) Come on in, he's fine.
MATT: "Help me out!"
MATT: He raises his hands up.
You can see now,
where once was two, now is none.
(sounds of dismay)
MATT: (grunts)
LIAM: You have to build him a hand.
TALIESIN: I know.
MATT: (grunts)
"I can't wait all day, here!"
SAM: Grog, can you get him out,
can you lift him up?
TALIESIN: Grog, can you lift the poor--
TRAVIS: All right, yeah.
TRAVIS: I grab the stump
and I pick him up into the air.
MATT: (screams)
TRAVIS: I shake him a little bit.
TALIESIN: I need him mostly intact.
TRAVIS: Oh. So on the ground?
TALIESIN: Treat him slightly better
than you would treat
a member of your own family.
MATT: "Don't shake me too hard."
TALIESIN: More than slightly better.
Much better.
LAURA: Oh, don't shake him too hard--
I'm not there.
TRAVIS: Oh. Gas.
MATT: "Sure."
TRAVIS: I put him gently
back on the ground.
MATT: "Thank you."
He pats you on the head
with his nub.
SAM: Ugh.
MATT: Goes over. You can see
he's kind of bandaged.
He goes over and then pulls the ladder up
that he didn't use, closes the--
TRAVIS: (laughing) The ladder
he didn't use?
MATT: "Okay. So. What do you want?"
TALIESIN: Well, I was hoping to buy
a little bit more black powder
from you, if possible,
and I'm curious if you had
anything else for sale,
and I wanted to ask you
a couple of questions,
just about other customers again.
MATT: "That's a lot."
TALIESIN: I know.
MATT: "I have powder."
TALIESIN: You do.
MATT: "I can sell you more powder.
Question one: yes. How much?"
TALIESIN: One question?
LIAM: First question.
TALIESIN: First question.
Has a one-armed lady,
a one-handed lady,
a doctor come by to purchase--
MATT: "Not a lady.
I am an honorable man!"
TRAVIS: Don't insult him.
TALIESIN: I know.
TALIESIN: And I would never
insult your honor
or preferences of any kind.
MATT: "Are you saying I'm pretty?"
TALIESIN: Victor, I think you know
how I feel about that,
but you're
a very attractive man, and--
MATT: "Your friend's hitting on me."
TRAVIS: I know it.
MATT: "I'm taken."
TRAVIS: He's taken.
TALIESIN: Are you dating right now?
MATT: "No, I'm just taken."
TALIESIN: Okay.
(laughs) I can't.
I'm sorry. I'm good.
MATT: "(shouting) How much?"
TALIESIN: Well, I was going to offer,
I was originally going to offer
some gold if you like,
but if you'd like,
I could make you a tool
you could use
with your current predicament.
Some sort of simple
clawing mechanism
for grasping, lifting,
not getting caught in your mine.
MATT: "Maybe. Maybe.
Maybe a trade? Maybe a claw?"
TALIESIN: I love trade.
Trade is brilliant.
MATT: "Build and bring.
Build and bring, and we trade."
TALIESIN: I would ask one other thing,
if I am to do this for you.
MATT: "Oh, so many questions!
"Does he have questions, too?
Does he have questions, too?!"
SAM: I do
have a question, actually.
TALIESIN: You have a question?
SAM: Yes, I do.
TRAVIS: I don't, no.
I don't have any questions. None.
MATT: (sighs) "I like him.
What's your question?"
SAM: I'm just looking
for a hat shop.
Is there a hat shop around here?
MATT: (considering noise)
And he starts pulling around
from a pile of oiled rags and shit
and he pulls up
what looks like a small burlap sack
that's torn somewhat at the opening.
"Hat."
SAM: Oh, god. Ugh.
All right, thank you. Thank you.
MATT: "My pleasure.
Happy to help." (chuckles)
SAM: Okay.
TALIESIN: That was everything
I could have hoped for, and more.
MATT: "Don't get near the fire."
TALIESIN: Really, don't.
SAM: Thank you.
TALIESIN: Has Dr. Ripley--
has a woman come by to buy black powder,
one hand, one mechanical hand,
one normal hand? Mechanical hand?
MATT: "Is that the one
you're saying you can make?"
TALIESIN: I'm going
to make you something,
nice and useful claw piece, yes.
MATT: "So you're saying
that this woman
"made a better hand
than you can make?"
TALIESIN: No, I can make
a better hand.
MATT: "Then make me a better hand!
Why would you give me a lesser hand?!"
TALIESIN: You're going to need to give me
quite a bit of black powder for that.
And more questions.
TRAVIS: Ooh.
MATT: "Really?"
(laughter)
MATT: "I've had a bad day."
TALIESIN: Is that recent?
SAM: That happened today?
TALIESIN: It doesn't look that recent.
MATT: (ripping sounds)
He starts unwrapping the wound.
TALIESIN: Oh, that's recent.
That's wet. That's very wet.
MATT: It's pretty recent.
TALIESIN: I can work with that.
I can work with that.
I'm going to go construct you something
that will be perfect for your needs.
I have a great idea.
I will need another hogshead and a half
of black powder
and a little information
about another customer
and then I will leave you
to your work. Is that fair?
MATT: "Fair!"
He turns around, rushes over,
and grabs the same phantom hogshead
that he has lying around his place.
TALIESIN: He eats a lot of pork.
MATT: Before he fills it with powder,
he goes over to Scanlan and goes,
"(hums) Too big."
TRAVIS: Good hat.
MATT: Fills it with black powder,
carefully brings it over,
holding it under his arm.
(grunts)
TALIESIN: Thank you. (grunts)
I will put this
in something reasonable.
I'll be back
in just a little bit with--
actually, do you have a glove
that you used to wear,
or anything like that?
Do you have something?
MATT: "Yes!"
He pulls out the glove
that was on the hand,
(laughing) and you can see
that it's blown apart,
hand burned to cinders--
TALIESIN: I can
take measurements from that.
MATT: It's more a sleeve
with a charcoaled edge.
TALIESIN: I'm going to be busy.
Can you cast the--
SAM: No, but Keyleth can,
and I think that would save you
a lot of time.
MARISHA: I'm not here.
TALIESIN: She's not here.
SAM: No, but we can go get her
and come back.
TALIESIN: To?
SAM: To just fix his hand.
TALIESIN: I don't think
she can just fix his hand.
SAM: Someone can restore something.
Maybe Pike can.
MARISHA: I can.
Not today, but I can over time.
TRAVIS: Want me to give it a try?
TALIESIN: While I'm tempted--
would you just--
I feel like I made a deal.
I'm just going to have to see to it.
SAM: I think he would prefer
a real hand than a claw hand.
TALIESIN: Would you prefer
a real hand or a claw hand?
MATT: "Depends.
How cool is the claw hand?"
TRAVIS AND SAM: (laugh)
TALIESIN: That's what I thought.
SAM: I would much rather
you spend time
on projects for us
than projects for him.
TALIESIN: This is projects for us.
TRAVIS: I vote for the claw.
It's pretty cool.
TALIESIN: And believe me, I would like--
MATT: "Cooler than that lady's hand?"
TALIESIN: Keeping him happy is pertinent.
I can make this myself,
it's just very difficult.
SAM: We have party members
who can regrow his hand.
TRAVIS: Hey, Percy.
TALIESIN: Yes?
TRAVIS: He wants the claw to be cooler
than that lady's claw hand.
TALIESIN: That's very easy to do.
She has no aesthetics whatsoever.
TRAVIS: All right.
Then eff the old original hand.
Let's give him
a reasonable claw, yeah?
TALIESIN: Don't worry about it.
SAM: All right.
TALIESIN: It'll be fine.
And if you can't do the mansion,
I know where I can
go get some work done.
SAM: Oh, you want me to make--
we have the Slayer's Take.
They have a workshop, don't they?
TALIESIN: If not, I know
where I can work on something.
I will be back.
I will not leave town
before I've delivered to you something--
MATT: "(squawks)"
He takes the hogshead.
TALIESIN: Oh! Absolutely fair.
MATT: "Trade when you bring hand."
TALIESIN: Yes, of course.
MATT: "Then I deliver with new hand.
Then all is well."
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: "No more questions!"
TALIESIN: No. That's fine.
We'll be back! It'll be good.
MATT: "You're small."
SAM: I need a big hat.
MATT: "Can't help you, sorry."
SAM: All right.
TALIESIN: Are we going to go
find a hat shop, then?
SAM: Maybe, if we pass one.
TALIESIN: All right.
We will be back. Stay safe.
MATT: "Okay.
Don't touch the door, please!"
TALIESIN: Yes. No. Just.
We'll be back. Bye!
TALIESIN: I'm going to go find
a workshop to work on something.
TRAVIS: I like you.
We'll see you later.
MATT: "(chuckles) He’s big."
TRAVIS: (chuckles)
TALIESIN: And I'm just right.
It's... a thing.
MATT: "I'm undecided about you."
TALIESIN: You're not alone.
I'm going to go see
if the Slayer's Take has--
SAM: We're going to leave.
TALIESIN: I cannot handle
any more of that. That was brutal.
SAM: Too good.
TRAVIS: I feel like
you’re just on a higher level.
ASHLEY: Right?
LAURA: So much.
LAURA: I just thought you were
going to make him not there
so you didn't have to do it.
MATT: No no no.
MARISHA: Yeah, yeah yeah.
He's just not home. Sorry, guys.
ASHLEY: Oh, I love him.
MARISHA: Victor's on vacation.
TALIESIN: So, I'm going to go
see if there's--
if there's not a blacksmithing,
if there's not somewhere I can do
a bit of basic smithing work
and technical work,
then I'm going to go
find that blacksmith from last time.
MATT: There's basic materials to do
essentially weapon repairs,
armor repairs,
minor armor construction
within the Slayer's Take.
If you want something
that's going to be
a little more to the level
of what you're doing,
you may have to actually
rent out a facility.
TALIESIN: Well, I'm going to go find
that young chap from before.
MATT: Okay. Yeah, easy enough to do.
If you want to rent the forge
for the day
to craft whatever it is
you're looking to craft,
he's charging you
50 gold for the day.
TALIESIN: 50 gold for the day?
Can I use all of his tools
and just my own materials?
MATT: You have to supply
your own material, but he'll let you rent.
TALIESIN: I'm going to run and find Vax,
get my stuff, and go to work.
MATT: Okay. You guys.
You four make your way
over towards the Duskmeadow.
LAURA: Trinket's out.
MATT: Trinket's out? (whoosh)
(bear moans)
LAURA: Come on, Trinket.
MATT: (grunts)
He rolls his head against you,
licks the side of your face,
happy to be out
of that stuffy little necklace.
You make your way towards the Duskmeadow,
which you've seen before.
It's a very comparatively...
glum-looking area of the town,
hence the name that accompanies it,
but this is the area
of the city that contains
the Raven's Crest,
the Amaranthine Oubliette.
It also contains
the entire town's catacombs.
This is where,
since this town's existence,
all of the dead are interred
perpetually deeper and deeper and deeper
beneath this part of the city.
Also one of
the oldest libraries of the city
is kept here as well.
As you approach the outskirts--
and you can see a very fine line
between this area and the Birth Heart,
which is the Melora section of the city.
There is a very, very wide river divide
between the two of them
and it's like night and day,
back and back.
Very, very, very directly
between the two of them.
You can see on Melora's side
there's just stalks and stalks of corn
and other vegetation
that's being grown for food.
There's almost like a lush forest
that curls around the outside of it
that doesn't match
the rest of the indigenous trees
you've seen in this area of Othanzia.
The entire Birth Heart area,
where this temple to Melora is,
is just this
plucked-out-of-nowhere section
placed into it.
And then you move over
to the Duskmeadow
and it's just... like the color
has left the vicinity.
And there you see in the center
of this part of the town,
this large, looming,
ominous obsidian and gold structure.
It's like a giant black stone aerie.
It has no intricacies
from this distance that you can see.
It's almost like a giant square building
that is just devoid of light,
with little glimmers of gold
when the light catches it at moments.
It's hard to miss
and definitely stands as a centerpiece
to this section of Vasselheim.
LIAM: The whole walk over,
I've been talking a lot,
mostly to Trinket.
You know, scratching him
behind the ears, saying,
"Buddy, you've been
trapped in there a while.
"It's good to see you out."
MATT: "(moans, snuffles)"
LIAM: Come hug your uncle. Come.
LAURA: He doesn't mind it.
LIAM: I'm sure he doesn't.
I'm just happy to see him.
MATT: He presses his nose
under yours
and lifts your chin up
and you bite your lip a little
from the sudden impact
from this very large bear,
but it's all with love.
LIAM: Yeah. It's cold. You're sure
you don't want to go back in?
Nah, you don't want to go back in.
I know.
MARISHA: (whispering) Hey, Pike.
LIAM: Just nervous talking
the whole way there.
MARISHA: (whispering)
I think Vax is talking to himself.
ASHLEY: (whispering)
He's very nervous right now.
ASHLEY: This is a big deal.
MARISHA: Yeah.
ASHLEY: This temple is very...
it's lovely.
MARISHA: It's gorgeous.
It's very intimidating.
Do you know anything about this?
You've lived here for a while, Pike.
ASHLEY: I've never been by.
MARISHA: Never been in?
ASHLEY: I've never been in, no.
MATT: You do know from your time here
and what little you've heard
that part of the purpose
of this vicinity
is not just to inter the dead
within part of these catacombs.
The library here
is kind of a loose partnership
between the people worshipers of her
and those who follow Ioun.
It is a center for knowledge and history
kept within the city.
But you'll see throughout the town
and the landscaped outer wall
that surrounds this entire portion
of Vasselheim,
there are repetitive glyphs
that line this entire area.
And from what you've heard,
at the very least, most of these glyphs,
which you see
across the corners of roadways,
and many of which surround
the entrance to the catacombs,
it is a perpetual enchantment that is
to seal any sort of possible undeath.
There once was
a terrible scourge of undeath
in this part of the landscape,
long ago,
that corresponded with a battle
hundreds of years ago,
and since then, the reinforcement
has been put in place
to prevent that
from happening again.
So the downside is
that the power of these glyphs
that prevent undeath
also prevent any actual vegetation
from existing in this area as well.
So all the ground
that you've come across:
no grass, no natural vegetation.
It's just dirt and ash and dust.
MARISHA: Can we recognize the language
in which the runes come from?
MATT: The magic itself
is divine in nature,
but it's based in the same
very, very base Draconic glyphs
that a lot of arcane magic
is based on.
It's very-- it's old magic.
ASHLEY: (laughs) It's old.
MATT: Yeah. It's based
in some sort of divine ritual.
MARISHA: What did you say
the name was
of the Raven Queen's temple, again?
MATT: The temple itself
is referred to as Raven's Crest.
MARISHA: Raven's Crest?
MATT: Raven's Crest, yes.
MARISHA: Okay.
ASHLEY: How are you feeling, Vax?
LIAM: I'm all right.
I'm just going to talk
to my sister for a minute.
ASHLEY: Okay.
LIAM: You know,
I know you want to--
I know you.
I know you want to be here.
LAURA: I know you don't
want me to come.
LIAM: I don't.
I really don't.
LAURA: I know.
And I won't, if you're sure.
I put you in this place
and I feel terrible about it
and I know you're extremely nervous.
Trinket can sense it, too.
He's very in tune with those emotions.
And I just--
LIAM: Listen to me.
You did not
put me in this place.
No one put me in this place.
LIAM: And everything's going to be fine.
LAURA: Everything will be fine!
LIAM: And I tug her sleeves
and make them a little more orderly
and I move a bit of hair out of her face
and I do a button that's not done.
LAURA: (laughs)
LIAM: Everything's going to be fine.
LAURA: I wanted it unbuttoned, actually.
LIAM: That's all right. Just wait here
I'll be out in a bit, all right?
LAURA: Yes.
LIAM: Everything's fine.
LAURA: I know. Everything's fine.
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: You don't need
to be nervous, either.
LIAM: I'm not.
LAURA: I will be here waiting for you
when you come out.
LIAM: I know. I'll see you--
LAURA: I love you.
LIAM: You know I love you, too.
LAURA: I'm proud of you, you know.
She's just going to love you so much.
And who knows,
you might have a new girlfriend
when you come out.
(laughs nervously, sighs)
I've heard other people
have dated gods before.
I've heard it's done.
That Cashew guy. Anyway.
LIAM: You're going
to wait here for me, right?
LAURA: I'll be right here.
LIAM: And then I drop the smile
as I walk off towards the other two.
MATT: Okay.
Which, as you turn and look,
when you originally approached
the stairs that lead up to the entrance
of this large structure,
it was just empty, doors closed.
There was no guard post
on the outside.
It was just these two looming,
almost dark glass-type doors
about 12 feet tall
and about 8 feet wide on each side
that are just locked shut.
As soon as you turn
to walk towards them,
the doors open and you see a figure
standing there at the door,
just looking directly at you.
Or at least you assume
is looking right at you.
It's hard to see.
This individual,
somewhat lithe in physicality,
is wearing long, dark robes
and their face is shrouded
in opaque black cloth,
like a death shroud
that just blocks the entire face.
You can see
the hint of a jawline, a nose.
It looks to be a person
of some background in there,
but they're just standing there,
watching you.
And as soon as you react
to their appearance,
the hand just beckons quietly.
LIAM: Were you expecting me?
All right.
I've brought a couple of friends.
Is that permissible here?
They'll keep quiet.
MARISHA: I turn to Vex.
LAURA: Keep him safe.
MARISHA: I swear to you.
We're all coming out of here alive.
LAURA: I know.
MARISHA: But if like an hour passes
and we don't,
maybe come in?
But we're all
coming out of here alive,
so don't worry about it.
It's fine.
ASHLEY: And I squeeze her hand.
I'll make sure
he gets out okay. I promise.
LAURA: All right.
ASHLEY: Okay. Please be safe.
LAURA: It'll be fine.
ASHLEY: It'll be fine. Yes.
LAURA: I'll just be right here.
Waiting here with Trinket.
ASHLEY: Okay.
LAURA: Just calmly leaning
against a wall. No big deal.
ASHLEY: Okay.
MARISHA: We've faced
way more terrifying things
than a few albeit creepy
men in robes.
LAURA: I don't even think she's that bad.
She's not going to be bad.
LIAM: Guys.
LAURA: Just go.
ASHLEY: Okay. We'll go.
We'll go in with you.
MATT: All right.
As you step up to the stairs,
the figure leads you all inside,
and as you step into the main center
of this initial walkway chamber,
the figure doesn't enter with you.
It just closes the door behind you.
(echoing thud)
You can feel
the hint of vibration of impact
as the doors close shut.
MARISHA: It's dark?
MATT: It's lowly-lit on the inside,
and it's interesting.
From the outside, it looks like
a black, solid,
impossible-to-see-through building.
From the inside,
you can actually look out
and the entire building
is made of this glass,
this somewhat-warped, dark glass.
And you can see almost
the entirety of the outside
from your position.
The doors are held aloft into it.
It's like a one-way
type enchantment,
or the construct, the material itself,
is somewhat translucent from this side.
MARISHA: Like an interrogation room?
Like one-way mirror type of thing?
MATT: Kind of. Or like a very,
very dark pair of sunglasses,
but made of naturally-formed rock, almost.
LIAM: Noticing that, I turn
and just sort of look at my sister
for 5 or 10 more seconds.
MATT: She doesn't see you
and she just stands there quietly,
looking around,
inspecting the vicinity.
Pets Trinket a little.
LIAM: (hesitantly) Let's do this.
SAM: (chuckles)
ASHLEY: Do I feel anything,
being in here?
MATT: You just feel
a natural tremble
stepping into a place
of powerful divine influence
that is not
the warm comfort of Sarenrae,
which has protected you before.
Now, you understand the way
many deities work in these lands,
and your place in it,
and Sarenrae's place in it,
and you know enough
about the Raven Queen
to know that this is not
an unwelcome place, per se.
Go ahead and roll a religion check.
ASHLEY: 23.
MATT: 23.
You understand the Raven Queen
has also not always been
the one who holds sway
over the domain of death,
the domain of winter,
the domain of fate.
Once mortal,
the Raven Queen ascended
as, essentially, a follower
and a partner
to the previous god of death,
which his name
has been erased from the books.
This mortal ascended many,
many years ago, pre-Second Spark,
and has since taken what was once
a tyrannical position of death
and afterlife and souls
and took it instead
as the natural transition that it is.
However,
due to a lack of respect,
or at least, a lack of,
for lack of a better term,
belief or trust from the other gods,
she only gained dominion
over the actual moment of transition,
not of the actual souls
of the afterlife.
That influence was given to others.
But the Raven Queen represents
one of the most feared elements of life,
which is the end of it,
but you also know
that that is a natural thing.
Your personal belief is up to you.
The sense you get here is that...
being an individual
that worships life,
that worships redemption,
that worships second chances,
you can't help
but swallow a little hard
at the idea of a god that's purpose
is to make sure
that if you're destined
to have once chance,
it stays one chance.
ASHLEY: Okay.
MATT: As you begin
to walk down this hall,
ever so slow as it is,
each footfall deafening
in the clack.
(clicking footsteps)
The hallway leads on
for another hundred feet or so
before the glass,
somewhat translucent material
shifts into the next chamber,
into an almost
deep gray and ivory ice-like interior.
The dark,
coal-black exterior you've seen
now transitions into what feels like
a very finely-carved
piece of architecture
from ice and bone.
MARISHA: Do I get the sense
as a druid, as an Ashari,
that we've switched into another plane?
MATT: Go ahead and roll an arcana check,
as this is not so much
a nature-based thing, yeah.
MARISHA: Oh! I rolled a 19.
(laughs) 21.
LIAM: Oh dear, oh my.
LAURA: Oh gosh, oh jeez.
MARISHA: Oh goodness gracious.
MATT: From your understanding
of transitional magic between planes,
there has been
no actual shift between planes,
it's just the material itself
is different upon the interior
of this building.
As soon as you enter this place,
you do see another figure
walking towards you.
Similar long, dark robes.
However, the veil
has been pulled back,
and you see before you
what looks to be
an older elven woman with very,
very bright silver hair
that just kind of falls long,
past her shoulders,
down to her back about mid-waist,
or down to the bottom of her waist.
With a smile.
You can see as she walks towards you,
a very welcoming grin.
As she approaches,
she pays very little mind to you three,
but directly to you, says,
LAURA: (whispers) I'm not there.
MATT: "You walk with Her sight on you.
"You are ever welcome here."
LIAM: I've come
to understand
my place in Her sight.
MATT: "Then I think, perhaps,
you are here for communion.
"Come. Our most sacred chamber.
The communion pool awaits.
"Only you may have entry,
unfortunately."
LIAM: Right.
LIAM: I plant a kiss on the cheek
of each of the women.
MARISHA: Do you need anything
before you go in?
Any enhancement of any kind?
LIAM: Just cross
your fingers for me, okay?
MARISHA: Okay.
I just kind of squeeze his hand.
ASHLEY: Same.
Be careful.
MARISHA: We're right out here
on the other side of this door.
If anything terrible happens,
you have the earpiece.
No one will stop Pike and I
from getting through there
if something terrible goes wrong.
Rules be damned.
LIAM: I made my bed. Now I gotta lie in it.
I'll see you soon.
I follow.
MATT: "Come, champion.
The Lady of Fates awaits."
And she turns around
and leads you 30 more feet
to what looks to be
an ascending staircase
that just enters
up and out of the sight of you two.
ASHLEY: We'll just hang out, yeah?
MARISHA: I guess we'll wait, yeah.
MATT: You ascend
a few feet behind her,
about 40 or so feet,
until it comes
to a single large doorway
of deep, deep dark oak wood
with what looks to be
a dark iron ring in the center.
As she steps up to it, she takes it
and (thud) knocks on it twice.
(deep creak) It just shifts open
and leads into a central chamber now
that looks about a hundred feet high,
and it is a large steepled dome
of what looks to be nothing
but stained glass.
It's awe-inspiring.
It's beautiful: the colors,
the light as it peeks through.
The source of light,
diffused as it is by the clouds,
is sourceless in here.
It seems like there are beams of light
coming from all directions
and all the colors
are just strewn across the floor
in what looks like this
perpetually-shifting kaleidoscope
of dots of reds and blues and purples
and yellows and pinks and whites.
You can see, across the room,
there are three other figures
that are all dressed
in the same dark robes,
the veils over their heads,
of varying size.
You can't make out
what their racial background is, per se,
but they are all stationed
around the center of the room,
in which lies, from what you can see,
a very, very large round pool
of some sort of deep crimson liquid.
LIAM: I have come to pay a debt,
and I do so gladly
and without question.
What would you have of me?
MATT: "You came to speak with the Lady.
"Well, the way is before you."
She gestures to the pool.
LIAM: I walk slow and straight in.
MATT: You step into it. (squelch)
It comes up to your ankles,
to your knees.
And what catches you first
is that the liquid is very thick.
It is viscous in a familiar way.
This is most definitively
a pool of blood.
And it is cold. It is ice-cold.
As you step in, you can feel that
as it begins to seep into your boots
and begins to find its way
into the crevices of your outfit
as you get down into your waist,
it's just chilling.
You can't help but to stand up straight
as you step further in,
not quite sure of how deep it gets.
And it gets deeper. And deeper.
Up past your chest,
up past your shoulders,
and you're not even
halfway into the center of the pool
before it's going past your nose.
LIAM: I keep going.
MATT: You take your last breath, hold it,
and submerge yourself in the pool.
Darkness around you,
the cold sensation.
Nothing...
LIAM: I open my mouth and inhale.
MATT: As you do,
you feel the blood fill your lungs
and immediately your lungs begin to seize
with the lack of oxygen.
You instinctually begin
to reach up for the water and pull,
but you can't rise.
You can't get up.
And at that point, the cold, piercing pain
of the liquid in your lungs
becomes warm.
All the liquid around you
And in the darkness,
where you cannot see,
you calm, as suddenly your breathing
is no longer difficult.
It's natural. It's like air.
And it's reminiscent
of being in the womb,
of the moment of birth
you'd forgotten so long ago,
that you're just surrounded
in darkness and comfort.
And piercing the center
of this darkness before you,
you see
a very faint bead of white light
just begin to spark
and grow, and grow,
and as that light widens out,
it becomes a face.
A porcelain face.
A nose, lips, a chin,
empty dark sockets,
long dark hair
that goes to crimson and surrounds you.
You see a small hand
reach up behind
and lift you from your legs.
And for what you thought
was only a few feet of liquid,
you look around you
and it is an endless space,
a space you've been before,
a space that you once visited
in your sleep, in your dreams.
You look down below and you can see
the infinite skein of threads
that you were once given inspection to.
As you look down, you see the very palm
of the Raven Queen
holding you aloft in this space
as the mask
pulls in close to you with a smile.
The lips don't move,
but you hear a voice
from all directions in your head.
A comforting voice.
A welcoming voice.
"My champion.
"Vax'ildan.
You've come to me at last."
LIAM: This was always
supposed to happen, wasn't it?
MATT: "There is destiny,
"but you still guide your path
where it must go.
"Especially you, fate-touched.
"You're one of the few
that bends threads near and around you.
"That's why you're
so interesting to me."
LIAM: (haltingly)
I give myself willingly to you
for the bargain that was struck,
although I question
if the bargain
was just the surface reason
for this to happen.
MATT: "When one such as your...
"unique essence walks these realms,
"do not think I am
the only one to take interest.
"And do not think you are
the only one, either.
"But I was there
to seize the opportunity when it arose,
"and as such, you are now mine.
"And I know that you hate me.
I know that you fear me.
"Most do.
"But only because they are
without understanding.
"Without death, life has no meaning.
"Finality drives change,
"innovation,
"greatness.
"It is the end that I bring
"that drives all of your gracious creations
of this land
"to make the world better than we did,
than those before me did."
LIAM: I would learn your ways.
I will learn your purpose.
And I will serve.
MATT: "Then understand
the wholeness of what it is you serve
"and what you represent, champion.
"Even after death, the soul is carried
to another purpose,
"but it is that transition
where it is at its most vulnerable.
"It is my charge, my gift--
your gift, now--
"to safeguard that beautiful moment.
"There are those that find
the immortal soul
"one of the most pure
and powerful means
"of energy, of sourced power,
in this world.
"That is an abomination.
"There are those
that wish to halt the process
"and live eternally
in some form of undeath or the other.
"That is an abomination.
"There is also a difference
"between bending your thread
around destiny, fate-touched,
"and perverting the thread entirely,
"for death is sacred.
"But not all deaths are destined,
in that moment.
"Some destinies require one
to endure beyond the moment.
"To meet that moment many times
before the final death is to come.
"We must guide these moments
across this web."
And as she sweeps her hand out.
Where she holds you in one palm,
another hand reaches out,
and the entire web of threads
just glows below you
in this curling wave
out into infinity, into the horizons,
endless, to each side of you and beyond.
"So, to bend destiny,
to bend these fates,
"is within our sphere of influence.
"It's those that find a way
to cheat this destiny,
"halt the progression,
"corrupt their thread to the point
it sickens those around them.
"Undeath, wayward necromancy.
"Perversion
of the sanctity of the cycle,
"of our very domain, is an atrocity
"and must be stopped
and stamped out.
"That is our cause.
"Your cause, now.
"Do you still accept this gift?"
LIAM: (whispering) I do.
MATT: "You, Vax'ildan.
I've had my eye on you for some time."
And the smile curls
into this much wider smile.
To the point it seems
somewhat perturbing.
"Your dual nature:
rushing prematurely towards your end,
"wantonly throwing your life
before the flames,
"only to pull away
in those last moments.
"Instinct.
"You test your path constantly,
without knowing
"you've been preparing
for this mantle your entire life.
"My beautiful champion."
The smile subsides.
The face goes stone.
Lack of expression. Blank.
The hand pulls back
and you now can see
the full immensity of her size.
Her body infinitely long,
looking down
before it disappears
into darkness.
And as you look up,
suddenly the mask
is there before you,
but normal, human-sized.
You're no longer in her hand.
You're standing on a floor,
a floor of the same white,
ice-bone type substance
that the interior of Raven's Crest
seems to be built from.
And for a brief moment,
you see before you
the woman before the god,
the ascended mortal,
no larger than you.
From the hair
that topples down the sides,
the hand reaches up
and grabs the mask and pulls it away.
Beneath the mask you see
a very beautiful,
very sad-looking woman.
But her eyes
are cold and red in the iris.
Her skin flawless and smooth.
White, pale, sunless.
Her brows thinned and furrowed.
She steps forward
and touches the side of your face.
"There are those
who will be frightened of you.
"But know what we do
"is one of the most important gifts
of all."
And she grabs your head,
pulls you down,
and kisses you on the forehead.
At which point, suddenly your lungs
fill once again with searing white pain.
You find yourself scrambling about,
instinctually spilling out liquid
all around you,
and you finally (coughs) come out
on top of the communion pool.
Your eyes open and you can see
just red crimson pouring in your vision.
You rub it out
and you're in the chamber alone.
Eyes wide, swimming around,
you can see the figures on the side
come to the edges.
They all bow.
The figure that led you in
stands at the mouth of this pool
where you entered.
She's smiling.
She has her hand extended.
LIAM: I take it.
MATT: She lifts you out of the pool.
One of the other figures runs up
and takes
one of the dark robes that they have
and pulls it off around them,
revealing just a simple
dark blue and black outfit beneath.
Still wearing the veil,
but wraps the dark robe around you
as the liquid is now
back to its freezing cold sensation.
Your teeth are chattering.
They lead you back
to the door you entered,
down the stairs,
and into the central chamber
where both Keyleth and Pike await.
You guys turn and see,
descending the stairs,
being flanked, essentially,
by two of the members
of the Raven's Crest,
both of the shoulders
with the dark robe wrapped around
a very cold and somewhat
freaked-out looking Vax'ildan,
who has smeared red across his face.
His hair is thick
with viscous crimson liquid.
ASHLEY: I run over.
You okay?
MARISHA: I stand
at the bottom of the stairs and I watch.
LIAM: (hoarsely)
I got answers in there,
but they led to more questions.
What am I to do
with those questions?
MATT: The woman
who had led you in there
smiles and says,
"That is the nature of death.
"We can't have all the answers,
my friend.
"It is the pursuit of those answers
that drives us.
"Do you trust Her?"
LIAM: I do.
MATT: "Then perhaps
you'll find those answers one day."
LIAM: Thank you.
MATT: "Thank you."
They pull the robe off
and they all head
back up into the chamber,
leaving you all there
in the room alone.
MARISHA: I walk over.
ASHLEY: (whispering)
I'm just going to stay where he is.
LIAM: I'm shell-shocked.
MARISHA: You look well.
LIAM: It's going to be good.
MARISHA: What did she say to you?
Did she speak to you at all?
LIAM: (whispering) Yeah.
MARISHA: (shocked laugh)
LIAM: Do you speak?
ASHLEY: Yes?
LIAM: To her?
ASHLEY: Sometimes.
LIAM: Do you understand?
ASHLEY: I don't think
any of us can fully understand.
I think, if we did,
then we would be gods.
MARISHA: Do you believe?
LIAM: Yeah. Yeah. I do.
I don't know what...
I don't know why, but...
this was fate.
MARISHA: Is that what she told you,
that this was fate?
LIAM: No.
I know it here.
MARISHA: Why?
LIAM: Everything has led to it.
You and I wouldn't be standing here
if my sister hadn't stolen a broom.
Where's the sense in that?
What else is it?
I teleported into the stomach of a dragon
with a gnome
and I am still standing here.
If it is not fate, what is it?
MARISHA: I don't know.
As someone
who is constantly questioning mine,
I don't think
I'm the right person to ask.
But I do know one thing--
and I grab his hands--
you were amazing
and talented and special
way before she found you.
If anything,
we can call her a god.
We can also call her
a great opportunist.
She didn't give you
anything special.
The Vax that I see before me right now
is no different than the Vax
that I saw before me ten minutes ago.
I'm not saying
that what you experienced
wasn't real and true.
I believe you whole-heartedly.
LIAM: This is real.
This was meant to be.
And I am on board.
MARISHA: Is it what was meant to be
or what you just really wanted?
And it found you?
LIAM: (disbelieving laughter)
It is not what I wanted.
Thank you. Thank you.
I need to see my sister.
And I head off towards the exit.
MATT: You guys make your way
to the outside of Raven's Crest.
The doors open once again.
The figure that let you in
is waiting for you, opens the door.
As you see the doors open--
LAURA: I jump up immediately.
I've bitten off all my fingernails.
MATT: (laughs) Rushing down the stairs,
you see Pike, Keyleth,
and your brother
in a little better spirits
than when he first entered,
if a little damper and redder.
LAURA: Is that blood?
Is that blood all over you?
Did she hurt you?
LIAM: It was really weird,
but it's fine.
I told you I'd be fine,
and I'm fine.
LAURA: I get out a rag
and I start wiping everything off.
(laughs) You're alive, though.
LIAM: (laughs) Yeah,
doesn't make any sense, does it.
LAURA: (laughing) Oh my god,
are you stronger now?
Are you so strong?
LIAM: I think I might be
a bit weaker, actually.
LAURA: Oh, I don't believe it.
LIAM: I have the jelly-legs.
LAURA: (laughs) Do you want
to ride Trinket for a while?
LIAM: Could I?
LAURA: Yes!
LIAM: He's going to get sticky.
LAURA: No, he loves the taste of blood.
MATT: (sad moaning)
LAURA: (laughs) Oh, Trinket.
MATT: Trinket comes over
and begrudgingly lowers himself
so you can climb on.
LIAM: No, don't lick.
Don't lick.
LAURA: He's very light.
Scrawny, scrawny, scrawny.
LIAM: But don't lick, Trink, please.
MATT: (grunts)
ASHLEY: Just one kiss?
One little lick?
LAURA: (laughs)
LIAM: Later, buddy. Later.
LIAM: I climb on top.
LAURA: Aren't you glad
you got out of the Pokeball for this?
LIAM: I give a quick look
back at my friends.
and then I take a nap on Trinket.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: So everything's good, then.
He's good? Everything's fine?
ASHLEY: I think so... I mean, it's--
it was very different,
but that doesn't mean it's wrong.
LAURA: He talked to her?
MARISHA: He talked to her.
LAURA: Were you there?
ASHLEY: No.
MARISHA: They didn't let us
in the room.
LAURA: Oh. Well, I'll find out.
MARISHA: We stood outside.
He didn't talk much about it.
Maybe you can find out more.
All he said was
that he knows that this was fate.
LAURA: Well, good.
He has a purpose.
ASHLEY: Yeah.
MARISHA: Oh. Yeah.
Well, that's one way of looking at it.
LIAM: (snores)
LAURA: I keep him steady
and I walk next to him.
MATT: Okay.
You guys eventually make your way
back to the Slayer's Take.
The three of you guys...
what are you doing
while this is transpiring?
TRAVIS: Eating my mechanical pencil.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: I've sent him
with a shopping list.
MATT: Okay.
What have they been sent to acquire?
TALIESIN: I'm going to need
a cheap gauntlet, some saddling straps,
three tankards, a pick-axe,
and two clocks.
MATT: All right.
How much gold do you give him?
LAURA: You've got--
TALIESIN: That's right, I've got.
SAM: Four gold.
TALIESIN: (snorts) I give--
LAURA: You've also got
a five-pound bag of gems, don't forget.
TALIESIN: I do. I give him--
MARISHA: (giggles)
TALIESIN: This is what happens.
MARISHA: Is that Riegel?
TALIESIN: That was Riegel.
MARISHA: (giggles)
TALIESIN: Don't read that.
That's not necessary.
SAM: (singing) I drew a dick
on his picture.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: And I need
that man's dick to finish the arm.
MATT: That'll go over well.
TALIESIN: Despite the dick on my page,
I'm going to give Scanlan 100 gold
to take with Grog
to find some junk items
that they can put together.
SAM: I'm going with Grog to shop?
All right, sure.
TALIESIN: If you're down.
SAM: Yeah. I'll do it.
Yeah, we'll go for all that stuff.
Do we find success?
MATT: I want you guys
to go ahead and roll--
actually, for you, just roll
a general charisma check
to ask around and get people
to give you the proper information.
TALIESIN: I love you.
SAM: What is this, just charisma?
MATT: You just add
your charisma modifier.
SAM: 18.
MATT: 18?
MATT: Yeah, within a very brief period
of talking to the right people
and smiling and getting folks
to listen back to you,
eventually you're given information
on where each piece of that list
is able to be found.
They're not too crazy items.
There's a lot in general stores,
general armor--
TALIESIN: I don't even need
an articulated gauntlet.
It just needs to be a clamp.
MATT: Yeah, just a basic
clamp gauntlet.
SAM: Do we also find a hat store?
TRAVIS: Yeah, we'd better.
LAURA: You want another beret?
MATT: Not in the Braving Grounds,
but you can definitely find one
on your journey in the Quad Roads.
SAM: If I can take
an extra side journey
to find a hat shop,
that would be great.
MATT: Do you go with him?
TRAVIS: Fuck yeah.
SAM: It's just hats, Grog.
We're just getting hats.
MATT: You guys make your way
to the busy streets of the Quadroads.
Eventually, asking around,
you find yourself
across from what is called
the Sore Socket Haberdashery.
SAM: The Sore Socket?
MATT: Sore Socket Haberdashery.
TRAVIS: I love it.
SAM: I love it.
MATT: And the picture outside
has a caricature of a guy,
smiling, with a giant black eye.
SAM: (laughs)
MATT: You walk inside and it's like
a small, localized bar--
not a tavern by any means,
but it has like
one small set-up in there
for just general beer,
and just loads and loads of hats.
Leathers, cloth,
all kinds of silly circumstances.
You see some nice fancy hats
with big feather plumes.
You see joking hats
that have multiple colors
and what looks to be
bells hanging from them.
As you step into the room,
you see two other random individuals
that are looking around, shopping,
and at the far end,
you see coming through
a big thing of curtains
what looks to be
a rather rotund woman
in her late 40s or so.
Big curls in her dark brown hair
and maybe a little too much makeup
on her face, who goes,
"Darlings, what are you looking for?
"What can I get you?
Are you looking for hats?"
SAM: Oh, man.
MATT: "I assume
you're looking for hats."
SAM: Wow. Yeah,
we've come to the right place.
TRAVIS: The guys
are missing out on this one.
(laughter)
SAM: Hi, ma'am.
My name's Scanlan. This is Grog.
We're just-- I needed one hat,
but you have
such a fantastic selection,
maybe we'll pick up a few.
SAM: How much money
do I have left over from his hundo?
MATT: After all those materials,
I'd say probably,
asking around
and your high charisma,
you probably have about 60.
TRAVIS: Bro, we got money.
SAM: Let's get some hats!
MATT: "My name is Deidre, dear,
so nice to meet you."
SAM: It's lovely to meet you.
MATT: "You're so adorable."
SAM: We've heard so much
about this store.
MATT: "Really?"
SAM: Yes, far and wide.
MATT: "Oh ho,
I can guarantee you, it's all true.
"And you, you're so big,
you're so strapping."
TRAVIS: I am.
MATT: "And that beard!"
MATT: She kind of tousles
the beard with her fingers.
MATT: "(giggles)"
TRAVIS: (giggles) Oh, stop it.
LAURA: Little food bits fall out.
SAM: I'm here to buy
just one quick thing in particular,
then we'll be on our way.
I just want a very tall hat.
Just very tall black hat
with a point.
MATT: "Tall.
Proportionally tall or regular?"
SAM: Like a big triangle hat.
MATT: "Hmm."
SAM: With a wide brim.
Like a wide black hat just like this.
MARISHA AND TRAVIS: (laugh)
MATT: She thinks for a second.
"I don't carry anything like that--"
SAM: All right, well,
it was worth--
MATT: "But I can make you something
"if you don't mind waiting a bit."
SAM: I could come back for it
another day, perhaps.
MATT: "Oh, but at least
let me measure your head, sweetie."
SAM: It's not for me.
MATT: "Do you know the size
of who it's intended for?"
SAM: Well, her head's
a little bigger than mine.
MATT: "I'll make it adjustable!
"You have to pay
half in advance, a custom order."
SAM: Sure, how much?
MATT: "That will be 10 gold now,
"and an additional 10
upon retrieval."
SAM: More than worth it.
I'll take it.
MATT: "All right."
SAM: And also,
can you get something for him
that would really
accentuate his features?
TRAVIS: Me? What?
SAM: Yes, you need a hat.
TRAVIS: Oh, this streamlined.
This is how the look goes.
SAM: But if it rains, Grog.
TRAVIS: But that's part of it.
My muscles ripple in the moisture.
MATT: "Nothing to block the muscles,
no, not at all,
"but I have to say,
with a fine, smooth head,
"it does need a little decoration,
if you don't mind me saying."
TRAVIS: Oh. You think so?
MATT: "(chuckles) You!"
SAM: Something
in a yarmulke, perhaps?
MATT: "I was thinking--"
And she whips out what looks like
this fancy engraved leather cap
with two straps on the side
and just (shoomf) right over your head.
It kind of folds everything in,
the straps just go very long
and dangle there.
LAURA AND ASHLEY: (laugh)
MARISHA: Yes! Yes!
MATT: She takes them
and snaps them underneath
to where these two little danglies
are dangling from under the chin.
And it just has
these really intricate flower patterns
punched into the leather all around.
SAM: I love it, Grog.
I think you look great.
TRAVIS: (stutters)
SAM: We don't have a mirror here?
MATT: "I think it speaks
of the seasons."
TRAVIS: Is it over my ears?
MARISHA: Is it like one of those
old-school leather helmets?
MATT: It looks almost
like the old football helmets.
MARISHA: Oh, football!
Yeah. Okay! Cool.
TRAVIS: I mean, I don't know,
does it do anything?
MATT: "It looks masculine.
You wouldn't believe.
"Here, let me show you!"
And she brings up a small mirror.
TRAVIS: (screams)
(everyone else laughs)
MATT: "Exactly.
"Men will fear you
walking down the road."
TRAVIS: No, please, more like--
a bit more like war,
death, battlefield.
More aggressive.
This is a bit more like sheep-herder.
TRAVIS: Here you go.
MATT: "Well, all right."
MATT: "Death. Battle. Aggressive."
SAM: Maybe something with spikes?
MATT: "Spikes. Spikes...
let me see what I can do."
MARISHA, LAURA, AND ASHLEY: (laugh)
MATT: And she runs off down the way,
gets into a bag
and you start hearing things going
(tink, thud) something rolls over--
"Ah, shit!"
Eventually she comes out.
"This is less of a hat
and more of a half-helmet,
"but maybe it'll do."
And she pulls forth
what looks like
this very wide metal brim,
almost in a swish shape
to a point in the front.
TRAVIS: (laughing) Conquistador's helmet?
MATT: Yeah, it kind of looks
like a conquistador's helmet.
But it's only the front,
so it's almost like
a rhinoceros horn
that sticks up to a point.
MARISHA: Yes.
LAURA: Oh my god.
MATT: And the rest buckles
to the back of the head,
so it's a giant metallic groove
for the front.
TRAVIS: I'll take it.
I don't even care if it fits.
LIAM AND MARISHA: (laugh)
MATT: "Oh, that's what I like to hear."
TRAVIS: How much is it?
MATT: "This will be 50 gold."
LAURA: (gasps)
TRAVIS: Is the point very sharp?
MATT: "Try it yourself."
TRAVIS: And I reach up
and I... hit it with my finger.
MATT: It's all right.
It can be sharpened.
It's more for decor.
It's not meant
to slice somebody in half.
TRAVIS: Yeah, it could be sharpened?
MATT: "Well, I mean, what are you
intending to do with this hat? (titters)"
TRAVIS: Nothing, just look sharp.
(groaning)
MATT: "I can do that for you,
my big muscley man."
LIAM: That is the very ceiling
of intelligence of his.
MARISHA: Yeah. (laughs)
TRAVIS: Oh, see that sweet jam
I just dropped there.
SAM: I did, that was a good line.
TRAVIS: Write that in a notebook somewhere.
TALIESIN: We'll be cleaning that
off the floor for ages.
MATT: So after about five minutes or so,
she grinds down
with what materials she has
to a little more--
it does mess with some of the polish
on the very tip of the metal,
but it does come to a more solid point.
"Be careful with that."
TRAVIS: So is it one piece
or is there a strap on the back
or it just goes (foonk)?
MATT: It goes on and then straps tight
in the back to fit your head.
TRAVIS: Beautiful.
LAURA: It's basically like a unicorn?
MATT: Kind of.
TRAVIS: Rhino.
MATT: It's like a big old rhino horn
that curls upward to a point there.
LIAM: Wow. Wow.
MATT: It looks a little ridiculous.
MARISHA: I'm so excited for the art!
TRAVIS: What do you think? Hold on.
What do you think?
SAM: Wow.
I mean, your silhouette
is magnificent. Imposing.
LIAM: Is this
your variant fighting costume?
ASHLEY: Oh, boy.
TRAVIS: Am I fearsome?
SAM: You are. You are.
We should go
to a silhouette artist after this
and get something drawn for this.
TRAVIS: They have those?
SAM: They do, they cut it out.
TRAVIS: Milady, you are
a master of your trade.
ASHLEY: Oh, boy.
MATT: "Well. So they tell me."
SAM: Our mom only gave us
60 gold to spend.
Could you give us both hats for 60?
We're brothers.
(laughter)
SAM: Something
went wrong with him at birth.
MATT: Make a deception check
with disadvantage.
SAM: With disadvantage?!
MATT: Yes.
LIAM: Doesn't matter.
SAM: Well, would a 1 be bad?
(laughter)
MATT: Deidre goes,
"(laughs) You silly, tiny man--
"No, seriously. We have a price
agreed upon. Pay it."
TRAVIS: Yeah, no, I got it.
I got 50 gold of my own.
SAM: All right. 20 from me,
50 from him. We'll take them both.
MATT: "Ooh, all up front? All right.
It'll be ready for you shortly."
She takes the coin.
"Thank you for the patronage.
"Return here in about...
ooh, an hour,
"and the hat
shall be prepared for you, sir--
"what's your name?"
SAM: My name's Scanlan Shorthalt.
MATT: "Scanlan Shorthalt.
All right, come soon."
SAM: See you soon.
TRAVIS: Can I hit my head
on the doorway on the way out?
MATT: (shoomp)
LAURA AND MARISHA: (laugh)
MATT: (creak) You have to
kind of pull it out.
Yeah. You leave a nice big groove.
TRAVIS: It is nice, right?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Okay, good.
MATT: (laughs) All right,
eventually you all gather again
back at the hall of the Slayer's Take.
You guys have just settled in
and are free to continue
any discussion you like
as you see Scanlan and Grog come in.
Say, you've since retrieved your hat
with your various
wonderfully-crafted accoutrements.
TRAVIS: 'Sup, bitches.
LAURA: Wow.
SAM: Look at that.
ASHLEY: Whoa.
TRAVIS: What happened?
SAM: Look at that.
ASHLEY: (gasps) Ohh...
TRAVIS: I know, right? Wait for it.
LIAM: (laughs)
LAURA: Whoa. Grog, you're so monstrous.
ASHLEY: What? Grog, that is so scary.
MARISHA: That's like
another 12 inches to you.
TRAVIS: I know.
MARISHA: You look so tall.
TRAVIS: It, like, changes
my whole battle strategy.
I'm now literally
the point of the spear.
ASHLEY: (gasps) You're so scary.
TALIESIN: How have we lived with this idiot?
TRAVIS: (laughs) I'm a sea monster!
ASHLEY: (roars)
TRAVIS: I'm like
the most wicked narwhal of all time!
Give me a pool! (laughs)
ASHLEY: Can I try it on?
TRAVIS: Yeah, you want to?
TRAVIS: (laughing)
I put it on Pike's head.
ASHLEY: Whoa, it's so heavy.
(all but Taliesin laugh)
TALIESIN: What is the world coming to?
TRAVIS: Is it as tall as she is?
MATT: You can see
the bottom of her mouth.
ASHLEY: Oh, Grog.
TRAVIS: Oh, yeah, look.
Wait, turn around 180 degrees
and then run as fast as you can.
MARISHA: Oh, yeah, go!
Go! Go! Go, Pike! Go, go!
LAURA: (clapping) Go, Pike!
Go, Pike! Go, Pike!
MATT: Okay, make a perception check.
TALIESIN: (groans)
EVERYONE ELSE: (laughs)
ASHLEY: 9.
MATT: 9. You go running
straight out of the door--
LAURA: No!
MATT: You guys are like,
"Oh. No, Pike!"
She's already out the door,
over the stairs
(repeated thuds),
outside of the hall.
(sounds of dismay)
TRAVIS and LAURA: Oh no!
ASHLEY: I'm okay!
MATT: You guys rush out to go catch her
and the helmet is actually
embedded partway into the ground
and she's kind of--
MARISHA: Yeah!
MATT: And she's just laughing.
ASHLEY: (laughing) Grog,
get me out of this helmet.
TRAVIS: I pick her up by the feet.
TRAVIS: That was excellent. (giggles)
ASHLEY: As he's holding me up like that
I try to stab him with it.
TRAVIS: I yank it off of her head
and put her back on the ground.
LIAM: Vax has been
laughing hysterically,
giggle fits,
clutching his ribs the entire time.
And then is there
any of the staff here?
Anyone that's here? Anyone else?
MATT: You haven't seen Mertin.
Vanessa doesn't seem to have left.
LIAM: What about underlings?
MATT: I mean, there are
a few individuals here
that are part of the guildhall.
The hierarchy here
is more like the few that run it,
and then everyone else
comes and goes as they please.
LIAM: Yeah, yeah, come here, you.
Do you have a tub?
Do you have a bath? Look at me.
Do you have a bath? I need a bath.
MATT: "You look pretty rough."
LIAM: Yeah?
MATT: "Yeah. We could--
"we got a washroom in the back,
if you need it."
LIAM: Is it hot?
I feel like I need it to be hot.
MATT: "You get what you get.
It's water, buddy."
LIAM: Okay.
That's perfect, thank you.
Grog, put that hat on again.
TRAVIS: Oh, yeah, hold on. (foomp)
LIAM: (laughs hysterically)
LIAM: All the way down the hall
to take a bath.
SAM: It's crazy. Did you guys
get him drunk or something?
TALIESIN: I don't know
what you people did, but...
ASHLEY: Well, he just...
TRAVIS: People respond to fear differently.
SAM: I guess so.
LAURA: He's gone insane.
MARISHA: He might have saw
the face of a god.
SAM: Whatever.
TRAVIS: He did?
MARISHA: Yeah.
ASHLEY: Yeah. The head of--
TRAVIS: By the way,
why is he covered in bloodbath?
ASHLEY: I think that was part of the--
MARISHA: Ritual? Communion?
ASHLEY: Getting to know his new god.
TRAVIS: Did he kill a lot of people?
ASHLEY: Maybe he had to. I don't know.
TRAVIS: He did?
LAURA: So many, Grog.
TRAVIS: Oh my god.
LAURA: Yeah. It was a giant battle.
TRAVIS: Like, how many on two hands?
LAURA: Like at least this many.
TRAVIS: That's a legendary amount.
LAURA: That's more than six.
LAURA: I know.
ASHLEY: Yeah.
LIAM: Somewhere deep in the building,
far away:
LIAM: This is not hot!
MATT: The gruff individual chuckles.
"Heh. It never is."
I need you to make a tinkering check.
TALIESIN: Okay.
I'm sitting with my tea and my tools,
trying to ignore these people.
LAURA: Can I heat water up
in the fireplace?
MATT: Yeah, yeah,
it'll take you a little while.
TALIESIN: Please don't explode.
SAM: When I delivered
the materials to him--
TALIESIN: Oh, Jesus H. Fucking Christ.
MARISHA: Oh no, Taliesin...
SAM: Could I have inspired him at all,
when I delivered the materials?
TALIESIN: Please.
MATT: Sure.
SAM: All right.
MARISHA: Please inspire.
SAM: I will inspire--
oh my god, it's not even worth it.
TALIESIN: (muffled) Please inspire.
Do it. Do it, you bloody gnome!
SAM: Okay.
So when I delivered everything,
I just sang him a little song
to inspire him. And I sang,
SAM: (singing)
Percy's gun, won't you come
and kill up all the dragons?
(others join in) Percy's gun,
won't you come, won't you come?
ASHLEY AND LIAM: Percy's gun!
(laughter)
MATT: Oh my god.
All right, take your d10.
LAURA: Ten! Ten! Ten!
LIAM: Do it! Do it!
MARISHA: Oh my god, it's a 10!
TALIESIN: Better!
SAM: That was a 10.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
MARISHA: I get excited. Sorry.
LIAM: Pretty good song.
TALIESIN: Proficiency,
tinkering, plus the--
MATT: Well, your proficiency
is what you get with the roll
and then it's your dex bonus.
TALIESIN: Okay, so proficiency,
dex, okay, thank you, god.
TALIESIN: (muttering) That's 11...
LIAM: (hums Black Hole Sun)
TALIESIN: 23.
MATT: 23. What did you roll naturally?
SAM: A 2.
TALIESIN: 2.
LIAM: (laughs)
LAURA: Whoa.
SAM: Plus 10.
MATT: Ah.
TALIESIN AND MARISHA: Plus 10.
TALIESIN: Made it 12.
MATT: Wow. All righty.
TALIESIN: It's not complicated,
but I've got a good design,
and it has two nifty things.
MATT: What are the nifty things?
SAM: Fingers.
TALIESIN: It doesn't actually
have fingers.
It's a mitt piece, strap-on,
it can lock the thumb
and lock the hand
so you can open it, lock,
close it, lock.
It's got little flip-locks.
MATT: Mm-hm.
TALIESIN: You can detach the hand
and put a pick spike on
for mining. Like a mining punch.
LIAM: Is it like Young Frankenstein?
(mechanical sound effects)
TALIESIN: It's more Dustin Hoffman "Hook",
but, you know.
MARISHA: Oh, sure.
LAURA: Oh, that's nice.
MARISHA: I was thinking
Go-Go-Gadget Finger.
TALIESIN: Because it's got
the click, pull, click.
MATT: Right.
TALIESIN: I can do it
with all these things.
I can graph it. So.
MATT: (laughs)
TALIESIN: Reasonable.
It's not pretty.
MATT: It takes you a few hours
and gets you into
the early parts of the evening,
but you do manage
to go ahead and complete it.
You manage to get it finished up
and you're pretty proud of your work,
actually, and you feel--
the whistle you're still doing
as you do the final bits,
you realize is the song
that Scanlan sang for you,
just looping in your head.
It happened to push you
through your work
and get your final piece completed.
TALIESIN: I also carved
a little message inside
that will not matter
unless it actually becomes pertinent.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: You don't get to know
until you ask offscreen.
SAM: You don't know.
LAURA: (laughs) Ohhh.
MATT: Okay. I'm excited. Okay.
MARISHA: That's right, DM.
TRAVIS: That never happens.
MATT: (laughs) Try me. Okay.
Do you go and deliver it?
TALIESIN: I do go and deliver it.
MATT: Okay.
As the sun begins to set in Vasselheim,
you make your way back over
to the Braving Grounds,
which as you look across, too,
as the night goes dark,
the Braving Grounds itself
has a whole different life to it.
There are so many forges
and smelters going that there's--
most buildings have
this bright orange glow
through the ceiling
and these various openings
where fumes and smoke and exhaust
are sent up
from the various
production constructs and such.
It has this very luminescent look
in comparison to a lot of the city.
It's very interesting.
It reminds you of the deep,
deep portions of Kraghammer,
where most of
the actual fire and melted rock
was being smelted
and gathered and heated.
So you make your way to the hovel.
The roof workers are no longer there,
and the door is closed.
TALIESIN: (knocks) Victor?
I've got your hand.
MATT: "(muffled) I'm sleeping."
TALIESIN: Do you want your hand?
MATT: "(muffled) You want me to sleep?"
TALIESIN: I don't see why
they're mutually exclusive.
MARISHA: (laughs)
MATT: You hear (scraping sound)
a bunch of different locks fiddling.
(series of clicks) (fwoosh)
And the door opens
and you see Victor,
clean-faced for the first time
you've really seen him before,
and he has a nightcap
which sort of (foomf)
in front of his face,
with a little puffball at the end.
He's like,
"I told you.
I was trying-- oh! Hey.
"(hesitantly) Percival?"
TALIESIN: Yes, that's quite good.
I love your hat.
MATT: "Thank you.
It's comfy to sleep in."
TALIESIN: It looks it.
MATT: "Did you bring my hand?"
TALIESIN: I did. I grabbed your hand
and I will show you.
It is very special.
MATT: "Come in! Come in! (grunts)"
And opens the door.
You see he's wearing
this long nightgown
that is covered in patches
and tears in it.
Most of it
has been turned black through soot,
but the cap is perfect.
Perfect condition.
TALIESIN: I have a special
set of pajamas myself, so I understand.
MATT: "They are comfortable."
As he walks in,
still bandaged on the arm,
you can see there's
a small kettle of tea
set by the small fireplace right there.
It's a tiny little table
and a tiny little stool
that he's just kind of
sitting on right there.
And he goes
and he reaches over for the kettle.
"(groans)"
Tries to pick up the cup
and just pours the tea into it.
TALIESIN: (alarmed stuttering)
TALIESIN: I'm going to stop
and attach and begin strapping this.
MATT: "(confused stuttering)"
TALIESIN: Let me show you.
It attaches like this.
MATT: "Ooh."
TALIESIN: Here are the two switches.
(clicking)
And for your mine.
MATT: "Eh? Oh."
TALIESIN: I grab,
hit the button, twist, pull.
MATT: "Oh? Eh? I just got that!"
TALIESIN: And I get the spike
and attach it.
MATT: "Oh."
TALIESIN: Remove it,
put the hand back on.
Tea?
MATT: (chuckle, click)
(excited laughter) "Tea?"
TALIESIN: Sure. Why not?
Always say yes.
MARISHA: (laughs)
MATT: "Need another cup. (grunts)"
He stands up and goes over,
still holding the kettle
and splashing everywhere,
and he's flipping through cabinets
and knocking pieces of glass out.
"Ah! Found it."
Pulls out another little ceramic cup
and pours the tea in,
sets it down. (chink, click)
"(cackles)"
SAM: (laughs)
MATT: "To new hands!"
TALIESIN: To new hands.
SAM: That's a great toast.
MATT: It is pungent. It is bitter.
MATT: It has been steeped way too long.
ASHLEY: Gunpowder tea.
MATT: But it definitely
cleans out the sinuses.
And there is a hint of gunpowder
to the flavoring.
You get the sense
that pretty much everything in this room
is marinated in some way,
shape, or form
to be flammable.
TALIESIN: (hoarsely) Victor.
(laughter)
MATT: "It can put hair on your balls."
TALIESIN: Ohhh, probably.
Has a woman been by
to buy black powder?
(coughs) Has a woman been by?
MATT: "Not in, uh, weeks, maybe."
TALIESIN: Weeks?
MATT: "Did you make her hand, too?"
TALIESIN: I did not.
Do you know where she goes?
MATT: "No. She paid well, though."
TALIESIN: Did she? What did she pay?
MATT: "Are you guys in a club now?
How many people want black powder?
"Tell me! Tell them!
Bring them more.
"I could use money."
(others laugh)
TALIESIN: How much black powder
did she buy, Victor?
MATT: "Uh... (mutters to himself)"
(click, click)
TALIESIN: Only counts to two.
I'm so sorry.
(laughter)
MATT: "Maybe... 12 hogsheads worth?"
ASHLEY: Whoa.
TRAVIS AND MARISHA: Oh, shit.
TALIESIN: Really?
And how often does she come by?
MATT: "She only come by once."
TALIESIN: Okay. (sighs)
Thank you. I'm so pleased.
I may stop by one last time
before I leave town,
just to say goodbye. Thank you.
MATT: "Please do! I have more tea.
"Many different flavors.
This is, I call, dark roast."
TALIESIN: It...
certainly scalded something.
Thank you. That was very lovely
and that was very charming
and I unfortunately have business in the--
MATT: "I want to try the other one
before you go."
TALIESIN: One more
and then I must go, thank you.
MATT: "(click, creak)
Come on, need this, too."
TALIESIN: Yes, of course.
MATT: "(creak, click) (cackles)"
TALIESIN: (uncertain laughter)
MATT: (thunk) He sticks it
into the wooden stool and the table.
Kind of breaks the wood
and snaps it.
"Oh. (cackles)"
TALIESIN: Remember
that it's attached to bone.
You can still break your arm,
so be gentle.
MATT: "Yes. Thank you!"
TALIESIN: Thank you. Good night!
Have a lovely evening.
MATT: "Good night!"
SAM: Aah.
TALIESIN: Good night.
Aah. Pleasure, as always.
Thank you.
MATT: "(slurps)"
TALIESIN: I leave
in a little bit of a panic.
MATT: You leave
and he's just sitting there
staring
at this long chisel point, going,
"(quiet cackling)"
SAM: His ring.
MARISHA: (laughs)
MATT: The door
slowly closes behind you.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
LIAM: A fighter is born.
MARISHA: Yes, yeah,
just give him an anime weapon.
TALIESIN: Yeah, okay.
We're sticking around for a day?
SAM: I assume so. I don't know.
We're going to spend the night,
at least.
TALIESIN: I'm going to take
a long walk before I come back
and I'm going to walk by
the Raven Queen temple
and just... peek inside.
MATT: Okay.
You make your way past the Quad Roads.
At this point at night
the whole clientele has shifted.
Most people coming here--
you hear laughter, you hear music.
The Quad Roads is the New Orleans
of the town, comparatively.
It's still nowhere near as rambunctious
as many places you've been,
but for what seems during the day
to be a rather dour
and serious business type city,
the Quad Roads
is where the celebration of humanity hits
when the evening hours hit.
So you come by
and there's some taverns
that are open.
You see, to a certain extent,
what even appears to be
an adult entertainment district.
LAURA: (laughs sarcastically)
MATT: You make your way beyond--
LIAM: (clears throat)
Ring-a-ding-ding.
MATT: It's the oldest profession.
You make your way all the way
to the outskirts of the Duskmeadow,
and there, amongst the
just barely peeking
through the cloudline starlight,
the looming dark structure
that is Raven's Crest.
TALIESIN: I'm just going to
gently open the door
and peek inside
and see if anybody's inside.
MATT: Okay. You go ahead
and push the door open. (creak)
Doesn't appear to be anybody there.
TALIESIN: I walk in just for a moment
and take a look around.
MATT: Okay. You walk in.
(clicking footsteps)
At this dark hour, looking around,
the obsidian-type walls
are translucent glass
on the other side,
though you can barely make out
through the material
the details of the outside world,
due to the lack of light
across the cityscape.
Especially here in Duskmeadow,
in which the magical lantern light
that illuminates the city streets
are relatively sparse
on this side of Vasselheim.
You take a few more steps in,
(clicking footsteps)
footsteps echoing across the long,
thin, dark material of the floors.
(creak, thud)
LAURA: (gasps)
MATT: Door closes behind you.
TRAVIS: (quietly) What would--
why would you do this?
LIAM: Said the T. rex.
TALIESIN: I'm going to
gently look around
and slowly back up
and see if I can see anyone.
TALIESIN: Hello? Hello?
MATT: (echoing) Hello...
hello... hello.
TALIESIN: What do I have to pay
to fix this?
MATT: (echoing) This...
this... this... this.
TALIESIN: I leave.
MATT: (thump-crash)
You hear the sound
of some sort of low,
distant hit and a rumble,
and you see a distant light appear
in a chamber just beyond the walkway,
just faint enough to illuminate
and give the presence
of some sort of life or movement
about a hundred or so feet ahead of you.
TALIESIN: I walk briskly towards it.
MATT: You enter the next chamber,
where you see the interior
of this structure
is ivory-white bone and glass,
with a blue hint,
very much resembling the interior
of a very naturally,
beautifully-carved ice cavern.
There is a stairway that ascends,
as well as other hallways
that lead out
from the central nerve center
of the lower floor
of the main structure.
As you walk into this central chamber,
you see, ever so faintly,
at the very top of the stairs,
a pair of feet (footsteps)
walk and disappear up the stairs.
TALIESIN: I'm going to
charge after them.
MATT: Okay. You go running
up the stairway. (thud thud)
You get to the top, and you can see
at the very top of the stairs
a dark wooden door
with a dark iron rim
and what appears to be
a large hanger or handle
or knocker bolted to it
and it (thud) just closes
as you come underneath
the top of the archway and up the stairs.
TALIESIN: I knock.
MATT: (doosh) Once?
TALIESIN: Three times.
MATT: (doosh doosh)
With each hit,
you can hear the reverberation
of the echo of the knock
through a much larger chamber beyond.
As soon as you release
the actual door knocker,
the door (thump-crash, creak)
just creaks open ever so slightly
into a very, very dark chamber.
You can see very, very little in here,
other than the basic outline
of what looks to be
a little bit of floor,
some sort of a smooth,
glassy surface
that refracts
just a little bit of light
that makes it through
what looks to be
some sort of broken-up
glass dome-type structure above you.
You can't make out much beyond that.
It's very dark in here.
TALIESIN: Hello? Please. (sighs)
Something terrible has happened.
I don't understand how these games work.
I need help to fix something.
Something terrible has happened!
You obviously
care little for this world.
I start to back out.
MATT: As you step out of the room,
you hear a whisper
come from beyond the chamber,
within the darkness. It says,
"Is it yourself
you wish to fix or something more?"
TALIESIN: I don't think I can be fixed.
There is something broken in the world.
MATT: "Then come. Let us talk."
TALIESIN: ...I don't understand
how these things work.
I'm so sorry.
Where do you wish me to go?
MATT: "Have faith."
TALIESIN: (disbelieving laugh)
MATT: "Step in. Join me."
TALIESIN: (sighs) ...I strip.
TRAVIS: (gasps)
TALIESIN: And put it aside.
SAM: Put "it" aside?
TALIESIN: Put my clothes
in the corner.
SAM: Oh.
You're gonna jump her, eh?
TALIESIN: You're filthy.
And I go into the pool.
MATT: All right.
As you step into the chamber,
freezing cold as your toes--
TALIESIN: We're cold people.
MATT: Your legs, your whole body
eventually finds itself
stepping into this thick,
freezing liquid.
You hear the whisper in your ears
just as your head
reaches the level of the blood,
that says,
"Come. Come to me with your questions."
Just as your head goes
beneath the surface.
TALIESIN: (sighs) We're doing this.
MATT: You're underneath
and in darkness,
feeling around the thick material,
kind of just
swishing your fingers around,
but amongst the liquid,
you still hear the whisper again
in your ear:
"Come. Bring your questions."
TALIESIN: And I swim down
until it's uncomfortable.
MATT: You swim downward
and you touch the bottom of the pool.
You reach a somewhat concave,
smooth floor to the pool.
TALIESIN: I'm going to
head to the surface.
I don't know what's...
MATT: You head to the surface.
There's no surface.
It just keeps going.
TALIESIN: (sighs)
I do not do well with this.
MATT: You do not.
You begin to panic.
TALIESIN: Yes, I do.
MATT: You begin to reach around
and try to swim up
and find the surface,
but it just keeps going.
The liquid's thick
and it's hard to pull through,
and you can't open your eyes,
and you can't see anything,
and the iron-like flavor
is starting to find its way
to the inside of your mouth
as it's seeping through your nose
and your ears.
You begin to panic even further
as the cold is starting to take
and you feel your muscles
beginning to shake and seize
from the onset of hypothermia.
You begin to head
to the bottom of the pool again,
and this time,
you crack your head on the bottom
in the middle of your stupor,
and you reach up and scream in pain.
As you do, the blood fills your lungs
and you begin to feel yourself drown.
You begin to shake and convulse
as you begin to try to find a way
to force it out of your body
and you can't.
And at that moment,
where all of a sudden
you realize that this is it.
This is the end.
This is how the tale of Percival
comes to an end.
The sensation goes warm again.
And it's like all that cold energy
goes away,
and you're now swimming in water,
then air,
and the pain subsides,
and you're breathing normally.
But you still stand in darkness,
and you hear these distant footsteps.
(clicking footsteps) Sourceless.
No light, just shadow.
And you look around
over your shoulder
and then right behind you,
you see immediately
a white porcelain face,
the head is just standing there
amongst the shadow.
TALIESIN: (takes deep breaths)
Do you know what I've done?
MATT: "I've watched."
TALIESIN: I have questions.
MATT: "Then ask them."
TALIESIN: First is, can we stop it?
Can we stop what's been released?
Is there something I can do?
MATT: "Many things
are released in this world.
"Many terrible, many wonderful.
Many things.
"Ask the right questions."
TALIESIN: Did it choose me
because I was broken,
or did it break me?
MATT: The mask, which has not shown
any expression at this point,
pulls back a little bit from you
and almost seems to grow in size.
It's strange;
the proportion seems to stay the same,
but suddenly your vision shifts
and you realize, no,
it's farther away from you
and is just suddenly immense,
like your visual focus just changes
and your whole perspective
suddenly causes you
to lose sense of scale and balance.
The voice comes in,
this time louder:
"You were always broken, Percival.
"And you were preyed upon,
just as it preys upon others,
"and will continue to do so
until finally destroyed."
TALIESIN: Can it be fixed?
MATT: "Perhaps.
"Your deeds will guide your path
to salvation or damnation.
"The choice is yours.
You skirt that line still."
TALIESIN: But the first deed is so...
there's so much,
and I don't think any of them see it.
I want it to die
before anybody sees it.
Can you help?
MATT: "I've already helped, Percival.
"Do not think the path
that you and your allies walk
"goes unseen.
"There are many of those in this world
that represent the will of us,
"just as there are those
who represent the will
"of those that combat us
and always have.
"There are a great many deeds
ahead of you.
"It's your choice to take them.
"Just know:
should you not watch yourself,
"you may not find yourself
on our side."
TALIESIN: I know.
There is nowhere
I can look for healing?
Other than deeds?
I like to fix things.
MATT: "All life is inherently
broken from the start, Percival.
"Take solace in that.
"There is no perfection in life.
"Otherwise, what would be
the purpose of death?
"It's to try to find ways
to better yourself before the end
"that gives us purpose.
"You are all broken,
but also understand,"
At this point, her voice
gets very deep and very resonant.
"Mortals can achieve great things.
"I did."
And the mask pulls back
into the shadows
and suddenly (gasp, cough)
you begin coughing,
finding your way to the surface,
pouring blood out of your mouth
and coughing
and eventually you find your way over,
breathing heavily,
to the side of the pool and (grunt)
pull yourself onto the side.
(cough) Cough the rest of it up.
A little bit of moonlight peeks through,
and you can see
the beams refracting through
the purples and reds and blues
and just hints of specks of light
that just shimmer
across the surface
of this dark,
glass-like floor.
TALIESIN: I'm going to take my sword
and I'm going to very carefully
scrape my body clean of the blood,
as much as I can,
and I'm going to take
the back of my shirt
and clean my hair off
as much as I can.
I'm going to take
a vial of the blood in the pool.
One tiny bit.
MATT: You do so.
TALIESIN: I'm going to
put my clothes back on...
and I'm going to cast Hex on myself
for my walk home
and banish it
before I come in the door.
MATT: Okay. All righty.
So, as Percival finally wanders in,
is there anything else
anyone wants to achieve
before the evening's done?
SAM: I'd like to go to the Raven Queen.
(laughter)
SAM: No.
LIAM: Are we next morning,
or we're still evening,
at this point?
MATT: We're still evening
at the moment,
if there's anything else
you wish to achieve. Otherwise--
LAURA: I've been slowly heating water
and giving it to Vax
to put in his bath.
MATT: You do manage
to draw a comfortable bath
for your brother and wash him clean.
LAURA: I don't wash him!
I just give him the fucking water.
MATT: You aid him in washing
himself clean. So you specify.
LIAM: Thanks, man.
TRAVIS: Do we see Percy
when he comes in?
MATT: It's going to be late.
TALIESIN: I'm going to walk quiet and late
and go tinker
on a little thing for a minute
until I pass out.
MATT: Okay.
You do notice Percy enter.
Looks a little frazzled,
but doesn't seem to--
LAURA: Do I see any of the blood?
Passive perception?
LIAM: You're in
the tubby town, though.
MATT: Make a perception check.
I want you to make
a dexterity check.
MARISHA AND TALIESIN: (groan)
LIAM: Sorry, Taliesin.
SAM: You've got him.
LIAM: Rolled high.
LAURA: 32.
TALIESIN: 32?!
Oh my god, what the--
I couldn't have rolled that.
Like, that would've been
a natural 20,
would have been
the only way around that.
MATT: You see, just faintly
behind one of his ears
and at the edge of his collar
on his coat,
just a bit of familiar crimson,
and a look of...
a distant stare that is familiar.
MATT: All right.
Do you all wish to rest
for the evening?
SAM: No, I would like
to take 12 hours to read my book.
MATT: Okay, so the first 12 hours
are completed,
but you do not sleep?
SAM: No.
LIAM: It's a page-turner.
SAM: Lots of centerfolds.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Don't be stingy,
share those with me.
MATT: Written by John Cleese.
It's a wonderful piece.
LAURA: I also spend
a lot of time that night reading,
but I'm reading
the book about the Raven Queen.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Pretty much
have it memorized at this point.
MATT: Yeah, fair enough. All right.
You guys all find yourself to rest,
except for Scanlan,
who takes
a point of exhaustion
for going through the night
without sleep.
SAM: I don't know what that is,
but someone will tell me.
TRAVIS: You'll find out.
MATT: Yeah. Basically,
it means any ability checks,
any skill checks
until you get a full night's rest
are at disadvantage, yeah.
All right, as you find yourselves to rest,
most of you
the morning light comes,
greeting you to a new day,
and we're going to go ahead
and take a break.
We'll be back here
in a few minutes, guys.
Reminder, once again:
Loot Crate, our awesome sponsor,
check them out at
lootcrate.com/criticalrole,
enter criticalrole-- one word--
to get $3 off a subscription.
We'll be back here in a minute, guys.
MARISHA: And get your Joe Mad poster!
MATT: Joe Mad poster!
MARISHA: Right now, pre-order.
SAM: Wait, there's a giveaway
at the break, I think.
LAURA: Oh, there's
a Loot Crate giveaway.
MARISHA: Oh, and giveaway!
MATT: For the DX boxes,
so be active in the chat.
LIAM: And please go check out
the Joe Mad poster.
LAURA: It's so sick.
LIAM: Also check out
Battle Chasers Night War.
It's a beautiful-looking game.
I played it today.
LAURA: Also, give your friend a hug.
Love each other.
MARISHA: (laughs) Yeah, and a high-five.
SAM: Bathe in blood.
We'll see you soon.
[Critical Role resumes at 2:22:43]
MATT: Welcome back, guys.
So, as we return to the game,
the morning comes to you all
in Vasselheim
as you awake
in the Slayer's Take guildhall.
A brisk morning, but not too cold.
The clouds are actually
a little more separate this morning.
You get brief moments of blue;
it looks like the weather
is a little clearer
than you're used to seeing
in this vicinity.
But the day is yours.
What do you guys wish to do?
LIAM: What do we need
to accomplish here in town?
Is there anything
we need to finish,
or do we want
to pick our next destination?
SAM: Do they sell
potions and things here in town--
SAM: No, they don't.
TALIESIN: No, very specifically they don't.
SAM: Then let's
get the hell out of here.
There's nothing for us here.
TRAVIS: What about the Feywild?
SAM: Oh, yeah.
MARISHA: We did talk
about the Feywild.
TALIESIN: Let's drop off our--
LAURA: Don't tease me about the Feywild.
TRAVIS: Wait, don't you have
to pick up something?
TALIESIN: Oh, I already picked it up.
TRAVIS: Not you, you.
SAM: Me?
TALIESIN: Oh, you have a hat.
SAM: I thought we waited for the hat.
MATT: Yeah, he picked up the hat.
TRAVIS: Oh, shit, balls, ass.
All right.
SAM: There's the Feywild.
There's dropping stuff off
at Whitestone.
There's Marquet,
which something is there in Marquet?
LAURA: Is one of the Vestiges there?
SAM: I don't know,
everyone just keeps talking about it.
TRAVIS: Really?
SAM: Wait, weren't we
going to go to--
MARISHA: One of the Vestiges
is in Marquet.
LAURA: Which one?
MARISHA: Hang on. Cabal's Ruin,
which is a magic-devouring cloak--
TRAVIS: Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Are we alone in this room?
MATT: You guys are right now
having breakfast in the guildhall.
There's maybe two
other individuals in the room.
One of them is
drunkenly asleep and snoring.
The other appears to be
going about their business.
TRAVIS: I'm just saying.
MARISHA: (whispering)
Okay, I'll speak quietly.
There's apparently
a magic-devouring cloak
who is being worn by the--
it's in Ank'Harel.
It's being worn by...
LAURA: It's a cloak
that devours magic?
MARISHA: A merchant warrior
with a missing eye.
SAM: And there's one
in the bottom of the sea somewhere.
LAURA: And there's a really beautiful
strong bow in the Feywild.
TRAVIS: Yeah, let's go to the Feywild!
We at least know that place.
TALIESIN: I say we drop everything--
we take a pit stop in Whitestone
and head towards the Feywild.
MARISHA: So, technically,
we don't even have
to head towards the Feywild.
Do you guys remember
how I kind of did that thing
with Grog's evil sword
and kind of
banished it away for forever?
TRAVIS: Are we bringing it back?
MARISHA: No.
LAURA: Yeah, to the Dread Emperor's.
MARISHA: Right.
LIAM: Not a good idea, Grog.
MARISHA: No, we're not
bringing it back.
I can do that with the rest of us.
LAURA: You can banish us
to the Dread Emperor's island?
MARISHA: No, it's not like
a banishment.
I can Plane Shift us
wherever we want to go,
to an alternate plane.
LAURA: To the Feywild?
So we don't even
have to find an entrance?
MARISHA: Yeah, we just hold hands
and think about it really hard.
TRAVIS: No way.
MARISHA: Yeah.
It's druid magic. It's great.
LIAM: And you put us
in a safe spot
somewhere in there, somehow?
MARISHA: I can take us
to where we've been before,
to where it's familiar.
LIAM: Have we been there before?
I don't know.
MARISHA: Very briefly.
TALIESIN: Yes.
LAURA: Is it somewhere
that you have to have been,
or can it be somewhere
that we have been.
MARISHA: It is somewhere
I am familiar with, I believe,
through means that I am familiar...
LAURA: Syngorn is in the Feywild.
SAM: Normally?
LIAM: No, not normally.
LAURA: They transferred
the entire city there.
LIAM: I know, but you're saying
we've been there,
but they just did that recently.
SAM: Grog's been to the Feywild.
MATT: You can specify a target
MARISHA: In general terms.
MATT: In general terms.
MARISHA: Such as "City of Brass
on the Elemental Plane of Fire."
SAM: Oh, is that
where we're going?
MARISHA: No.
SAM: Oh. Sounds like fun.
TALIESIN: It does, actually.
MARISHA: If you guys want to go
to the Plane of Fire,
that's like,
a hike and a jump through a hole.
TALIESIN: Ah.
TRAVIS: No, no, not the Plane of Fire.
Just the Feywild.
MARISHA: All right.
Yeah, I can get us there.
SAM: To the Feywild.
How big is the Feywild?
Is it like a football field?
MARISHA: It's very big.
LAURA: It's a whole other plane.
SAM: Well, how do--
do we know where we're going
in the Feywild?
MARISHA: I imagine we'll figure it out
once we get there.
TALIESIN: Do I know anything
about the Feywild?
MATT: You have
no knowledge of the Feywild.
ASHLEY: Would I know anything else?
MARISHA: What about me?
LAURA: Would we have learned
something about it in Syngorn?
MATT: You have
a general idea of it, somewhat--
MARISHA: Team Half-Elf, yeah.
MATT: Somewhat,
just through your learning.
You never actually visited there.
The Feywild is a near plane,
a plane that overlaps
this Prime Material Plane.
It's a version
of the world you live in right now
that is shifted and changed
in a place where time,
distance is relative and shifts.
Nature grows rampant and in cases
is hard to really expect its direction.
Things and entities exist there
that prefer to trick and lose wanderers.
It's a very strange place
where some believe
elves initially come from
or craft from there, at least.
LIAM: Do the two of us know enough
that were you to jump
from the same place here,
would you necessarily end up
in the same spot in the Feywild?
MATT: You have no idea.
LIAM: We don't know. All right.
MATT: You don't know anything
about the transition to the Feywild.
You just know that certain doors open
at certain times,
especially with full moons
in certain locations,
the classic toadstool rings,
areas where the moonlight
in the realms
can be a little thinner
and the barrier doors do open,
and those are where creatures
can transition out or through.
You do know it's a place of fey magic,
it's tricky, it's difficult to follow.
SAM: Terrible.
LAURA: It sounds awful.
MATT: Very, like, Oberon and Titania.
Weird. Interesting.
MARISHA: Question.
MATT: Yes?
MARISHA: Hmm, okay.
SAM: Good question.
MARISHA: It says
the Wrath of the Fey Warden
is what we're looking for, the bow,
and that it now acts
as the heart of a cancerous tree,
corrupting the verdant land.
Is there something I can do,
maybe try and...
TRAVIS: Hold on, is our stream up?
Are we offline right now?
LUCAS: (muffled, from offscreen)
I'm checking. Just wait.
ASHLEY: Hold, please.
LUCAS: It says we're still online.
Hang on.
LIAM: Loot Crate. Check out Loot Crate.
SAM: No one can see it.
LAURA: No, it says it's offline.
LIAM: Refresh it.
MARISHA: It says offline?
LIAM: Quit the program
and go back in.
TRAVIS: The chat is saying it's off.
LUCAS: No, we're still online.
LAURA: Okay.
LIAM: Tell them to quit and re-login.
SAM: It's back. It's back.
LUCAS: I'm not sure what happened.
I'm not sure it even
dropped frames on my end.
LIAM: Whoa, we were
in the Feywild for a second there.
ASHLEY: Oh, it was crazy.
MATT: You guys missed six episodes.
(exaggerated sounds of relief)
MATT: Everything turned out okay.
LAURA: Yay! And we got the warden thing.
LIAM: Dragons are dead.
MARISHA: Guys, I'm so glad
we won DND. We beat it.
LAURA: Yeah, that was the best.
TALIESIN: Roll the credits scroll.
MARISHA: Can I maybe sense a sick tree?
You know what?
Let's go to Whitestone.
Let's go to Whitestone
and drop some stuff off.
LAURA: You know,
because the more I think about it,
I mean, we almost just
died many times
and the last time we tried
to get a Vestige
it almost killed us,
and maybe we just need
a little bit
more preparation, maybe?
TALIESIN: Let's empty our bags,
let's prepare ourselves.
There are certainly stories
in the woods of Whitestone
of strange happenings,
so I'm sure
there's probably some connection
to the Feywild,
and we'll see what happens.
LAURA: Make sure Whitestone
is actually
preparing something underground
just like Westruun.
TALIESIN: Well, we have something.
MARISHA: Yes, they have
something underground already.
LAURA: Exactly, but there's
a spinning orb of death there.
TALIESIN: Which, to be fair,
is probably going
to keep a dragon away.
LIAM: But I also think
we've earned more
than a single day of rest.
TALIESIN: Yes.
LIAM: Let's go to Whitestone.
TALIESIN: Let's go to Whitestone.
MARISHA: All right.
ASHLEY: Where's the sea?
SAM: The Ozmit Sea?
ASHLEY: Yeah.
MATT: The Ozmit Sea is
to the east of you, east-southeast,
and that is a wide gulf that separates--
from your perspective, looking at me,
there's Othanzia, Ozmit Sea,
and there's Tal'Dorei right here.
LAURA: Oh, okay.
LIAM: (sneezes)
TALIESIN AND MARISHA: Bless you.
LAURA: Bless you.
MARISHA: The Water Ashari
live in the Ozmit Sea.
LAURA: Are they like mermaids?
MARISHA: No, I think they've got an island.
ASHLEY: It's also the sea that I sailed.
MARISHA: Really?
LAURA: (gasps)
SAM: Ohhh.
TALIESIN: Really?
LAURA: In your roving pirate days.
ASHLEY: I know it well.
MARISHA: How familiar are you
with the sea?
ASHLEY: I'm pretty familiar with it.
TRAVIS: What if we go there?
SAM: We could.
LAURA: Wait, could I see
the list of Vestiges?
SAM: The one in the bottom of the sea
is called Whisper, right?
LAURA: Whisper?
MARISHA: A blade forged from metal
pulled from the Far Realm,
it was the center of many dark rituals.
SAM: It now lies
at the bottom of the Ozmit Sea,
sunken with the lost ship,
The Shrew.
LAURA: (sing-song) The Shrew?
ASHLEY: (deep voice) The Shrew.
SAM: A storm three hundred years ago
near an island of glass.
Anyone know about the island of glass?
LAURA: Have you heard
about an island of glass?
MARISHA: Have I heard
Have Pike or I heard
of an island of glass?
MATT: I'll have both of you guys
make history checks.
MARISHA: All right.
I rolled a natural 1.
MATT: You barely know
what glass is right now.
MARISHA: Guys, water isn't glass,
that's stupid.
TALIESIN: I would have
a theory as to what it was.
TRAVIS: She rolled a 20.
MARISHA: You rolled a 20? Oh, go Pike!
ASHLEY: Not a natural 20. Total.
MATT: Explain.
TALIESIN: Should I roll to figure out
that this is probably an active volcano?
MATT: Make an intelligence check.
TALIESIN: I'm down.
LIAM: Come on, man.
TALIESIN: No! Wow.
SAM: Onesies.
MARISHA: Team ones. Whoo.
MATT: Natural 1?
TALIESIN: Natural 1.
LIAM: Snitch.
MATT: Doesn't quite come to you,
but what it could be.
The idea of a volcano
possibly comes to mind, but--
TALIESIN: I'm distracted.
MATT: Yeah.
You have not been there,
you haven't seen it,
but some of your crewmates
while you were traveling
aboard your ship
for that five, six-month period,
a couple of them did mention something
about on the sea,
a mirage-like island
that glistens in the distance,
but they said to avoid it,
said it was dangerous.
SAM: Did they say where it was?
MATT: No.
SAM: Damn it.
ASHLEY: Heard many tales of The Shrew.
LAURA: Yeah?
ASHLEY: Yeah, the ship lost at sea.
MATT: You know of The Shrew,
you definitely know of The Shrew.
ASHLEY: All sailors know of The Shrew.
MARISHA: What's the story of The Shrew?
SAM: Come on, sailor.
ASHLEY: There was a storm
three hundred years ago.
LAURA: Near an island of glass?
ASHLEY: Near an island of glass.
MARISHA: It was really bad.
ASHLEY: And The Shrew
just didn't sail on.
SAM: It was tamed.
ASHLEY: It was tamed.
LAURA: (laughs) I was waiting for it to--
MATT: Come around again?
Yeah, it was good.
LAURA: Come around, yep.
TALIESIN: Taming of the Shrew fits, yeah.
ASHLEY: Good tale,
but we'll get there one day.
MATT: What's the plan?
LIAM: Whitestone.
SAM: Yes, Whitestone.
TRAVIS: Can I make
one other suggestion?
Emon...
go take Thordak right now.
SAM: Good call...
TRAVIS: Yeah, one taker?
MARISHA: You know what, Grog?
LAURA: It's a good plan, Grog.
LIAM: It's cheeky.
MARISHA: We will put that
in our back pocket
and we will think about it.
LIAM: That helmet
is really something else.
LAURA: You could really do
something terrible to him with that thing.
TRAVIS: I'm just saying,
I think we have an edge now.
LAURA: I think you're probably right.
SAM: (chuckle) Attaboy.
LIAM: That's technically true, yes.
TALIESIN: You do... have a point.
LAURA: But let's make sure
that Whitestone is safe
before we do such a thing.
SAM: Percy, we are in a place
that has an airship dock.
TALIESIN: That is true.
SAM: We could go steal an airship.
TALIESIN: We could go steal an airship!
LAURA: We don't need an airship.
MARISHA: We don't need an airship.
LAURA: We have an instant ability
to transport anywhere.
SAM: It would be so cool, though.
TALIESIN: Then we wouldn't
have to go to Whitestone.
It would hold all of our things.
LAURA AND MARISHA:
When we kill all the dragons...
TALIESIN: We could hold
all of our things on the airship,
and I could have cannonades...
LAURA: That will be the first thing we do
when Thordak dies
is we jump on an airship.
ASHLEY: Party on the airship.
MARISHA: We'll buy it
with all of the gold
that we've stolen
from all the dragons.
It'll be great.
TALIESIN: We won't need the airship
if the dragons are dead.
LAURA: All the fun has gone out of it.
TRAVIS: What are we doing?
LAURA: We're going to Whitestone.
MARISHA: We're going to Whitestone.
MARISHA: (piercing spell noise)
SAM: Before we leave, do you want
to sell these stupid white dragon scales?
TALIESIN: No.
SAM: All right, let's go.
LIAM: Let's go to Whitestone.
MARISHA: (repeats piercing spell noise)
Through a tree!
MATT: All right, as you guys walk
outside of the Slayer's Take guildhall,
you find the nearest tree,
which you've used before to traverse.
As you all step through the portal,
Percy and Scanlan
look over their shoulder
at the distant skyport
and see the one airship docked there
and think, "One day..."
LIAM: So handsome.
SAM: Someday, it will be ours.
TALIESIN: You'll make a fine sailor.
SAM: Passenger.
LIAM: Swabby.
MATT: You jump through
and emerge out the other side.
As you step out of the portal,
you find yourself
jumping out of the center
of the Sun Tree.
MARISHA: Can I do something?
SAM: Nope.
MATT: What do you want to do?
MARISHA: While I'm in the tree,
can I do something?
TRAVIS: Like kill us all?
No no no. Say they go first.
"Go, go, go, go."
And I kind of start teleporting
through the tree
and while I'm in the Sun Tree
I just want to be like,
"Hey, boo."
LAURA: (laughs)
MARISHA: "I missed you.
"Have you heard of this whole
cancerous tree situation
"in the Feywild?"
SAM: (whispering) You're talking to a tree?
MARISHA: Shh, no.
I'm in the middle of the tree.
I'm in the tree.
LAURA: You're stuck in the tree?
MATT: As you finish this thought,
you hear this sound emerge
(vacuum sealing sound)
and realize it's the sound
of the whole portal you've made
closing behind you
because it only lasts for six seconds
and you should probably
get the hell out of the tree.
MARISHA: Aww. I step out of the tree.
ASHLEY: Good try.
MATT: As you step out, a voice goes,
"Hey, boo, sorry.(kiss noise)"
(laughter)
MATT: And it closes behind you.
MARISHA: I'll talk to him later.
MATT: You guys emerge.
Due to the time differences,
you land here in Whitestone,
looking at where the sun is in the sky,
it's early afternoon,
as opposed to the morning
where you guys just stepped away from.
There are people in the streets,
and you see a few,
a little bit of life
has returned to this town square,
though still, by comparison--
there are folks now
that are bringing in actual,
healthy, looks to be fruits
from nearby trees.
There's a little bit of trade going on.
This is the first real chance you've had
to see a little bit of Whitestone
coming to life again.
As you emerge from the tree,
a few individuals nearby
stop and look and smile and wave,
recognizing you as you approach.
LAURA: Are there any leaves
on the Sun Tree yet?
MATT: Actually, no, there are not.
There are no leaves on the Sun Tree.
SAM: (quietly) Because it's winter.
LAURA: Whatever.
TRAVIS: We should check
with the border patrol.
SAM: There's a border patrol?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: A wolf.
SAM: Oh, the wolf.
TRAVIS: (whistles) I whistle
as loud as I can.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: What's his name?
MARISHA: I don't know.
Let me find it.
SAM: Oh, boy. Harold?
LAURA: I just want to go find Zahra
and give her a hug and say hello
and see how she's doing
while he's talking.
MATT: You whistle as loud as you can
for a little bit. Nothing.
TRAVIS: Must be off doing something
(belches) important.
TALIESIN: Quite.
MATT: You head off and, asking around,
you find Zahra is actually
up in Castle Whitestone right now,
just poring through
one of the studies of books,
and is just currently
reading and reading on her own.
As you eventually ask around
and find your way there,
entering the room, you see her
with a small set of spectacles
at the end of her nose.
She takes them off and,
"My darling Vex'ahlia!"
And comes up
and just gives you a big hug
and picks you up and sets you down.
"I'm so glad to see
you're all right."
LAURA: Dear, the dragon arrow
you gave me? Killed him.
Well, I didn't kill him,
actually, with it,
but I did a lot of damage.
MATT: "You killed a dragon?"
LAURA: Umbrasyl. Dead. One down.
MATT: "I knew you would."
LAURA: Where's Cashew?
MATT: "I don't know.
He's testy these days.
"I'm sure he's around."
LAURA: I know his name
is fucking Kashaw.
So he's not there.
MATT: "Probably down
in the city somewhere.
"He's helping where he can.
You know broody types."
LAURA: I do know broody types.
MATT: Yes, you do.
LAURA: What are you reading?
MATT: "Oh, I'm just learning
about the history of Whitestone
"and I'm very intrigued
as to the actual properties
"of this stone
the entire town is built on.
"There's a lot of really,
really interesting things
"that can be done with the materials
in these mountains."
LAURA: I'm sure you have ideas.
MATT: "I do."
LAURA: I sit down next to her and ask,
just catching up,
and see if they've spotted any dragons.
MATT: You guys continue your conversation,
catching up,
letting her know how things happened,
and vice versa.
You don't get any info
that any dragons have come by.
Apparently, there have been
a few other arcane practitioners
that have been helping set up
some sort of barrier to help,
essentially,
dissuade attention towards the city.
The idea of keeping this place
as far off the map as possible,
should any prying eyes
find their way there.
It's in the process
of being set up right now.
LAURA: Zahra, how long did it take you
to make that arrow?
MATT: "A few weeks."
LAURA: If I were to give you
some more money,
do you think you could do it again?
MATT: "Probably, based on what--
(sighs) if I'm able to use
"some of the resources
here within the castle, maybe."
LAURA: I'll talk to Percy,
but I'm sure, if it's for a good cause...
MATT: "All right, perhaps I can."
LAURA: All right.
I'll come find you, dear.
MATT: "Wondrous."
What else are you guys
trying to achieve here?
LIAM: I am trying to find Shaun Gilmore.
LAURA: That's his first name?
SAM: Shaun Gilmore?
MATT AND MARISHA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Yeah, Shaun.
LAURA: Shaun?
How did you know that?
MARISHA: He told us.
MATT: He told you guys that
a long time ago.
LAURA: I fucking know, I remember.
MATT: (laughs)
TALIESIN: Tattooed
at the small of his back.
MARISHA: Yeah, he's got a tramp stamp.
ASHLEY: Tramp stamp.
SAM: Can I accompany Vax on this trip?
LIAM: Sure, come on.
SAM: I want to see Gilmore.
LIAM: Let's start
asking around town for him.
MATT: You start asking around.
You come across
a few folks you recognize,
you find a few of the guards
who helped you
with the initial reconstruction
of this city and such
and asking around.
One of the nearby guards
takes his helmet off and is like,
"First off, I am so excited
"that you guys are back.
I'm so glad you're all safe.
"I heard that you were
off to do some dangerous things."
LIAM: You heard right.
MATT: "Well, great,
I'm glad that you've survived.
"Looking for Mr. Gilmore,
"he's actually down with the Realmseer.
"They're inspecting
the ziggurat underneath the city,
"so you could head down there
if you wanted to find him."
LIAM: Thank you.
I'm not terribly familiar
with Whitestone,
could you point us
in the right direction?
MATT: "It's under the castle."
LIAM: The castle.
MATT: "Yes."
LIAM: Can't miss that.
SAM: Yeah, we've been there before.
Yeah, let's go.
LIAM: Let's go.
MATT: He puts his helmet back on.
"Thank you again
for all that you do."
He clicks his heels together
and continues walking through the city.
LIAM: All right, yeah.
SAM: I guess we'll head
down to the ziggurat.
LIAM: Let's do it.
MATT: Everyone else going with?
TRAVIS: Fuck yeah, let's go.
ASHLEY: Yeah. Yeah.
LAURA: We taking a trip?
TALIESIN: Sure.
MARISHA: Oh, are we all
going down to the ziggurat?
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Nothing else to do.
MARISHA: Sure.
MATT: All right. You make your way
down to the basement area
of Whitestone Castle,
into the family catacombs,
which have been cleaned up
and you can see
Cassandra has put a little bit of care
into restoring it to what it was before.
The tunnel that was carved in
has been given a little more support,
and as you're making your way
down a familiar tunnel,
the same tunnel where you had
the showdown with Orthax,
you hear a few voices
from up ahead.
Two familiar voices.
You hear the echo of some older,
gruff, elderly gentleman
and a little more rambunctious
familiar voice.
As they turn the corner,
you see them deep in conversation.
It's the Realmseer himself
hunched forward
with his white hair
and balding top, turns around,
"And it's a great mystery to me
"that they can put a--
Oh, look! They've returned.
"Vox Machina themselves."
Gilmore, at this point,
opens his arms, standing and healthy.
"My god, I've been waiting for you."
LAURA: (laughs)
ASHLEY AND MARISHA: Aww.
MATT: "And all of you
so graciously clean!"
LAURA: You look so healthy, Gilmore!
ASHLEY: Very healthy.
MATT: "Well, I have you
to thank for that.
"Still a ways to go."
LIAM: But in two or three weeks,
it's not bad. You're looking well.
MATT: "Well, you all have Kima
to thank for that.
"She's been quite attentive
to my needs."
MARISHA: How is Whitestone finding you?
MATT: "Curious place, this Whitestone.
"Well, the company's interesting."
MARISHA: Sure.
MATT: The Realmseer laughs. He's like,
"(chuckles) So I've heard."
"We've spent a little bit of time
"looking at this strange oddity
beneath the city,
"and I'm not going to lie to you,
it's really confusing.
"I've a few theories on it,
as does the Arcanist,
"but we're still comparing notes
"and we don't want
to jump to any conclusions,
"as tests have been inconclusive
and rather dangerous so far.
"However, before anything else
goes underway, I believe there's
"a very important bit of business
that we must attend to."
SAM: Business?
What business, Gilmore?
MATT: And he walks straight up to Grog
and just gives you a big hug.
SAM: Aww.
LAURA: Oh?
MATT: And pats you on the shoulder
and is like,
"(chuckling) You big lug."
TRAVIS: You... Gilmore.
(laughter)
MATT: Walks over to you, Pike,
and kneels down and gives you
a little pinch on the cheek
and is like,
"Looking as spry
and smiley as ever, I see."
ASHLEY: Hello, Shaun.
(more laughter)
ASHLEY: I give him a kiss
on the cheek.
MATT: "Ooh."
ASHLEY: (laughs) "Ooh."
MATT: He turns to you.
"Vex'ahlia, look at you.
I hear, if my words say correct,
"that you folks are
a recent dragon-slaying bunch, hmm?"
LAURA: That we are.
MATT: "(chuckles) Good to know."
MATT: Skips over you.
LAURA: Oh.
ASHLEY: Save the best for last.
MATT: And goes to Scanlan
and goes to ruffle your hair, and goes,
"And you, you,
my little bardish friend."
SAM: Little?
MATT: "No, you're actually
physically little."
SAM: Oh, I know.
MATT: "You are a tinier person."
MATT: "Embrace it!
It's what makes you different."
SAM: That's true, I suppose.
I suppose. Yes, absolutely.
We've been spreading the good word
about you and your works.
MATT: "So I've heard
from all sorts of interesting folk.
"I only hope one day
to wear clothes as fine as you."
SAM: Oh! That's a nice compliment.
MATT: "Percival."
TALIESIN: Good patron.
MATT: "Thank you
for taking me into your home."
TALIESIN: You do nothing
but brighten these halls.
MATT: "I'm...
happy to keep things lit. (sighs)"
At which point,
he goes to look towards you.
The Realmseer's sitting there
tapping his arm; he's like,
"Right, get on with it,
we've got work to be done."
And, "Shh. You be quiet.
These people have saved my life.
"Keyleth. Sweet Ashari princess."
MARISHA: Hi, Gilmore.
MATT: "You've grown.
I can see it in your eyes."
He gives you a big hug.
MARISHA: I give him a hug back.
MATT: "Vax."
LAURA: (giggles)
MATT: "Vax'ildan.
Light of my eye. Smiling boy."
(laughter)
MATT: And he walks up
and puts his hands across your shoulders
and kind of cups your face.
"I've missed you most of all."
And pulls you in for a big hug
and lifts you up off the ground.
LIAM: Oh, hey, you.
LAURA: You're strong enough to--
be careful of your wound, Gilmore!
MATT: As he sets you down, he’s like,
"Ooh, I shouldn't have done that.
My apologies."
LIAM: I pat him on the ribs.
MATT: "Don't touch that.
It's still very tender."
LIAM: It's fantastic to see you.
You're a sight for sore eyes, yourself.
We're very happy to see you.
MATT: "My sight is sore,
so this works out well.
"But please, these tunnels are dank
and not becoming of us.
"Dinner should be happening soon
"and you should join us,
now that you've returned, please."
MARISHA: Oh, before dinner,
I think we were all just curious
on the state of the... ziggurat,
as we were calling it.
LAURA: The orb.
MATT: "Let's talk over dinner."
MARISHA: Spinning orb of death,
is what we call it.
MATT: "Let's talk over dinner."
MARISHA: All right, yeah, sure.
TRAVIS: Wait, you said
you were doing tests on it, right?
Did you throw things at it?
Did it blow up?
MATT: "That is part of the test.
Nothing blew up. Things did go away."
TRAVIS: They went away?
LAURA: They get sucked in, Grog.
MATT: "We'll talk over dinner.
"I hate to have this discussion
without Allura here.
"I think this would only
behoove the conversation
"if we're all present."
TALIESIN: An excellent argument.
LAURA: We have some delicious
and very expensive wine.
MATT: "(chuckling) Well!"
ASHLEY: Expensive-ass wine.
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: Expensive-ass wine
we could bust out with dinner.
MATT: "Color me intrigued."
LAURA: Oh, I haven't got to wink
in a really long time, you guys.
It felt so good.
MARISHA: Back to your old self.
LIAM: Hard life.
MATT: "It was a good wink.
Finest in the land.
"Well, come to the surface, then!
This place is dreary."
TALIESIN: Yes.
MATT: "You, too, Eskil."
MATT: "Aye.
"Too many smiles
in this area. I like it. It's jovial.
"Don't see that
around these places too often.
"It's good to see all of you.
Come, now, yes, let's move!"
MATT: You all eventually make your way
back to the surface, to Whitestone.
MARISHA: I go to Vex and Pike and go,
"Is this a good opportunity
for us to break out our formal wear?"
ASHLEY: (gasps) Yes!
LAURA: Definitely, dear.
MARISHA: Okay.
TRAVIS: Oh, jeez.
TALIESIN: I genuinely have no idea
what you're talking about.
MARISHA: The ladies take,
like, 20 minutes.
TRAVIS: Let's be honest, it's 2 hours.
TALIESIN: 40 minutes.
TRAVIS: Fucking 20 minutes, my ass.
On what plane are you
right now? (laughs)
LAURA: (laughs)
MARISHA: Not the Feywild.
But maybe soon.
ASHLEY: There's magic involved.
TALIESIN: Same plane as the break room.
5 minutes is 15. (laughs)
MARISHA: (laughing) Yes, yes, yeah.
TRAVIS: "I'll be 20 minutes."
The next day...
LIAM: On the way out,
as we're all walking out,
I walk along with Gilmore
and I give him
just a gentle shoulder.
Shoulder to shoulder. And say,
"It's really good
to see you on your feet.
"It's the best smile I've had in ages."
MATT: "You and me both."
LAURA: While we're getting ready,
I would like to talk to Pike
about a certain proposal that happened.
None of us have addressed it.
ASHLEY: I know, because I just--
LAURA: What happened?
ASHLEY: What should I do?
LAURA: What did you tell him?
Did you tell him yes, did you tell him no?
ASHLEY: I'm just so--
MARISHA: Hang on,
what exactly did he say, by the way?
ASHLEY: I just said we'll circle back.
LAURA: We'll circle back?
MARISHA: Circle back.
LAURA: (laughing) How did he take that?
ASHLEY: I think he was fine with it.
He just understands that I just--
MARISHA: Treat proposals
like we do our dungeons?
(laughs) We circle back.
ASHLEY: Isn't that the only way
to just treat all things?
I guess, I don't know.
I don't know.
MARISHA: (giggles)
LAURA: How do you feel about him, Pike?
ASHLEY: I just don't know.
I just feel so confused.
MARISHA: I understand that.
ASHLEY: He wears you down a little.
LIAM: (cracks up)
ASHLEY: And there's
something there, for him.
MARISHA: I don't know if that's
a good reason to say yes, though.
ASHLEY: Oh, I don't know.
He's just very charming.
MARISHA AND LAURA: He is very charming.
LAURA: And I noticed,
he's becoming more charming.
ASHLEY: Yes, I know!
MARISHA: Yeah, what is with that?
I didn't know that was possible.
ASHLEY: How? I feel like
he goes to sleep
and then the next morning
he's like--
ASHLEY AND LAURA: Even more charming!
LAURA: I don't understand it.
ASHLEY: Why is that?
MARISHA: I don't know.
LAURA: Like, every once in a while
I look at him and I go:
MARISHA: Yeah, no,
and then I feel really--
LAURA: No, but he's small,
but at the same time,
I'm kind of interested.
MARISHA: Right! And you kind of
think about it for a second
and you entertain it,
and then you feel really gross
about yourself.
LAURA: You feel like-- yeah!
ASHLEY: Yes! Yes.
LAURA: But if you're actually interested,
then it's not gross at all.
MARISHA: No! Of course it's not gross
if you're actually interested.
ASHLEY: I know. I just. (groans)
I've had feelings for someone
for a long time,
but maybe they're slowly fading.
I don't know.
LAURA: Wait.
MARISHA: Wait, what?
ASHLEY: I have. I don't know
if I feel comfortable talking about it.
But it's fine.
LAURA: We don't want to push you, Pike,
but you know, it's just us girls here.
MARISHA: I know! And we've been through
so many uncomfortable things together.
ASHLEY: (groans)
MARISHA: Most of life
is so uncomfortable.
Be comfortable right now.
ASHLEY: I just. I don't know.
It's still something
that I need to think about.
LAURA: All right.
MARISHA: We understand.
ASHLEY: I'm just.
LAURA: You pray
to your Sarenrae about it.
ASHLEY: Okay. (laughs)
You do look lovely, though,
in your dress.
LAURA: You look beautiful.
MARISHA: You look so cute.
LAURA, ASHLEY, AND MARISHA: (laugh)
ASHLEY: Thanks.
ASHLEY: I do a twirl.
(more laughter)
MARISHA: I do a little air cantrip
to make the skirt poof out.
ASHLEY: Ooh.
LAURA: I tug up my dress.
MARISHA: Hey, do you guys mind
tying me up a bit?
LAURA: Of course!
MARISHA: Nice and tight. (grunts)
LAURA: Can you breathe?
MARISHA: (strained)
No, but that means it's right.
LAURA: All right.
MARISHA: All right, I'm good.
TALIESIN: I assume there's clean clothes
for everybody in their quarters?
MATT: Yeah, it's all good.
TRAVIS: I'm wearing the same shit.
(laughter)
SAM: And the big hat?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: (laughing) To dinner. (shoonk)
TRAVIS: (laughing) Yeah.
I paid money for this thing.
TALIESIN: And I'm going to arrange
for our stuff to be stowed in the vault.
MATT: Okay. Not a worry.
All right, so as the sun sets,
you find your way down
to the proper dinner table.
Gilmore is there, Eskil is there,
Cassandra is there...
MARISHA: We look fabulous.
MATT: You guys look fantastic.
SAM: They do.
MARISHA: Yes. We do.
MATT: Fine outfits have been provided
for the men,
if they wish to wear them,
as well. Some do not.
TALIESIN: Oh, I am dressed.
LIAM: I'm dressed, yeah.
SAM: Oh, I'll dress up.
I'll dress up for dinner.
MATT: All righty.
As you guys sit down,
pleasantries are exchanged--
(yawns) Pardon me.
You catch up a bit with Cassandra.
Partway through--
LAURA: Aw, Matt.
MATT: What?
LIAM: E3, y'all.
TALIESIN: Sit down, have a beer,
watch our game.
MARISHA: (laughs) 2 pm.
MATT: Within the next 15 minutes or so,
before food is brought to the table,
Allura finally enters
in a very, very nice dress, and says,
"It is so good
to see you all are safe."
MARISHA: Allura!
ASHLEY: Hello.
LAURA: I give her a hug.
MATT: She then gives you a big,
wonderful hug.
LAURA: How's Kima?
We haven't seen her yet.
MATT: "Well..."
She looks over this way
and Kima walks in,
for the first time you've seen her
really out of armor
since you first saw her.
Her hair is also in similar braids
to her side
and she herself is wearing
a golden dress,
though she's kind of like...
TRAVIS: Yeah, I know the feeling.
(laughter)
MATT: She comes in.
MARISHA: Kima.
MATT: "Hello."
ASHLEY: Oh, you look lovely.
MARISHA: Keyleth goes over
and gives her a hug.
MATT: She gives you a hug and goes,
"It's good to see you guys.
I'm glad you're all right...
"This feels weird. Does this feel weird?
This feels weird."
MARISHA: It's only for a few hours.
Don't worry about it.
TRAVIS: What are you wearing?
MATT: "That's what I'm saying!
Do I have to wear--
"he's not wearing anything.
Do I have to wear--"
LAURA: You don't have to wear a dress, Kima.
MATT: "You don't have to wear it, Kima.
It was just a suggestion."
LAURA: (chuckles)
MATT: "I'm going to go change.
I'll be right back."
TRAVIS: Yeah, go change.
MATT: She darts off for a bit
and Allura smiles and facepalms a bit.
SAM: You two are at the kiddie table.
(laughter)
LIAM: You ought to let her
try that helmet on later.
SAM: Show some class, man.
TRAVIS: (laughs)
MATT: You guys catch up a bit
as Allura speaks
about her and Drake's escape
from Westruun.
Kima eventually comes back,
wearing ratty clothing.
Shirt, pants, the general wear
she'd pick up throughout the city.
And is still carrying
her small maul at her side.
It's like her little comfort blanket.
(thud) Next to the table.
TRAVIS: Yeah. That's better.
MATT: She scoots up next to Allura.
Gilmore snaps his fingers
and wine begins to pour
from the servants. Cassandra says,
"Well, thank you all for coming.
"I believe there is much
to get underway here. This,"a
MATT: And she gestures
towards Gilmore and Allura; they nod.
Eskil raises his hand a moment.
MATT: "So, while you've been gone.
"Allura, you've been
doing this research for a bit."
"Thank you, thank you.
So, we've been trying
"to ascertain the nature
of the ziggurat beneath the city.
"The ziggurat itself is built over
"what appears to be
an ancient temple of Ioun.
"The glass substance,
"the diluted whitestone
that has been reformed into glass,
"is used as a very strong arcane current.
"A lot of energy was being placed
in this location,
"as there is an actual,
what appears to be
"an arcane leyline, a nexus point,
"near and above Whitestone,
hence the Sun Tree's placement."
TALIESIN: Yes, of course.
MATT: "And why it flourishes
so well in this region.
"But everything within
a certain vicinity of this temple,
"of this dark spot, if you will,
is eaten.
"Doesn't vanish, it's not cancelled,
it's taken. Devoured.
"Everything placed within
that small little globule of darkness
"is taken somewhere as well.
"Now, at first, we thought
maybe it was just destroying,
"but the arcane energy we feel,
"the flow of it,
it's drawing it somewhere.
"Meaning that this is not
what I had feared to be
"a sphere of annihilation,
an object of complete destruction.
"Instead it feels like it's a siphon.
"Now, a siphon. Siphons are very old.
Siphons were used in the First War.
"They were used as a means
"of transferring extremely powerful...
"raw magical powers.
"They were placed strategically
throughout the world's crust
"at these various nexus points
"as a means of creating
extremely powerful relics.
"The ones that you seek, the ones
that made the Vestiges themselves,
"were crafted through the use
of some of these siphons,
"but they have been lost and,
many thought,
"destroyed for a very long time,
or at least inert.
"I have reason to believe
that this may be one.
"And it may be active.
"As to where the other side lies,
I do not know.
"Because each siphon has two points."
TALIESIN: So it's fair to assume
that at the other end of this
is something old, something trapped,
something hungry.
MATT: "Perhaps."
LAURA: Would it be in this plane
or another?
MATT: "I have no idea.
"Everything we've attempted
to put through it
"that had any sort
of magical connection,
"whether it be
through inter-planal scrying,
"anything that would bring us
to the other side of this,
"is crushed, consumed,
and transferred as part of it.
"None of our rituals
or enchantments
"will let us see through this
spinning marble, as you call it."
LAURA: You haven't
put any blood through it, though?
TALIESIN: Let's not.
LAURA: No, I'm hoping
that hasn't happened.
MARISHA: So nothing survives
the transfer.
It is destroyed into its...
purest components, it sounds.
MATT: "Seemingly, yes."
LIAM: Or is it? Don't know?
Is it that you have no idea
what happened to things put through?
MATT: "We're still delving into it,
"and it may be a little while
before we figure this out,
"but this is the best I can ascertain
with my knowledge at my disposal.
"And the Realmseer and Gilmore
can back up this research.
"We've all worked together
these past weeks
"and we're all kind of
coming to the same conclusion."
She gestures to Gilmore.
Gilmore says,
"I've only been
on this case personally
"for a few days
"of rising health standards
in my body
"and I've thrown everything
I can at it, honestly,
"and it's all just come to nothing.
Gone. (pthbbt)"
TALIESIN: This is disappointing.
MATT: "You're telling me."
TRAVIS: What about a person?
MATT: "(laughing) I'm not
sending a person through there."
MARISHA: To be fair, Grog,
I might have tried that, a little.
SAM: What?
TALIESIN: Yes, that's right.
MARISHA: I sort of stuck my hand
in the spinning ball of death
and let's just say
I'm glad I'm still here
standing with you all.
LAURA: Was it sucking you in?
MARISHA: It did a considerable
amount of damage to my hand
and definitely felt
like it was sucking me in
and I had to resist pretty hard.
But it seems like anything
that goes in that sphere
doesn't come out the other end intact.
LAURA: Gilmore-- any of you, Allura--
have you experienced
any kind of draw toward the orb?
Do you feel different,
having been around it for very long?
MATT: Gilmore cocks a curious eye
to the Realmseer.
The Realmseer thinks
and scratches his chin,
looks to Allura.
Allura looks down at the table
with her arms crossed,
looks to Kima.
Kima's finishing her big drink.
"I stay away from it.
It creeps the hell out of me."
"Not to my knowledge.
Do you think we should be worried?"
LAURA: Well, I don't know.
I mean, it is a very strong relic
that we don't know how it works.
MATT: "The difficulty
in our research
"is most of our means of inspection
are, well,"
LAURA: Up close and personal.
MATT: "Of arcane nature."
TALIESIN: I was hoping
that perhaps we could talk
about some engineering possibilities
of finding ways
that science can measure what it is
where magic cannot.
Something safe.
SAM: (scoffs) Science, Percy?
TALIESIN: In this sense, as it stands.
MATT: "We're open
to all possible suggestions.
"We're kind of at the end of our rope
for the time being.
"We may send a few of us
across the way to, well,
"a few different places
for more information.
"May do a bit
of traveling ourselves, it seems."
TALIESIN: I'll sketch something
with my copious free time.
MATT: "Hm. Please do."
SAM: No dragons
have buzzed by here in our absence?
MATT: They kind of
look to themselves.
"None yet,
but we've been very careful.
"We're in the process of installing
some semblance of,
"(sighs) for lack of a better term,
sort of a screen.
"Ways to reflect
and perhaps cloud anyone
"who attempts to peer too far
into the northern regions of Whitestone.
"The last thing we need
"is any of these dragons
finding their way up north
"where you've kept all of us
and the refugees safe,
"so we're trying not
to piss any of them off,
"while also trying to make sure
that maybe they're
"not really looking
behind this curtain of cloud."
TALIESIN: Any fortifications
would be helpful.
LAURA: Don't dragons sort of
see past those things?
MATT: "We're doing our best
to try and meet those standards."
TALIESIN: I have another request
in that direction that might help.
If there was a way
to spread the word in this city
and amongst those who travel,
to not speak of us.
We should probably not be hailed
in this city at all.
Our names should be stricken
from any record of it.
MATT: Allura leans forward
on the table.
"No, I see. You're right.
"There is merit in that,
though it will be difficult.
"Many here look up to you.
"They see you as the salvation
of this city.
"But I believe we can go about
and speak with them
"and help instill the idea
that it's for the better good
"that you are not mentioned."
TALIESIN: Best to be nameless,
at this point.
MARISHA: It's for their own safety.
TALIESIN: It's for everybody's.
LAURA: We-who-must-not-be-named.
SAM: The Unmentionables.
TALIESIN: (cracks up)
You're a terrible person.
LAURA: (gasps) I love it.
MARISHA: Yeah. My choice is
The Unmentionables. I like it.
MATT: Allura says,
"I did find some research
"on some of these Vestiges
you are seeking."
TALIESIN: Oh!
LAURA: Yes!
MATT: "From what I could bring forth
"from the Cobalt Reserve in Westruun,
"there is an artifact
that lies in the Feywild,
"swallowed by a terrible tree."
LAURA: Yes, the Warden.
MATT: "Is that the name of it?"
LAURA: The Wrath of the Fey Warden.
MATT: "So you've found
some information yourself?"
LAURA: Just the name.
SAM: And that it's
in the Feywild, but nothing more.
MATT: "(sighs) This tree that holds it,
it's a tree seeded by the betrayal
"of an archfey whose hatred burned
into a black heart of disease.
"The cleansing rivers
of the Gilded Run
"prevent the spread
of the Shademirk Bog that seeps from it."
TRAVIS: Sounds nasty.
MATT: "It doesn't sound very fun, no."
SAM: The Shademark Balg?
MATT: "The Shademirk Bog."
SAM: Ugh, it sounds awful.
MATT: "It seeps from this tree.
"It is held at bay
by the rivers of the Gilded Run."
MARISHA: The rivers are called
the Gilded Run?
MATT: "Mm-hm."
SAM: Okay. Well, that helps us.
Those are clues.
LAURA: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
MARISHA: And the Shademirk Bog
pours out of the tree?
LAURA: Out of the cancerous tree.
MARISHA: The tree is responsible
for a swampy bog.
MATT: "From best I could ascertain
from my research, yes."
LAURA: And Fen-wraths?
What's the name?
SAM: Fenthras,
Wrath of the Fey Warden.
LAURA: Fenthras is inside of the tree
that is terrible.
MATT: "It is very possible."
TALIESIN: Oh no.
SAM: Okay.
LIAM: Do you know anything
about the Vestige itself?
MATT: "I don't, unfortunately.
Most of the Cobalt Reserve was destroyed
"and I was under siege at the moment
from the return of the dragons. (sighs)"
LAURA: Did you happen to find
in your research what, perhaps,
we might face in the Feywild?
I mean, we've learned
a little bit of it,
but I know
that it's going to be rather dangerous.
MATT: "I've not been there myself,
to be honest. It creeps me out."
LAURA: (laughs)
TRAVIS: (laughs) No? Sorry.
MATT: "I did find also
about the Spire of Conflux.
"It is a staff
that can bend the elements
"and was taken into The Abyss
"by Joran the Sea-Speaker,
hero of the Verdant Expanse,
"about four centuries back,
and was never heard from again."
MARISHA: Joran the what?
MATT: "Joran the Sea-Speaker."
SAM: He speaks to the sea?
MATT: "Perhaps."
TALIESIN: Or just the letter C.
LAURA: (laughs)
SAM: Cookie Monster.
TRAVIS: Hero.
MATT: "I do have some research
about the dragons, as well."
LAURA: Oh.
MATT: "I've done a bit
of looking into the personality types,
"the habits of some of these chromatics
you may be coming up against.
"The black dragon,
you seemingly already dealt with,
"if word has come to me correctly."
LAURA: Yes.
MATT: "Which is magnificent
and well done. Very dangerous.
"Let's hope they don't decide
to strike back soon."
LAURA: Good thing we didn't provoke them
in the cave at all, Percival.
TALIESIN: If they came there,
they would've been provoked,
I figured.
MATT: "I did find that
the white dragons, they're more primal.
"They're overall less intelligent
than other chromatics."
And some
of this information you know.
LAURA: Yeah, why am I writing this down?
I know this shit.
MATT: "But what they do is they--
"(sighs) well, don't let
the lack of intelligence
"lull you into comfort.
"They are also unpredictable and raw.
"Dangerous hunters,
"they stalk in ruined lands
of ice and vengeance.
"Their memory is eternal.
"They recall every slight defeat
"and have been known to hold vendettas
for centuries and centuries.
"They despise other dragons
"and this loose alignment with Thordak
"is stranger than the others
for the white dragon.
"Though Vorugal's distance to the others
is intentional, most likely.
"I mean, the entire alignment
between them is strange, anyway,
"but particularly
with the white dragon.
"They generally steer very clear of,
or are bent on destroying,
"any other types of dragons
that may wander in their midst."
LAURA: (whispering) Interesting.
MATT: "Green dragons, in particular,
are manipulative.
"Liars, by nature, finding pleasure
in power over others.
"Through deceit and promises
of wealth and glory, they corrupt.
"They play subservience
to other dragons,
"then plot their demise
to claim their hoards.
"They're the seedy underbelly
of the chromatic world, if you will.
"They amass powerful allies,
human and beyond, to their will,
"bending them and using them as tools.
"Their life and their very presence
"is poison to those around them,
"and is the very basis
of their danger.
"They corrupt the air around them
to be venomous.
"I found a bit about
this Raishan you mentioned,
"and word has spoken,
though little that exists out there,
"that she is also
a very practitioned
"weaver of the arcane arts,
so be warned."
MARISHA: So much so
that she could almost pass
as a druid wielding natural magic?
MATT: "I can imagine
that's quite within her grasp.
"I've heard rumors of her
calling the sky down upon her enemies.
"Previous individuals
that hoped to raid her space
"were swallowed in quaking earth
as she laughed from above."
SAM: Druid-y things.
MARISHA: I want to kill her so hard.
(strained) I want her to die.
TALIESIN: Do we know where these--
where these dragons have been
all this time,
where they were banished to?
MATT: "I mean, most of these dragons
"lived their lives
wherever they once were before.
"Raishan used to exist
in the mountains outside of Syngorn
"and actually had amassed
"a sizeable horde of followers,
lizard-men. Lizardfolk, all sorts."
TALIESIN: Wait, then Thordak
was banished to the Fire Plane?
MATT: "Thordak we had banished, yes.
Thordak, in particular.
"Now, red dragons are true tyrants,
built on impulse and rage.
"Arrogant to the core,
"they see themselves
as rightful rulers over all.
"And Thordak, the king
of all other dragons, as well.
"He is powerful enough
to amass networks
"of spies and followers far beyond
"just the dragons that we've battled,
I'm sure.
"So the more time that passes,
"the more powerful
that network will become."
LAURA: (muffled) Oh, fuck.
TALIESIN: I've had a terrible thought,
and it is sort of my business
to have terrible thoughts.
What else has been banished
to the Fire Plane?
TRAVIS: The djinn?
TALIESIN: Well, I say this
because if I were to slowly
open the portal to the Fire Plane
and power it and make it bigger
and bigger and bigger,
eventually it would be
a hole into that dimension
that's big enough
for a dragon to fit through,
but still not big enough for me,
so I need to keep eating,
to make it bigger.
LAURA: (gasps)
TALIESIN: And maybe they might
be looking for what's down there
so they can feed it
and make a bigger hole.
Just a thought. It may be nothing.
LAURA: You think there's something
bigger than Thordak in the Fire Plane?
TALIESIN: I have terrible thoughts.
It's a terrible thought.
MARISHA: I mean, I'm sure there is
something bigger than Thordak,
probably in the Fire Plane,
but the Fire Ashari closed the portal.
TALIESIN: That may
not have been the portal.
MARISHA: That was the portal
that Thordak came out of.
It ripped apart my entire--
TALIESIN: That may just be
where he escaped.
That power may still be flowing.
MARISHA: Well, Allura, how did you
lock him in the Fire Plane to begin with?
MATT: "Well, we had,
through clever subterfuge,
"managed to have a member of our team
"work as a follower of Thordak,
"work into his greater trust
"and convince him
that to perpetuate his wealth,
"his growth, his strength,
"that he needed to truly embrace
the essence of fire.
"And there are crystals,
"there are remnants of the First War
"that exist in this world and others.
"The very core
of the elemental chaos itself,
"the hearts of the titans left behind.
"These heart-stones are
the very basis,
"or, at least,
shadows of the basis
"of what made the elements
when creation came to be.
"We had found one of these
on the Fire Plane,
"but the nature of these
is that they cannot be removed.
"If they are brought
beyond the plane themselves,
"they generally shatter,
"and the few that can
be brought across temporarily,
"the magics that contain them
do weaken,
"and those that attempted
to harness their power
"leave it to ruin,
destroying all around them
"before it whirls itself
into a frenzy
"of uncontrollable arcane mass
and destroys everything nearby.
"These were many of the fools
"who ushered in the beginning
of the Second War.
"So. Essentially,
we convinced Thordak
"to find one of these in the plane
"and convinced him
that he had the power to contain it.
"Once there,
all of our forces gathered
"and we attacked him,
pressed him down,
"and the gem
that we had convinced him--
"the heart-stone
that we had convinced him
"to take into himself,
"well, we found a way to seal it,
"to banish it permanently to that plane
so that he could not escape."
MARISHA: All right. So, that's all good.
But he did escape.
LAURA: Could he still
potentially have it inside of him?
MARISHA: Exactly!
That was my question!
SAM: Well, she asked it,
so, technically, it's hers.
MATT: She turns and you can see Gilmore's
sitting at the table like this.
"I got a very good close
at that dragon.
"A very good close look,
to finish my sentence.
"I've been drinking
plenty of wine tonight; don't judge me."
ASHLEY: Expensive-ass wine.
TALIESIN: It's the best wine.
MATT: "It is very expensive,
fine wine."
TRAVIS: Matt’s Vineyard is the best.
MATT: "Thank you, Grog,
it's wondrous."
MARISHA: (laughs)
MATT: "But his mass,
"his unforeseen size
to a creature like that.
"I couldn't help but notice
that within his torso
"there was a pulsing heart...
"of red glass."
LAURA: All right.
TALIESIN: Look how clever
food makes all of us.
MATT: He looks over to Allura.
Allura nods.
"Well, if that is the case,
then it's, I think,
"there's very much a chance
"that he did escape
with the heart-stone intact."
TRAVIS: I have a question.
We've got one of the Vestiges
in these Titanstone Knuckles,
made from the heart-stone.
If I left the plane with these,
are they gonna blow everybody up?
MATT: "An intact heart-stone
is the true source of power.
"Those have been carved from one,
an inert one, or, at least,
"they carry but a smidgen of the power.
"I think you're safe, Grog."
TRAVIS: Oh, thank god.
ASHLEY: Phew.
LAURA: Which one?
TRAVIS: Kord.
LAURA: Oh, Kord. I got it. (chuckles)
MATT: Allura leans in again.
"I have been keeping an eye on Emon
from this distance, as well.
"It seems that Thordak's very essence
"twists the land with elemental magic."
TRAVIS: (whispering) Oh, shit.
MATT: "My distant views of the city
"have shown the center of the town
cracked with volcanic fire
"as he digs and burrows
beneath the city itself."
TALIESIN: (whispering) Fuck.
LAURA: Oh, fuck.
TRAVIS: Wait, why is he
digging and burrowing?
LIAM: He's reshaping the land
as he sees fit.
TRAVIS: Or is he looking for something?
LAURA: Because he's a dick.
TRAVIS: Is he not
looking for something?
TALIESIN: He might be
looking for something,
or might be making--
MARISHA: So these heart-stones
embrace the essence
of where they reside?
MATT: "Their essence
is created where they reside."
MARISHA: And he has the heart-stone
of the Fire Elemental Plane
living inside of him.
MATT: "A heart-stone. There are many."
MARISHA: A heart-stone. Right.
LAURA: I'm confused.
TRAVIS: I need more wine.
Do you think he was
just making himself at home,
or do you think he was
looking for something?
MATT: "I don't know.
He seems pretty lax.
"From what I could tell
from my investigations,
"the major step
in the Conclave's plan
"is already over."
LAURA: Take over everything.
MATT: "Now they settle
into the divided territories
"and forget each other.
"Now, I feel that Thordak
is far too old and covetous
"to be content with just Emon.
"Now, this was vengeance,
which is now complete.
"Who knows what the next stage
in his terrible design is."
MARISHA: So you're thinking
the Chroma Conclave
was simply a temporary alliance?
MATT: "There are very few
"permanent alliances
between chromatic dragons."
LAURA: Well, that's good.
MARISHA: We can use this.
LAURA: Maybe they won't take vengeance.
ASHLEY: Maybe we can get one of them
on our side.
TALIESIN: We can only be so hopeful
that they tear each other apart.
LAURA: Maybe the white one will want
to help kill Thordak with us.
MARISHA: Turning them against each other
is not a bad idea.
TALIESIN: Our best hope, at this point,
is just to amass power.
We are not strong enough.
LAURA: No.
TALIESIN: But we will get stronger.
LAURA: Does the heart-stone make him
even stronger than he already was?
MATT: "I don't know,
"but he was not that large
when we sealed him."
LAURA: Shit.
TRAVIS: Seize.
MARISHA: So we can take-- yeah.
LAURA: If we can pry it
out of his body,
we could shrink him down.
Perfect plan.
SAM: Then we could go
inside a dragon again.
LAURA: We can go in another dragon.
LIAM: Every one of them,
one after the other.
TRAVIS: You seen any dragons
on the outskirts of the town?
Have there been any flyovers
or close calls within, say,
50 to 100 miles or so?
Any reports?
MATT: "Hundred miles.
"There were reports
of the white dragon a week ago,
"south of us. Far south of us."
TRAVIS: Far south.
LAURA: Doing what, just flying?
MATT: "Just flying. Flying east."
TALIESIN: Unless they know
what's underneath the castle,
there's nothing of value here.
LIAM: Do we know where Vorugal
has taken up roost? No one knows?
MATT: "No. I've tried to scry,
"but they're apparently
protected against that now."
TRAVIS: What about
means of protection for Whitestone.
Do you have a defense planned?
A warning system?
MATT: "We're just getting now
to that point.
"It may be a few weeks
before we're ready to go.
"It's a lot to build
and it's a very big space to protect,
"but me and Drake
are working on some ideas. (sighs)"
MARISHA: Do you know exactly how
these heart-stones are forged?
MATT: "They're not forged.
They existed.
"They were the hearts
of the primordial titans
"that existed on this world
before the gods even came here."
MARISHA: Oh, that's right.
LAURA: Wow.
MATT: "They were the true denizens
of this world, before any of us."
SAM: This is an awesome dinner,
by the way. Super good.
LAURA: So good.
TALIESIN: I love game meat.
MATT: "I'm sorry,
it's been a very tense time."
LAURA: This wine is pretty good.
ASHLEY: It's very good.
MATT: "Perhaps rest is in order
for all of us.
"It's been a lot. I'm so sorry.
It's good to see all of you."
TRAVIS: You, as well.
LAURA: You've done so much.
MATT: Allura brightens up a little bit.
You can see that she feels guilty
that she just did
this information dump and is like,
"(sighs) It's good
to see all of you."
MARISHA: It was good to see you.
MATT: "(sighs) Well,
let us rest for the evening."
Drinks the last of her wine,
stands up.
"We'll talk on the morrow."
She gets up. "Kima?"
"I'm coming, let me finish."
LAURA AND MARISHA: (laugh)
MATT: "No, seriously,
it's good to see you all.
"I'm glad you're all right."
LAURA: You should have been with us.
MATT: "I should've been with you.
I didn't know you left!"
LAURA: Sorry, Kima. We're dicks.
MATT: "Is Westruun okay?"
LAURA: It's... better.
MARISHA: (whispering)
It's not great, though.
LAURA: It's getting better.
TALIESIN: It lives. It lives.
SAM: That's true.
MARISHA: It stands.
MATT: "Does my house still stand?"
(hesitant noises)
SAM: What's a house, really,
but a bunch of bricks.
MATT: "Oh, it's fine."
MARISHA: Home is
where you make it, Kima.
MATT: "Object impermanence.
(glug glug)
"Next time you're going there,
you tell me."
LAURA: Oh, yes. We will.
TALIESIN: We will be returning.
TRAVIS: On one condition.
Don't wear any more dresses.
LAURA: (laughs)
MATT: "You saying
I wasn't pretty, Grog?"
TRAVIS: I like you
in your armor better.
MATT: "That's why I missed you."
She reaches out
and smacks your cheek.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
(laughter)
MATT: "All right, kiddies,
sleep it is."
Kima gets up and joins Allura,
and they both leave.
Gilmore stands up,
Realmseer stands up.
"All right, everyone.
Rest well. See you in the morning.
"And, ah, glad you're all safe."
LIAM: Good night, Shaun.
MATT: "Good night, everyone."
ASHLEY: Good night, Gilmore.
MATT: "Sleep well."
MATT: They all leave.
SAM: So we rest here
for a night or two
and then, to the Feywild?
TRAVIS: Yeah, Feywild.
SAM: Or to the--
TRAVIS: We even have a geographic--
demographic location to like--
SAM: True.
MARISHA: We do.
TALIESIN: I feel like
the Feywild calls to us.
LIAM: What do you say
we go get you a new bow?
LAURA: We could go get me a new bow.
There's also the ocean.
SAM: Yeah.
LIAM: Nah. Let's get you a bow.
MARISHA: Let's go get you a bow.
ASHLEY: I'm going
to pour another glass of wine.
TALIESIN: Ocean next.
SAM: Pike could go off
to get the ocean one herself.
LAURA: No! You're crazy.
LIAM: That's a shitty idea.
MATT: (laughs)
TRAVIS: I think you've had
too much to drink, Scanlan.
LAURA: Or the two of you together.
SAM: Yeah, I like the ocean.
I don't really like the ocean.
(laughter)
MATT: You guys all going to rest?
MARISHA: I have one thing I'd like to do.
MATT: Okay, what do you want to do?
MARISHA: I want to go back
to our little cave that we dug out
under where the Sun Tree is.
Is that still there?
MATT: Yeah, it's still there.
MARISHA: I want to go there,
and I want to kind of sit down
and meditate for a second.
And I want to cast Speak With Plants
and have a little chat
with the Sun Tree.
MATT: Okay. (laughs)
You cast the spell,
you reach out
and touch the roots of the tree,
the roots of which have more color
than they did before.
The dull gray has become
more of a full brown.
The earth here smells of fresh,
damp earth.
The tree, while still
in the winter phase,
is definitely teeming with life,
to where it once didn't.
MARISHA: I reach out
and I touch the roots.
Can I just kind of feel,
sense the arcane ley-lines
that Allura was talking about
that the tree's in the center of?
MATT: Mmm... not really.
In speaking to the tree,
you can ask questions,
but you're not quite--
you find yourself unable
to tune into that
or tap into that source of magic.
At this place, at least.
MARISHA: Okay. So I just reach out,
touch the tree, and say,
"Hey, old friend.
"How are you feeling? Doing better?"
MATT: "Hey, bud. Much better."
(laughter)
MARISHA: You're pretty cool, Sun Tree.
MATT: "Sun Tree, A-OK."
(laughter)
MARISHA: Hey, Sun Tree?
MATT: "Yeah?"
MARISHA: I was just wondering
if you knew--
if you could tell me anything
about this
terrible cancerous tree
in the Feywild,
if you knew anything about it?
He might be like
your brother or something.
MATT: "Tree cancer? What?"
MARISHA: No! No, okay.
There's this tree in the Feywild
and it might have
a man living in it
called Fenthras.
TRAVIS: (quietly) The bow.
MARISHA: No, sorry,
that's the name of the bow,
the bow is in it, named Fenthras,
and it might be a really sick tree.
Can you tell me where there's
a really sick tree, maybe in the Feywild?
MATT: "That sounds sad, but no.
"I don't know
a tree like that, sorry.
"I've been here in Whitestone
since day one."
(laughter)
LIAM: Want to play hacky sack?
TALIESIN: Born and raised.
MATT: So I graduated from Berkeley
and made my way to Whitestone.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: My twigs smoke the doob.
SAM: "Barkeley."
MARISHA: "Barkeley!"
ASHLEY: Put a pair of Birkenstocks
on its branches.
TRAVIS: "Birkenstalks."
MATT: (groans)
LAURA: "Birkenstalks?" I like it.
MARISHA: Hey, Sun Tree?
MATT: "Yeah?"
MARISHA: You apparently kind of live
in the middle of all these
arcane ley-lines of the world.
MATT: "Yeah."
TALIESIN: (cracks up)
MARISHA: How far do those stretch?
MATT: "Long way, Kiki.
"Long way."
(laughter)
MARISHA: Can you kind of give me
a rough idea?
Do they go
to the other side of the world?
Can you stretch all over the world?
MATT: "Nah, just right here.
Pelor put me here for a reason."
MARISHA: Who? Pelor?
MATT: "Yeah."
MARISHA: Right.
So you're not a natural tree,
you're a tree from the gods?
MATT: "Sure."
MARISHA: All right.
Well, anyway,
you're really awesome, Sun Tree.
MATT: "Speak for yourself, Kiki."
MARISHA: Yeah, you're so cool.
Okay, so it was good talking to you.
MATT: "You, too."
MARISHA: I'll walk through you soon.
Okay, bye.
MATT: (laughs)
MARISHA: And then I leave.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: I want to make a once-over on Vax
and make sure that--
So you did,
you got all the blood off, then?
LIAM: What are you doing?
Yeah, I took a bath.
LAURA: I mean,
we got all cleaned up for tonight.
I just want to make sure
you didn't ruin it
by keeping some of the blood
in your freaking hair.
LIAM: Don't I look all right?
I'm fine! What's your problem?
LAURA: Nothing! Just making sure
you're doing all right.
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: All the blood's gone.
LIAM: Yeah. It's all gone.
LAURA: You're great.
LIAM: I'm doing much better.
LAURA: Good.
LIAM: Much better.
You ready for the Feywild?
LAURA: Fuck, no, not ready,
but we can do it.
LIAM: Oh.
TALIESIN: Stupid to settle.
MARISHA: (snorts)
LAURA: I walk over to Percy.
TALIESIN: I was about
to walk out the door,
but if you're walking--
LAURA: Before you leave,
I whisper in your ear,
"You still have
a little blood behind your ear."
TRAVIS: (gasps)
TALIESIN: Do you want
to take a walk with me?
LAURA: (sighs) Sure.
TALIESIN: We take a very quiet walk
around Whitestone.
I want to pass all of the temples
that are either
still standing or destroyed.
I just want to take a temple tour.
Not stopping, not talking,
I just want to see what they look like.
Pelor looks good.
The one in the cemetery?
MATT: The one in the cemetery
is still under construction.
That one needs a little more work.
TALIESIN: While in the cemetery--
I assume that it's still a mess.
MATT: Most of the graves
have been refilled,
the corpses have been brought back.
Most of the dead that were brought forth
from the previous owners
have been returned.
That was one of the first
orders of business
that people who live here did,
was to return their families
to the earth.
TALIESIN: There were
a couple of lords' crypts in there.
Was there an Anders family crypt,
at one point?
MATT: There would have been, yeah.
TALIESIN: Cool. All right.
I'm going to walk back to the castle,
with you in tow,
and I'm going to find Zahra.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Are you going to tell me
why you went and saw the Raven Queen?
TALIESIN: Yes. Come.
MATT: All right.
You come back to the study
where you originally found Zahra.
She's still there poring over books,
but is now half-asleep.
She has a little candle
that's starting to flicker out
and she has her feet up on the desk
and her tail's kind of curled up
and she's falling asleep
into the book as you walk in.
LAURA: (whispering) Dear--
MATT: "What?"
LAURA: We all need sleep sometimes, hon.
MATT: "Sleep's for the boring."
TALIESIN: I have a task for you,
if you have the time and energy
for something a bit quiet, but necessary.
MATT: "What do you ask, Percy?"
TALIESIN: I'm going to have
the deeds
to the Anders family crypt
transferred to your name.
I want you to clean it out.
Throw the bodies wherever;
he has disgraced himself.
Clean them.
And if you can,
if you can find people who can do it,
I want to very quietly,
in that crypt,
create a small shrine
to the Raven Queen.
This will help.
And I bring out
the vial of blood from the pit.
Perhaps they will know
what to do with that.
MATT: "Intriguing."
TALIESIN: But I would like her
to have a quiet mark in this city.
LAURA: Is this for you,
or for my brother?
TALIESIN: ...It's for your brother,
so that he can help us.
We're apparently all in this together.
LAURA: I give Percy a kiss on the cheek.
TALIESIN: Oh. Thank you.
MATT: "All right."
TALIESIN: We need all the help we can get.
MATT: "Very well.
I'm sure it can be done.
"I never owned a crypt before.
I'm excited."
LAURA: It's exciting. (laughs)
MATT: She takes the vial
and puts it on the table.
LAURA: I think it suits you.
TALIESIN: Tell anyone you'd like
where I went. It's not a secret.
I just wasn't ready to...
I don't think your brother--
I would hate for him
to think I'm competing.
I just had some questions.
LAURA: I won't tell anyone, Percy.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
LAURA: Your business is yours.
And mine, because I noticed.
(chuckles)
MARISHA: (snorts)
TALIESIN: Thank you for noticing,
and... I'm trying hard
not to make it my business.
It's hard to remember sometimes.
TALIESIN: (sighs)
LAURA: (quietly) We're all family.
TALIESIN: That's awful, isn't it.
(sighs)
I'm going to go to my room--
LAURA: Oh! Percy!
TALIESIN: Yes?
LAURA: Sorry.
If Zahra wanted to make
some dragon arrows,
could she use stuff here
in the castle?
TALIESIN: I'll talk to my sister
on the way out.
I'll write her a letter
and see if they can--
they may have to delve
into our materials for it,
but I think we're good.
LAURA: Yes.
TALIESIN: We'll talk about
using our materials for such a thing,
and I will talk to her about that.
LAURA: All right.
TALIESIN: I'm going to do
my little thing and if it works, great,
and if not,
we'll speak not of it for a while.
MATT: Okay. Go ahead
and make your tinkering check.
TALIESIN: Better! 30.
MATT: That'll do.
TALIESIN: I craft a brooch.
It's not even a brooch,
it's a clasp.
I had built these pieces of it
earlier on in the game.
For the last three weeks
I've been working on this.
I've taken the raven skull
that you gave me
and made a mold
and poured melted silver
into a bird skull,
a silver bird skull.
Taken a ruby and set it behind it,
built it into a clasp
that does not reflect,
and in it,
put a sachet of-- satchel...
MARISHA and LAURA: Sachet.
TALIESIN: Thank you. My brain? Coffee.
Of myrrh and--
SAM: Frankincense?
TALIESIN: (snorts and laughs)
Myrrh, sandalwood, opium,
and dragon's blood.
Not real dragon's blood,
but dragon's blood--
SAM: True blood.
TALIESIN: Sap. It's a sap.
It's a tree sap.
Put the whole thing together.
LIAM: You've had opium
this whole time and you never...
TALIESIN: It's not, it's just poppy.
LAURA: What does it do?
TALIESIN: You will find out
when I present it.
MATT: All right.
Everyone else going to rest?
TRAVIS: No.
I ran out of dinner super fast
and I ran outside of Vax's room
and I took the jug
and I whispered into it, "oil,"
and I poured one quart of oil
on the ground outside of his door.
Looked around real quick.
Is there anyone in the hallway?
MATT: Make a perception check.
TRAVIS: 10.
MATT: Looks clear.
TRAVIS: (giggles)
And I run away.
(laughter)
MATT: All righty.
LIAM: That was super awesome
and I can't wait to see the outcome,
but before that happens,
I was standing right here
when these two walked off,
so I am waiting in the exact same spot
for my sister to return.
MATT: A lot of time passes.
LIAM: It's fine.
MATT: A few hours pass
before she returns,
but she eventually does.
LAURA: Are you still here?
You should go to bed.
LIAM: I will.
I took a little bit of a nap.
LAURA: In the dining hall?
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: What?
LIAM: You're a grown-ass woman,
and you're twice as strong as I am.
LAURA: I know.
LIAM: So your business is your business.
Just... both eyes open, yeah?
LAURA: Always. (chuckles)
I'm very perceptive.
LAURA: (cackles)
LIAM: Don't do that to me.
TALIESIN: That's two.
Two winks! Ah hah hah.
LIAM: Please don't ever
do that to me again.
LAURA: I love you so much.
LIAM: And if you do, you will
never use that wink on me again.
It is not for me.
LAURA: All right.
LIAM: Just... he's charming,
but both eyes open, please.
LAURA: I don't know
what you are talking about.
LIAM: Yeah, the fuck you don't.
I'm going to go to my room now
and see if I splat on the floor.
MATT: All right, make a perception check.
TRAVIS: Come on, big money, no whammies.
(laughter)
LAURA: Ohhh.
LIAM: Sorry, buddy, it's a 31.
MATT: As you approach the door,
you look down
and see a smear of dark,
reflective oil
across the walkway about two feet
leading up to your room.
You guys have a cluster of rooms
in this long hallway,
and it arcs around like an L.
So you guys are in this big L
of all your rooms scattered throughout.
LIAM: How thick is it? Is it viscous?
MATT: Yeah, it's pretty slippery.
LIAM: Put my hand in it. Does that stay?
MATT: The hand stays for a minute, then--
LIAM: Goes away.
MATT: Yeah, it's pretty thick.
LIAM: All right.
MATT: Also has a fume to it.
LIAM: Okay.
I'm going to scrape
a bunch of it up just into my hand,
so I have a big handful of it,
and I'm just going
to go to Grog's room,
and I'm going to slowly,
just at the door, take time to write,
Grog smells
like farts and--
LAURA: I walk by him
as he's doing this and say,
You know he can't read, right?
MARISHA: (laughs)
LIAM: I picked specifically small words!
(laughter)
LIAM: Poo.
TALIESIN: Oh, he can read that.
LIAM: And I draw--
No. I'll tell you what I do.
Pull down my breeches
and I put the oil on my butt
and I go (squelch).
(laughter)
LIAM: A little signature.
MATT: All right. Well done.
TALIESIN: Preschoolers run amok
in my gentle abode.
LIAM: Get busy living
or get busy dying. Butt-print.
MATT: All right.
You guys all get into bed.
Anything else you want to get done?
SAM: I just told Pike
she looked real pretty tonight
and I go back to my reading.
MATT: Okay.
You guys all find yourselves
back to your respective rooms,
resting for the night.
Some doors
adorned differently than others.
Partway into the evening's resting,
we'll say the wee hours of the morning,
post-midnight or so,
your door opens slightly, Vax.
You hear a little
(knocking sound) on your door.
LIAM: Yes?
MATT: You look over and you see Gilmore
pop his head in with a soft smile.
"I'm sorry if I'm waking you up."
LIAM: It's all right.
MATT: "Here."
And he produces what looks like
a folded pile of material
and throws it
on the foot of your bed and goes,
"Come, Vax, I made you a gift.
"Put it on, come walk with me awhile.
We have a lot to talk about."
LIAM: I open it up.
MATT: It's a very well-crafted silk robe
of dark blue and black.
Beaded, nice against the skin.
It's really, really nice.
LIAM: (quietly) Give me a minute.
(louder) There's a wooden screen
in the room.
I go behind it
and wipe any oil left off my butt.
(laughter)
MATT: That's fantastic.
LIAM: Everything looks all right.
And I put it on.
MATT: All right.
He waits for you patiently in the hallway.
So he begins walking along.
Puts his arm out to you.
LIAM: Take it.
MATT: You take his arm.
You guys walk up along the hallway.
He leads you to a staircase
that leads up further, and he goes,
"I know a lot has happened
these recent months.
"I've been watching from afar,
"keeping tabs on your journey
best that I can.
"But I still know so little."
You ascend the lengthy staircase
and you make your way
to the higher floor.
You eventually open
an intricate door
and walk out
onto a wide balcony on that tower
that overlooks the grounds
and the castle before you.
Beautiful moonlight, the night air.
You see the moon is nearly full
and the white light illuminates
the densely-forested countryside
surrounding the castle.
He closes the door
and walks up to you
at the edge of the balcony,
looking over it all,
elbows on the edge.
"Some time has passed, Vax.
"And much of the world
moves on to newer, greater threats.
"But true pain never really heals."
He turns to you
and steps up to you,
looking you close in the face.
"You hurt me deeply.
And continue to hurt.
"Agony, for weeks, months.
"Pain I had never experienced.
"(deepening to a growl)
It's all I can think about."
LIAM: Can I make an insight check?
MATT: You would, if you had time.
MARISHA: Oh my god!
LAURA: (gasps) I knew it. I knew it.
MARISHA: No!
MATT: The pain hits you suddenly,
before anything else does,
as you're lost in that face
and the sudden feeling,
the sensation
of terror and horror.
You suffer 18 points
of piercing damage,
and I need you to make
a constitution saving throw.
LIAM: Oh, that's my specialty.
TALIESIN: (whispering) We don't know
what the hell this is.
LIAM: Constitution save?
MATT: Mm-hmm.
LIAM: 11.
MATT: You feel the poison--
LIAM: I'll use luck.
MATT: Roll again.
LIAM: 18.
MATT: You feel what should be
a pulse of poison hit your system
and you manage to fight it off
as suddenly you look down
and there is Gilmore
holding a blade thrust into your stomach,
your robes now beginning to fill
with crimson red around the wound.
It's at that moment you see him
pull you in and stare into your face
with a very low growl,
"It's all I think about."
And you watch
as a flicker to his form happens
and you see for a second
there's a flash: not skin, but fur.
You see teeth, you see whiskers,
and the hand holding the dagger
is facing the other direction.
That's where
we're going to end tonight's session.
(shocked exclamations)
MARISHA: Nooo!
LAURA: The rakshasa?
MARISHA: Is it a rakshasa?
MATT: (laughs)
LAURA: Oh my god.
TRAVIS: Ohhhh.
MATT: We'll be back next week.
LIAM: That fucked
with my head, Matt.
LIAM: What are you doing?
TALIESIN: Wow.
MATT: What a rakshasa does.
SAM: Good job, man.
LAURA: Oh my god.
MARISHA: What the fuck?!
TALIESIN: Wow.
MARISHA: Has he been a rakshasa
the whole time?
Wait, is it the rakshasa
who's different?
Is it not Gilmore?
So many questions!
LIAM AND MATT: (laugh)
MATT: Perhaps this will be revealed
next week as we kick in
at this very moment.
LAURA: Oh my god.
Why does it always leave off
when he's about to get killed?
MARISHA: Right!
Why is it always you?
SAM: Because he's always
almost about to die.
LIAM: This one did die!
TALIESIN: Because he runs
into all the rooms first
and he makes out with everybody.
LAURA: Because you do. That's the thing.
TALIESIN: That's why it happens.
TALIESIN: He runs into the rooms first
and he puts his tongue exciting places.
MARISHA AND LAURA: (laugh)
MATT: You also happened
to lean in real close--
TALIESIN: I'm not yelling at you, man.
I'm envious.
MATT: And whisper in the ear
of the rakshasa
as he slowly slit its throat
across the floor.
TRAVIS: Oh, that's right,
you did do that.
LAURA: Oh, so what did you do?
What did you do?
LIAM: I slit its throat, yeah.
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: It's all right.
MARISHA: Hang on, wait.
MATT: It just wants to come back
and show you the same love.
MARISHA: Oh, wait,
did you get the final blow
in the rakshasa in the Slayer's Take?
LIAM: Yes, I did.
Yeah, I cut his throat.
LAURA: And you said
something shitty to him.
LIAM: He threatened my family
and I said,
"Say something
about my sister again,"
and I slit his throat.
LAURA: Oh, nice!
MATT: Oh, boy.
TALIESIN: It's about to drop.
MARISHA: But he was dead.
What the fuck is going on?!
LAURA: Was he? Did you chop him up?
MARISHA: No, because I'm not a psycho.
SAM: This is exciting.
MATT: This will be interesting
next week when we kick in.
TALIESIN: There's a fine line
between psycho and practical.
MARISHA: I can see
chopping someone's body up
might be psycho.
TALIESIN: It's not psycho
if you drive a very small car
with not a lot of trunk space.
TRAVIS: Nicely done, Matt.
LAURA: Nice, Matt.
MATT: Guys, great game tonight.
LAURA: Thanks, guys.
TRAVIS: That Raven Queen, whoo.
LIAM: Whoo.
LAURA: That can be
the name of the episode:
Yas Queen.
(laughter)
MATT: Awesome.
Well, guys, we're going to go ahead
and get home and rest.
Hope you enjoyed tonight's episode.
TALIESIN: Is there going to be
one more giveaway?
MATT: Is there?
LAURA: Are we doing another giveaway?
LIAM: There were two Loot Crates, one--
LUCAS: We'll do a giveaway
afterwards.
MATT: Okay, we'll do
a giveaway afterwards. Perfect.
One more DX Loot Crate box
coming your way.
LAURA: Thanks, Loot Crate!
LIAM: Thanks, Joe Madureira,
for the art!
LAURA: Thanks, Joe!
ASHLEY: Get your posters!
TALIESIN: It's so cool.
LAURA: Thanks, Critters,
for being awesome!
MATT: Hope you guys got to enjoy
our silly E3 couple hours
we did earlier on GameSpot.
I'm sure that'll go up soon, anyway.
But anyway, guys,
we'll see you next week.
Until then, rest well and,
is it Thursday yet? See you then.