(giggling)
TRAVIS: We're fucking doing this. Hello! Welcome
to this evening's episode of Critical Role. I will
be your DM for the evening. My name is Travis
Willingham, and this is where a bunch of us
nerdy-ass voice actors play Dungeons & Dragons.
TALIESIN: This feels sacrilege.
TRAVIS: Oh yeah. I'm going to soil this seat all
night long. Just soil it and make it mine.
Welcome! Tonight you will be enjoying a game DM'ed
by my Critical Role character, Grog. Certainly not
me. Any mistakes I make, I am not responsible for.
It is all Grog's fault. Tonight's episode is
brought to you by a wonderful sponsor, Marvel
Puzzle Quest! Sam!
SAM: In honor of Marvel Puzzle Quest sponsoring
this episode, we actually had Grog write the
advertising copy.
TRAVIS: I remember that, yeah.
SAM: It starts like this. I am Grog. I smash
things and people. Sometimes, I use a hammer, much
like another big man named Thor! Thor is not a
goliath, but he is strong, almost as strong as
Grog. I like Thor because his name is easy to say.
Thor is on a quest to a place called Marvel
Puzzle. This Marvel Puzzle Quest must be magic,
because it happens only on telly-phones and
inty-nets. You have to press buttons to rage.
That's the dumbest thing I've ever heard! Inspired
by Thor's rock, he calls it Ragnarock, the Sakaar
Arena event is going on, where you team up with
Thor in 20-person lightning rounds for prizes.
Grog would not have to team up with anyone to win
in any arena, because Grog is already the champion
named Philip. You can load-down this Marvel Puzzle
Quest for free! That means no gold, Vax-- Vex.
Fuck! You can download it at the Apple Store. I
like apples! Google Play. I like to play! Or the
Amazon app store. I like amazons. Or Steam! I
don't like steam. It is angry water and it makes
my face hurt. Also, ale. The end.
LIAM: How did you do that without moving your
mouth?
TRAVIS: It was a long online tutoring session that
Sam paid a lot of money for.
SAM: Pike wrote it down.
TRAVIS: Yeah, Pike got it all down, that's right.
Thank you, Sam.
LAURA: That sounded just like him.
SAM: My voice acting is good.
TRAVIS: Right?! It's super good. Announcements! Do
we have some merches?
LAURA: Oh, well! In addition to our Vox Machina
dice that came out last week, we've got this
amazing, oh, you know, "How do you want to do
this?" scarf! I think I'm holding it upside down.
How do you want to do this! Yeah, yours is out in
the kitchen.
LIAM: It is soft.
LAURA: It's soft and wonderful. We wanted this
last year for Christmas or holidays, and then it
didn't happen, so it's this year and it's
beautiful and amazing.
LIAM: It's not one of those scritchy-scratchy
scarves. It's soft.
TALIESIN: It's even what passes for cold out here
in beautiful California.
LAURA: If it's not cold, you can hang it on your
wall. It's a good banner.
TRAVIS: It looks so nice.
LAURA: It's beautiful and we love it.
TRAVIS: That's gorgeous.
LAURA: Isn't it? You could wear it with your
hoodie, or a t-shirt, or some Critical Role socks.
You could wear it with your Critical Role hat and
be full-on-- oh my god, I want to see someone
decked full.
SAM: That would be amazing. Wearing all the
shirts.
LAURA: All the shirts, and the hoodie, and the
hat, and maybe the necklace.
TALIESIN: And it's on Twitter.
SAM: Did we ever have socks? We have socks. I
don't own the socks!
LAURA: I have so many extra pairs at home.
TALIESIN: It was your pun! You were the one who
demanded Socks Machina.
LAURA: I was the one who was supposed to pass them
out, but then I didn't.
TRAVIS: Other announcements. Some of you will be
attending PAX Unplugged in Philadelphia. Is that
correct? Yes? Who?
LIAM: M & M, and you and I, Tal.
TALIESIN: Yes, M & M and L & T.
LIAM: Not Marshall Mathers. We meant Matt and
Marisha.
TRAVIS: Matt and Marisha. Yeah. It's November--
TALIESIN: It's in two weeks.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I don't remember the exact date--
TALIESIN: The weekend of November 17th.
TRAVIS: Right. Friday, I think, everything is on?
If you're going to PAX Unplugged, find these
patsies and go and see them. They will be there.
Patsies? I said Pats Unplugged, so I tried to play
it off of Patsy. We will be in Australia. We'll be
at Supanova.
LAURA: Yeah, the other L & T!
TRAVIS: That's right! For two weeks in November,
we'll be at Adelaide and Brisbane. So, if you're
Down Under, come see us.
LAURA: How you feeling, baby?
TRAVIS: Oh man, this is terrible. This is awful.
This is great.
LAURA: I can see this long-distance stare.
TRAVIS: Oh yeah, thousand-yard stare? Pretty much.
Anything else? What am I forgetting?
LIAM: Couple things. Next week, Marisha will be in
your chair, running a game of Honey Heist.
TRAVIS: No idea what that is.
LIAM: We're all bears.
LAURA: Except Travis and I won't be there.
SAM: We're all bears?
LIAM: They're not bears, but the three of us and
everyone else who's going to be here are going to
be bears. It's the worst episode for you not to be
here.
LAURA: I know! I'm missing the Honey Heist!
TRAVIS: Yes. Oh, we do have one last announcement.
We are excited to announce the Critical Role: Vox
Machina wrap-up. Yes. It's the pearly gates Q&A
session we've been talking about since day one. It
will be a Talks Machina episode hosted by the
illustrious and never-stinky Brian W. Foster. Live
Thursday, December 14th, in the normal Critical
Role time slot.
LAURA: So that's a Thursday.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we'll be discussing the entirety of
the Vox Machina campaign.
LAURA: That means we get to ask Matt all of the
secrets, and he has to tell us?
SAM: And we can ask each other, too! I'm going to
read that letter that I wrote to Pike! All kinds
of shit.
TRAVIS: And the note that I have says, "Please
keep an eye on various social medias as we will be
"breaking up the question submissions into five
story arcs." So more info to come on that. Yep.
TALIESIN: There are a few other-- I don't know if
they gave you the full page.
LAURA: Do we all get to talk as Grog tonight?
TALIESIN: (Grog voice) I think so, yeah.
TRAVIS: You can, but it might get you killed.
TALIESIN: There's a few other things that
happened, also. The Critical Role podcast got
updated today. It now goes to 70, I believe. We're
now at episode 70. It goes all the way to 70 now.
I know, it's great.
TRAVIS: I know what that number is.
TALIESIN: We're also, some of us are going to be
at BlizzCon tomorrow.
LAURA: Oh, that's right!
TALIESIN: You can find us. There's a Geek and
Sundry panel at 4:00 on the Epic stage at
BlizzCon. I have this in my head. Now that I don't
have a game in my head, all of this new
information has flooded through. Also, Phil LaMarr
is coming onto the Wednesday Club next week to
talk Thor and his hammer. It's going to be fun. I
was asked to inform everyone that there's going to
be no Gather Your Party, because BlizzCon, so
instead it's going to be Tales from the Loop with
Amy Dallen, Vorpahl, Sax, Rachel, Gina, and Kelly
Del Angelo is going to be GMing, and it's going to
be nuts. That'll be Friday while we're partying at
BlizzCon.
LAURA: Can I say one more? What? It was just
announced that I joined the cast of Last of Us 2!
LIAM: Look at these guns!
SAM: Everyone, do your Laura Bailey impression!
LAURA: Check out that trailer if you feel like
feeling shaky and, yeah. It's pretty brutal.
SAM: She plays the car that's on fire.
LAURA: That's right.
LIAM: Feel-good game of the year.
LAURA: I'm very excited.
TRAVIS: And you haven't told me anything about it.
Nothing.
LIAM: Did you even know she was in the game?
TRAVIS: In what game?
LAURA: It's all NDAs, you know. We're not allowed
to share it with anybody.
LIAM: No duh! Also, tomorrow will be the first
character playlist. It will be mine, so you can
find it sometime tomorrow.
SAM: Shit, I never did mine.
LIAM: You've got time!
TRAVIS: Yeah, I didn't do it. I barely did this.
LIAM: It'll drop sometime tomorrow.
LAURA: Okay, okay, okay!
TRAVIS: Anything else? Is that it? Okay. I guess
if we have no other distractions--
LIAM: Madness! Yeah, episode two dropped on
Project Alpha today. It's pretty great, it's
pretty spooky.
LAURA: I want to point out that Keyleth's dice
just rolled a one. No, I don't have my dice jail
with me. But I rolled an 18 on my own personal
dice. I rolled the best. No, Matt's roll was a
natural 20. So those ones stay out.
TRAVIS: All right, fuck it! No more stalling! It's
time for you guys to die. With that, we're going
to roll some credits for tonight's episode of
(long inhale) Critical Role. (guttural noises)
[dramatic music]
TRAVIS: I like that. I expected a little bit more. We
start this game as you guys playing your
characters. Grog has asked all of his members, all
of his fellow warriors in Vox Machina, to join him
in Scanlan's Magnificent Mansion for a game that
he has heard about.
SAM: You're turning into Grog right now?
TRAVIS: What? Yeah. Oh my god! Guys, you're all
here! Oh, thank god. Did anyone have the salad?
SAM: Yeah, yes, they just whipped up a fresh batch
of tzatziki sauce to go with it.
TRAVIS: Chicken, did anybody have the chicken
instead of the salad?
LAURA: No chicken. There's no more chicken, Grog.
TRAVIS: I was making sure it wasn't me. Hey, look,
I know we've got a night to ourselves. I was
wondering if maybe we could all, like, play a game
I heard about.
SAM: I mean, should I go wake up the others?
TRAVIS: No, no. I don't think so. It's a little
above their head. Yeah, it's only for us big
thinkers. Okay. Yeah. So, I was in this tavern the
other day, right? And I heard about this game. I
think it's called Bunions and Flagons, right. And
you are all going to play as little, itty-bitty
versions of yourselves. All you got to do is use
your imagination. Right? I'm going to tell you a
story and then you contribute, tell me what you
want to do, and I draw out little maps, and we'll
go on an adventure.
LAURA: So we're, like, baby versions of
ourselves?
TRAVIS: No, it's like, the size of your thumb,
like tiny. We're going to move them around. Yeah.
LIAM: Like Tiny Vax, but tiny everybody, this time?
SAM: Grog, I'm already tiny. Even tinier?
LAURA: You'll be the size of a pinky, maybe.
TRAVIS: Yeah, you know, you're tiny, but you've
got a big, uh, heart. What do you think?
SAM: It sounds great. I mean, this is so unlike
you.
TRAVIS: Oh, yeah, you know, I've been thinking
about it for a long time. I actually made art for
each of you guys, so like, I made Percy, right,
and then I made Vex. Right, with the ears and the
arrows. And then there's Vax'ildan, with his
little ears bleeding. Then the Scanlan.
LAURA: That looks just like you!
SAM: The eyes are haunting.
LIAM: That's drawn to scale, that one.
SAM: That's amazing! Wait, did you draw Grog? I
guess you're not playing with us? How does this work?
TRAVIS: Oh shit. No, I am playing with you. I'll
be there.
LIAM: Is there a ball involved in this game? A
ball? Games are typically-- ball, a ball.
TRAVIS: Not a bowl, but a ball. Not a bowl you eat
out of, but a ball.
LIAM: Not that my father ever played catch with
me, but you know, the type of ball that one would
play catch with, with one's father, if they gave a
shit.
TRAVIS: No, no ball.
LIAM: What kind of game is it, then?
TRAVIS: I'm going to put everything on this big
table in front of us. It'll be right in front of
you, and you get to sit in your chair.
TALIESIN: Like cards, then?
TRAVIS: Yeah, it's pretty nice.
LAURA: Can your servants bring over some liquor?
Because I think we're going to need it.
SAM: Keep the wine coming!
TRAVIS: Yeah, always a good idea, when playing
this game, to drink heavily.
LIAM: Vegan wine, yeah.
TRAVIS: Yes, all right, so.
SAM: I should warn you, I'm a power gamer.
TRAVIS: Power gamer?
SAM: Yeah, you know, I get really into it.
TRAVIS: In your brain theaters, all right, I want
you to imagine that Vox Machina has been
successful on its latest mission. We are
triumphant!
LAURA: As always.
TRAVIS: As always. It's the wee hours of the
morning, and we have found our way to a tavern.
Small, maybe off the beaten path, right. It's
shambly outside. We go in and it's deserted,
right? There's only like one other couple in the
whole fucking place. We got the run of the lot. We
go in. It's time to drink. We're raising glasses,
we're cheering, we're drinking. Everybody's
boozing, right? Yeah! Who wants to make a toast?
LIAM: This is the game?
SAM: I'll make a toast. I'll make a toast, yeah.
(clears throat) Right then! My character has a
different accent than Scanlan does.
TRAVIS: You're just playing you, though.
SAM: Well, I know, but I want to get into it,
right?
LAURA: No, I like it.
SAM: Right then, we did a really good job in the
fight today! So I think that we should all propose
a toast to the one that fell. Keyleth. I'm sorry
she'll never be joining us again. To Keyleth.
LIAM: That's an odd story choice to make.
TRAVIS: Cheers, yeah. To Keyleth. Underpowered her
whole life, really. Nothing at her disposal.
LIAM: The last of us.
TRAVIS: May her memory live forever.
LAURA: Mm-hmm.
TRAVIS: As we are drinking, and we're on, like--
What's a big number? Our second cup. Everybody's
really starting to feel it a little bit,
especially our little gnome, Pike. Pike gets up on
the table, right. She's like-- Pike! Flower! My
friend. Pike gets up and she's like, "You guys, I
"love being your friend."
TALIESIN: Too real.
LIAM: The dimensional distortion there for a
second!
TRAVIS: "I'm really, like, all of your friend! You
are good!" And she turns to you, Vex, yeah, and
she's like, "You know, we're so close! And you
know, I--" (gulping) And you start to see, right,
that maybe she's had one too many, which is really
saying something for that little tank. She goes,
"Ah, nope. I got it-- urp!" And in that moment you
start to see all the color come up to her face. I
need you to roll a dexterity check.
LAURA: Okay.
SAM: What does that mean? What's a dexterity
check?
TRAVIS: I don't know, I heard a guy at the bar say
it.
LAURA: I'm going to roll one of these fancy gems
that I have. All right. Oh, that's really good! Oh
wait, just a check? 11 plus-- 18. No, 29! That
means it's 29.
SAM: How do you know what to add?
LAURA: I'm really smart! I'm very smart.
TRAVIS: Yeah, totally, right. So, 29, that's
great! At the last moment you see what is bound to
be a shoot of vomit in your face and you just,
boop! Duck out of the way. She catches it with her
lips and this little stream of bile comes, like,
shooting out and goes over your shoulder.
LAURA: I want to grab a glass and try to catch it
in a mug. So it doesn't get all over the floor,
you know.
TRAVIS: You raise the glass right in front of her
face. As she sees it, she sees more alcohol in the
glass, and she goes, "Mm!" and turns away, and
paints the bar. Except that other couple that was
in the bar with you, they're right in the path of
her destruction. Yeah. And she Alphabits and
Lucky Charms all over the place. All over the
table on this couple. You see, as this gentleman,
this greenish-skinned with large lower teeth and a
hood and a cloak, stands up and starts to turn
toward you. He's like, "What the fuck?"
LAURA: So sorry about all of the vomit.
TRAVIS: "Yeah. Is she with you?"
LAURA: Yes, she is.
TRAVIS: Well, I'm sure you guys are going to take
care of this, right? I mean, it's in my drink,
"it's on my food, it's on my--" And you see with
him is also this very lovely lady. She's got
slightly bluish skin and she is also, like,
staring in revulsion at all of this mess that
she's wearing. Right? It's on her. Maybe there's a
little bit hanging off of her lip. She starts to
go, "Wha-- (gulping) what--"
LAURA: Oh, no! I hold the cup under her mouth as
well.
TRAVIS: She holds it in, but this really
infuriates this half-orc looking gentleman. He
stands up, right? and he's like, "That's it. You
and I-- You! You and I, we're coming to blows. I
"want answers for this."
LIAM: I was just standing here!
TRAVIS: "Nope, I've stood up! I'm making a point
that doesn't make any difference, and I'm too
"embarrassed to back down now."
LIAM: Yes, but wait one second. Grog, you're very
good at this. Have you been spending time at the
theater and not telling us?
TRAVIS: What's a theater?
LIAM: Let's fight this fucking guy! What do I do?
Do I actually use this, or what do I do? Are we
fighting?
TRAVIS: Nope, imagination weapons. Yeah. You tell
me what you want to do.
LIAM: I would like to poke him in the eyes.
TRAVIS: With what?
LIAM: These.
TRAVIS: Oh, yeah! Okay. So, you, yeah! Take one of
those big, globular, like, d20 dices.
LIAM: All right, I'm going to use this weird--
TRAVIS: The mansion provides.
LIAM: I'm going to use this weird purple one,
where you can't read the numbers on it.
TRAVIS: Roll to hit.
LIAM: I think it says 13. And what?
TRAVIS: The servants bring over a sheet that has
modifiers for you to use. Yeah. These are things
you add.
LAURA: What do you add to it?
LIAM: I think I'm improvising this weapon, is that
accurate? All right, so I would add, I have no
fucking idea. You know what I'm going to do? I'm
going to add my wisdom modifier.
LAURA: Why wisdom? No, it's strength!
LIAM: Why would I add anything?
TRAVIS: He's pretty wise.
LIAM: How strong are my fingers? Is that the
point? Sure, I'll add my strength to my fingers.
So 15.
TRAVIS: 15? That's all you need. You, boink, right
in his eyes, and he's like, "Argh! In the eyes!"
LIAM: That's fucking hilarious.
TRAVIS: Right. The girl stands up at the table and
she's like, "No! No, please! Not his eyes!"
LIAM: I have four of these.
TRAVIS: Right, and she sees you standing there,
ready to go, and she's like, "No, please, please!"
LIAM: You threaten me all the time!
LAURA: Yeah, but she doesn't have any weapons on
her!
LIAM: Neither do I!
TRAVIS: Actually, do you want to see if she has
any weapons?
LAURA: Oh, well I'm very perceptive, Grog. You
know that.
TRAVIS: Oh, you are perceptive. Right. Roll a
perception check.
LAURA: Okay.
LIAM: This game thinks of everything.
LAURA: A 31.
TRAVIS: You don't see anything, unfortunately.
That's just unfortunate.
LAURA: Grog, 31 is higher than 15. 31's really
high. It's high.
TRAVIS: Right, so you see her genealogy going
back, like, four generations.
LAURA: Do you even know what genealogy is?
TRAVIS: Yeah, it's like, you know, a blue denim.
Yeah. So you see at her side this spear that's
laying up against the table. Yeah, yeah. I don't
know how you missed it the first time. It's a
fucking spear, right there. She stands up and
she's like, "No, no, please! No more eye-poking!"
SAM: Grog, Grog! I'm going to try to turn
invisible, if that's all right. Can I just do that?
TRAVIS: I don't know. Can you just do that, or do
you roll?
SAM: I normally just do that.
TRAVIS: Okay. Go invisible.
SAM: All right, I'm going to go invisible and I'm going
to try to swipe the spear before she gets to it.
TRAVIS: Okay. Roll a stealth check.
SAM: Okay. Seven, plus-- ten. So, it's ten. This
many.
TRAVIS: Ten total? Okay, great. So you go
invisible, right, and you walk over behind the
blue-skinned lady and right as you get to the
spear, you grab for it, but there's something that
catches your eye and you fumble the spear and it
falls to the ground.
SAM: Oh shite, I dropped the spear!
TRAVIS: Good, I love it. As she hears the spear
fall, she turns and she swings her hand wildly,
catching you dead in the face. Boom! Knocks you
back. You fly back onto your back five feet. You
take two points of damage.
LIAM: You're intelligent. Do you understand what
is happening?
TALIESIN: Not in the least. None of this makes any
sense. These numbers seem completely arbitrary.
SAM: He's so good at this, though! I feel like we
should keep supporting this!
LAURA: I feel like we're in a tavern right now.
TALIESIN: I think he might have eaten
something in the back. This is not normal.
SAM: He's never been good at anything intellectual
and now this is it! So maybe we should support him
and go with it.
TRAVIS: Scanlan, the reason that you fumbled for
the spear is that you saw this small little bundle
next to her chair. In fact, it looks like--
LAURA: Is it a baby?
TRAVIS: It looks like a small baby, all swaddled
up in cloth. No, small.
TALIESIN: Is the baby also covered in vomit?
LAURA: Wait, I have a question. Are we teeny at
this moment, or are we normal sized?
TRAVIS: No, yeah, I'm going to put this out like,
what's that game where you move the--?
SAM: Sorry?
LAURA: Parcheesi? Checkers? Chess?
TRAVIS: Yeah, that one! We'll be like that on a
big map.
SAM: Really quickly into my earring, I say: She's
got a baby with her!
LAURA: Oh. Are we going to fight a baby now?
SAM: I don't know, just thought you might like to
know.
TRAVIS: Well, you're not that far from her, so she
goes, "It is a baby, it is! Please, we just want
"to leave, I'm sorry if we caused you any
trouble!"
LAURA: Does it really look like a baby?
TRAVIS: Would you want to go over to it?
LAURA: I want to go over and look at the baby.
TRAVIS: Yeah, walk on over and make a perception
check. It's a baby.
LIAM: I'm sorry, I know I keep slowing things down
here, but in this imagination game, can we do
anything that we do in life?
TRAVIS: Good question. Yeah!
LIAM: Can we do things that we can't do in life?
TRAVIS: You can try.
LIAM: That sent a shiver down my spine.
TRAVIS: Pretty much, if you get an idea and you
want to try it, you ask me. We'll roll a dice.
Then I'll let you know how it goes.
LIAM: I would like to cast Faerie Fire.
SAM: You don't do that.
LIAM: Yes I do. I had the craziest dream last
night, Scanlan.
SAM: That you became part druid?
LIAM: Yeah. And then I died, and then I wasn't
here, and then I was. And then there was like,
three weeks where I was a father in this other
city, washing dishes, and I had this "car." There
were no horses but it was just wind. I had these
kids. I don't know who these kids were.
TALIESIN: I feel like we have warned you about
eating cheese before bed.
TRAVIS: The moldy cheese. The point of this is,
there's a small baby, right, and you've got a
couple covered in puke, and she's asking if maybe
they can leave instead of-- avoid further scrum.
LAURA: Well, I fink we should let them leave! I
"fink?" I'm listening to Grog too much!
LIAM: I'm going to save that for later. I'm going
to put these away.
TRAVIS: You see his demeanor, like, he totally
goes, like, another eye-poking avoided. Whoosh.
Right? He says, "All right. People make mistakes.
Try to enjoy the rest of your night." He goes over
and gets his blue-skinned wife up, and she grabs
her little bundle, and they start to make their
way out of the tavern.
TALIESIN: I grab the spear.
TRAVIS: You do?
TALIESIN: Yes. They didn't take it, so I will take
it now. It's my spear.
LAURA: That's terrible! They do seem suspicious.
Can I read their lips on the way out? Are they
talking? Can I read their lips?
TRAVIS: Sure.
LAURA: What are they saying?
TRAVIS: Roll a d20.
LIAM: Everybody seems to know what's going on.
LAURA: Am I adding anything to it?
TRAVIS: Perception. Do a perception check.
SAM: Just "yes, and," Vax. Yes, and.
LAURA: 24. That's good.
TRAVIS: Whoa. So you see that she's actually going
like, "That was so embarrassing. I want to go home
"and take my clothes off and you and I go and we'll
have a great night."
LAURA: Okay, I think they really want to go bone.
TRAVIS: Yeah, lots of boning in their
future.
TALIESIN: I wish to examine the spear. Is it a
special spear? Is it an interesting spear? Does it
do anything? Does it require batteries?
TRAVIS: Batteries? What are batteries? You see the
spear is a long wooden pole wrapped with some
cloth where you might hold it with your hands. At
the tip is a very rusted metal sharp point at the
tip. You got yourself a spear. So now, now you
truly have the tavern to yourself. It's just us
five. Yeah. You see Grog sitting there and he's
aghast at how rude Pike was to puke all over this
couple, and that you would go and poke them in the
eyes. Grog's very dignified. No, that's not true.
Grog goes over to Pike and goes, "Okay, Pikey-poo,
maybe it's time to, let's put you to sleep
"upstairs. Barkeep!" And you look behind the
tavern, and there is a-- fuck, in your mind, he's
fucking over there.
TALIESIN: It's a muscle reaction, it's
inevitable.
TRAVIS: He might be over there in a second. Stay
with me. So Grog picks up Pike and goes over to
the barkeep and he's like, "Do you have any rooms
that I can put this little gnome in?" And he's
like, "Yes, I have, I do! Have rooms!"
SAM: Good voice, Grog!
TRAVIS: (wheezing) "How much money do you have?"
And Grog's like, "I have ten gold." And he's like,
"Sure, that'll fucking do it!" So Grog goes and
takes Pike upstairs, puts her in a room, comes
back down. And like, "Whoa, she is hammered."
LAURA: Ten gold for a room, Grog, is a lot.
TRAVIS: I don't know if you know, but I'm super
rich because I never really buy anything.
LAURA: You do buy some things.
TRAVIS: I always seem to find the money. That's
what I do. Find the money. So now, it turns out
that your cups are all slightly emptier than
before. Your plates are rather empty. It doesn't
really seem like we want the night to end. Does
somebody want to maybe check with the barkeep and
see if he has any more?
LIAM: Grog-- not Grog, but Grog-- did we get any
points?
TRAVIS: Points?
SAM: He does not understand this game.
TRAVIS: Oh, right. Oh! Like, did we do something
right?
LIAM: Did we win?
TRAVIS: No. Actually, like, at the end of this
story, you either win or lose, like, overall.
LAURA: Oh, are you going to judge us? Does one of
us win more than other people?
TRAVIS: Potentially.
TALIESIN: Did you not take any drama classes as a
child?
LAURA: I'm going to win so good.
TRAVIS: Don't you like the theater?
LIAM: I love the theater. But we're playing a
game!
TRAVIS: Oh yeah, no, it's one big long game.
Preferably three to four hours long.
LAURA: That's a long game, Grog.
LIAM: I thought we were near the end of the game,
but we're just getting started?
TRAVIS: Oh, we're just kicking this shit off. Get
comfy.
SAM: If we're going to be here for a while, Grog,
can I have some of my invisible servants come in
and lightly play a light accompaniment music? Play
some strings or flutes?
TRAVIS: Set the tone, the mood? Totally.
SAM: Oh there it is, it's nice.
TRAVIS: Hold on, can you ask them to bring in
some, like, meats? Like a meat and cheese plate?
SAM: I actually can't.
TRAVIS: Come on, Kaylie won't fucking know,
please! I'm so tired of this green shit!
SAM: I will know. She'll be able to read it on my
face. She can see all of my lies.
LIAM: It's a game! It's make-believe!
SAM: Oh, if it's make-believe, then, here you go!
Here are your meats for you, right there!
TRAVIS: Nope, you got to stay in the game. That's
only in the game with that stuff. So you're in the
tavern. You need more to drink. Who wants to go
talk to the barkeep?
TALIESIN: I'll go talk to the barkeep.
TRAVIS: What do you do?
TALIESIN: Another round for everyone. Your
finest.
TRAVIS: "Eh?"
TALIESIN: (shouting) Another round for everyone!
Your finest!
TRAVIS: "Oh yes, yeah, oh! To drink, or to eat?"
TALIESIN: To drink! Another round of drinks! For
everyone!
SAM: Ask him his name.
TALIESIN: Why would I do--? Your finest! What's
your name?
LIAM: We want to get fucked up!
TALIESIN: Why do I care about his name?
SAM: Because I want to hear what Grog comes up
with!
TALIESIN: But his name is Grog!
TRAVIS: "My name? It's Bob!"
TALIESIN: All right, I'll admit, that is quite
charming.
TRAVIS: "Bobaline is my full name, but people call
me Bob!"
TALIESIN: Bobaline, I feel, really, is quite
appropriate.
TRAVIS: "It's a family name. If you want more to
drink, unfortunately, I was not planning on you
"being here. It's quite late. I do, however, have
more food in the pantry below the bar. Or, there
"are some extra casks of ale out with the pigs."
TALIESIN: I don't understand how a bar runs out of
alcohol after one round for five of us.
SAM: It's not run out, he said he has more
downstairs, or there's some outside in the back.
LAURA: I think we should go down to the cellar.
LIAM: Bobaline, are you going to go down and get
it and bring it up, or are you--
TRAVIS: "No, unfortunately, me son is the one
who normally goes and gets it. He's not here."
TALIESIN: What's your son's name?
TRAVIS: "Timothy!"
TALIESIN: Bobaline and Timothy. That's excellent.
I should write that down to make sure that you
don't forget it or screw it up later.
SAM: Vax, he's presenting us with a choice.
We, as a group, must make this choice together.
LIAM: He's sending us to his basement.
That's creepy!
TRAVIS: "Well, it's not a huge deal, I just need
one of you to either go down and get the food,
"and one of you to go get the ale."
LAURA: You and I will go down to the cellar.
TRAVIS: "Yeah, you go down to the cellar, and
Grog-- I will go get the ale, unless somebody
"wants to go out in the pig sty. I'll go."
LIAM: We will go with you, Grog, to the pig sty.
TRAVIS: "Or do you two want to go get the ale?"
SAM: I volunteer to go to the sty.
TRAVIS: Okay, cool. So you, Vax, and Sam,
you make your way out back. Scanlan!
LIAM: I'm not going to the basement, because once,
in Syngorn, a comic book shop owner tried to get
me to go to the basement to look at comic books,
and I'm not doing that. Yeah. So good luck in the
cellar. Let's go see the pigs.
TRAVIS: As Vax and Scanlan start to head
toward the back door, Vex and Percy,
would you like to try and find
the latch under the bar that leads--
LAURA: Yes, we would.
TRAVIS: You find it. Fuck, it's right there.
Good job. Right, so you lift the latch in the
floor and you go down. It's a very small room that
has different salted meats and cheeses, and some
bread and stuff like that.
TALIESIN: This cellar has better food
than your mansion.
LAURA: We take it all.
TRAVIS: You take armfuls?
LAURA: After a little bit.
TRAVIS: I mean, do you want to see maybe what else
is down there?
LAURA: Yeah, let's see what else is down there.
TRAVIS: Roll perception checks.
LAURA: Oh, this is good. 28.
TALIESIN: 23.
TRAVIS: Nice. You also see three of these bottles
with hided, belted locks on it, and it says
"sandkheg" on there. It looks really, really
expensive. There's three bottles of that. Yep.
LAURA: I'm going to try to pick the lock so I can
get them. Can I do that?
TRAVIS: Sure. What do you roll to pick a lock?
LIAM: I don't know whether to shit or go blind in
this game.
LAURA: What do I roll to pick a lock?
SAM: Vax has no idea.
TRAVIS: What about Liam? What does Liam know?
LIAM: Intelligence, I'd think.
Yeah, you have to know how locks work.
LAURA: I'd think it's dexterity or something.
TALIESIN: Dex proficiency, for god's sake.
TRAVIS: Roll for it.
LIAM: What are those words you're using?!
TALIESIN: Were you never in school?
Have you never done this before?
LIAM: I didn't pay attention through any of
school. I copied everything that she wrote down.
TALIESIN: This is everything I did in school.
I remember this game.
LAURA: 15.
TRAVIS: Oh, that's not very good. Unfortunately,
this is a better expensive bottle of sandkheg.
After trying to break the lock, or pick it, you
get the lockpick stuck in there. Yeah, and it's
all fucked up. But you're really resilient and you
smash the top of the bottle. It seems stupid to
have a lock on a glass bottle, but it works.
LAURA: I don't want to smash the bottle.
TRAVIS: You did it already. It's too bad.
LAURA: Is all the drink spilling out?
TRAVIS: No! You just smashed the top off. You have
the rest of the bottle.
LAURA: Well, okay. That's good.
TALIESIN: We should try it.
LAURA: Yeah!
TRAVIS: You got some salted meats, some cheese.
LAURA: And this bottle of fanciness. We have to
drink it all because we can't close it back up.
TRAVIS: You also see some dead rats in the corner,
some empty shelves, and one old leathery book.
Yeah, it's all dusty shelves.
TALIESIN: Oh shelves!
LAURA: Do you see anything else, Percy?
TRAVIS: There's a leathery book on one of the
shelves.
TALIESIN: There's a leathery book?! I'm taking the
leathery book, my god.
TRAVIS: Do you want to open it up?
TALIESIN: I want to read the title.
There should be a title on the cover.
Books have titles on covers.
TRAVIS: Yeah, they do. It says "Ledger."
TALIESIN: It says "Ledger." I'm going to open up
the book.
LAURA: While he opens it, I'm going to take a sip
of this fancy wine.
TRAVIS: Great, yeah. Roll a constitution check.
SAM: You've really caught onto this game quickly.
LAURA: 13.
TRAVIS: 13. Right. You take a sip, and boy does it
burn. You're like (gagging). You feel like you
could breathe fire. It starts to spread down into
your chest.
LAURA: Does it make me breathe fire?
TRAVIS: No, not literal fire, like (gasps) fire.
TALIESIN: Vex, why are you making a Keyleth face?
LAURA: This-- what is it called?
TRAVIS: Sandkheg.
LAURA: This sandkheg is really strong.
TALIESIN: Well, I've got to try this really
quickly.
TRAVIS: Oh, Jesus.
TALIESIN: I take a sip. Sip. Sip.
LAURA: You have to be very careful because it's
jagged on the top.
TALIESIN: I know, you have to be very careful
because there's broken glass.
TRAVIS: Roll a constitution check.
LIAM: What kind of role playing are we doing
here?
TALIESIN: The best kind. No. I rolled a four.
TRAVIS: Yeah, so the warmth starts to spread,
right?
TALIESIN: Oh my.
TRAVIS: You also feel this immediate desire to
upchuck the liquid because it's so strong. In your
rush to cover your mouth, you drop the bottle and
it shatters all over the floor.
SAM: Do we hear it upstairs?
TALIESIN: We speak of this never again.
LAURA: Ever. Nobody knows.
TALIESIN: We should open the book, though.
LAURA: Yeah, let's open this ledger.
TRAVIS: You open the book, and it's got numbers in
it with letters.
TALIESIN: Are they in a particular order?
TRAVIS: I guess.
TALIESIN: Using my deftness of wit, can I start to
put together some meaning to the numbers and words
within this ledger?
TRAVIS: Unfortunately, no, it's beyond your mental
prowess. So, back upstairs!
TALIESIN: Goddamn it!
LAURA: All of the food. We're carrying meat and
cheese and all of that.
TRAVIS: Y'all want to stay in the pantry or come
back up?
LAURA: We did for a while.
TRAVIS: Yeah, you stayed down there for a while?
TALIESIN: For a while.
LAURA: And then we came back up.
TRAVIS: Fair enough. Vax and Scanlan, y'all head
out back.
LIAM: We're getting ale for our buddy, Grog. Got
to keep the big man hydrated.
SAM: That's right, we have to. He'll know if we
don't get him some, so let's go sneaky back there
to make sure there's no monsters hiding.
LIAM: Do you know how to sneak with dice?
SAM: Sure!
LIAM: How do you do it?
SAM: We tell our Bunion Master that we're going
out there to sneak around and then he'll make it
happen for us.
LIAM: Okay. Night at the Improv, here we go.
TRAVIS: Use your imagination.You get to the back
door and you push it open. You see before you,
right, a pen full of muck, mud and these three
large hogs rolling around in the muck. Off to the
side, you see a large cask of ale.
LIAM: Neither one of us are very strong, can you
do your handy thing?
SAM: To pick it up?
LIAM: Yeah, I don't want to get all muddy and
shit, could you just grab it from here?
SAM: Sure I could, but shouldn't we try to lift it
first?
LIAM: It seems to plebeian, don't you want to skip
the hard work?
SAM: Sure, right, this is all make-'em-up. It
doesn't matter, right?
LIAM: Sure! I can make a purple hand!
Can I make a purple hand? Why not?
I thought it was imagination?!
TRAVIS: No, it's not what you do.
TALIESIN: You're imagining wrong.
LIAM: Is my fun wrong?! I guess it is! All right,
well, show me how to handle a pig.
SAM: I'm picking up a pig?
LAURA: No, it's a cattle-- I'm not there.
Yes, I am. I am still technically here.
TRAVIS: No, actually, you're not there.
LIAM: I'm so confused!
TRAVIS: Percy and Vex have made their way back to
the table. You two are--
LIAM: But we're right at the table!
TRAVIS: No, the table in the tavern. You two are
at the back hall room there.
SAM: And we're trying to move a pig?
LAURA: No, a cask!
SAM: That's what I thought.
TALIESIN: Can't tell them, you're not there!
LIAM: No, I got confused for a second because this
is confusing.
TRAVIS: It's normally my job, but yeah.
LIAM: Yeah! I'm roleplaying a little bit today.
You're going to grab the booze
and carry it back with us.
SAM: Yeah! I'd like to cast Bigby's Hand and lift
the cask.
TALIESIN: Don't forget the pig.
TRAVIS: Right. It's simple enough. So Bigby's Hand
just appears around the cask and it wraps its
purple fingers around the cask, picks it up, and
holds it in mid-air.
SAM: All right. Come with me, O hand that holds
the cask of our dreams.
TRAVIS: Flavor. That's some good color. You guys
should really step up your fucking game. Leave it
to the bard, but yeah. Nice job. You get 300 XP for
that performance.
SAM: I got points!
LIAM: What did he get?
TRAVIS: Don't worry about it.
SAM: Wait, I got 300 points. I'm winning!
TRAVIS: You remember being in school and they gave
out gold stars when you did good things?
LIAM: I was daydreaming, but I guess.
LAURA: I'm starting to take notes.
LIAM: But you said there were no points and you
got points?
TRAVIS: No, they're not points. They're XP.
SAM: What does that stand for, Grog?
TRAVIS: Xylophone Players.
TALIESIN: 300 Xylophone Players. My god,
you could retire on that! In fact,
you could retire quite well on that.
LIAM: That's a fancy word!
TRAVIS: So you get the cask and you draw it back
over.
LIAM: It's no mystery that Grog likes you better
than he likes me, so--
LAURA: Shut up! Let Grog tell a story!
TRAVIS: Did you bring the cask back to the table?
SAM: Yes, I float it back in and I present it in
front of the barkeep and say, Bob!
TRAVIS: "Yes?"
SAM: Your cask awaits.
TRAVIS: "You did a really great job. You guys are
good. Good. Please, I'll give 70 percent off,
"because shit, no one's here, so nobody will
know."
LAURA: Great! That's wonderful. Thank you, Bob.
TRAVIS: "So please take, enjoy. It's just you."
So you take the cask and the food back over. You
two look a little disheveled, like you may have
fallen down some stairs, going into the pantry.
TALIESIN: That may have happened.
TRAVIS: That's fucking gross. Yeah, so you pour
ale all around, you get your cups full again.
You've got a little more food into your belly,
and you make one more toast for the night
to your successes as warriors, victorious.
Who wants to make a toast?
SAM: This would be a good opportunity
for you all to get some XP.
LAURA: Oh right. I would like to make a toast
to the greatest fighters, to someone
who used his smart hand to carry a cask of ale.
This sucks. I'm really shitty.
TRAVIS: No, that's good.
TALIESIN and LAURA: And to Grog!
LAURA: Who's so strong and brave and very smart.
TALIESIN: Extremely intelligent.
LAURA: And to all of this meat that we get to
eat!
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA, TALIESIN, and TRAVIS: Cheers!
TRAVIS: Everybody drink to that.
LAURA: What did you actually call it,
the purple hand? What'd you call that?
SAM: I call it Bigby's Hand!
LAURA: This is not in character.
I'm asking you.
SAM: Oh. I call it Bigby's Hand because a man
named Bigby invented it.
TRAVIS: Yeah. It's supposed to be us. It's a
concept.
SAM: I don't know anything about this Bigby.
TALIESIN: I was assuming it was actually his hand
you were manifesting, like he was a large purple--
SAM: I learned it from another bard a long time
ago.
LIAM: What did he play?
TALIESIN: Was his name Bigby?
SAM: It was a he. He was actually a stand-up
comedian. That was his thing.
TALIESIN: Oh, so it was an applause hand?
SAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: As the alcohol starts to go down the
throats into the belly, down into your belly,
the world starts to get a little hazy.
SAM: Oh no. Did we just drink poison?
LAURA: Oh no! Did this stupid Bobaline poison us?
TRAVIS: You got a 150 XP for saying it. Also, you
feel a lot of warmth in your face and you feel
almost as if the world's been tilted on you. Like
someone's pushing you around and you don't have
much control. You reach out to steady yourself and
to warn your other friends, when all of a sudden,
the lights go out and you feel gravity take over
and you just fall.
TALIESIN: Timothy, is that you?
TRAVIS: And fall, and fall. The end.
SAM: Wait, that's it?
TRAVIS: No, that's not the end!
SAM: But we were just having fun!
TRAVIS: (shouting) You come to! (normal voice)
Sorry, Chris. You come to and you're lying on the
floor. It's cold.
LAURA: Do we feel drunk?
TRAVIS: Nope.
LIAM: Do we feel hungover?
TRAVIS: Nope. It's cold. It feels like stone
underneath you. It's moist and damp. There's dirt
everywhere and it feels uneven. You open your eyes
and the light of the tavern is not the same as it
was before. In fact, you're on a wood floor and
you remember, but now there's stones beneath you.
LIAM: Do we have all our shit?
TRAVIS: You got all your stuff. You look and you
seem to be in some sort of dimly-lit cavern. You
all look around and you see your mates around you.
All there, but the environment has changed.
LAURA: Is there any light?
TRAVIS: There is light. You look around and there
seem to be along these stone walls around you,
random torches. So there is some torchlight down
here.
SAM: He really paints a vivid picture.
LAURA: Can I stand up?
TRAVIS: You can.
LAURA: Can I go grab a torch?
TRAVIS: Would you like to? They're a bit high,
unfortunately. They're about eight to ten feet
off the floor. It's just out of your reach.
LAURA: Can I use my broom to fly up and grab it?
TRAVIS: You can, if you want to.
LAURA: Yeah, I'll grab it.
TRAVIS: All right. So you hop onto your broom,
kick up off the ground and grab the torch. You
pull it out and off in the distance somewhere,
you hear a scraping sound. Very faint,
but you hear it.
TALIESIN: What strange intelligence would have
gone through this hall and lit torches that were
eight to ten feet off the ground? That's very
particular.
SAM: You have that special sense! Try to sense if
there's any flagons around?
LAURA: Yeah, I'm going to try to sense if there's
any flagons. Big ones, with wings.
TRAVIS: Roll a perception check.
LAURA: No, it's not a perception check,
it's just my--
TALIESIN: Flagon sense?
LAURA: It's my flagon sense.
TRAVIS: Is it? Yeah. Yeah, go for it.
LAURA: Are there any flagons around?
TRAVIS: Yeah, no fucking flagons around.
LAURA: I'm going to mark off a spell.
LIAM: What are all these papers?
TRAVIS: Currently, Vex is the only one who's
gotten to her feet and grabbed a torch. Are you
all standing up, looking around?
LAURA: Just be quiet. I'm going to cast Pass
Without a Trace on all of us.
So that we're quiet.
LIAM: Can I hide?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: I can? I'm going to hide.
Do your thingy, though.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Everybody please roll a stealth
check.
LIAM: You don't have to clap or--
LAURA: I've already cast it. I cast it already,
but roll a stealth check.
SAM: 18, Grog!
TRAVIS: 18. Good.
LAURA: Add ten to it!
SAM: I did already.
TALIESIN: 19.
LAURA: I don't know what that means, but I don't
know why would you do that.
TALIESIN: Why not add ten?
SAM: Oh, we got something!
Something's happening!
TALIESIN: Have you been at the arts and crafts?
TRAVIS: Okay, now listen. This is where the fun
starts.
LIAM: What are these things?
TALIESIN: Let's not look. He's setting something
up. I'm not going to look. Close your eyes.
SAM: Marvel Puzzle Quest. It's a fantastic game.
LAURA: Do you need help?
TRAVIS: No.
SAM: It looks like two boobs.
LAURA: It looks like a butt with a staple in it.
LIAM: You've seen that before. Oh, I'm right at
the crack! Of course. That guy looks just like
you, Grog! He looks like me! That looks like
Scanlan!
TALIESIN: That looks nothing like me.
LIAM: That doesn't look like you at all.
TALIESIN: It's totally off.
LAURA: Where's Trinket?
(gasps) Grog! Trinket's here!
Trinket's popping out of my necklace!
TRAVIS: There you go.
LIAM: What, you got a fucking bear?
TRAVIS: Look at that. You're all there.
LIAM: Where did you get these toys?
TRAVIS: I stole it from a small child. So as you
look around your environment, you notice the floor
is stone, the walls are stone and you seem to be
in some sort of circular cavern. There's also a
domed ceiling above you. There is just pure wall
for most of this circular room except for an area
that seems to lead into another chamber beyond.
LAURA: Oh, I have an idea! Can I shoot one of my
oracle arrows and see what's in the other room?
TRAVIS: You may. Roll an attack.
LIAM: Also, I rolled a 39 for stealth.
LAURA: I rolled a 45.
LIAM: Is that good? Is 39 better or worse than
45?
TRAVIS: It's so good, in fact, that you take one
step into the wall and you turn and face it like
the creepy person from Blair Witch, and you stay
there.
LAURA: 32.
TRAVIS: 32. Great. So you turn so that you can see
into the other cavern and you shoot your oracle
arrow. And your sight goes (zooming) and you see
it fly approximately (counting) 25 feet and it
just hits another wall made of stone in the
cavern, very similar to the one you're in.
LAURA: It looks the exact same?
TRAVIS: Yeah, almost identical to this one.
LIAM: Jeez, Grog, you're inspired today.
TALIESIN: This is very impressive.
SAM: Come on, even in this imaginary game, we're
invincible heroes of justice. Let's just go look!
LAURA: Can we see forward? Can we see?
LIAM: Well, hold on. We know that I like to stick
my dick into things, so why don't I creep ahead
and see what is happening?
TRAVIS: Very smart. Make a perception check.
LAURA: Watch for traps! You don't want to explode,
I don't know what Grog has set up for us.
LIAM: I'll roll this one with the book on it
because I feel goodness from it. I got a 19 on
that, plus perception. Oh my gosh, that's really
good. 33 for perception.
TRAVIS: You open your eyes, and because you're
staring at the wall like a nerd, you notice the
mortar is very fine. Would anybody like to make a
perception check besides Vax?
LAURA: I would like to look around the whole
room.
TRAVIS: Vex, please roll a perception check.
LIAM: I didn't understand the rules!
TALIESIN: 17 for me.
TRAVIS: Oh, very nice, Percival.
LAURA: 34 for me.
TRAVIS: 34, that is a high perception. You should
be a rogue.
LIAM: It's not as high as mine, I would like to
point out, but I was facing the wall.
TRAVIS: So you see that the room extends out to an
edge and you move to the middle and you see that
these two rooms seem to be identical. There are
torches lighting your way, and above you on this
rounded ceiling, there are two hatches. Iron
hatches. And above them you see maybe a chute.
And you wonder, as you see water dripping
from the hatches in the ceiling,
if that might have been how you got in this room.
LAURA: Can I use my broom to fly up and check out
that hatch?
TRAVIS: You may. So you fly up and you get to the
hatch, and it's solid iron, with rusted-- There's
water dripping out of it. And you see there is a
chute indeed. No light coming from it.
LAURA: It's bars?
TRAVIS: Bars, but it looks as if it goes straight
up, and up, and up.
LAURA: Is it closed off?
TRAVIS: It is. It's closed very securely.
LAURA: Can I try to pull them?
LIAM: May I turn around from the wall first?
TRAVIS: You may, yes. There you go.
LIAM: Can I use some sort of perception or
insight or one of these numbers to figure out if
we are in a room shaped like a cock and balls?
TRAVIS: You may. Roll a perception check.
LIAM: Okay. I've got a total of 23, Grog.
TRAVIS: You move forward, and as you approach Vex,
you do see there is an additional hallway
that extends forward. Not in the shape
of a cock and balls per se, but there is another
hallway in front of you, and it extends forward
into darkness, but you do see a very faint torch
at the end of it all.
SAM: A tip.
TRAVIS: Tip of the hallway, yeah.
LIAM: I'm a big fan of the show Stillben Vandal,
it's quite good.
TRAVIS: So you are going up. Ooh, this is you!
LAURA: Can I pull on the bars to see if I can get
out?
TRAVIS: Yeah, you pull on it, and, man, that shit
is-- Roll a strength check. I'll give you a shot.
LAURA: Because I'm really strong, Grog. Nine.
TRAVIS: No, no. It doesn't even move. It doesn't
even do the pothole thing. As soon as you step
on it, it goes boop boop, I'm going to fall.
But no, it's solid.
LAURA: Is there a lock to be seen?
TRAVIS: Not that you can tell. If you want to
check and see if there's a latch to it.
LAURA: I want to look and see.
TRAVIS: Roll an investigation check.
LAURA: Ooh, Grog, what a big word! What is that,
23? 23.
TRAVIS: 23. You reach through one of the slots in
the plate that's holding--
LAURA: Did you burp?
LIAM: I did burp.
LAURA: Really stinky burp.
LIAM: I love you too, Stubby.
TRAVIS: You put your hand through, and as your
fingers curl around, you do feel a very large
latch, but it is thick and very secure, and it
extends into the mass around it, the wall itself.
You get the impression that it would take quite a
mechanism to unleash this thing.
LAURA: Okay. All right.
SAM: Well, let's go explore. I'm going to walk
around the room. I'm going to walk up the shaft.
TRAVIS: You both head down the hallway?
LAURA: I'm going to follow them down the shaft.
SAM: Maybe you left, me right?
TRAVIS: What's the marching order here?
SAM: I'll be to the right of the shaft. He's pants
left.
LIAM: But slowly move up the shaft.
SAM: You don't want to go too fast down the
shaft.
TRAVIS: You said to the right of the hallway?
And you're going to be on the left? To the left?
SAM: No, no, he's all the way on the left wall.
TRAVIS: Vax?
LIAM: I will follow behind Scan-Man.
TRAVIS: Okay. And Vex?
LAURA: Behind Percy. And Trinket's going to stand
next to you, Grog, because he loves you so much.
SAM: Just going to really just snug the edges of
the shaft.
LIAM: Yeah, you know, palm the sides as you go.
LAURA: Just move forward, nice and easy.
TRAVIS: Would you like to proceed down the
hallway?
SAM: Yes.
TRAVIS: Okay, so you move forward?
SAM: We do move forward.
TALIESIN: Gently, checking for traps.
SAM: I did not say that.
TRAVIS: Well, as Scanlan is just ahead of you in
your pursuit down the hallway, Scanlan feels his
foot fall on a piece of the floor and it sinks.
LAURA: Oh no.
TRAVIS: You hear a grinding noise that you've
heard before in our adventures, and it's not good.
And instinctually, you look to your right
immediately on the wall, and you notice there are
all these holes in the wall.
LAURA: Oh no!
TRAVIS: And sure enough, just as you're looking, a
fucking dart sinks right into your cheek. Just
poof, right into your-- (yelling)!
SAM: (screaming) My cheek, it burns, it burns!
TRAVIS: And just as your hands go up to your face,
another one hits you in the thigh.
LAURA: Back up! Scanlan! Back up!
TRAVIS: As you turn around, one sinks into your
butt cheek.
LIAM: I pull him back!
TRAVIS: Yeah, you pull him back. You take--
LIAM: What if I suck the poison out?
SAM: We don't know if it's poisoned yet.
LIAM: Well, just on principle. Just on principle.
TRAVIS: You take 13 points of fucking dart
damage.
LIAM: Is that a lot? Is that all you have?
SAM: I assume not. I assume I'm okay.
TRAVIS: You look at the wound in his cheek, and
the wound in his arm, chest area, they don't seem
so bad, but the one in his butt is starting to
swell a little bit. Kind of bruised and red.
LAURA: Yeah, you should definitely suck the poison
out.
LIAM: I definitely should. Or I could use my
paladin ability--
LAURA: No, you should just suck it out.
SAM: I pull down my pants.
TRAVIS: Make a medicine check as you suck on
Scanlan's ass.
LIAM: Okay, I'm feeling lucky, though.
LAURA: Oh no!
LIAM: But it knocked the first die into a higher
number, can I go with that?
TALIESIN: That's not how the game works, no.
LIAM: We've never played this game before!
TRAVIS: I will make a ruling. Because you are
sucking on Scanlan's ass, you may roll with
advantage.
LIAM: Not for the first time. So go again. Look at
what I got! That's a good ass suck right there.
SAM: I'll be the judge of that.
LIAM: 19, how did I do?
TRAVIS: Fantastic. You manage to get the right
amount of pressure right on the butt cheek, right?
And you suck all the poison out, and you spit it
out, because you know, if you swallow it, also bad
for you, and you manage to take your head away
just in time as a Scanlan little boop farts out.
LIAM: I wave it away and then I take the
opportunity to do one of these. (blows raspberry)
TRAVIS: Oh man. Yeah, nothing like mom's kisses.
That's nice. Good job. So, you've taken 13 points
of damage, you've pointed it out, I assume, to the
rest of the group.
SAM: There's lots of holes with darts in them,
what, what?
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Oh no.
TRAVIS: Yeah, in this game, if you notice
something, call it out to each other. Because what
one person sees, the other somehow might not see.
And just because you know it at the table, doesn't
mean that you know it in your mind pictures.
LIAM: You just made that up.
TRAVIS: That's how this goes, I promise.
LIAM: Where did you learn this game?
TRAVIS: I was in a tavern, and this long-haired
guy was playing a game at the table, and I thought
it was fucking great. And I watched for a while.
Like, hours. I was hooked.
I might go back next week and watch.
SAM: Do you need any kind of subscription to watch
it, or can you--
TRAVIS: I'm not sure, actually. That's a great
question.
LAURA: So, wait. So you saw darts coming out of
the wall, then?
SAM: Yeah, there's traps. There's lots of traps
down the shaft.
LAURA: Okay, so, you guys, I'll let you go ahead.
TALIESIN: I'm going to carefully examine the
floor.
TRAVIS: So you notice that right here--
SAM: That is a permanent marker.
TRAVIS: It is, I don't give a shit. There is this
area.
SAM: Is that yours?
TALIESIN: Matt's going to get his-- That mat is
permanently scarred.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I don't fucking care. Or you have to
build a map with that integrated into it. You
notice that that area of the floor, you step on
it, bad shit happens.
LIAM: Every map has a dick in it, from here to
eternity.
LAURA: So we don't step on that section.
TRAVIS: Well, you haven't gone past it yet. Would
you like to try and cross that area?
LIAM: I will start looking for traps up this
shaft.
TRAVIS: Nice. Be very careful with the shaft.
Okay. If you would like to try and cross over that
area, you all need to make an acrobatic check as
you try and leap over.
LIAM: Jump over that spot.
LAURA: Jump over it! Whoa. 33, Grog.
TRAVIS: That's good.
TALIESIN: 22.
SAM: 17.
TRAVIS: 17.
LIAM: Ooh yes. 36.
TRAVIS: 36. Everyone but Vax manages to leap over,
successfully over, well done. Vax catches his
foot, he's like, (yells) and he falls flat on his
face. And the darts go pew pew pew! Vex, if you
want to turn, you can try and drag your brother,
who has luckily had all the darts go above his
lying, goofy body on the floor, and try to pull
him off the plate.
LAURA: Yes, I would love to try and pull my
brother to safety.
LIAM: I like to evade stuff like this, can I use
some sort of evasion?
TRAVIS: Unfortunately, no. Strength check?
LIAM: I knew this was what this game would be. I
knew it.
LAURA: Yeah, a strength check? Oh gosh. I'm not
very strong, Grog. Ooh! 22!
TRAVIS: That's enough, because Vax doesn't have
very many muscles. So you pull him off the plate,
and he's there, all of you are right there, ready
to go again.
LAURA: What about Trinket? And Grog?
TRAVIS: All right. Yeah, hold on. Look, Grog makes
it over, and then Trinket comes up. Roll a
acrobatics check for Trinket.
LIAM: Grog, I didn't see anything hit you, but I
might better just suck poison out of your ass,
just to be sure.
TRAVIS: You know what, save it for later.
LAURA: I'm going to say that's a 14 for Trinket.
TRAVIS: Ooh, yeah, so unfortunately--
LAURA: Grog, save him as he falls!
TRAVIS: Sure. So he falls and I start to hear the
grinding again and I pull him by his ear, and
whoop, everybody's on the safe side of the trap.
What would you like to do next?
LIAM: I would like to see if there are any more
traps before we get to the tip.
TRAVIS: Roll a perception check.
LIAM: Perception, which one is this? There's a
picture of a monk on this one.
LIAM: Dungeons and Flagons! Perception? 22.
TRAVIS: 22? Yes, indeed. There are no further
traps towards the tip, but your keen half-elf ears
pick up a (wind blowing) sound.
LAURA: Does it sound like ghosts that we have
encountered?
TRAVIS: "Turn back." And you spin on your heel,
and outside of Grog's amazing deltoids, which
look swollen from shoulder day, you see behind
you a spectral form starting to make its way
towards you.
LAURA: Oh no.
SAM: It's a ghost of some sort, holding a shovel.
TRAVIS: I need you all to roll initiative.
LIAM: What?
TALIESIN: Initiative.
LIAM: What's initiative?
TALIESIN: What we're rolling.
LIAM: That's a die, you're rolling a die.
TALIESIN: Yes. You roll your initiative die.
LIAM: I had so many ghosts in that box over there,
Travis.
TRAVIS: I already bought that one.
LIAM: I brought six tubs of miniatures. So many
miniatures.
SAM: You bought that ghost with a shovel already?
TRAVIS: Yeah. It was two dollars or
something.
SAM: Why is he holding a shovel?
LAURA: 24.
LIAM: 16.
TRAVIS: 16. Percy.
TALIESIN: 16.
TRAVIS: Wow. 16, Percy. Really?
TALIESIN: 16. I rolled very poorly.
SAM: 14.
TRAVIS: Vex, you're up first. You see the
spectral form starting to move towards you.
What would you like to do?
LAURA: Oh, I'm going to shoot an arrow at it.
TRAVIS: You shoot an arrow at it?
LAURA: From a blazing bowstring, because why not?
TRAVIS: Okay. Roll to hit.
LAURA: 25?
TRAVIS: Hold on! Wait. There's music and shit.
Fuck.
SAM: Shall I tell the unseen servants to change
the music?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
SAM: Play something more rousing, please.
Thank you.
LIAM: What, what?
SAM: I'm not in character now.
I'm just Scanlan.
TRAVIS: I'm sorry, what was it?
LAURA: Shit. 25.
TRAVIS: Hit. Yeah, that definitely hits.
LAURA: Okay. Oh jeez. I'm going to decide what I
should, you know, attack should-- Sure. Ten.
Plus-- Oh, I didn't Hunter's Mark him
because I'm stupid.
TRAVIS: Yeah, too late for that.
LAURA: 15 plus fire. 15 plus eight is 23.
TRAVIS: 23, nice.
LIAM: Look at Grog on that board, looks like he's
staring and judging the toys.
LAURA: And then for my bonus action--
LIAM: A what?
LAURA: Can I have Trinket jump across the thing
that he just crossed and attack the ghost, too?
TRAVIS: Yeah, roll an acrobatic check first.
LAURA: Although I don't think I can actually have
him attack after I shot an arrow.
TRAVIS: Oh, then no--
LAURA: Yes, I can! Because I only
attacked once, that's how it works.
LIAM: Bonus action? This is what all those ballet
classes for Trinket were for, right now.
LAURA: That's an 11 for him.
TRAVIS: For the acrobatic check?
Trinket falls right on the plate. And he's like,
boom. And then, because it shot all those darts,
and Vax fell, and they were like, "Oh, none
of the darts hit," they're all aimed down.
And Trinket takes like six darts.
He looks like the guy in The Godfather
He's like, (distressed bear sounds, darts)
covered in darts. Trinket takes--
SAM: Don't worry, Vex, it's not Real-Trinket, it's
Imagination-Trinket. Real-Trinket is still alive.
TRAVIS: 24 points of damage.
LAURA: That's a lot.
TRAVIS: But he manages with his bear strength
to pull himself just out of the line of fire.
But he is right there.
LAURA: Can he continue his attack?
Probably not. Can I attack with my second arrow?
TRAVIS: No. Vax, you're up.
LIAM: I will run at the ghost. Right?
Because I have to get up to it.
I could throw, but where's the fun in that?
So I run at the ghost,
and I'm going to use Whisper,
and I'm going to dagger, dagger, dagger.
And I'm going to use the power of my deity
and do something called Divine Smiting.
I've never told you guys what it's called,
but it's called Divine Smite.
TRAVIS: Well, give me an acrobatics check,
because you jump over the plate area.
You want to run into melee with the ghost?
LIAM: Yeah. So that's 33.
TRAVIS: You learn from your previous errors
and man up,
and you totally make it across just fine.
LIAM: Yeah, I rolled lower than the last time.
Great. I jump across, run.
How do I hit it with my knife?
TRAVIS: You stab it.
LIAM: Okay.
TRAVIS: Roll to attack.
LIAM: Okay, so I roll once. I'm going to use my--
LAURA: Your second luck of the day.
LIAM: I have endless luck. It's endless.
That's a one. So instead I get a 19.
TRAVIS: A 19. Which hits.
LIAM: It does? Oh my gosh. God, there's
all these numbers on this piece of paper.
LAURA: You've used two of them.
LIAM: I've used 17 lucks. It was a six. I'm not
very good at math; I copied all of her answers.
I think that's around 13, plus eight, 21,
and then the Divine Smite,
which I'm going to peg somewhere around 3d8.
So a 31. That'll do.
38. That was a 42. 44.
Grog, 44 points of damage.
TRAVIS: Boy, that's a lot of damage
with that Divine Smite.
LIAM: Feathers everywhere, David Bowie-style.
Does it hurt the ghost?
TRAVIS: Boy, it really does. You see him go like,
"Ouch!" And his form shivers and stuff,
and he's like (pained sounds).
You see the area where you stab evaporates
and then comes back into form,
but he's still standing there
He gleams at you
with these fucking dead ghost eyes.
LAURA: Is he a dwarf ghost? Because he seems
rather short. He is a dwarf ghost?
TRAVIS: Yep. Yeah. He is a dwarf ghost.
LIAM: But I can attack so many times, Grog.
Can I do another quickie?
LAURA: I only got one arrow.
You only get one dagger.
TRAVIS: That's fair.
That sounds like a good idea.
LIAM: Is that how it works?
TRAVIS: Yeah, that's how it works.
He turns to you after being like,
"It hurts so bad." You really hurt him really bad.
And he is going to use Horrifying Visage on you.
LIAM: What the fuck is that?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I need you to make a wisdom saving
throw.
LIAM: A wisdom saving throw? Okay, so I don't have
any of that. Oh, that's good. I rolled an 18.
TRAVIS: Oh, that succeeds. You see him almost
glare into your soul, you feel your little
butthole pucker, and you're like, "Oh no, it's so
scary!" but you shake it off because you've seen
so much worse in your time. Yeah. And you throw up
the double-birds, and he's like (hissing), and you
shake it off. That's good.
Percy, it's your turn.
TALIESIN: Yes. Well, I'm going to back up
and take a shot at this--
TRAVIS: Back away from the ghost, or towards him?
TALIESIN: No, away from the ghost. Away from the
ghost a bit, and I'm going to take a shot.
I'll just take one, since it seems we're being
sporting about it. So I'm going to use my magical
psychic shot. And that's not bad. That's a 24.
TRAVIS: 24 hits.
TALIESIN: All right. Well then, I'm going to do
that, plus this. And I'm also going to hit him
with a bit of electricity, as well.
TRAVIS: Yeah, do it.
TALIESIN: Ooh, that's lovely. That's
ten points of damage, plus six points
of psychic damage,
plus four points of electricity.
TRAVIS: That is just enough. You hit him, and his
form-- You hear this shriek, and he just--
turns into a puff of smoke.
Disappears into nowhere, and the ghost is gone.
Calm retakes the hallway.
LAURA: Back towards the tip.
SAM: Yes, musicians, calm down.
LIAM: Let's refocus on the shaft.
TALIESIN: I'm going to peruse the rest of the--
TRAVIS: Make a perception check to explore the
hallway.
LIAM: Just the tip, though, Percy.
TALIESIN: If I get too close to the tip, I might
experience a burning sensation from the torch. 20.
TRAVIS: 20, yeah, that's great. You move forward,
and you see no doorways, no exits, but you do see
a line near the end of the hallway that seems to
be a bit of an inequality in the rocks. Almost
like if you push on it, something might happen.
LAURA: Maybe you should push on it, Percy?
LIAM: We should backtrack the way we came.
TALIESIN: Really? All right, I'm pushing on it.
TRAVIS: Yeah, yeah, you push on it.
Give me a strength check.
TALIESIN: Oh, this will go well.
LIAM: Push it real good.
TALIESIN: Pushing. Push it. Oh no.
That would be a--
LIAM: That's the lowest number
you can get on that thing.
TALIESIN: That is indeed the lowest number
you can get.
TRAVIS: Right. Strangely, you lean into it, about
to give it a big shove, but your feet slip out
from under you on the slick rock.
And you fall flat on your face, and you bite
a bit of your tongue and lip.
TALIESIN: (lisping) I could use some assistance
with this. Please.
SAM: I'll show you how it's done.
Scanlan, in real life, is not a very strong
person, but I'm playing my character
as very strong, so Scanlan runs in
and pushes hard on the wall.
TRAVIS: Great, yeah, make a strength check.
SAM: Ooh. 16.
TRAVIS: 16. You lean in and you push, having
Percy, just like little bloody mouth right next to
you, and sure enough, the wall starts to move, but
you can see light coming from the other side. It's
just too heavy for you to move.
SAM: I need some help over here!
LAURA: Trinket's going to run over.
Damn it, he has to cross the thingy again.
TALIESIN: He's going to have to cross the thingy
again.
TRAVIS: "You know what, I got it." Grog goes up
towards the end of the hallway.
He's like, "Maybe I'll just fucking handle
this, you guys, don't worry."
And he rolls a million, and the door flies open.
Almost comes off whatever invisible hinges it had.
Like, rock falls out of the door.
LIAM: Just like life.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Pretty much. I know. Doors can't
faze me. The rest of you, it's a problem.
Not always true. You see before you a lit cavern.
Something off in the distance, but you're still
in the doorway. What do you do?
SAM: A lit cabin?
TRAVIS, LIAM, and TALIESIN: Cavern.
LAURA: I'm going to shoot another oracle arrow
into the lit cavern.
TRAVIS: Do you have another oracle arrow?
LAURA: I do, I have one more.
TRAVIS: Yeah? Roll to attack. Shoot.
LAURA: 26.
TRAVIS: You nock, and you pull, and you release,
and your vision goes into the arrow, and it shoots
forward. You see stone floors beneath you, and all
of a sudden, it shoots past what looks like a
flowing fountain of water, and it just arcs past,
and you see as it clears past the fountain, a
small, furry shape on the ground, and it hits into
a ground, and it scatters, and the arrow shatters
on the floor.
LAURA: There's a furry shape! There's an animal in
there. Let's go in! I walk into the room.
TRAVIS: Okay. So. Would you all like to follow
her? You all want to go?
LIAM: I'm going to hang back at the tip of the
wang there.
TRAVIS: Vax hangs back.
LAURA: Oh no, we all fell over.
TRAVIS: You all fell over. There you go. So you
see this fountain right here.
LAURA: Jesus H. That's lovely, Grog.
TRAVIS: Scanlan right here, and Vax over here.
LIAM: Yeah. I don't want to leave. I don't want to
go. I feel safe in the shaft.
TRAVIS: There's a fountain right in front of you,
and as you go in, you see there appears to be
like, just this rouge, flushed-skin type water
coming out of it. Some sort of fluid. And it's
just a beautiful fountain, right in the middle of
the room. Circular, from what you can see.
What do you do?
LAURA: Where was the furry creature?
TRAVIS: It was past the fountain somewhere, you're
not sure.
LAURA: I'm going to look at the ground and see if
there's any traps.
TRAVIS: Traps? Do a perception check. Is that what
you're doing for traps?
SAM: I think it's investigation.
TRAVIS: Okay, do roll an investigation check.
LAURA: 12.
TRAVIS: 12. There do not appear to be any traps.
LAURA: Great. Then I walk forward towards the
fountain. And past it.
SAM: I will stick with her. So I can protect her.
LAURA: Thank you, Scanlan.
TALIESIN: You're not doing the voice anymore?
SAM: That's only when I in-character talk to
someone else.
TALIESIN: Oh, so this is the narrative. The
narrative voice is different.
TRAVIS: You see before you what looks like a dog.
A tiny little dog. Where is the dog?
Where's the dog gone?
Right about here, at the edge of your vision.
TALIESIN: Is the dog over there? By Bigby's Hand?
LAURA: Do you want this to be a dog?
TRAVIS: Sure, yeah, we'll use this to be a dog.
Here's the dog right here.
SAM: Did you buy a dog?
TRAVIS: No, it's one of Liam's.
It was in the box.
LIAM: Eight tubs of minis. Eight tubs of minis.
There's a die on the map.
TRAVIS: You see a dog, his tail just sweeping
behind him.
LAURA: Grog, can I cast Speak With Animals?
TRAVIS: If you'd like to.
LAURA: I want to. And I want to talk to him.
TRAVIS: Go for it.
LAURA: I want to say: Hey, dog. What are you doing
down here?
TRAVIS: As you do that, the dog whips around
and looks at you, jumps to its feet
and starts to growl.
Starts to growl and he's like "Intruder.
Intruder!" You see as these bone shards
start to protrude from his back and shoulders.
His spine starts to lengthen,
and he's no longer a fucking dice dog.
It is this massive thing.
SAM: Some sort of demon dog.
LAURA: Oh shit. I immediately shoot an arrow at
him.
TRAVIS: You do?
LAURA: But I want to Hunter's Mark him first.
TRAVIS: Roll to attack.
SAM: Doesn't she have to step back to shoot an
arrow?
LAURA: I'm not right on him.
LIAM: You're at disadvantage if you're right up
against.
LAURA: But I'm not right up against him.
SAM: Well, ask the Bunion Master.
LIAM: I mean, I just feel like that's a rule.
TRAVIS: You're at disadvantage because you're so
close.
SAM: Thank you, Grog. Thank you.
LAURA: Fucking dick, Scanlan. Fine. 26.
TRAVIS: 26. You hit the vicious hell hound. What's
your damage?
LAURA: Oh, okay.
LIAM: Must be like a rottweiler or something then
because they're so mean. Not really. That's just a
myth, isn't it?
TALIESIN: I think it's just a myth. Although I had
a neighbor with a chihuahua once.
LIAM: Maybe a chihuahua. It's probably a
chihuahua.
TALIESIN: They're all bite-y.
LAURA: That's 16 plus six is 22 plus six is 28.
TRAVIS: 28 points of damage with one shot.
Amazing. Great. Is that the end of your turn?
LAURA: I want Trinket to run up and attack him
too.
TRAVIS: Okay.
LAURA: He does, right?
TRAVIS: Trinket runs up around the other side.
LAURA: Oh he got a natural 20!
TRAVIS: Natural 20.
TALIESIN: That means something.
TRAVIS: If you can't tell from her exuberance, a
natural 20 is like the best thing you can roll.
LAURA: That's really good.
LIAM: Have you played this with him before you
played with us?
LAURA: So I happened to be in the same tavern that
he was in.
SAM: Yeah, we all were Vax. Sorry, we didn't want
to tell you but we were all there, that's why we
know how to play the game so well.
LIAM: Why didn't you let me sleep in with Keyleth
then? Why am I here? Jeez.
SAM: It's such a good game that we all wanted to
play and share it with you.
LAURA: I thought you would really like it.
LIAM: I want to fucking sleep in for once.
SAM: But we also knew that we would probably win
because you don't know how to play.
LAURA: Trinket attacks him.
TRAVIS: Okay great. And what's the damage?
LAURA: Oh, I don't know.
TALIESIN: This has never happened before.
LAURA: I know, he doesn't do this very often.
TRAVIS: He critted.
LAURA: He did. Ah! Okay, so 2d4 plus nine. Because
it's a claw attack.
TRAVIS: Okay.
LAURA: Okay. Where's my other-- there it is.
TRAVIS: There's fucking mysterious music. Have the
people change it to some sort of--
SAM: Oh sorry, change the music again please.
TALIESIN: Switch tracks, my friend.
LIAM: Is it like the ghost piano at the Magic
Castle?
LAURA: 23!
TRAVIS: Whoa, 23. Trinket putting out some
damage.
LAURA: I mean that's pretty great, right?
TRAVIS: Yeah, that's pretty good.
LAURA: I should have had him do that before me, I
could have gotten sneak attack damage.
TRAVIS: Yeah, seriously. Okay so, as Trinket
attacks and takes a vicious chunk out of the side
of this hell hound right--
LAURA: With his claws!
TRAVIS: You hear a growl even further into the
cavern.
LAURA and TALIESIN: Oh no.
LIAM: How far does this go? Oh look, isn't that
clever!
LAURA: Oh it's boobies. I thought it was an anus.
LIAM: It's tits.
LAURA: I thought it was an anus.
SAM: No, that's just the shape of the cavern.
TRAVIS: No, these are caverns.
SAM: Yeah.
LIAM: Caverns.
TRAVIS: What are you smoking? And you see from
behind the fountain coming another hell hound to
see what the cry of its fallen brethren are.
TALIESIN: I'm going to take a run at the first one
and I'm going to throw my spear.
TRAVIS: You're going to throw your spear?
SAM: The spear that you picked up at the tavern?
TALIESIN: I am. I pick up that tavern spear and
I'm going to throw it.
TRAVIS: Actually, now the other ones as well, I
need you to roll initiative again.
LIAM: Okay we're doing it again, let's roll one of
these little balls.
SAM: 18.
TALIESIN: 16 yet again.
LAURA: 14.
LIAM: 21.
TRAVIS: 21. Vax, you, back near the tip, are up.
LIAM: Okay, I click my boots. Do I have my boots?
TRAVIS: Do you normally have your boots?
LIAM: Always.
TRAVIS: Then you do.
LIAM: Fuck yeah! I click the boots, and I bolt
through, out the end of the penis and to the
boobs, or the egg, or whatever it is. I go from
the tunnel--
TRAVIS: The hallway.
LIAM: Yeah, the hallway into the cavern. The first
round cavern that is identical to the next one.
TRAVIS: Strange words coming out of your mouth.
You come into the cavern.
LIAM: Painful stuff. Yeah, I'd like to run around
between my sister and Trinket and get up into the
grill of that first spiky dog, because I should
have a better chance of hitting it because it's so
preoccupied with my sister.
TRAVIS: Move your little character wherever you'd
like to go, yeah.
LIAM: Jeez. So I jump over here. So I bang like that,
I can jump over Grog, and I go (whoop), right up
in the middle like that. And then I stab.
TRAVIS: You stab. Roll to attack.
LIAM: I'm going to roll twice. Because I'm feeling
good. Ooh, that's good. 30.
TRAVIS: That hits.
LIAM: Oh, it does. Okay. So I roll this pointy one
that's like a caltrop, and that's a two. And then
I add eight to that, that's a ten. And then I roll
again for psychic damage. That's 12. Look at all
these in a box, oh my God, look at that. 14,
eight, no. 25. 29. 32. 32, Grog.
TRAVIS: With that first dagger, you sink it into
the side of the hell hound, and you hear a (pained squeal),
and he recoils from the pain, and all of
a sudden, his flesh and fur just turns into flame,
and he catches fire and burns into nothing. He
just absolutely disintegrates.
LAURA: Does that hurt Trinket standing right next
to him?
TRAVIS: No, it doesn't.
LIAM: And then we all only get one attack per
turn, is that right?
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Well, don't you have more attacks?
Normally I see you do a lot of shit.
LIAM: I do, but before-- Yes. I have four more.
Five more, seven more attacks.
TRAVIS: How about one more attack? Sounds good.
LIAM: One more attack is good. It might be more,
but we'll just do one more.
LAURA: That's a really cool dagger.
LIAM: That's a 31.
TRAVIS: That hits.
LIAM: Yeah. On that one, I'm throwing it, so
that's not as crazy because I kind of blew my wad
on the first one. That's a nine.
TRAVIS: A nine?
LIAM: A nine.
TRAVIS: Nine damage?
LAURA: Trinket did more damage than that.
TRAVIS: The bear did.
LIAM: How much did he do total?
LAURA: 23.
LIAM: Were you here when I did, like, 30-something
on the attack just before?
TRAVIS: This is not a competition. You hit it, and
it totally gets its attention. It sinks right into
its shoulder blade, and it's (pained growling),
and focuses on you.
LIAM: It focuses on me, but it was talking to
you.
TRAVIS: That's true, yeah. Scanlan, you're up.
SAM: I'm going to step forward and call to the
beast. "Beast, look in my eyes and follow my
"commands!" And I will cast Dominate Monster on the
beast. He has to roll a wisdom save.
TRAVIS: You got it. Okay.
SAM: Against 22.
LIAM: You must face Bavmorda.
TRAVIS: 20. It fails. You dominate the monster.
SAM: I command you, beast, to attack this bear.
LAURA: Scanlan!
SAM: Relentless attack!
LAURA: What the fuck?!
SAM: I don't get to do this in real life, so I
thought I'd experiment with different things in
fantasy land.
LAURA: Asshole.
TRAVIS: And next in the initiative order is
actually the hell hound, and he takes off running
straight towards Trinket. Yeah, it's real
unfortunate. He's going to unleash a bite att--
No, he's going to do Firebreath in a 15-foot cone.
Must make a DC 12 dexterity saving throw.
LAURA: Who all is in that cone?
TRAVIS: Roll a dexterity saving throw, Vex, Vax,
and Trinket.
LIAM: Vex, Vax, and Trinket? Oh. Oh, my boots are
on, so I do better at that now.
LAURA: Oh no. That's terrible for both of us.
Well, not bad for me. 18.
LIAM: 21 for me.
LAURA: 18 for me.
TRAVIS: You both succeed.
LAURA: Trinket, though, is a four.
TRAVIS: Four.
TALIESIN: A four?
LAURA: He's not very dexterous.
TRAVIS: So Trinket takes 29 points of fire
damage.
LIAM and LAURA: Oh no.
LIAM: So what does he look like? Set the scene
for us.
TRAVIS: You guys both take 19 points of fire
damage. Halved, because you made the save.
SAM: Wait, 19 is half of what?
TRAVIS: Wait.
SAM: Of 29? That tracks for Grog, sure.
LIAM: But what am I subtracting that from?
LAURA: Your health.
LIAM: What health?
LAURA: How much health do you have?
TRAVIS: Call it 14 points. We'll call it 14
points.
LIAM: I feel fine.
SAM: The BM is always right.
LIAM: Percival, what do I subtract it from?
TALIESIN: From your hit points.
LIAM: What are hit points?
TALIESIN: Your hit points are your hit points.
LIAM: Is that over here somewhere?
TALIESIN: I mean, I would hope so.
TRAVIS: You can read, right?
LIAM: I mean, I can. Doesn't mean I do.
TRAVIS: Well, you should.
SAM: Grog, this noob is bringing
the whole table down.
TRAVIS: I know, it's terrible. I mean seriously.
LIAM: That says my name, Vax'ildan--
LAURA: Oh, right here.
LIAM: Where?
LAURA: Right. There.
LIAM: Oh, I got a lot. That's so many hit points.
I bet I have the most in the group. So I take
away, I think you said 14.
LAURA: Jeez, Trinket's pretty close to dying.
TRAVIS: Percival, you're up.
TALIESIN: I've really been excited about the spear
so I'm going to run forward and throw my spear.
TRAVIS: Okay, what's your speed? How far can you
move?
TALIESIN: I can move 30.
TRAVIS: 30? One, two, three--
TALIESIN: One, two, three, four, five, six...
TRAVIS: So unfortunately, Trinket stands between
you and the hell hound.
TALIESIN: Well, I was going to angle out my little
walk a bit to the outskirts.
TRAVIS: Out this way more?
TALIESIN: Yeah, out that way more.
TRAVIS: Okay, so maybe over here?
TALIESIN: Right there. Yeah, like there. And I
think I can throw it--
TRAVIS: You want to throw it?
TALIESIN: Yeah, like a javelin, yes.
TRAVIS: Okay, roll an attack at disadvantage.
TALIESIN: Why disadvantage?
TRAVIS: Because I've never seen you throw a
fucking spear before.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: What is my attack with the spear?
TRAVIS: Plus two.
TALIESIN: All right.
LAURA: Oh shit, that's really low. Roll high,
darling.
TALIESIN: A seven then, if it's plus two.
TRAVIS: Yeah, good. You throw the spear and it--
SAM: Hits Trinket!
TRAVIS: It just disappears. You're not quite sure
where but you hear a sploosh. You hear the splash
as it seems to disappear into the fountain behind
the hell hound.
TALIESIN: Well, fine then. I'm going to just sit
there and be disappointed then.
TRAVIS: Good, nice. Vex, you're up.
LAURA: Oh, okay.
TRAVIS: You have a bonus action if you want it.
TALIESIN: Okay. What can I do with a bonus action?
Can I just do whatever I like?
SAM: I've seen you burn grits.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I just assume you'll know that
better than me.
TALIESIN: I let you cook, this is your
mansion.
SAM: That's true.
TALIESIN: And my grits are best burnt. Makes them
a little crispy.
LAURA: I'm going to-- Trinket is going to bite
him back because he's a dick.
TRAVIS: Nice, roll an attack.
LAURA: Okay. That's good. 28.
TRAVIS: That'll hit.
LAURA: Okay. So he's going to do this. Ten for
him. Does he get my Hunter's Mark as well?
TRAVIS: No.
LAURA: All right. Just checking. And then I'm
going to shoot an arrow while he's doing that so
the creature's distracted, right?
TRAVIS: Sounds good.
LIAM: Why do you decide for Trinket what Trinket
does?
LAURA: Well, I mean, he's not at the table playing
right now, so I have to say what he's going to do.
TRAVIS: He's outside.
LAURA: No, he's right behind me.
TRAVIS: Oh, he's asleep?
LAURA: Yeah, he's right there.
TRAVIS: Oh, sorry. He blends into the furniture.
SAM: It's true, all my furniture is bearskin
furniture.
TRAVIS: That's super insensitive.
LIAM: But only since you met Vex.
LAURA: I got 31.
TRAVIS: 31 damage?
LAURA: No, 31 to hit.
TRAVIS: Oh, to hit. It hits.
SAM: I don't even clean it, it's just bloody bear
skin.
LAURA: You're terrible. 16, 17. Where are they?
LIAM: Just make it up, this is imagination.
TRAVIS: Are you lacking die?
LAURA: I don't know.
TRAVIS: How is that possible?
LAURA: Oh, what did I say I was at?
TRAVIS: 13.
LAURA: 13? Okay, good. 13, 16, 17.
TRAVIS: 17.
LAURA: Yes.
TRAVIS: And with that you hit the hell hound and
the arrow sinks in and he too starts to catch fire
from the wound and he's like (howling), and he
just evaporates.
LAURA: I killed it!
TALIESIN: Look at that. That's brilliant.
LAURA: It's dead. Trinket and I killed it! Good
job, darling.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Not that's it's a competition, but
you've killed something, Trinket's killed
something, and you've killed something.
SAM: Any points?
LIAM: Did I get any points? Did I get any XP?
TRAVIS: There were only 450 to give out for the
entire game, so it's all been used.
TALIESIN: You still have another 200 to give.
TRAVIS: There is 200 more to give. You'll get 50
XP.
LAURA: Thank you.
TRAVIS: Thank you, Percival.
TALIESIN: You're welcome.
TRAVIS: I can only juggle so many, you know,
parrots at one time.
LIAM: So how it works is you have to get all the
XP at the very beginning.
TALIESIN: Yeah, the XB.
LIAM: The XB; what does the B stand for?
SAM: Boints. Xylophone bears.
TRAVIS: So the hell hounds have been destroyed and
the cavern is again quiet. What would you like to do?
LAURA: I want to run my hands through the
fountain.
TRAVIS: Okay. So you go up to the fountain--
SAM: I'd like to go to the other fountain and
do the same.
TRAVIS: You can go to this one, yep.
LAURA: Just so we can do this. In the fountain
water.
TRAVIS: Roll a constitution saving throw.
LAURA: Oh no!
LIAM: Gently first, though.
SAM: 11.
LAURA: 14.
TRAVIS: Yeah, it's just water.
LAURA: Oh good. Okay. So I'm going to wash my
hands off.
TRAVIS: So you notice as you're washing your hands
off right, it's a very nice color, Grog wanders off--
SAM: Do the fountains get any harder?
TRAVIS: No they don't. Just nice and yeah.
TALIESIN: Is it hard water or soft water I think
is what he's asking.
TRAVIS: It's a good question. Would you like to
roll an intelligence check?
TALIESIN: I'm going to roll an intelligence check
on that.
TRAVIS: Which fountain are you inspecting?
TALIESIN: I'm inspecting Scanlan's fountain.
TRAVIS: Okay, you come over to Scanlan's fountain
and you're inspecting that one as well.
LIAM: Maybe you should taste it.
LAURA: Shut up. That's-- no, he really shouldn't.
TALIESIN: Ooh. Is this investigation?
TRAVIS: Intelligence.
TALIESIN: Intelligence? All right, then that's a
24.
TRAVIS: 24, yeah, this is very soft water. It is
very nice. It's got like a salt treatment to it.
It's very nice, yeah. It's good for your skin,
there's vitamins in there, there's potassium and
mercury and stuff.
LAURA: Do you have any dessert? Do you have
servants making any dessert?
SAM: In this or in the game?
LAURA: In here, in the mansion.
SAM: In the mansion. Sure, yes. We have some
desserts. Trying to think of vegan desserts. Not flan.
TALIESIN: You know, you can make a very nice vegan
creme brulee.
LIAM: Sorbet?
SAM: Sorbet is right. It's just fruit and sugar,
right? All right. Five...six? Five. We're five.
LAURA: Yeah. Well, six because we might have
extra. Trinket.
SAM: Five pomegranate sorbets please.
TRAVIS: Nice.
SAM: Seeds in.
TRAVIS: So as you're inspecting the fountains, you
notice that Grog, having watched you guys be very
careful checking for traps and everything is doing
the same, he's trying to do his part. Yeah, and lo
and behold he finds an edge in the wall just like
you found before and he pushes it open and inside
there is 20 platinum.
SAM: Wow!
LAURA: 20 platinum?!
TRAVIS: Yeah. "Guys! I found 20 platinum in this
secret passage."
LAURA: Oh my god. Can I see some platinum too? Can
I go over there?
TRAVIS: Platinum's mine, but you never know what
else is around. Maybe look for yourself.
LAURA: I look for other secret doors.
TRAVIS: All right, roll a perception check.
Investigation check!
LAURA: Okay. 25.
TRAVIS: 25? Yeah, in fact on the exact opposite
side of the cavern you find a similar door and do
you want to push it open?
LAURA: Yeah!
TRAVIS: Yeah. So you push and there seems to be
something coiled up on the ground in the corner.
LAURA: Is it a monster or is it platinum?
TRAVIS: It's not a creature or anything. Do you
want it or not?
LAURA: Does it look like platinum?
TRAVIS: Could be.
LAURA: Okay. Can I look at it?
TRAVIS: Yeah. Roll a perception check.
LAURA: 29.
TRAVIS: It's a big pile of poop.
LAURA: Aww.
TRAVIS: You found a poo.
LAURA: Grog.
LIAM: May I search the bottom of each nipple?
TRAVIS: Each what?
LAURA: It's a fountain.
LIAM: That's what I said.
TRAVIS: You want to search the bottom of each
fountain?
LIAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Sure.
LIAM: Like feel around, see if there's any loot.
TRAVIS: Which one would you like to start on?
Scanlan's or--?
LIAM: Well there's one right behind me.
TRAVIS: Yeah, sure.
LIAM: I should do the one closest to me.
TRAVIS: There you go.
LIAM: I'm going to see if there's any traps in
there if I'm going to stick my hand deep into that
thing.
TRAVIS: Yeah, roll an investigation check.
LIAM: Of course. Oh, that's really good. I'm
getting the hang of this. That is a 26.
TRAVIS: There do not appear to be any traps. Yeah.
Bottom of the fountain you find-- it's like a
mossy bottom and there's some pebbles, but it
seems like that might've come from the stones
overhead, but there doesn't appear to be any
objects in the bottom of the fountain.
LAURA: What's that door on the far end?
SAM: Let's go investigate that door over there.
TRAVIS: Who does?
SAM: I'll go over there.
TRAVIS: You'll go over there?
SAM: Yeah.
LAURA: Trinket's going to join him.
TRAVIS: So Scanlan's little legs just like
(footsteps) all the way over here.
There goes Trinket. So you see before you--
LAURA: Trinket's going to bite Scanlan's
shoulder.
TRAVIS: Roll to attack.
LIAM: I love how automatic that was.
LAURA: Oh, that's not my attack,
it's Trinket's attack. 19.
TRAVIS: 19. What's your AC?
SAM: That hits.
TRAVIS: Ooh. Roll for damage.
LAURA: Great. Okay.
This is what you get, Scanlan.
SAM: Sure.
LAURA: 14.
TRAVIS: 14 points of damage.
The bear sinks its teeth into your shoulder
and gives you a little jiggle.
SAM: (groans)
TRAVIS: That saliva starts to burn.
Yeah, bear saliva.
LAURA: Yeah, he doesn't brush his teeth.
SAM: Ow! Ouch! Why would you do that, Trinket?
LAURA: (bear growling)
TALIESIN: That's a very good Trinket.
That's very impressive.
LIAM: He's got breath worse than a decrepit old
dachshund, too.
SAM: I feel like I should retaliate.
LAURA: I don't think you should.
SAM: But that might piss off Vex.
TRAVIS: Might. There is also this incredible door
in front of you.
LAURA: You should check out the door.
He unbites you and licks your shoulder.
Which really just adds more bacteria to it.
SAM: I will inspect the door.
TRAVIS: Make a perception check.
SAM: Five.
TRAVIS: Five. You see before you a door,
magnificent, brilliantly ornate. It's made of
several different kinds of wood and iron. You know
everything about this.
SAM: I open it.
TRAVIS: How do you open it?
SAM: Is there a handle?
TRAVIS: Yes, there is, there is a latch.
LIAM: This is game of fantasy and imagination, so
it's just going to open and not hurt us at all.
SAM: I'll open the latch.
TRAVIS: The door opens. It just opens.
TALIESIN: What madness is this?!
LIAM: This is a utopia!
TRAVIS: The door swings open. You notice as it
opens there's a carving in the wood of a large
tower. As it swings open, it reveals in front of
it a small structure about 30 to 50 feet out in
front of you and darkness beyond.
TALIESIN: Nothing happened when we opened the
door?
TRAVIS: No.
TALIESIN: Are you sure you're doing it right?
TRAVIS: Yeah, shockingly.
LAURA: What was outside of the door?
TRAVIS: As Scanlan and Trinket are looking through
the doorway, they see a structure about 30 to 50
feet away from the doorway. Further into another
space is just darkness beyond.
LIAM: My own bathroom door in Whitestone hits me
for one point of bludgeoning damage every time I
use it.
TALIESIN: It's designed for that; it's a door!
LIAM: This door is faulty.
LAURA: We go through it. I want to walk towards
the structure.
TRAVIS: You go through the doorway?
SAM: I'm going through the doorway first with
Trinket.
TRAVIS: Would everyone like to go through the
doorway?
TALIESIN: I'm going to watch everyone else go
through the doorway.
TRAVIS: You're going to stay behind?
TALIESIN: I'm going to go through once they've
started to go through. I'm going to make sure
everything's good.
TRAVIS: Who goes first?
SAM: I will go first.
TRAVIS: Scanlan, you get to the doorway and the
second you start to cross the threshold, you feel
the force start to pull you towards the door,
almost as if someone has removed the stopper from
a bathtub. You feel yourself being pulled through.
I need everyone to make dexterity saving throws.
LAURA: All of us?!
TRAVIS: All of you.
LIAM: Even if we didn't say we were going towards
the door?
TRAVIS: Yep.
LIAM: I knew it was too good to be true.
SAM: I rolled a one.
LAURA: I rolled a one!
TALIESIN: I rolled a 21.
LAURA: Let's see what Trinket rolls. That's
cocked. Trinket rolled 18.
TRAVIS: 18? Okay. Vax?
LIAM: Vax'ildan rolled a 30.
TRAVIS: 30. Everyone except for Vax and Percy are
immediately pulled through the threshold.
LAURA: What about Grog?
LIAM: Freddie. Up top!
TRAVIS: That's a seven. Grog also pulled through
the doorway.
TALIESIN: Oh, that's right, we didn't go through
the door.
TRAVIS: Vax and Percy manage to cling to the side
of the threshold.
LIAM: Fucking dummies, right?
TALIESIN: This is why you never trust a door.
TRAVIS: You still feel this force pulling you,
like there's been an atmospheric pull through the
doorway. You hear, on the other side, your
comrades getting up, seemingly fine.
LAURA: What a nice journey that was! I really
enjoyed that.
TRAVIS: For you two, on this side of the door, the
pull is still incredibly strong. You can try and
fight it or you can go through.
TALIESIN: I'm curious to hear how this sensation
will be narrated.
LIAM: Yeah, I'd like to wait and also to mull over
who is this more painful for: you, Vex'ahlia's
husband and lover, or me, her oldest friend and
twin brother. It's hard to tell. Grog, can you
enlighten us?
TRAVIS: Yes. As you're mulling this over, you get
12 points of force damage.
TALIESIN and LIAM: That's fine.
LIAM: Let's feel this out.
TALIESIN: I was curious what kind of hardware is
attaching this door to the wall? Is it standard
brass brackets? Triple bracket?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Does it have a two-way turn? Can you
describe this?
TRAVIS: It's almost as if you saw it for yourself
with those descriptions. Really quite impressive.
TALIESIN: Can you describe me seeing it for
myself?
TRAVIS: Yeah, it's the triple brass tracket.
There's lumber and stone.
TALIESIN: There is lumber and stone.
TRAVIS: Iron. Gold inlay on the door.
TALIESIN: That's quite nice.
TRAVIS: Yep. And a picture of a tower.
LIAM: While he studies the door, I'm studying
Percival. Does he look more rugged and
good-looking as his hair is blown towards the
door, or less?
TRAVIS: You know right when you slap someone after
you've had too much to drink and their face is
doing the pull? That's what his face looks like
constantly.
TALIESIN: Well, if you'd said that, I'm letting
go and I'm going through the door.
TRAVIS: You let go and you go through the door.
Vax, you're the only one still on this side of the door.
LIAM: Okay. I do a five-count: One, two, three,
four, five. And then I just go: Motherfucker! And
I grip my own shoulders and dive.
TRAVIS: Yeah. And you go right through the doorway
as well. You both fall with a clatter to the
floor, and you notice that in front of you is a
structure.
LIAM: The Pentagon.
LAURA: What is this? Oh, look at all those
carpets. Do they fly?
LIAM: Is this Heaven?
LAURA: Is this Heaven?
TRAVIS: You're prone, Percy's prone.
TALIESIN: I don't think I can go prone.
TRAVIS: Really?
TALIESIN: I don't think I can prone.
LAURA: Really?
TALIESIN: Let me double-check this. I don't
think I can.
LIAM: Can you be pwned?
TALIESIN: There's no pwning here.
TRAVIS: You see before you--
TALIESIN: Yep. I cannot be knocked prone.
TRAVIS: Nice. You're on your feet.
LAURA: Just Vax, then.
LIAM: I also cannot be knocked prone.
TRAVIS: You see before you a brilliant structure
in the shape of a circle. It's quite massive. Made
of stone. There seems to be some sort of
architecture about it.
SAM: Are we able to see inside, like we are right
now, Grog?
TRAVIS: No.
SAM: So we don't know that there's carpets in the
individual rooms in there?
TRAVIS: No.
LIAM: I can see them, though, right there.
TRAVIS: Just pretend like you don't.
LAURA: Are those doors, or are those windows on
the side?
TRAVIS: Those are doors. You see on each side of
the structure, there are doors. Around you, you
find yourself in a void, black space all around.
In fact, you turn around to see the doorway with
which you came has disappeared.
LAURA: What are we standing on?
TALIESIN: That's really mysterious.
TRAVIS: You're standing on stone, but in each
direction it just seems darkness after about 20 to
30 feet. There is no determinable light source.
It's just you're able to see here.
SAM: I'm just gonna walk around the five-sided
circle and just make sure there's doors on each of
its five sides.
LAURA: They look like they have different symbols
on them.
TRAVIS: Right. There is, in fact, doors on each
one of the faces. One of them appears to be open.
LIAM: And is this also permanent marker?
TRAVIS: Maybe.
LIAM: All right.
SAM: Which one is open?
TRAVIS: It appears that the door on this side is
open.
SAM: The one with the star on it. I'd like to go
investigate that door.
TRAVIS: All right. Yes. So, you go over and find
this open door. And as you look, there is a symbol
above the doorway. It seems to be the symbol of a
star. And the door is open. Would you like to
investigate?
SAM: I would like to investigate.
TRAVIS: Roll an investigation check.
LIAM: Grog, may I use an action to stand up?
SAM: 24.
TRAVIS: 24. Yes, you may stand up.
LIAM: Yes!
TRAVIS: You are facing the wrong way again.
LIAM: That'll be my next action, to turn
around.
TRAVIS: You see before you a wooden and iron door
with a handle. And it has been seemingly forced
open. Inside, there is a room, and from what you
can see from your vantage point, it seems a very
comfortable room. You see a rug on the floor, a
potted plant on the side, and what seems to be a
chest at the end of the room.
SAM: No traps that I saw?
TRAVIS: Does not appear to be trapped.
SAM: All right, I'll step into the room.
TRAVIS: You step in.
LIAM: Seems wise.
SAM: While no one is looking at me, I will take
out a bit of meat and the poison I've never used
in the game, it's called Death Blade Poison. I've
had it since we ran Pathfinder.
LAURA: Oh shit.
SAM: I'm gonna just tuck it into the meat. Just
keep it with me.
LIAM: Oh no. I think you're supposed to keep what
you know and what you don't know separate.
LAURA: But I know.
LIAM: That's called, what was it-- Mata-gaming.
Mota-gaming?
SAM: Meka-gaming.
LIAM: Meka-gaming. You can't Mega Man-game--
SAM: All right, I'm looking about the room for
anything interesting.
TALIESIN: There's a potted plant.
TRAVIS: From your investigation check, you saw
there was a potted plant on the side of the room.
A nice rug on the floor. An open chest near the
back of the room, and it looks like to be just a
simple table with chairs on the other wall.
SAM: All right. I will look under the rug.
TRAVIS: Under the rug?
TALIESIN: Under the rug?
TRAVIS: You pick up the rug?
SAM: Just a little bit, yeah.
TRAVIS: There's floor. Stone floor. A little
dusty.
SAM: All right. What's that thing at the far side
of it? Is that a chest? That's an open chest,
isn't it?
TRAVIS: It does appear-- Yeah.
SAM: I go look in the open chest.
TRAVIS: Okay. You go and look in the chest. It is
an empty chest.
SAM: Nothing's here, someone's been through here
already.
LIAM: It's been about three minutes, I'd like to
use another action to face the same direction as
everyone else.
TRAVIS: Roll a dexterity check.
LIAM: Okay. The boots have worn off, so I can only
roll this ball once. It's not very good.
LAURA: Oh no, that's terrible.
LIAM: 14.
TRAVIS: In your effort to turn, you slip and you
catch yourself, and you face the same way as
everyone else. Well done.
LAURA: Yay. Can I walk up to the door in front of us?
TRAVIS: Sure. Directly in front of you?
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: You walk up.
TALIESIN: I want to take a look at the square, if
that's all right.
TRAVIS: Percy, you go up to the square.
SAM: There's nothing in this one, guys.
LAURA: Well, maybe there's one in the room with
the-- Is that a money symbol?
TRAVIS: It does appear to be a money symbol.
LAURA: Can I go in the money room?
TRAVIS: Would you like to try and open the door?
LAURA: Yeah!
TRAVIS: You go to the door.
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Doesn't seem to open.
LAURA: Is it locked?
SAM: Maybe the symbols correspond to us. The star
being me, because I'm the star. Money for you,
because you're greedy. The square for Vax, because
he's a square.
TALIESIN: It could be money for me, because I have
it.
LAURA: Well, I have it now too, darling.
TALIESIN: That is fair, we actually both have it
at this point. I'm going to try my door, the
square.
LAURA: Maybe a circle for Percy, because there's a
circle on his glasses.
TRAVIS: Percy goes and reaches out, tries the
handle. Door doesn't seem to open. You do notice,
there's not just the handle, there seem to be five
inlaid gems above the handle.
TALIESIN: What sort of five inlaid gems?
TRAVIS: They're fucking gems.
LAURA: Five gems on each door, or five gems, one
gem on each door?
TRAVIS: Five gems above the handle, they're all
very shiny.
LIAM: Circle door.
SAM: Are there any gems on my door, or are they
all gold?
TRAVIS: In fact, as you all communicate with each
other, these doors seem to be identical. A handle
with five gems above each handle, and one of the
gems seems to be glowing.
LAURA: Can I push on the glowing gem?
TRAVIS: Nothing happens.
LAURA: Can I push on all the other ones?
TRAVIS: Nothing seems to happen when you push on
the gems.
LAURA: Can I pull the glowing one out?
TRAVIS: It's inlaid in the wall, it's just
attached. As you're all examining your doors, you
hear a sound, almost like a grunt. Vex, behind
you, you hear a sound.
SAM: Almost like a grunt.
TRAVIS: Almost like a wicked grunt.
LAURA: Is it Grog? Is Grog farting behind me?
TRAVIS: No. You hear footsteps walk up behind you,
as a fist grabs the back of your neck and
slams your face into the door. Grog seemingly has
changed into some sort of other creature.
LAURA: What is that thing?
LIAM: I know what that is. But that's Liam, not
Vax.
TRAVIS: That's a natural 20.
LAURA: You rolled a natural 20 against me?
TRAVIS: I actually did, which is shocking. You
take 19 points of bludgeoning damage.
LAURA: Oh. Fuck you.
TRAVIS: Do you turn around and face your
attacker?
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: There's a fucking doppelgnger behind you.
This amorphous, shapeless creature has come up
behind you and is trying to attack.
LAURA: Is it trying to be like me? Is it going to
take the shape of me?
TRAVIS: I don't know, he's just back there.
LAURA: Trinket runs up and attacks him from the
other--
TRAVIS: He makes another attack before you have a
chance to communicate with your bear.
LIAM: Yeah, they're very fisty.
TRAVIS: That's a natural one. He misses. He swings
forward with his other hand and takes a chip out
of the door.
LAURA: Right. Trinket runs up behind him. I
Hunter's Mark him, and Trinket bites him.
TRAVIS: He bites him?
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Roll to attack. Oh God.
LAURA: Natural 20!
LIAM: Ooh, Trinket is killing it!
LAURA: Oh. Why doesn't he do this in real life?
TRAVIS: I don't know.
LIAM: Irony.
LAURA: Ten. 19.
TRAVIS: 19 damage?
LAURA: 19 damage.
LIAM: Na-na-na-na-na-na.
LAURA: Na-na-na-na-nineteen.
TRAVIS: He takes a bite out, and you see like a
purplish blood start to pour from this wound, and
he takes a big bite out of him.
LAURA: Okay. Then I am going to, for my
attack, use my Rope of Entanglement on the
doppelgnger.
TRAVIS: You are very close.
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Okay.
SAM: Was Grog always a doppelgnger?
LAURA: Is Grog a doppelgnger?
TRAVIS: Make a strength check.
LIAM: You don't know.
TALIESIN: He may have been. We don't know.
LIAM: We don't know.
TALIESIN: We've all got a Grog we don't know
about.
LAURA: Strength. 16.
TRAVIS: 16. Unfortunately, the rope goes over and
he just shakes it off, just slips the rope.
LAURA: Aww, that's bullshit.
TRAVIS: Yeah, well he's a tricky one, this guy.
TALIESIN: I want to start running towards where
this commotion is.
LIAM: Yeah, I'm right around the corner.
TRAVIS: Is there a commotion? Did she call out?
TALIESIN: Did you call out?
LIAM: We didn't hear oof, aaf, or the bear going
(growling)?
TRAVIS: I mean, you seem to be pretty preoccupied
with these doors in front of you.
SAM: I'm looking at a ficus in my room. Seems
nice.
TRAVIS: He will take another swing at you.
LAURA: No!
LIAM: I feel like my twin sense would have kicked
in.
TRAVIS: Probably. It's a little delayed right now.
You keep tripping over everything.
TRAVIS: 16.
LAURA: 16 to hit? Doesn't hit me.
TRAVIS: He misses on the first one. Shit. 13.
LAURA: Okay, I'm going to kick him in the crotch!
TRAVIS: Roll to attack.
LAURA: I don't want to use that one. I'll use this
one. That's terrible. Wait, what do I add? Is this
just a regular attack?
TRAVIS: Yeah, just a straight roll with your
strength modifier.
LAURA: Oh, well, that would be a two.
TRAVIS: That misses. You go to kick and he just
like Jean Claude Van Damme jump splits. And then
comes right back down.
LAURA: Okay. Shit. Trinket's going to attack him.
TRAVIS: Okay.
LAURA: He's going to bite him. So that is 25 for
Trinket.
TRAVIS: That'll hit.
LAURA: 12!
TRAVIS: 12 points of damage?
LAURA: Yes.
TRAVIS: Okay. He's still up.
LAURA: I'm going to go "Doppeljenga!"
TRAVIS: Doppeljenga?
LAURA: Yes.
TRAVIS: You all hear "doppeljenga!" What would
you like to do?
LIAM: I'm running towards the sound of the sister.
TRAVIS: Fair enough. Vax comes charging around the
corner. Percy comes skipping around the corner.
TALIESIN: Yes, right there.
TRAVIS: Beautiful. The doppelganger will take one
more swipe at you. Yeah, he's just furious. 23.
LAURA: Ooh, that hit me.
TRAVIS: That'll hit.
LIAM: (growling)
LAURA: What are these weird sounds coming from
you?
LIAM: It's not coming from me at all, you're just
imagining it in your brain.
TRAVIS: You take 14 points of bludgeoning damage.
LAURA: Fuck. All right.
TRAVIS: Yep. Vax. You get there quick.
LIAM: Okay so I'm going to throw Whisper and bamf
to this motherfucker. At advantage. I'm getting
the hang of this. That's a 28 to hit.
TRAVIS: That'll hit.
LIAM: Okay. Where the fuck is the four-- there it
is. (counting)
LAURA: 52 points of damage so far. Fuck. Kill
him!
LIAM: 44 for the first and a paladin attack, we'll
go attack attack and I'll use my bonus action to
attack--
TRAVIS: I will say because you and Percy were
up at the same time you get one attack.
LIAM: One attack?
TRAVIS: One attack.
LIAM: Well that's how Flungeons and Kragens work.
So one more attack. That is a 25 to hit.
TRAVIS: It hits.
LIAM: Which is a little bit less. That's a seven.
TRAVIS: A seven?
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: Just a little less.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Got it. All right. Percy, you may do
whatever you want. He is bleeding a bunch.
LAURA: Ooh, maybe just flick him in the forehead.
TALIESIN: I'm just going to walk up and slap him
with the glove.
LIAM: Yes.
TRAVIS: Just a slap?
TALIESIN: I'm just going to do a slap.
SAM: Insult his honor?
TRAVIS: A regular glove or with--?
TALIESIN: Oh no, with my fancy glove. I'm going to
use the fancy glove. Let's see, where is that?
TRAVIS: How about you roll an attack and add your
strength modifier?
TALIESIN: Oh no, there's actually a thing for
this.
TRAVIS: Oh, is there?
TALIESIN: Yeah, oh yeah, I have numbers.
SAM: This is his electric glove.
TALIESIN: 23 to hit.
TRAVIS: That hits, yes.
TALIESIN: And that's 14 points of damage and then
he has to make a constitution save or he's
stunned.
TRAVIS: He doesn't need to make a constitution
saving throw because you slap him and his lower
jaw just flies off of his face.
TALIESIN: That's very, very pleasing.
TRAVIS: It just sprays purple gore all over Vex
and Vax. Just this snowcone of gore.
TALIESIN: Is there none on Trinket? Is Trinket--
TRAVIS: No, the way you came up and smacked him he
went that way and Trinket was like "Yeah, nicely
"done." You have removed this doppelganger. So Grog
has been removed from your party.
LAURA: What? Grog's been a doppelganger this
entire time?
TRAVIS: It seems to be.
SAM: Scanlan falls to his knees, feeling
a great pain in his soul. A hollowness that wasn't
there before.
TALIESIN: Oh god, Scanlan's another doppleganger,
quick, kill him.
SAM: I can't believe I lost me mate. What what?
TRAVIS: Yep, good.
SAM: Do I get any XP for that?
TRAVIS: Nope. You are now wrestling with the loss
of clearly your favorite and strongest party
member. And we will take a break at this moment.
(yelling)
LIAM: This is the most fun game!
LAURA: Oh good, we can eat our sherbet. Or whatever
it is that we got.
TALIESIN: I think it was pomegranate sherbet.
TRAVIS: We will return in a moment. I wanted to
thank also Kristen Mack made this wood burned DM's
screen. Which is super, super impressive.
LAURA: Who made all those little stick figure
drawings?
TRAVIS: This is actually Arcade.
LAURA: Really?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: Aww, that's awesome.
TRAVIS: Yeah, he's amazing. We will be giving away
this amazing black walnut hero vault which will be
signed by the cast. And the word-- am I doing this
right?-- in the chat is Regerts.
LIAM: Regerts?
LAURA: Regerts! No regerts!
LIAM: Can you spell Regerts?
TRAVIS: Just regerts. R-E-G-E-R-T-S. So "regerts"
to win this amazing Wyrmwood dice vault. And we
will be back in a moment.
LAURA: Oh my goodness!
[break]
TRAVIS: Welcome back. That's my best Mercer. Is
that--?
LAURA: Oh, yeah!
TRAVIS: We did have a winner in La Chat. The
winner is Avarlic. Or, Ava Rolic. A-V-A-R-L-I-C.
Congratulations, you are winning this gorgeous
Walnut Hero Vault. Signed by all of us at
Critical Role.
LAURA: Yay.
TRAVIS: Let's get back
in. So one quick note. I got a little confused,
actually. When Vex strode up to this door that had
the money symbol on it, and she placed her hand
on the handle, one of those inlaid gems of the
five lit up. So now there are two lit up gems in
the door.
LAURA: Ooh. That's probably important. I wonder if
we touch it too many times without knowing what
we're supposed to do if they, like, explode, and
then we can't open it at all.
TALIESIN: I think all of us have to be touching
one of the doors at the same time. We should
surround the tower.
SAM: Wait, it's still glowing now, right?
TRAVIS: As she's holding it, it's, yeah.
LAURA: Oh, but all of us reach for a door at the
same time!
TALIESIN: Yes, let's all go and touch doors.
LAURA: What about Scanlan's door? Are there any
jewels lit up on your door?
SAM: The same two jewels are lit up on mine.
LAURA: Really?
SAM: Is that true?
TRAVIS: Actually, in your door, all the jewels,
they are not lit up. But if you explore other doors.
LIAM: Scanlan?
SAM: Oi.
LIAM: No, not Scanlan. Scanlan.
SAM: Right.
LIAM: I'm out of vegan wine. Could you get some
more vegan wine in, please?
SAM: Servants. Continue the creepy music and bring
us more wine, please.
LIAM: Thank you.
TRAVIS: The more you drink, the better you play.
LAURA: Yeah.
SAM: Are you sure we shouldn't go wake up the
others upstairs?
TRAVIS: No, we're too far in it now. We've formed
an elite group here.
SAM: I guess it's not the others. It's just Pike,
because Keyleth is dead.
LAURA: Well, no. No, Keyleth is dead in the game.
SAM: No, she's really dead.
LAURA: So all of us should touch a door at the
same time. Yes?
TALIESIN: I'm going to touch a door.
LAURA: Wait, at the same time.
TALIESIN: Well, since you're already touching a
door, I'm going to touch the next door.
LAURA: I'm not touching it yet. I let go of it,
because I got attacked by a doppelganger.
TALIESIN: Well, then I'll go touch--
TRAVIS: Did you let go of the door?
LAURA: Did I?
TRAVIS: Did you?
LAURA: I did. Well, I was getting attacked, so I'm
assuming.
LIAM: You were dealing with a melted humanoid.
TRAVIS: Would you like to grab the handle again?
LAURA: I'm going to wait until other people grab
their handles.
TRAVIS: Fair enough.
TALIESIN: All right. I'm going to go back to my
square.
LAURA: And then all of us can time it.
LIAM: I'll go to my circle. Circle door.
LAURA: So Scanlan should go to the triangle.
TALIESIN: ("Scanlan" voice) Go to the triangle, Scanlan.
SAM: What is that stupid voice you're using?
TALIESIN: That's you, that's what you sound like.
All the time.
SAM: No, my character in the game talks like
this.
TALIESIN: Your character in the game talks a bit
stupid.
SAM: Yeah. All right, on the count of three.
LIAM: You are a world-class performer.
LAURA: Do we touch it on three, or do we touch it
after three?
SAM: I'm representing my character!
LAURA: On three, or after three?
SAM: On three! On three!
LAURA: All right.
LIAM: On free? Three or free?
TALIESIN: Not on four.
SAM: Free.
LAURA: One. Two.
EVERYONE: Three.
TRAVIS: You grab the handles, and you see as three
gems light up while two do not.
SAM: We've got the wrong doors. We got the wrong
doors! Yours is correct, Vex, because you are
greedy.
LAURA: Yeah, ooh. Okay.
SAM: I'm a cube. I'm a cube.
LAURA: Oh, you're a cube! Because you've got a
dick that's a cube!
SAM: Switch with me, Percy!
TALIESIN: I'll switch with you, that's fine.
LIAM: That makes sense, that makes sense.
LAURA: And maybe Vax is--
TRAVIS: Three of the five gems lit up.
LAURA: --a triangle, because he stabs.
LIAM: Dagger, dagger, dagger? Maybe three daggers?
Three sides? Let's try it.
LAURA: Percy, you have circle glasses, right, that
could be something.
TALIESIN: I do have circle glasses.
LIAM: Well, it matches the symbol for your home a
little bit.
SAM: Oh, the de Rolo!
LIAM: De Roll-o. That's what it was all along.
TALIESIN: Oh my god, I've never heard that before.
No one has never made that joke. I can't imagine
I've been going my entire life.
LIAM: You are the richest, most powerful people in
town. Who is looking down on you?
LAURA: One. Two.
ALL: Three.
TRAVIS: All five gems light up.
LAURA: We're so smart!
TRAVIS: You hear a lock release, and the door,
with the weight of your hand on it, starts to
swing open.
LAURA: I go in. Is there a chest?
TRAVIS: You just walk in?
LAURA: I check for traps?
TRAVIS: Roll an investigation check.
LAURA: Okay.
SAM: What are you drinking, piss? What is that?
TRAVIS: Apple juice.
SAM: Oh. That's a lot of apple juice.
TRAVIS: Yeah, man.
SAM: I don't think I've drank that much apple
juice since I was eight.
TRAVIS: Yeah, well, I'm kind of doing Grog.
LAURA: 14.
TRAVIS: 14. You look around the room. You see no
traps. Doesn't seem to be trapped in any way.
LAURA: What about the chest? Is it trapped?
TRAVIS: Would you like to check the chest for
traps? Roll an investigation check.
LAURA: 18.
TRAVIS: 18. Does not appear to be trapped.
LAURA: Can I open it?
TRAVIS: You can. The chest opens.
LAURA: Oh, is it a mimic or is it a chest?
TRAVIS: No, you open it, and inside you see a
small vial with a little liquid.
LAURA: What's it look like?
TRAVIS: It looks like a greater healing potion.
LAURA: Oh. Okay. What's that circle on the table
behind me?
TRAVIS: During your investigation check of the
room, you see the rug, the potted plant, the
chest, the desk and the chair. You also see above
you, in the ceiling, it seems to be a hatch above
you. An iron hatch in the ceiling.
LAURA: Is it bars or is it solid?
TRAVIS: Solid plate metal.
TALIESIN: I will go into my room. Check for traps,
check underneath the carpet, check the desk for
anything interesting and then I'm going to open my
chest.
TRAVIS: Okay. Roll an investigation.
TALIESIN: I will.
LAURA: I took my potion, right?
TALIESIN: That's terrible. Eight.
TRAVIS: Eight. You look under the rug. There is
nothing under the rug. You don't see any immediate
traps. You go over to check the desk. Nothing
seems to be wrong with the desk. However, as you
are checking your desk for traps, you feel the
slashing whip of twigs and thorns across your back
as this twig blight has come across the room and
attacks you from behind.
LIAM: It's a tree creature.
TALIESIN: I'm going to turn around and start
slashing at it with my sword.
TRAVIS: Fair enough. Hold on, he attacks first.
TALIESIN: Yes, that's fair.
TRAVIS: A 21.
TALIESIN: That hits.
TRAVIS: It does hit?!
TALIESIN: Yeah, 21 hits. Yes.
TRAVIS: That is surprising. You're going to take a
whopping--
SAM: Grog, what is with your voice?
TRAVIS: A whopping five points of piercing
damage.
TALIESIN: Five points of piercing damage. All
right.
TRAVIS: It's very hard to sustain this
personality.
SAM: What are you talking about?!
TRAVIS: You turn and you start slashing.
TALIESIN: I'm going to make three quick slashes
with my sword.
LIAM: It's like a medium pain reaction.
TRAVIS: Can you give me an ABC?
TALIESIN: Oh my god. Two natural 20s.
TRAVIS and LIAM: Ooh!
TALIESIN: And a 21.
TRAVIS: Your might is clearly on display in this
visceral and violent outburst.
TALIESIN: I'm attempting to carve it into a shape,
so I'm going to slowly carve it into a lovely
standing statuary of Keyleth. May she rest in
peace.
TRAVIS: Oh, indeed. In the most glorious Edward
Scissorhands movements you ever gestured, there
before you stands a very dead, but green standing
statuary of Keyleth. Very much no longer a threat
to you.
TALIESIN: Quite nice. Quite fitting.
TRAVIS: Leaning against the wall.
TALIESIN: Now I'll open my chest.
TRAVIS: Yes, you go to the chest. It opens and
inside, you find a small vial. Greater healing
potion.
LAURA: I'm going to stand at the corner of my room
and aim--
TRAVIS: Which corner?
LAURA: My room.
SAM: "My room."
LAURA: This corner right here and aim up at the
hatch. Is anything happening?
TRAVIS: When you aim at it?
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Your shoulders begin to burn ever so
slightly.
LAURA: Does it look like there's a lock on the
hatch?
TRAVIS: No.
LAURA: Does it look like there's a handle on the
hatch?
TRAVIS: Nope.
LAURA: Does it look like it opens outward or
inward?
TRAVIS: You can't tell.
SAM: I'm going in to investigate my room. One.
TRAVIS: Cool. You go in, you walk in and you're
facing backwards. You fall down and it seems to be
a very normal room.
SAM: I'll open the trunk.
TRAVIS: Okay. You go forward and as you get to the
trunk, the mimic opens its mouth.
SAM: (yelling)
TRAVIS: A pseudopod attacks you.
SAM: A pseudopod attacks me?
TRAVIS: You become attached--
LAURA: To the chest?
TRAVIS: It has you and it does--
TALIESIN: Mimics are the worst. Just made of
promises--
TRAVIS: 16 points of damage.
LAURA: (laughs) 16?
SAM: 16 points of damage.
TRAVIS: It grabs you and it wraps up with its
pseudopod and because you're so small, you're now
grappled and it covers your mouth so you cannot
scream.
SAM: Nor cast a spell.
TRAVIS: Indeed.
SAM: Unless I have a spell that does not need a
vocal thing. Let me just check.
TALIESIN: Also grappled, I don't know if you can
actually move your hands either.
SAM: Let's see here.
TRAVIS: You are grappled for the moment, Scanlan.
SAM: Sure. Carry on--
TRAVIS: Anyone else?
LIAM: Yeah. I'll do all the same shit. I want to,
before I check for traps at the door, perception
check for anything--
TRAVIS: Well, don't be so excited about it. It's a
unique room. You don't know what adventures lie
inside! So roll an investigation check. See what
happens.
LIAM: Why'd I roll two? I don't know why I rolled
two. I'll take the lower of them. 23.
TRAVIS: Your arm falls off. It just falls off
behind you.
LIAM: I do not understand this game, Grog!
TRAVIS: No, you come in the room.
LIAM: Jeepers creepers.
TRAVIS: You come in. The room does not appear to
be trapped. You do sense movement somewhere in the room.
LIAM: Do I know what direction I sense the
movement from?
TRAVIS: It's in front of you.
LIAM: In front of me? Is it the rug or the chest?
TRAVIS: You're not sure.
LIAM: Hmm. What is this thing moving? Sam, wiggle
your hand.
LAURA: Scanlan.
LIAM: Where's the movement? It's there. So I go
over to this desk and open it.
TRAVIS: Right. As you do, the Rug of Smothering--
LIAM and SAM: Yes!
TRAVIS: --with its false appearance grapples
you from behind and will attempt to smother you.
LIAM: What does it have to do?
SAM: I'm trying to figure out, did Travis find
these things and put them in the room or did he
think, what can I put in a room?
TRAVIS: I just went to the Monster Manual.
SAM: I'll go through the Monster Manual and be
like, ooh, a rug! And put that in there. What else
can I put in a room... ooh! A plant!
TRAVIS: It is a 21 to hit and you take-- that does
hit.
LIAM: I believe so.
TRAVIS: You take 11 points of bludgeoning damage
and you are restrained, blinded and at risk of
suffocating.
LIAM: Sweet.
LAURA: You're going to die from a rug!
TRAVIS: You cannot gesture, make a sound or
anything in your tiny little room.
TALIESIN: You're getting murdered by the touring
company of Aladdin.
TRAVIS: Percy, what would you like to do?
TALIESIN: Can I hear any of this? Is there
anything--
TRAVIS: You are in solid stone rooms. You are at
risk of suffocating.
LIAM: (muffled) Can I say Jenga? Jenga!
LAURA: But you can't reach your earring, so nobody
can hear you saying it.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we didn't-- we have to do that.
LIAM: We have to do this?
LAURA: Yeah, we have to touch our earring in order
to-- it's kind of the thing.
TRAVIS: You've got to tickle your earlobe when you
talk.
LIAM: I will use a game to experience death. It
will be enlightening.
TRAVIS: Yeah. I mean, you never know when it might
come for you out here.
TALIESIN: Is there anything else? Is there
anything in the ceiling? Is there anything on the floor?
TRAVIS: There is a hatch above you in the ceiling.
A plate metal hatch.
TALIESIN: I'm going to back up to the same corner
that Vex is in and I'm going to take a couple
shots at the hatch, see what happens.
TRAVIS: You back up. Roll to-- no, fuck that. It's
a hatch. You fire. How many shots would you like
to fire?
TALIESIN: Three in quick succession.
TRAVIS: Brilliant. You fire off three quick
shots-- no need to roll-- they all ricochet off of this--
TALIESIN: Two of them crit!
TRAVIS: Oh. All right. That makes a difference.
TALIESIN: It does! I just rolled six times and
four times have been critical.
TRAVIS: You fire your first shot and while it
ricochets off, it starts bouncing around the stone
room dangerously close to yourself. You are so
calm and cool, and with that debonair Percy charm,
you merely make a slight adjustment with your gun,
and you fire. The door-- it hits and you see it
start to crack and start to loosen from the wall.
A small piece of the hatch is now showing some
visible line of sight between it and the ceiling.
TALIESIN: I think I'm starting to open this hatch
which is in my room. Can everybody hear me?
LAURA: Can we hear him? Can I hear him?
TRAVIS: You can hear him.
LAURA: I can hear you, darling.
SAM: But I can't talk.
LAURA: I can hear you, darling. What's up?
TALIESIN: Oh, I've got a hatch in my room and I've
got it a bit open at this point.
LAURA: I've got a hatch too!
TALIESIN: I wonder if there's five hatches?
LAURA: Scanlan, Vax, look up. Do you see a hatch?
TALIESIN: Be rude. That's fine.
LAURA: Dicks.
TALIESIN: So rude.
SAM: We're not going to mega-game.
LAURA: Should I come in your room and look at your
hatch, or should I continue to look at my hatch?
LIAM: Mega Man is for cowards.
TALIESIN: My hatch is a bit-- Have you
loosened your hatch yet?
LAURA: Let me give it a try.
TRAVIS: While you're talking, the mimic in
Scanlan's room will again try to smother you with
a bite attack while it's grappling you.
SAM: Sure.
TRAVIS: Hold on, I've got to add. Five seconds.
Where's the music?!
SAM: Servants, come on, now!
LAURA: They got so tired.
TALIESIN: Union break.
LIAM: Grog, you're breaking the verisimilitude.
LAURA: There it is. The back.
TRAVIS: With advantage, that is 24 points of
damage.
TALIESIN: How are you doing right now, Scanlan?
Not that I know. I shouldn't know.
TRAVIS: Where are you at?
TALIESIN: Is that a yummy sound?
TRAVIS: Vax, your rug of smothering also begins to
crush you again.
LIAM: This is not my first time.
LAURA: Being smothered by a rug?
LIAM: Having my breathing snuffed out.
TRAVIS: Actually, before this happens, roll a
strength check.
LIAM: A strength check? All right. I roll the
round die. I'll roll the Grog one. That's a one.
I'm going to use another luck.
LAURA: That's your last one.
LIAM: It's not. It's my third one, a-hole. I have four.
TRAVIS: You don't need to roll your modifier.
That's enough. You break free, and the rug starts
to shimmy down across your legs. It's not
smothering you anymore, but it's still keeping you
in place. Your arms are free, and you can
breathe.
LIAM: The most important thing to me right now is
to point out that my strength is 14, which is
slightly above average, which is very different
than your shit-ass seven, with a modifier of
negative two.
TRAVIS: While it is around your legs, it will bite
you for 21 points of damage. Not bite you, crush
you. Sorry.
LIAM: Does it roll to hit, or do I make a dex
save?
TRAVIS: It's still grappling you, so you're in the
same place, still, but you can breathe and you can
move, but it's still around your legs.
LIAM: What did I just roll to do, though, Grog? I
don't understand.
TRAVIS: So you could breathe and not suffocate.
LIAM: That's very important. Is it important for
me, though? I haven't breathed very much at all--
TRAVIS: You, technically? No. Not important for
you.
LIAM: I would have been fine in there.
TRAVIS: But your singing career would have been
limited.
LIAM: Okay, so I take a bunch of damage, right?
TRAVIS: 21 points of damage.
LIAM: 21 points of damage, okay.
TRAVIS: And you are now free.
LIAM: Hey, I have 69 hit points. Nice.
LAURA: Can I fly up and look at the hatch up
close?
TRAVIS: Sure. You take out the broom, you fly up
to the hatch--
LAURA: Also, can Trinket come in the room?
TRAVIS: Sure. Trinket comes in.
LAURA: He's going to stand in the other corner.
LIAM: Are the hatches bars?
TRAVIS: Plate metal. A square piece of plate
metal.
LAURA: What can I see up close? Anything?
TRAVIS: It is a plate metal hatch. A sheet of
metal with rivets, and it's solid.
LAURA: Can I push on it?
TRAVIS: You cannot.
LAURA: Can I get my fingers in and pull on it?
TRAVIS: No.
LAURA: Can I stick a dagger in at the edges and
try to pry it open?
TRAVIS: No. You could try, and I could make you
roll a bunch of times. It wouldn't work.
LAURA: Well, he rolled two criticals, and
something happened. What if I roll a critical?
TRAVIS: Roll a dice.
LAURA: Ooh, so close. It was a 19.
TRAVIS: You pull on it, and you hear (metal
creaking).
LIAM: There's a witch behind it.
TALIESIN: I've got mine kind of open, if you want
to come here.
TRAVIS: Scanlan, roll a strength saving throw.
SAM: 13.
TRAVIS: 13? That's actually exactly what you
needed. You manage to get your arms free, and you
break free of the mimic, but it is still coming at
you. Now you see teeth coming out of this chest, a
giant pseudopod tongue.
SAM: Should I escape, or should I kill it? I don't
know.
LAURA: Kill it!
SAM: I will step back, and I will Lightning Bolt
it at level five!
TRAVIS: Go for it.
TALIESIN: What does any of that mean?
SAM: I will Lightning Bolt it at level five!
TALIESIN: It was like you started to say four and
said five. It turned into an accent.
LIAM: I thought you said you played GURPS in grade
school.
SAM: He has to make a dex save. I think it's a dex
save.
TRAVIS: Of what?
SAM: Oh boy. It's probably either 15, or it's my
spell DC. If it's my spell DC, I wouldn't have the
cone up, so it would be 20.
TRAVIS: That is a 13.
SAM: Well, either way, he fails, so he gets 10d6
of damage.
LAURA: That's a lot of lightning damage.
LIAM: Sounds like a lot of something, of
something.
SAM: How many is that? That's nine.
LIAM: These scarves were a wonderful purchase for
the group. They are so cozy.
LAURA: So warm.
LIAM: We need them in Vasselheim.
SAM: 39. Oh! And one more. 43.
TRAVIS: With that one lightning, you see the mimic
shake, tense up, quake, and burst apart into
purple goo. It splatters little green noodles all
over the floor where it was, and you see in its
muck a little vial where it was.
SAM: I inspect the vial.
TRAVIS: It's a greater healing potion.
SAM: I chug it.
TRAVIS: Yeah, you chug it. Go for it.
SAM: What is that, four something?
LAURA: 4d4.
SAM: Everyone, all the rooms have horrible
creatures in them! Be careful!
LAURA: Mine didn't have any creatures in it.
TALIESIN: Mine had a mildly irritated house
plant.
LIAM: Fuck the lot of you!
TRAVIS: That's it? Not "help?" While he's healing,
Vax, what would you like to do?
LIAM: My hands are free? I throw Whisper 15 feet
out the door and bamf to where it strikes on the ground.
TRAVIS: Nice. You pop outside the door.
LIAM: Yeah, and then I will turn now-- it's up to
you, Grog--
TRAVIS: Unleash Armageddon. Do what you do.
LIAM: I'm going to use two daggers, if I can.
TRAVIS: Now's the time, mate.
LIAM: Wait. I'm going to use my Vow of Enmity on
the rug, and then I'm going to attack.
TALIESIN: Are you going to cut a rug, then?
TRAVIS: You get 150 XP.
TALIESIN: 150 XP for the terrible pun. Huzzah!
SAM: How many do you have?
LIAM: I have zero points!
TRAVIS: I am susceptible to puns.
TALIESIN: Good to know.
SAM: That is good to know, actually.
LIAM: (giggles) 31, and because my Vow of Enmity
on this rug is in fucking effect, I get sneak
attack damage, so that is two, plus eight is ten,
and then we add some of that. 12, and these guys
go, as well. (counting)
LAURA: I like that you can sneak attack the rug.
It doesn't know you're there!
TRAVIS: Right. It's a rug.
LIAM: 39 points of damage on the fucking Persian
carpet.
TRAVIS: And with that, the rug quakes and falls
flat, deflated. A regular rug now. Slightly
unraveled at the corners.
LIAM: Hardwood floors are much fucking better.
Fuck you. And I'm going to walk in and check out
that chest.
TRAVIS: Indeed. You hear, all of a sudden, as you
check out the chest-- indeed, there is a greater
healing potion. As Vax terminates the rug, you
hear a click in all of the latches above your heads.
LAURA: Oh no. Am I still up at the latch? Am I
still right at the latch?
TRAVIS: Are you?
LAURA: Well, I said I was. I never stopped being
there.
TRAVIS: Yeah. There you are, just flying right
next to it.
TALIESIN: I'll take another shot at mine.
TRAVIS: You fire, and the latch flips open at the
top.
TALIESIN: Hello?
LAURA: Can I push on mine?
TRAVIS: No response. You may push on yours. It
lifts. It comes right back down, but lifts.
LAURA: My latch is open. My hatch!
TALIESIN: Mine, as well.
LAURA: Scanlan, Vax?
SAM: Seems like mine's open, too.
LAURA: Should we go in?
TALIESIN: I'm going to activate my spider boots
and head on up there.
TRAVIS: Excellent. You walk up the side of the
wall, doing the little shimmy that Percy does so
well in his bedroom when he's getting dressed in
Whitestone. He pops through the hatch. Do you go
up, as well?
LAURA: I do. I bamf Trinket into my necklace,
first.
TRAVIS: Trinket goes in the necklace. You go up
through the hatch. What about you two fellows?
SAM: I'm going to turn into a dung beetle and fly
straight up.
TRAVIS: Right, yeah. Into this tiny little dung
beetle, you fly. You hit the hatch.
SAM: It's solid?!
TRAVIS: There was a click. It didn't fucking
open.
SAM: I thought it had bars.
TRAVIS: (popping)
SAM: I thought it had bars!
TRAVIS: You take five points of stupid damage.
SAM: Then I'm back out as a gnome, and I guess I'm
falling.
TRAVIS: Yeah, you fall a whole ten, 11 feet.
SAM: More damage?
TRAVIS: You take two points of gnome damage.
SAM: All right. Shit.
TRAVIS: Vax, what are you doing? Wings? Yeah, the
fucking wings come out, even though you're on the
ground, and you walk, very badass, back through
the room.
LIAM: I'll grab the potion. I will use them to
easily hop the 12 feet up, and then I will pull
the wings in. Press the wings into the back of me,
and slide and crawl my way up this tunnel.
TRAVIS: Brilliant. You pop up through the hatch.
LAURA: Is it another room, or is it a tunnel?
TRAVIS: We'll shortly see.
LIAM: My wings are silky smooth.
TRAVIS: Scanlan, what are you doing? You come to,
and you're like, "Fuck. Why did I turn into a dung
"beetle? The latch was still closed."
SAM: All right. Now I will turn into a monkey.
TRAVIS: A monkey. What kind of monkey?
SAM: A gibbon.
TRAVIS: A small gibbon. Okay.
SAM: Big enough that it has muscles.
TRAVIS: We'll find out.
SAM: I crawl up to the top and try to push open
the latch.
TRAVIS: You get up there, and as you start to
push, roll a strength check with disadvantage.
SAM: Natural 20.
SAM and TALIESIN: Natural 20!
ALL: Whoa!
TRAVIS: This very large metal latch flies open.
SAM: I shit on the latch and keep going.
TRAVIS: You pop up through the latch. As Scanlan
makes his gibbon way through the latch, all of you
find yourself in a new space, and all of the
latches slam closed. You find yourself in a new space.
LAURA: Grog, you are so artistic!
TRAVIS: Aren't I? It resembles the shape of the
previous map.
TALIESIN: That resembles the shape of the previous
map.
SAM: That's a circle, just like the last one.
TRAVIS: You find yourselves with a flat floor. You
have a visual line of sight with all of the
members of your team.
LAURA: We can see each other?
TRAVIS: You can see each other.
SAM: Except for one. Who would have been the
star?
TRAVIS: There's some sort of body laying above the
area of the room with the door that was already
open.
TALIESIN: I'm going to examine it.
SAM: Wait, are there walls separating us?
TRAVIS: You are on what seems to be the roof of
the room previous, and there's a giant tower right
in the middle of all of this. At the top of this
tower, not to size, there's a large platform dome
area up here with light radiating out of it.
LIAM: Guys, from my point of view, I can see
Fletcher's Mill emblazoned at the base of the
tower. I just imagined it!
LAURA: Is that Sharpie at the bottom of that
pepper mill?
TRAVIS: No. Nope.
SAM: Did he ruin your designer pepper mill?
LAURA: Travis Willingham!
TRAVIS: It was a wedding gift. Who cares?
(laughter)
TRAVIS: So you see your comrades up atop the roof
of this platform and some sort of corpse or
motionless body.
LAURA: Can we walk over to it?
TRAVIS: You can try.
LAURA: I want to walk over to it and kick it.
TRAVIS: You start to walk over, and as you reach
this border, you are struck by an invisible field,
and you take eight points of force damage.
LAURA: Oh no, eight points.
LIAM: I wanted to pickpocket Scanlan so I could
start Robbing Gibbons.
TRAVIS: As you hit the wall, there is a shimmer of
energy that quickly dissipates in between your
section and someone else's.
LAURA: Is it gone now, or is it still there?
TRAVIS: It shimmers and disappears.
LAURA and TALIESIN: It's probably still there.
TALIESIN: I want to try stepping up the column.
TRAVIS: As you move towards the column, you see on
this tower, it is made of stone, but there seem
to be built-in footholds and handholds.
TALIESIN: I ignore them. I'm not going to put my
hands or feet in any of those holes.
TRAVIS: It appears the same energy covers that
tower, and you take eight points of force damage.
As Percy touches and activates the shield for a
second time, the lights around you dim, and you
feel heat around each of you individually.
You are struck with horror as form begins
to take shape in front of each of you. Behind
Percy, all of a sudden, the form of a mind flayer
begins to take shape. Behind Vax, a red-skinned,
armor-clad, winged demon appears. A cambion, right
in front of our rogue.
SAM: You looked these up last night, you had to
look these up.
TRAVIS: In front of Vex, a pony.
LAURA: Oh, a pony, yay!
TALIESIN: Don't touch it, it's evil.
TRAVIS: And in front of Scanlan materializes, to
his horror,
a fucking T-rex.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: A giant roar echoes across the land.
LIAM: Over a gibbon!
TALIESIN: I have been waiting for gibbon versus
T-rex my entire life!
TRAVIS: A T-rex versus a gibbon. You all stare in
horror at perfectly picked enemies for you. I need
you all to roll initiative.
SAM: I rolled one. 20, 20, one, my last three
rolls.
TALIESIN: 23.
TRAVIS: 23, that's the Percy I know. Vex?
LAURA: 22.
TRAVIS: Vax?
LIAM: A big 12.
TALIESIN: That potion was 4d4?
SAM: I did 4d4 plus four, is that right for a
greater healing potion?
LIAM: It is.
TRAVIS: Okay. The cambion turns and faces Vax at
the top of the initiative, and he will unleash his
Fire Ray at you. 26 to hit.
LIAM: Yeah, that'll hit.
TRAVIS: This is hard. You take 12 points of fire
damage.
LIAM: Okay, I'm going to pretend like the
Deathwalker's Ward is set to fire.
TRAVIS: Sure.
LIAM: So halve that.
TRAVIS: So six, nice. And he will make a ranged
spear attack against you. It's only 19.
LIAM: Does not hit. Sidestep.
TRAVIS: The deer shoots-- The deer? The deer
bounds past-- The spear misses you, as you are
presented with this new foe, and with a bonus
action he will take flight. But I'm not breaking
out those fucking stands, so let's just say he takes
flight. Next in the initiative order, this pony
takes a few steps towards you and (snorting).
LAURA: No, don't attack me, pony!
TRAVIS: And turns into a mystical unicorn.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: A large, celestial, lawfully good enemy!
TALIESIN: You're going to have to kill it.
LAURA: No, I'm not going to, it's so cute!
TALIESIN: We have to murder and eat our opponents,
it's the only way out.
TRAVIS: And it will cast Entangle on you.
LAURA: What do I have to roll to avoid it?
TRAVIS: You have to make a DC 18. It is a dex.
LAURA: Okay. 17.
TRAVIS: You feel all of a sudden these vines come
out of the stonework and it holds you where you
are. And it will charge straight at you using its
magical horn. 22.
LAURA: It hits. But I have uncanny dodge and
evade, which one do I use?
LIAM: Evasion for a dex save, uncanny dodge can
halve one melee attack per round.
TRAVIS: It does 12 points of piercing damage and I
need to you roll a strength saving throw or be
knocked prone by its mystical power.
LAURA: A strength saving throw? If I use evasion
does it still have to do that?
TRAVIS: I have no idea.
LIAM: Evasion only triggers if you have to make a
dex save.
LAURA: That was so fucking close. 25.
TRAVIS: You're not knocked prone, you sidestep it,
but you only take the damage. Percy, you are up.
TALIESIN: I am going to throw Manners at this
creature.
TRAVIS: Brilliant.
LIAM: Is it a JRPG, you're throwing mana?
TALIESIN: Manners, not mana. Let's see, that's a
ranged attack roll, that's 30 to hit.
TRAVIS: That will hit.
TALIESIN: My target is restrained. On its turn, it
can make a DC 20 strength check to try and get
out. At the moment, it's restrained.
TRAVIS: A natural one, he is restrained.
TALIESIN: And while he's restrained, I'm going to
walk over and I'm going to burn an action surge.
I'm going to stab him with my sword three times.
And since he's restrained I think I get a bonus on
that, don't I?
TRAVIS: You're so nasty. Melee attacks.
TALIESIN: Let's not waste bullets on anything like
this. I'll take three swipes. Is it an auto-crit
if they're restrained?
TRAVIS: Yeah. No, you have advantage, I think.
TALIESIN: I have advantage, okay. So I'll go with
that. I don't actually remember.
TRAVIS: If I overheard the guy at the tavern
right.
TALIESIN: That's one normal hit. 25 to hit.
TRAVIS: Yeah. He has a very low AC.
TALIESIN: And the last one is 24 to hit.
TRAVIS: All three hit.
TALIESIN: So that's 36 points of piercing damage.
And I'm going to breathe deep. I may use my bonus
action to take a healing potion.
TRAVIS: Please do. All right, next up: Vex.
LAURA: That's me! Are my hands restrained or is it
just my feet?
TRAVIS: Just your feet, you cannot move. Let me
check, because I'm sure I'm getting this totally right.
LIAM: What are you checking, Grog? Do you have a
book or something for this?
TRAVIS: No, I carve notes into the thingy. Yeah,
you just can't move.
LAURA: I can't move my feet? Okay. I'm going to
cast Grasping Vine. And I'm going to try to hook
a vine around the unicorn and pull him back
towards the corner right here.
LIAM: Oh, you killed him!
LAURA: He dies.
TRAVIS: He is top heavy. Let's go with option
number two. None of these guys want to stay up!
You're so drunk.
SAM: Go home, unicorn.
TRAVIS: Unicorn will use one of his legendary--
LAURA: He's got legendary actions?
TRAVIS: Yep, and he resists the Grasping Vine.
LAURA: What a fucking dick!
TRAVIS: I know, unicorns, right? Fuck me.
LAURA: Fine, well, Grasping Vine is a bonus action.
I don't think he can resist it, but whatever.
TRAVIS: Are you a unicorn? Then how do you know?
LAURA: It's not like it's a spell effect, he has
to make a dexterity save.
TRAVIS: Are you arguing with the BM?
LAURA: Nope, not at all. Can I shoot him? No, I
don't want to shoot him! Can I talk to him?
TRAVIS: Sure.
LAURA: I want to say: Unicorn, why are you
attacking me? I don't want to fight you.
TRAVIS: What language are you speaking in?
LAURA: I'm speaking in Unicorn.
SAM: You already cast Speak With Animals today.
LIAM: Celestial for unicorn.
LAURA: I'm speaking in Unicorn.
LIAM: And your six seconds are up.
TRAVIS: That's not a language.
LAURA: Grog, how do you know it's not a language?
TRAVIS: I know these things. It's what I do. I
drink and I know things.
LAURA: All right, then I'm going to speak in
normal, and I'm speaking Elvish! I feel like
unicorns might be able to understand.
TRAVIS: Well, the unicorn speaks Celestial,
Elvish, Sylvan, and telepathy, but because you
just spoke in Common--
LAURA: I said Elvish.
TRAVIS: Good thing it understands you-- It has
telepathy!
LAURA: So I say: Why are you fighting me? Why? I
don't want to fight you. I don't want to hurt you.
I love you.
TRAVIS: And he's like, "I am a unicorn. There can
only be one."
(laughter)
LAURA: That's my whole turn.
LIAM: You know that was like 87 seconds.
TRAVIS: The T-rex will take its turn!
SAM: Bring it.
TRAVIS: It is going to run towards you with a
multi-attack on your carrion form. It's going to
make a bite attack first. That is an 18.
SAM: That hits.
TRAVIS: Yeah! Oh god. Okay.
TALIESIN: So much math.
TRAVIS: That is 36 points of damage. Does that
knock you out of your carrion form?
SAM: Oh yeah, I'm no longer a monkey.
TRAVIS: It's a bite, so you are in the jaws of a
T-rex, Scanlan.
TALIESIN: (squawks) I don't think they make that
noise, but--
LAURA: I don't think so. It sounded kind of like a
bird.
TALIESIN: They are very bird-like.
TRAVIS: And we are going to make a tail attack
against you. Oh, it's only 18 to hit.
SAM: Yeah, that hits. Scanlan has an AC of 14.
LAURA: What? That's so low.
TRAVIS: That is 28 points of damage as it smacks
you with its tail.
SAM: Great.
LAURA: How are you doing, Scanlan?
SAM: I'm still double digits.
TRAVIS: Next up: Vax.
LIAM: All right. I regain one hit point as a
revenant. So that's going to make all the
difference. I use my action to cast a level one
druid spell, Faerie Fire, on this flying fucker.
It has to make a dex save versus my DC of 16.
TRAVIS: Okay.
LAURA: You really caught on.
LIAM: I did.
TRAVIS: That's an eight.
LIAM: Poof! Lit up like a disco ball, and I now
have advantage on the attack against it so I can
fucking sneak attack, which is going to be
clutch.
TRAVIS: Indeed. It stands there, not thinking much
of you and a burst of fiery light surrounds his
form. All of a sudden, you are very sure about
where to hit and how.
LIAM: Right in front of me, and I will use my
bonus action to throw a fucking dagger. Oh dear,
that is a 23 to hit.
TRAVIS: 23 hits.
LIAM: Yes, it does, and it gets (counting), plus
these guys. Jeez, that was a shitty roll. 33 and
I'm going to dump my other level two spell slot
for Divine Smite. 48 total from Whisper.
TRAVIS: 48 massive points of damage. Shit. Damn.
Cool. Sam. Scan! Lan. You're up!
SAM: (muttering) Challenge rating. Am I in its--
TRAVIS: No, it smacked you with its tail away. It
bit you, and then it was like (spits out), and hit
you with its ass extension.
SAM: All right, I'm contractually required to turn
into a triceratops.
TRAVIS: I mean, have you done that before?
SAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Great. I should have that, but I didn't
plan that far ahead. So we're going to turn you
into this--
SAM: This unicorn.
TRAVIS: This giant werebear looking fucking thing.
There you go.
SAM: Oh, before I did that, I Healing Worded
myself for like ten points of health there, as a
bonus. And now I am a triceratops and I will use
the rest of my turn to back into the corner.
TRAVIS: Okay, that's your turn.
SAM: Yeah, that's it.
TRAVIS: Okay, the cambion is up and he's going to
multi-attack against you. 16 will miss. 24?
LIAM: It will, but I'm going to use my last luck.
Roll again.
TRAVIS: Oh. 18?
LIAM: Does not hit.
TRAVIS: Nice. He has one last-- 25.
LIAM: Does hit.
TRAVIS: Great, you only get hit once though, which
is nice.
LIAM: What's it hit me with?
TRAVIS: He hits you with this fiery spear.
LIAM: All right.
TRAVIS: That is 16 points of fire and piercing
damage.
LIAM: Fire, so that'll be halved to eight? And
then it might be four, I'm going to look something
up really fucking quick. Uncanny dodge. I'm going
to halve that down to four.
TRAVIS: So four points of damage. There you go.
Brilliant. He's going to use his movement to--
Just right in your face! "Look how big my wings
are in comparison to yours!" It is now the
unicorn's turn. The unicorn rushes forward--
LIAM: Have you ever seen this unicorn before?
LAURA: No, I have no idea--
TRAVIS: He is going to make two hooved attacks
against you and a horn stabby in your face.
TALIESIN: Friendship is magic.
TRAVIS: That's true. 16?
LAURA: Doesn't hit.
TRAVIS: 25?
LAURA: That hits.
TRAVIS: And the horn. That hits.
LAURA: How do you know?
TRAVIS: Because it's 27. That is 19 points of
piercing and bludgeoning damage, respectively.
TALIESIN: Could be worse.
TRAVIS: And he will stay where he is. He will try
to stand up again. For the brave-- (gasps) He's a
show pony. Percy, you're up.
TALIESIN: I actually should be right in the face
of this terrible--
TRAVIS: Oh yes, sorry. You did stabby the fuck out
of him.
TALIESIN: I'm just going to keep stabby, stabby,
stabby. With advantage. So, stabby. Yes, that
hits. Stabby. Ooh, that's nice. That's crit-- Oh,
it's not crit because it's not a gun, it's just a
sword. And that's really hard to read, because
that's Scanlan's dice. My lowest number is 28 to hit.
TRAVIS: They all hit, very hard.
LAURA: It is really pretty though, Scanlan.
SAM: Thank you.
LIAM: The triceratops diddles his iPhone in the
corner.
SAM: I'm looking up all my stats.
TALIESIN: 36 points of damage.
SAM: I haven't been a triceratops in over a year.
TALIESIN: Is he still just doing that, just
there?
TRAVIS: Yep. He looks like he is quite surprised
as to why he's there in the first fucking place,
and that you are--
TALIESIN: I'm just going to add a little bit of
extra damage on there with my Hex. So let's just
add five points of lightning damage as well, for
fun. 14 points of lightning damage on top of that.
TRAVIS: He will react to that extra salvo,
(snarls) with all his stupid things.
TALIESIN: Try and mental me or anything?
TRAVIS: He is going to use Mind Blast right at
you. I need you to roll an intelligence saving throw.
TALIESIN: All right. I can do that.
TRAVIS: Wasn't it you that he tried to suck the
brain out of before?
LAURA: That was Scanlan.
TALIESIN: Intelligence saving throw, that's 23.
TRAVIS: Yeah, that doesn't happen at all. Cool.
Good deal. He is going to make a simple melee
attack against you.
TALIESIN: Oh no, he's not. He's restrained.
TRAVIS: Oh, yeah, he's restrained. He's just, like,
baffled by how dominant you are in this whole thing.
TALIESIN: I'm just going to keep stabbing him in
the face over and over again.
TRAVIS: Yeah, he really wishes he wasn't here
right now. He's not sure who he pissed off. Vex,
you're up.
LAURA: Yeah! Am I still entangled?
TRAVIS: Oh, make a strength saving throw.
LAURA: Saving throw? That would be 19.
TRAVIS: You break free of the vines and they
wither and die in the ground.
LAURA: I'm going to use my bonus action to use the
Grasping Vine again and try to wrap right around
his leg and yank him back.
TRAVIS: Great. I roll, don't I? What is it?
LAURA: That is a dex save.
TRAVIS: That's a seven.
LAURA: Oh, then he's restrained. Or he's pulled
back at least.
TRAVIS: He's pulled back on his heinies.
LAURA: Yeah! So it falls over, it's all right. And
then I'm going to cast Speak with Animals,
although I don't need to because he already--
TRAVIS: Speaks more languages than you do.
LAURA: And I'm going to say: You're a very good
creature. I know you're lawful. What are you doing
fighting me? I'm good too!
TRAVIS: (hums)
LAURA: Anything? No response?
TRAVIS: I mean, on his turn he might.
LAURA: Okay, just know that I don't want to attack
you, I'd rather just ride around on you, because
you seem really beautiful.
SAM: One more time, just not trying to kill you.
LAURA: And then for my movement, I'm going to hop
on my broom and fly up in the air.
TRAVIS: How high?
LAURA: Not quite to the top of the tower. How high
does the tower go?
TRAVIS: Looks like it's 120 feet to the top of the
tower.
LAURA: I'm going to just go up 40 feet.
TRAVIS: That's good. At 40 feet you are hovering
up at the top of the tower, and you hear somewhere
above you a buzz of energy. I don't know how many
this is.
LAURA: Ooh, you have them!
TRAVIS: Well they're over here, so fuck it.
LAURA: Wait, maybe flip it over.
SAM: You got it wrong.
LAURA: That's it!
TRAVIS: How's this shit work? What was wrong with
the first way I was doing this? Here, you're
flying 40 feet in the air. Sam, make that work.
SAM: We are missing a piece.
TRAVIS: Oh, here, there's a base over here!
LIAM: There you go!
TRAVIS: I'm sure there's a certain number of
things you've got to count, but-- That's really high.
LAURA: Yeah (counting). I'm about ten feet higher
than I should be.
TRAVIS: You hear a buzz of energy above you, but
you seem to be fine. Scanlan. No, Vax. No, T-rex!
T-rex charges forward towards the triceratops,
nurturing its ancient rivalry with such a foe. It
will make a multi-attack. It will bitch slap you
with its tail. 25.
SAM: That hits.
TRAVIS: For 23 points of bludgeoning damage. And
it will make a bite attack against you. 21.
SAM: Hits.
TRAVIS: 4d12 plus seven. I suck at subtraction
math. Adding, I'm okay. That is 37 points--
SAM: Whoa!
TRAVIS: Of piercing damage.
SAM: Great.
TRAVIS: Good. Oh, you're a triceratops, you're all
sorts of muscled up.
SAM: A little bit.
TRAVIS: Nice. Vax, it is your turn. He's just
going to be like (grunts).
LIAM: I'm going to use a level one spell slot and
cast Faerie Fire again on the illithid by Freddie.
So it has to save versus a 16.
TRAVIS: As you go to cast Faerie Fire, you see it
disperse along the barrier wall between your
section and his. Unaffected.
LIAM: I thought that would affect physical, not
magical. All right, well then I will fuck this guy
up in front of me then. That's a 23?
TRAVIS: 23 hits.
LIAM: 19, that's good. 36 total. And I'll just
stick it out right in front of him.
TRAVIS: He's looking very rough. Scanlan, your
turn.
SAM: Without leaving his attack range, and thus
not provoking an attack of opportunity I hope, I'm
going to charge for his leg and hit it with a gore
attack. So I'm going to move down the line and
attack his leg. Rolling a two. Plus nine.
TRAVIS: A two! The triceratops runs forward. No
effect.
SAM: End of turn.
TRAVIS: (laughs) That's what the triceratops has
got?
LIAM: That was Sam as Scanlan as Scanlan as T-rex
as bear.
TRAVIS: Okay, the cambion getting its ass handed
to it by Vax will look him in the face, and it
will cast Command at-- let's say fourth level.
LIAM: What, to fly into the wall over and over
again?
TRAVIS: You need to roll a constitution saving
throw.
LIAM: Okay, Colville, it's up to you. Not good.
Eight-- 15.
TRAVIS: 15, not good. He commands you to grovel in
front of him, and all of a sudden you feel this
overwhelming urge. You drop to your knees and you
lay prone right in front of him, not able to get up.
LIAM: I don't understand this game! The rules
don't make sense! Can I have some XBs, please? Can
I have some XBs?
TRAVIS: I'm a fan of puns, you get ten XPs. He
will have advantage on his flaming spear attack
against you.
TRAVIS: That's a natural 20.
LIAM: Sure.
TRAVIS: It was advantage.
LIAM: Sure. What a good idea, to grovel.
TRAVIS: 39 points of piercing and fire damage,
which is halved.
LIAM: But which part of it?
TRAVIS: Well, I don't know.
LIAM: Just give me a number, Grog. You're the
mathematician.
TRAVIS: Let's call it 20, down to 20. Let's call
it 19 points.
LIAM: Okay, I would've got back a hit point,
because I'm a revenant. So that's 41, so I'm
sitting pretty.
TRAVIS: Good deal. There you are. Next up is the
unicorn. Having heard your humanitarian pleas for
peace--
LAURA: He's also stuck in that position because of
the Grasping Vine.
TRAVIS: Casts Levitate. Kidding, he doesn't have
Levitate. Why did I move him? He's there. The
unicorn who's stuck, which I totally forgot about,
will use... Ooh! Yes! Teleport! He casts
Teleport.
LAURA: Where? Where does he go?
TRAVIS: Once a day he magically teleports himself
within five feet of where he was.
LIAM: Within five feet of where he was?
TRAVIS: Poof!
(laughter)
SAM: Wait, five feet Teleport? What spell is
that?!
TRAVIS: No, any willing creatures within five
feet, but that's what I saw first, so that's the
rule. It can go up to a mile away, but it's five
feet.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: It will use its horn of rainbow attack
against you.
LAURA: Oh no.
TRAVIS: That is a 23.
LAURA: Ugh, it fucking hits me.
TRAVIS: That is 22 points of damage. That ends its
turn. Percy, you are up.
TALIESIN: I'm just going to stab him three more
times.
LAURA: Do need to make a dexterity save to see if
I stay on my broom?
TRAVIS: Nope. You take it like a champ.
TALIESIN: Three more attacks. That's 21 to hit.
TRAVIS: That hits. If those two hit, just roll
damage for those two.
TALIESIN: They all hit.
TRAVIS: He's looking pretty gross.
TALIESIN: Oh, that's terrible. 28 points of
piercing damage.
TRAVIS: With the sword, right? As you take your
silvered sword and repeatedly jam it into his
general thorax and face, repeatedly-- Tentacles
falling off like freshly cut sushi, he just falls
backwards, guts spewing like Stephen King's The
Thing. He is toast.
LIAM: (as Clarota) Go fuck yourself.
TALIESIN: For my bonus action I'm going to retract
my little Manners ball, and then I'm going to
walk, and attempt to tap the wall to
see if it's still standing.
TRAVIS: As you walk to the wall, you notice that
there seems to be no force field on your side of
the tower.
TALIESIN: I'm actually in the far corner, put me
behind the unicorn, please.
TRAVIS: Oh, you tapped this one. I got you. You seem
to see no effect.
TALIESIN: All right, good. That's the end of my
turn.
TRAVIS: Vex.
LAURA: Okay. I'm going to take the greater healing
potion. Which is 4d4.
TRAVIS: You better attack this fucking unicorn.
LAURA: Whoa, that's a really good 14 points plus
four, right? So 18 points healed. And then I'm
going to fly over the unicorn, and drop down,
landing on its back! And I'm going to use my Rope
of Entanglement to make like a harness thing and
hold on to the fucking unicorn like a fucking
rodeo.
SAM: Why aren't you killing the unicorn?
LAURA: Because he's lawful good.
TRAVIS: I need you to make an acrobatics check.
LAURA: Okay. That would be a one. (laughs)
SAM: Please tell me she falls on the horn.
TALIESIN: This is everything I've ever wanted.
TRAVIS: You plummet, falling toward its head. And at
the last moment, having been affected by your
wonderful message, it looks up. And you find
yourself impaled, gored on its horn! It even
jumps up and spins!
SAM: Like Free Willy!
LAURA: I deserve that.
TRAVIS: You will take, jeez, 18 points of piercing
damage.
LAURA: Right back down to where I was before I
healed. But thank god I healed!
TRAVIS: You just manage to roll off the horn,
laying on your back across its mane. Not riding
it, but just there for the moment.
LAURA: Am I on my back or on my stomach?
TRAVIS: You're on your back, in a very
uncomfortable arched position. The T-rex turns!
Tail whip!
SAM: (screech)
TRAVIS: That is 26 points of bludgeoning damage,
and the bite attack against you--
SAM: Wait, you have to roll to hit.
TRAVIS: Oh shit, fuck. Oh, 17.
SAM: Hits.
TRAVIS: Okay, that is 39 points of piercing
damage.
SAM: Okay, back to Scanlan.
TRAVIS: Oh yeah? Vax, you are prone and up.
LIAM: I will use half my movement to stand. And
then I will use the other half of my movement,
which winged is 30 feet, and fly up to this
asshole. And I will use a bonus action to down
that potion that I grabbed, which is 4d4 plus
four. So that's (counting) 14. And then I will
stab this asshole in the asshole. That is a 33 to
hit.
TRAVIS: An asshole for an asshole. That hits.
LIAM: All right, here we go. (counting) And then
here come all the d6s.
TRAVIS: Jesus.
LIAM: (counting) 44, and I will dump--
TRAVIS: You're very good at adding all those dice
for someone who's never played this game before.
LIAM: I'm good at math, I'm not good at whatever
the fuck this game is. This is the best game,
though. So it's in the high 40s, you made me lose
track. I'm going to say 49.
TRAVIS: I'll take it. Oh god. Any other attacks
after that?
LIAM: Yeah. Not much. That is 26 to hit.
TRAVIS: Yep, hits.
LIAM: Seven, and I will dump my last spell slot
in. 17.
TRAVIS: And with that, the dagger pierces through
the armor. And you hear (snarls) as a spurt of
black blood comes out of its mouth. Its wings fall
to the side. And it's like, "How did you..." And
falls over dead.
LIAM: Slow dance down to the ground.
SAM: Meanwhile, me and Laura still haven't dealt
any damage to ours at all.
TRAVIS: Scanlan, you're up.
TALIESIN: There's a Tyrannosaurus rex and a
unicorn that still need to be dealt with.
SAM: Put Scanlan back on there.
TRAVIS: Oh yeah! Where is Scanlan?
LIAM: Very quickly, covered in gore, Freddie and
Vax nod.
TALIESIN: Quite proper.
SAM: As a bonus action, I will 2nd-level Healing
Word myself. Need to do that. That's seven plus
six. Oh, that's 13 points, that helped. And I will
just step back a little, not a lot. Then I will
cast Reverse Gravity and send him skyward.
(laughter)
SAM: He has to make a dexterity saving throw
against 22. But he's dexterous, it could work.
TRAVIS: Six.
SAM: Does it hurt him to hit the top?
TRAVIS: Yes. In fact, you see ripples of
energy just going out. And you start to smell
fried alligator. He falls 50 feet.
LIAM: (sings Jurassic Park theme)
TRAVIS: 25. Damn it, he's barely-- (groans)
SAM: He would actually technically not fall. He
just stays there.
TRAVIS: Oh really? So each round he'll take more
of that energy damage. Fair enough.
SAM: He stays there for a minute. So that's ten
rounds of damage.
TRAVIS: The unicorn, feeling this upside-down
half-elf on his back, shakes you off.
LAURA: No! Can I try to hang on? I want to try to
hang on to his hair!
TRAVIS: Sure. Roll an athletics check with
disadvantage.
LAURA: Well, I don't need to roll the other one,
because it's a one.
TRAVIS: Well, there you go. You fall-- Yeah, there
you go.
(laughter)
LAURA: Oh no, am I getting eaten by the unicorn?
TRAVIS: The unicorn comes over, and begins to
smell the fallen half-elf. "You showed me great
"respect, Vex'ahlia. Your kindness will live
throughout the ages. All the unicorns will be told
"of your mercy." And it kneels down and touches its
horn to the ground, and all of the enemies
disappear.
LIAM: Well earned.
LAURA: Thank you! It worked!
TRAVIS: You also see a similar shimmer disappear
from the barriers, and you can see the stones on
the tower even more clearly than ever before.
SAM: What do they look like?
TRAVIS: Like stones.
LAURA: I'm going to cast Cure Wounds on myself at
3rd-level.
TALIESIN: I'm going to go take a look at that body
that was sitting in the--
TRAVIS: Yes. Percy, you get over, and you see what
seems to be some sort of humanoid figure. Roll a
perception check.
TALIESIN: That's not great. 14.
TRAVIS: You see tattered clothes, but you also see
slashes and big gashes and flesh peeling back.
There's also bits of hair, multicolored, and big
gashes in the floor. There's tons of gore, but it
does appear as if whatever this was was mauled by
something, almost.
TALIESIN: How big is this body, approximately?
TRAVIS: Very close to your own. Very similar.
SAM: Any clothing that we recognize?
TALIESIN: I don't know, take a look.
SAM: I'll come look.
LIAM: My wounds are starting to heal up somewhat.
TRAVIS: Yeah, because they do that.
SAM: Seven perception.
TRAVIS: You come over and you're like, those are
fucking clothes. Old brigade navy and, you know,
all sorts of stuff that you kind of recognize but
not really.
LAURA: Can I bamf Trinket out and see if he
recognizes the scent?
TRAVIS: Yeah, you bamf Trinket out of the
necklace, and he's like, whoa, unicorn piss! And
he goes right back in the necklace because I don't
know where he went-- There he is. He's out.
LAURA: Can he smell for perception on the body to
see if he recognizes who it is? Yeah, he has smell
perception.
TRAVIS: Yeah, roll the whatever that is. He's got
that?
LAURA: He's got advantage on smell perception.
TRAVIS: Yeah, go for it, advantage style. What?
LAURA: Does that count?
TRAVIS: Did you roll it on purpose?
LAURA: No, but it's a natural 20!
TRAVIS: No, you've got to roll it on purpose!
LAURA: Damn it.
SAM: I'm going to inspire the bear.
LAURA: What does that mean?
TRAVIS: How do you do that?
SAM: By feeding it meat.
LAURA: Okay. (gasps)
SAM: Go on, Trinket. Smell real well tonight,
Trinket!
TRAVIS: Trinket takes the meat and just starts
gobbling it down.
SAM: And I will actually inspire the bear.
LAURA: Great. So 26.
TRAVIS: Trinket comes over and he begins sniffing
the body, and he does recognize some of the scent.
It's almost that of an animal, like perhaps
another bear, or a wolf even. Some sort of animal
scent on the body. Right then, Trinket (groans)
and this little hairball covered in mucus comes out.
LAURA: What's going on?
SAM I don't know!
TRAVIS: (bear dry heaving)
(laughter)
TRAVIS: And you flip Trinket over on his back and
pat his stomach.
LIAM: I would like, not in the game but out of the
game, to hide.
SAM: Oh no, does anyone know CP-bear?
TRAVIS: That's what our dachshund does. Trinket
takes 27 points of poison damage.
LAURA: I think he's dead.
TALIESIN: Well, he's unconscious. I think he goes
back into the necklace.
LAURA: Yeah, but I'm going to kill Scanlan
anyway.
TRAVIS: Hold on. So Trinket (groans). Face first,
ass up in the air, and goes back into your
necklace.
LAURA: I bamf him back out and heal him. I cast
Cure Wounds at 3rd-level. What are you doing down
on the ground?
LIAM: I'm hiding because you're going to murder
our friend.
SAM: I don't what's happened to your bear!
Something's wrong with him!
TRAVIS: Trinket heals 15 points. Do you leave him
out?
LAURA: Yeah, I leave him out, and I cast Speak
with Animals on him.
SAM: I think you've done that already today.
LAURA: And I have another one, you dick! It only
lasts ten minutes. And I go: Trinket, what
happened?
TRAVIS: "Well, I had the worst stomachache. I
don't know, I ate that meatball from Scanlan and
"then I fucking died. I don't want to make any
assumptions, but--"
(laughter)
LAURA: Scanlan! Did you kill my bear? Did you kill
him? Why would you do that?
SAM: I-- (laughs)
TALIESIN: Who betrayed this grizzly murder?
SAM: (wheezing) I don't know! I mean, maybe it was
something else? Maybe it was the unicorn?
LAURA: I try to put Scanlan in the necklace.
TRAVIS: How does that shit work? You've got the
card, right?
LAURA: I think he has to be willing.
TRAVIS: Scanlan, make a deception check.
SAM: It was the unicorn's powerful magic.
Deception check? 33.
TRAVIS: He really doesn't know. He doesn't know
what Trinket's talking about.
LAURA: So I don't try to put him in the necklace?
But don't I have to roll?
SAM: You can beat my deception. You can roll
against it, right?
LAURA: Well, I can. But you have to roll a DC
wisdom save.
TRAVIS: Just roll a wisdom saving throw.
SAM: What's the DC?
LAURA: Ten.
SAM: I rolled a 15. But it's minus two! But it's
still 13.
LAURA: Balls. Well, do I believe him?
TRAVIS: You do believe him. He doesn't know.
SAM: I don't know what happened with your bear.
TRAVIS: He seems quite flummoxed over Trinket's
sudden--
LAURA: It's just so weird that he got sick right
after you gave him food.
SAM: You know, I found that meat back there. Maybe
it was poison or something, but I wouldn't know
from poison, I'm a simple pauper.
LIAM: You know, I have never seen you feed a
single thing to that bear in all the time we've
known you.
TALIESIN: That is peculiar, isn't it? The
deception was against her, I think you have to
roll separately for us.
LIAM: What was your reasoning for feeding Trinket
right now?
SAM: Seemed hungry!
LIAM: He's always hungry, Scanman.
TRAVIS: You're interrupted by an explosion from
the top of the tower. A sound of noise.
(deep humming) A flash of light. Your attention is
directed to the top of the tower. What do you do?
LAURA: Is the electric field still up?
TRAVIS: It seems to have dissipated.
TALIESIN: I'm climbing up the tower.
LAURA: I fly up, put Trinket back in my necklace
and fly up.
TRAVIS: Fly up. Spider walk.
SAM: Climb.
TRAVIS: Climb. Athletics checks for Percy and
Scanlan.
SAM: First, I'm going to bonus Healing Word myself
again.
TALIESIN: A seven. I mean, it's just walking.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
SAM: Is this an acrobatics check?
TRAVIS: Athletics.
SAM: Athletics check. I will inspire myself. Ooh,
that's four plus three plus four.
TRAVIS: Four plus three plus four, that's good.
Great. As Percy is walking up the tower, he trips
and falls into the tower and smashes his face and
stands back up with his boots. You take eight
points of smash-your-face damage.
TALIESIN: I regret nothing.
TRAVIS: Scanlan, you fall after about 15 feet. You
take eight points of bludgeoning damage.
SAM: I've essentially undone my heal.
TRAVIS: You start climbing back up to the tower.
You all reach the top. It has a very similar--
just ignore that. Whatever. And there in the
middle is your friend, Grog. He's like, "Guys! I
"knew you would come and find me! I mean, one
second we were all in the tavern, and then all of
"a sudden it went hazy. You won't believe what I've
had to go through. There was a big hallway with a
"ghost, and then there were all these monsters."
SAM: Insight check.
TRAVIS: Roll an insight check.
LIAM: If it's a doppelganger, we have to murder
him together.
SAM: Nine.
LIAM: Insight check for sure. Oh, that's
terrible.
LAURA: I'm going to join in.
LIAM: Four.
TALIESIN: Six.
SAM: Four, six, nine, and--?
LIAM: Come on, girl!
LAURA: 15!
TRAVIS: You can tell that Grog is telling the
truth. "I had to walk through all these things and
"I came to this door and I saw a star and I
recognized the star on the door as the symbol of the
"Dallas Cowboys and I went in and I found a healing
potion and I had to go up. There was this thing up
"there and I had to kill it, and when I did there
was like a zoo I was in! There were all these
"other creatures and these partitions and I'm here.
I'm so glad-- did you teleport here, or Plane Shifty?"
SAM: We did the same thing what you did.
LAURA: Yeah, we were just a little behind you.
TRAVIS: "You didn't fight your way here, did you?
You didn't go through the rooms?"
TALIESIN: Oh yeah, that whole thing.
SAM: Why?
TRAVIS: "I don't want to fight you." You hear a
voice echo from above you as you see a cloaked,
levitating figure take form. A female voice shouts
out, "I need a hero! I need a hero until the end
"of the night! He's got to be strong, he's got to
be fast, he's got to be fresh from the fight!" And
you see Trish the Dish floating above the
platform. Trish, the god of Whitestone, looking
down and saying, "I need one of you to be my
champion."
LAURA: That's how I pictured your mom singing it.
TRAVIS: It's pretty close. You should hear her in
church: awful. You see now as Grog shakes his
head, goes into a rage, and I need you all to roll
initiative.
SAM: Are we fighting each other or are we just
fighting you?
LAURA: We're just fighting Grog.
TRAVIS: Natural 20.
LIAM: Terrible.
TALIESIN: 28.
LAURA: 16.
LIAM: Stinkaroo. Seven. Rolled a two on the Matt
die.
SAM: Ten.
TRAVIS: You watch as Grog goes into a rage and you
see a hesitation. He doesn't want to attack his
friends. He looks down at his arm and you see
there similar scrapes, cuts, gashes as you saw on
the corpse below. He looks up, grins, and lets out
a ferocious howl as he transforms into werewolf
Grog! Destiny fulfilled! The time has come! He
charges forward. He races towards Percy and will
make a reckless Great Weapon Master attack.
LIAM: This is Grog porn if ever there was any.
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: 26.
TALIESIN: That hits.
TRAVIS: That is 27 points of damage.
LAURA: Oh man! I really should have healed up
more! Shit!
LIAM: Hit die! Too late.
TRAVIS: Minus five. 20.
TALIESIN: That hits.
TRAVIS: 24 points of damage. That will end Grog's
turn. Actually, he'll stay there because he's
within melee range. Next up: Percy.
TALIESIN: Let me do this. I'm still very
reasonable. Let's do a few things. We're right
next to each other. You get an attack of
opportunity if-- actually, I'm going to use the
Cinture of the Stone King to do a shockwave of
thunderous energy. I'm going to cast shockwave at
level five which is a DC 16.
TRAVIS: Is that dex?
TALIESIN: Thunderwave, let me find out.
TRAVIS: I'll look also. Thunderwave. Constitution
saving throw. Nope.
TALIESIN: All right, then. Failed save is 2d8
thunder damage and is pushed ten feet away. 2d8
plus five. I hope I'm doing this right. That's
6d8.
TRAVIS: Jesus.
TALIESIN: Boy, this is so much math. Hold on.
Sorry.
TRAVIS: I know, I hate the ones that have math.
TALIESIN: Two, four. Six. And one more.
LAURA: How crazy will it be to go back
to just rolling one die?
LIAM: It's going to be the best. The best!
TALIESIN: 38 points of damage. And you're pushed
ten feet away.
LAURA: No!
LIAM: I strike for four hit points of damage.
TRAVIS: I'm already ten feet away, good.
TALIESIN: So there we are. The next thing that's
going to happen is I'm going to burn an action
surge and I'm going to shoot you several times.
First shot.
LAURA: Hey, Percy, leave some Grog for the rest of
us!
TALIESIN: Oh, I will. There'll be plenty. First
shot, I'm going to shoot you in the head.
TRAVIS: That's so casual! Okay!
TALIESIN: God fucking damn it. My gun jams and I
take five points of psychic damage. So that's
funny. My gun jams and I'm going to back off to
the right about 30 feet. For my bonus, I'm going
to heal a little bit and then that's the end of
me.
TRAVIS: Vex, you're up.
LAURA: Okay. I'm going to bamf Trinket out and run
up to Grog, but he's not going to attack him.
TRAVIS: Trinket's going to run up?
LAURA: Yeah, he's going to run up next to him. I'm
going to Hunter's Mark Grog. Then I'm going to
shoot him twice. Well, I'm going to shoot him
first, hold on, let's see if it hits. 22.
TRAVIS: 22 hits.
LAURA: That's a bramble shot. That's going to be
4d8 of piercing damage plus regular damage! Nine,
17, 19. Plus-- what was that? 19? 19 plus five is
24 plus eight is 32. Plus lightning. 36. Hunter's
Mark. 37. Plus sneak attack. 43. 46 damage on the
first arrow, and Grog has to make-- like this is
going to be really hard for him-- a strength
saving throw.
LIAM: Come on, one. One!
TRAVIS: 12.
LAURA: He's restrained.
TRAVIS: You notice as you do all this damage of
the physical variety, it's not doing as much
damage as you thought it might.
LAURA: Well, Grog is restrained.
TRAVIS: He's restrained. A raging werewolf.
LAURA: What does a werewolf take? Silver?
LIAM: Magic.
TRAVIS: And remember, Grog has all damage halved.
LAURA: Oh. Fucking hell! Okay. I'm going to shoot
him again while he's restrained.
TRAVIS: Sure. Advantage.
LIAM: Sneak attack damage.
Did you already use it?
LAURA: I already used it. That definitely hits.
30-something. Ten, 12, 15. 15 for the second
arrow, and I fly up in the air.
TRAVIS: Kick up on the broom and fly up?
LAURA: Kick up on the broom and fly up in the air.
That high. Sure, why not?
TRAVIS: Nice job. Scanlan!
SAM: Scanlan? What do I do?
TRAVIS: How many hit points do you have?
SAM: I will bonus action heal myself again.
Consistently healing myself. Good. Yeah, sure.
All right, that's something.
Are we trying to kill Grog?
LAURA: Maybe try to get him unconscious or
something.
LIAM: We've got to kill him to be sure.
SAM: All right. I will cast Bigby's Hand at
6th-level, and I will punch Grog.
TRAVIS: Bigby's Hand comes out. Crunch.
SAM: It's 10d6, and it just hits because you're
restrained, I think. It's d6s, right?
It's either 6d8 or 10d6. Let me look it up real fast.
Bigby's Hand. (muttering)
Clenched fist. It's 6d8. I need d8.
TALIESIN: Here's 3d8.
SAM: All right. That's it. 6d8. That's what I did.
24.
TRAVIS: 24.
SAM: Yes. It doesn't automatically crit or
anything, right?
And then I will back away, slowly.
TRAVIS: As you hit Grog with Bigby's Hand, you see
the pain ripple through his body, and the wolf
form fades, painfully. You see his wounds are all
quite evident. He is already quite hurt from his
struggles up the tower.
SAM: Maybe speak to him in unicorn language.
LAURA: Yeah, I'm going to try.
TRAVIS: He takes a knee and says, "I'm hideous.
I thought I really wanted to be like this,
"but I'm not sure it's all it's cracked up to be.
Percy, you have a silvered sword. End it."
LIAM: Shank him, Percy.
TRAVIS: "Wait, you're not really going to do it,
are you?! Fuck! I was kidding. Jesus! Oh my god!"
TALIESIN: I thought we had an arrangement.
TRAVIS: "We did, but I wanted to see
if you'd go through with it! Hold on.
"Let me get my courage up."
TALIESIN: Oh my god, what is that behind you?
I turn, and I run, and I attack him!
TRAVIS: Roll to attack.
TALIESIN: That's 26.
TRAVIS: 26 will hit. It doesn't matter.
TALIESIN: That's fine.
TRAVIS: The silvered sword sinks
into Grog's chest. He goes,
"Thank you, you dark motherfucker."
And Grog falls over.
You hear (laughs), as Trish the Dish,
above in her robes, says,
"I see a champion has fallen. You four. Hmm.
Interesting. Another time, then."
And she evaporates from the air.
You find yourselves instantly transported
back to the tavern, with Grog's bloodied body
on the table, pouring everywhere,
and the poor old innkeeper going, "Oh my god!
You're going to have to pay for that."
SAM: He dies, too?
TRAVIS: He dies.
TALIESIN: Quick, what was his son's name?
TRAVIS: Timothy.
TALIESIN: Oh my god!
SAM: Is Grog dead?
LAURA: Can I use my last Cure Wounds at 3rd-level
and heal him?
TALIESIN: There's a half-conscious Pike we could
wake up.
LAURA: Yeah, I'll heal him for now, and then Pike
will really heal him.
TRAVIS: What has the story taught you?
SAM: What has the story taught us?
TRAVIS: How much you care and need Grog.
LAURA: Yeah, obviously.
SAM: No, it actually taught us that in the end,
we have to kill Grog.
TALIESIN: And we're willing to do it.
LIAM: And to get while the getting is good. And I
would like to shave the other side of Grog's face
that I didn't shave that one time.
TRAVIS: The mystic werewolf powers within him will
regrow, even in an unconscious state, any hair
that you shave.
LIAM: Shave, shave, shave. It keeps growing back!
TRAVIS: And the sun rises on yet another day.
SAM: Before the sun rises, I cast Wish that Trish
has persistent gonorrhea forever.
TRAVIS: Is there a DC save against persistent
gonorrhea?
SAM: I think I do have to roll something.
TRAVIS: You roll a d20 and I'll roll a d20. Ready?
One, two, three. Eight.
SAM: 17.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Persistent. The rest of her cursed life.
And that will bring an end to our game.
TALIESIN: That's amazing!
SAM: Wow. Wait, because that was the end of
Bunions and Flagons. We're still in character.
LAURA: Oh, that game was so fun!
TRAVIS: It really was good, right? It's not as
good as the long-haired guy in the tavern
down the way. If you want to see
a real chapter, you should see him.
LIAM: Did you happen to catch this man's name?
TRAVIS: No, I didn't. It was something like Bursar
or Cathew. I missed it.
SAM: Cathew Verser?
LIAM: Cathew Verser.
SAM: All right, we'll look out for him.
TRAVIS: Yeah, he's a champ. But think about what
you want to do differently next time that was--
LAURA: Questionable?
TRAVIS: From a strategic-- I'm a genius at
tactics. Percy, I like what you did.
Scanlan, nicely done.
SAM: I think bard gnomes are not that good. I
think next time I'm going to be a ranger.
LIAM: What a shitty combination.
Can we do a sci-fi bent next time?
Rifts or Shadowrun or cyberpunk?
TRAVIS: A do-ron-ron?
LIAM: A do-ron-ron, yeah.
LAURA: Grog, that was great.
LIAM: It was very entertaining.
TRAVIS: I'm a little bit tired because that was
a three and a half hour game,
right in that sweet spot.
LIAM: Who won the game, though, Grog?
TRAVIS: Who has the most XP?
TALIESIN: I have 150 XP.
LAURA: I have 200.
LIAM: Ten.
SAM: I have 300 XP.
TRAVIS: I have a bonus 500 XP to give,
but you have to guess my favorite color.
LAURA: Red.
TALIESIN: Six.
LIAM: Titties.
SAM: Ale.
TRAVIS: Percy guessed it.
LIAM: Not titties?
TRAVIS: It's six.
LIAM: I don't know you anymore.
TALIESIN: I've always known you.
That's why I will be the one to end you.
TRAVIS: It was so good, I had to give it to you.
I'm going to bed. Good night!
SAM: I call a servant over, and I say:
Bring him some chicken.
TALIESIN: Soy chicken, but at least it's
something.
TRAVIS: And that's it!
(cheering)
TRAVIS: Done! Oh god.
TALIESIN: I missed Percy. That was really fun.
LAURA: That was really good.
TRAVIS: You find in the distance, the T-rex and
the unicorn find each other and start a new
magical hybrid race.
LIAM: That's the thumbnail image, right there.
TRAVIS: Well, that was awful.
TALIESIN: You did very well.
TRAVIS: That math is impossible,
as well as keeping track of that shit.
TALIESIN: It's panic-inducing back there.
It's a lot!
TRAVIS: I don't know how he keeps track
of all that stuff.
TALIESIN: Do you have anything taped
to the screen?
TRAVIS: It's a mess.
LAURA: How do you plan the next move
that you're going to do when every turn
is your turn, as well?
TRAVIS: Yeah. It's a big struggle.
LAURA: "Stroogle?" It is a "stroogle."
TRAVIS: It is a "stroogle." I suffer from
the same problem Sam had.
I think I had a bit too many enemies.
SAM: You had the perfect amount!
TRAVIS: Okay, good.
TALIESIN: It felt good from this end.
TRAVIS: Well, for those that stayed with us, thank
you. That would be my first and probably only
foray into being a BM master. We would like to
thank our sponsor for tonight's episode:
Marvel Puzzle Quest.
SAM: Go to bit.ly/marvelcrit, and make sure that
they know that you came from Critical Role.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Thor: Ragnarok comes out this
weekend, and we hope you all enjoy it very much.
Laura and I will be gone, but next week is
Marisha's Honey Heist, and there will be
a Talks Machina on Tuesday, apparently.
I won't be here to talk about it,
but I'm sure you'll say lovely things.
LIAM: We will say lovely things.
TRAVIS: I will watch from Australia.
LAURA: And also, we have scarves!
LIAM: The scarves are the fucking bomb. They're so
soft and cozy.
SAM: They're not those one-sided scarves.
LAURA: Dual-sided scarves!
LIAM: Hey, good job with those three of my 400
miniatures, Travis.
TRAVIS: Hey, man. Thanks. Your miniature
collection is to be applauded. I looked at it,
and I couldn't see the forest--
LIAM: How lucky are my eight- and 11-year-old?
TRAVIS: So lucky.
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: Love you, baby.
TRAVIS: Love you. Thank you, guys, and what's the
old signoff? Is it Thursday yet?
SAM: That was the worst delivery of that line.
TRAVIS: Good night.
[music]