MATT: And welcome back to our second half of our
Shadow of War game, brought to you and sponsored
by WB Games. Thank you so much for letting this
happen. All of us are all voice actors in the
game, in case you didn't check out the intro to
the first half. We're excited to bring these
orcish characters of this one-shot together. If
you haven't seen the first half, you should
probably go back and watch that first. Otherwise,
you'll be really confused.
LAURA: You should because it's really good.
DARIN: Well, we could do it right now.
LAURA: Yeah, do it all again?
MATT: Yeah! Fine! But yeah, Shadow of War comes
out October 10th, looking forward to that. The
Shadow of War iOS and Android game is out now, so
check it out. Anyway, bringing us back in. As the Forcs--
TRAVIS and LAURA: The Forcs!
MATT: As the Forcs have taken their break to rest
themselves for a moment, to assess what to do
next, you are now standing on the opposite edge of
one of the Mithrim Spur Mountains, just past the
crest. As you traveled down, you found hidden in
this alcove, six uruks, five of which are
currently sleeping and bundled, and one who's
keeping watch with a burning torch.
LAURA: Wait, did we actually take a short rest?
SAM: No.
TRAVIS: I got the numbers wrong.
LAURA: I thought it was intentional.
TRAVIS: Totally.
LAURA: We took a moment, so I didn't actually get
my action surge back.
MATT: Nope.
SAM: Why are you Australian now?
LAURA: Am I?
TRAVIS: It's super flexible.
LAURA: Don't you worry about it, Samuel.
DARIN: If you've seen the first part, please send
us a clip of what we sounded like at that point.
So we can go back, "Oh, right!" Because apparently
(French accent) I am this orc. I enjoy a fork.
TRAVIS: Slavic. Listen, I have not bathed a short
sword in blood under the cover of dark in so long!
I want to sneak up, and I want to take their
bowels and pull them out while they sleep. But! We
have to take care of that one that's watching
guard, first. Who's sneaky?
LAURA: Should I run down there and kill him?
TRAVIS: Naw, are you sneaky?
LAURA: I don't know.
TRAVIS: Can you look?
SAM: Skak, don't you have some sort of a
crossbow?
TRAVIS: I do!
SAM: Maybe you should be the one to take him
down.
LAURA: Maybe we can lead him toward us and then--
SAM: Oh, we could cause a diversion!
LAURA: Yeah, and then you can take him out away
from the guards that're sleeping.
TRAVIS: I like it!
SAM: Wait. If we make a noise or something, won't
he wake up everybody else?
LAURA: What if we hit him with a rock and he comes
looking for it?
TRAVIS: Yeah, or you crack a branch, right?
(cracking noise)
LAURA: Oh, that's a good idea! And I take a really
big branch and I break it in half.
SAM: Oh no. We're dumb.
MATT: The minute you hear the (cracking) sound,
you hear this faint (grunt) sound over the cliff.
As you glance over, you see the one with the torch
is now like--
SAM: How far away is he?
MATT: About 25 feet from you, 30 feet, down
below.
SAM: Crossbow him!
LAURA: (hooting)
MATT: He's now walking toward one of them to
start--
LAURA: I'm trying to sound like an owl in the
night. Hoo-hoo!
MATT: Make a performance check.
LAURA: Okay.
TRAVIS: Can I aid her? Can I aid her with my Minor
Illusion?
MATT: Sure. How-- what are you going to do?
TRAVIS: Let's make it, like, a two-headed owl.
LAURA: I like it. Do I roll at advantage, then?
MATT: Because it's a two-headed owl? No. Sorry.
What'd you roll?
LAURA: Oh, I rolled a three. Minus two.
MATT: (laughing) So it's a (gurgling).
LAURA and TRAVIS: (hooting and gurgling)
TRAVIS: Wait, harmony.
LAURA and TRAVIS: (harmonizing) Hoo!
SAM: Little pitchy.
MATT: The uruk keeping guard immediately goes,
"What the shrak?" Goes and starts shaking one of
them awake.
LAURA: Oh no! Hit him before he does that!
TRAVIS: I take the crossbow and I try to put it
right in the back, where his head meets his neck.
MATT: Okay. He doesn't currently see you,
necessarily. Roll a stealth check.
TRAVIS: 20.
MATT: Does not seem to see you, so roll advantage
on the attack.
TRAVIS: Okay. Natural 20.
MATT: So go ahead and roll the dice.
TRAVIS: Okay. d8 plus four. Eight, (counting).
MATT: Well, roll your sneak attack damage too,
because that all gets doubled as well.
TRAVIS: 16, 19, 22.
LAURA: 22 times two.
MATT: Well, you don't add the modifier to it yet.
Double dice. So 22 times two? As he's shaking one
of the uruk, he's like, "Hey, get up! Oof!"
(gurgling) The one uruk's like, "What the shit?
"I was sleeping!" The other one's like, (gurgling)
and falls onto his back, dead. He's like, "Huh?"
The other one's getting up. He's leaning forward
now, inspecting the one who was there keeping watch.
TRAVIS: I can cast Sleep.
LAURA: Do it!
DARIN: I can use Misty Step. Can I? To sneak
over.
MATT: You could appear right behind him if you
wanted to.
DARIN: I would like to use Misty Step.
MATT: All right, so, as you're doing this, you
slip into the shadows and quickly dart through the
shadow, appearing behind the one who's waking up.
He's like, "What in the--?" What are you going to do?
DARIN: I speak for Sauron. And I try to rip his
throat out.
TRAVIS: Oh shit.
LAURA: Rip it out quietly!
TRAVIS: Shh!
MATT: Make a grapple check. So go ahead and roll
athletics.
DAVIS: 16, plus my strength? 19.
MATT: All right, so, as it's sitting up from its
weird, tattered bedroll, you whisper in its ear,
"I speak for Sauron." Grab the back of its head.
Go ahead and roll an attack to try and bite into
its throat.
DARIN: That is 13.
MATT: 13? Roll damage.
DARIN: Seven.
MATT: Okay. Seven points. All right. As you pull
the head back and bite into the throat, it's like
(gurgling and gasping). You tear a chunk out of
its throat, but it's making all these gurgling
noises. All the other uruks start rousing.
LAURA: You should snap its neck! It's quieter!
MATT: So what do you want to do?
DARIN: I have another attack. I'm going to bite
his neck again.
MATT: Go for it.
LAURA: He's a creative one, Mozuu.
DARIN: You see, Mozuu the Chosen means, I choose
one thing and I do it over and over again, and
that's it. That's it! That's what Sauron said. It
is a 13.
MATT: 13, all right. Go ahead and roll damage.
Second time.
DARIN: For the love of Pete's Dragon. Okay, that
is another seven because that's what happens.
TRAVIS: I thought he said quietly!
MATT: All right, as you go, (growling) Still
alive. Bite down again and pull out another
piece. You're taking chunks out of this orc's
throat but it's still alive. It's like (yelling),
reaching up and grabbing at you now, and it's got
the back of your head and is trying to pull you
onto the ground. All the other ones are rousing
and grabbing their weapons.
LAURA: I think they know we're here.
SAM: Are they up? Are they behind a wall?
MATT: They're in an alcove, like a little
cliffside platform at the side of the mountain.
There's a mountain wall and then an outcropping,
and they're on the outcropping. It's hidden,
recessed. Below you.
SAM: Below us! Oh, we're coming in from the
mountain. So we can jump down.
MATT: If you want to try.
LAURA: We didn't take a short rest, though.
MATT: It's about 25 feet down below.
LAURA: That would've been real smart.
DARIN: To be fair, they know I'm here.
LAURA: Maybe I should rest while this is going on
because I should really rest.
TRAVIS: I'll cast Sleep on them.
MATT: So you pull out a small pouch--
TRAVIS: Yeah, with like, sleeping powder and
herbs. I untie the top of it and I go, (whoosh).
MATT: All righty. So--
LAURA: You're going to sleep too!
TRAVIS: Oh shit, well, I'm sure--
MATT: All right, roll 5d8.
LAURA: Wow, 5d8?!
DARIN: Orc throat makes me sleepy.
LAURA: It's 5d8 of--? Oh, okay, I know.
TRAVIS: 32.
MATT: 32. So two of the uruk that are getting up
out of bed are like, (grunt) reach for their
weapons, and are like (grunting, then snoring),
and fall immediately back to sleep. The other
three, however, are still rousing up from their
slumber.
TRAVIS: The other three are?
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: That's the best I got.
MATT: At this point, combat is definitely engaged.
I need you all to roll initiative.
DARIN: And I'm okay? I did not fall asleep?
MATT: Well, no, because it affects creatures with
the lower hit dice, and you actually have a higher
hit point value than most of them there. So you
weren't affected.
TRAVIS: And I choose? I choose which one--
LAURA: No.
DARIN: 14.
TRAVIS: It says I choose--
SAM: Well, it doesn't matter.
MATT: All right.
SAM: Seven.
MATT: Seven, all righty.
LAURA: Eight.
MATT: All righty.
TRAVIS: 21. I need to be a little intelligent
bastard from now on.
MATT: All righty. So Skak, you're up first. You
just threw the sleep powder into the air. You
watch as they get to their feet and begin to pull
their weapons out. It looks like the fray is on.
You're at the top of the combat round. What do you
want to do?
TRAVIS: I'll take the nearest one with my crossbow
and fire.
MATT: Okay, go for it.
TRAVIS: Is he within melee range of him, for sneak
attack? Probably not, because he's working on the
guy with the throat, right?
MATT: Yeah, the guy with the throat is the only
one that you have sneak attack on.
TRAVIS: 15.
MATT: 15 hits.
TRAVIS: Nice. That does seven points of piercing
damage.
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: Are we hopping off down a cliff, or are we
running in toward where they are?
MATT: That's up to you. They're about 25 feet down
below on this cliff.
TRAVIS: I'm going to stay up on my perch.
MATT: Okay, stay up on your perch. Got you. You
still have a bonus action if you wanted to hide.
TRAVIS: But I can only hide or disengage or--
LAURA: You could hide so they can't see you.
TRAVIS: Oh, well, let them see me.
MATT: All right, there you go. So Skak is up in
the open. Mozuu, you're up.
DARIN: Okay. I am going to keep ripping at the
man's-- Well, not the man. I'm going to keep
ripping him.
MATT: The uruk, so go ahead for the attack.
DARIN: Oh, for the love of Pete's Dragon. Five.
MATT: Five. You go to bite and this time it's
reached over and it's grabbed a blade and a dagger.
It jams the pommel up into your mouth and it hits
the roof of your mouth. (gagging) You're now being
partially choked by its blade, by the hilt of its
blade. So your first strike does not hit it. You
want to try a second time?
DARIN: Yes. And I have a blade in my mouth?
MATT: You have the pommel and hilt jammed up into
your jaw and it's trying to keep you at bay.
DARIN: I'm going to try and jab the pommel in its
eye. No, it's not stuck in my mouth, right?
MATT: Not at the moment, but you could bite down
if you wanted.
DARIN: All right, I will. For the-- Seven.
MATT: Seven. You try and bite down on it. Actually
breaks a tooth on the inside and you're like,
"Ugh!" You feel the pain sting through your jaw.
This is a stronger uruk than you expected and it's
currently putting up quite a fight. So that ends
your turn, Mozuu?
DARIN: Ends my turn.
MATT: All right. Arby and this group are all going
at the same time. So what are you doing, Arby?
LAURA: I'm going to jump down. I'm going to run at
them and attack the one that's got him.
MATT: Okay. So as you leap, make an acrobatics
check.
LAURA: Oh no.
TRAVIS: How far? 25 feet down?
MATT: 25 feet, yeah.
LAURA: Four!
TRAVIS: Plus anything? Oh no!
MATT: Mozuu, make a dexterity saving throw.
TRAVIS: Oh, no way.
DARIN: 18 plus-- that's a
19.
MATT: Okay. So you suffer seven points of
bludgeoning damage as you fall from the cliffside
above. As you fall, you land like a large
cannonball, right in the space where Mozuu was.
Mozuu, at the last minute, mouth filled with gore
and dagger, looks up and sees the shadow
encroaching. Kicks away just as you (impact).
LAURA: Slam down with my maul right as I hit the
ground!
MATT: You land right on the guy he had. So you
slam the maul into the ground, because you don't
know where he is. You look around for a moment to
look down and realize that your feet are six
inches deep into the torso of this once-living orc
that has been splattered on the ledge. All right.
LAURA: I'll use my second attack to hit another
one!
MATT: All right, go for it.
TRAVIS: You are slaughtering today.
LAURA: I'm screaming as I'm doing it. 24!
MATT: 24 hits.
LAURA: Deet de deet de deet. Ooh, ah! 15!
MATT: 15? All right. That'll destroy him. All
right, so. So it was seven from that one to, okay.
As you land and crush him, you swing wide with
your giant maul and it hits one and pins it
against the wall. It hits it and slams against the
wall. You watch it splatter across the side,
destroyed.
LAURA: Like a gnat, that one! Ha ha, ha!
MATT: All right, that'll end your turn, Arby? As
that's happening, the orcs are getting up and
grabbing their weapons. There are the two still
sleeping. As all this is happening, they're
(snoring) in the middle of their bedroll. These
two other ones that are wounded are going to stand
up. They're both going to go after you since
you're the one who just arrived aggressively. The
first one's going to swing at you.
TRAVIS: Frustrated DM.
MATT: That's a ten.
LAURA: No.
MATT: The side of their battleaxe, clang! Against
your armor, no effect. A natural 20!
TRAVIS: There's the make-up. There it is.
LAURA: That's a load of shrak, that is!
MATT: One on a d10, so that's two plus-- You take
five points of slashing damage from its critical
hit. You deflect it with a chuckle, your giant
olog-hai physical self able to withstand such
paltry blows. You're called Unstoppable for a
reason.
LAURA: That's right. Unbreakable. That's me.
MATT: All right, so. That ends the orc's turn
there, the one you crushed there, the one that's
sleeping. Yeah, they don't get a saving throw
until they get hit or the spell ends. Fun. All
right. There's a third orc right now that's
backing away. Hands up, full belly shown, like
(heavy breathing).
LAURA: Kill the weak one!
MATT: "No, no no!" Eden, your turn.
SAM: I will jump on the weak one.
MATT: Roll an acrobatics check, please.
SAM: Oh boy. Check? 15.
MATT: 15, all right. You land on it without issue
and you actually reduce the damage from the impact
to two. You only take two points of bludgeoning
damage from the fall as you land on top of it. Go
ahead and roll a d4. Add your strength modifier.
SAM: d4, add strength.
MATT: Oh god, which one is it?
SAM: Three, plus strength is one. So four!
MATT: Four, so. You land and it slams onto the
ground. We'll see if it manages-- Nope! It's
knocked prone. So it falls onto the ground. You're
on top of it currently. Felt a bone snap somewhere
in its ribcage, the back of its shoulder blade.
It's currently pinned onto the ground underneath you.
SAM: I will take my quarterstaff and-- like
churning butter.
MATT: All right, go ahead and roll some attacks.
It is considered prone, so you have advantage on
your attacks against it.
SAM: Good, because that was a two. And that's a
natural 20!
MATT: Oh, shit! Okay, so roll your first attack
damage.
SAM: d8, seven, plus four. 11.
LAURA: Wait, seven times two, because it was a
critical. So 14.
SAM: 14 plus four is 18.
MATT: Okay, so the first hit, as you jam down, you
go to stir it. You hit right at the base of the
skull and the neck breaks immediately. But you
feel like you still have to go through the motion
so you still stir inside, even though it's not
living. The body's limp and being pushed around in
a circle. You're like, (yelling in disgust).
TRAVIS: What's it look like, being pushed around
in a circle?
MATT: (yelling) About like that. So that's your
first strike.
SAM: Well, is he dead?
MATT: Yes. He's very dead.
SAM: Orc physiology is not my specialty. Do I see
other orcs? Uruks, around me?
MATT: There are two sleeping and there is one that
was first struck by you with your crossbow, that
was wounded, but it's still standing and its
blade's out.
SAM: I get one more attack, right?
MATT: You do.
SAM: I will move to that one and hit him. Right?
MATT: Okay, what's your movement?
SAM: 40.
MATT: Actually, yes. You would have enough,
because you are quicker than the other. So you
have enough speed to get right up to him. Go ahead
and make your second attack.
LAURA: You're so speedy.
SAM: Not with advantage?
MATT: No.
SAM: That's probably a miss. It's a nine.
MATT: Yep. This one sees you crush his friend and
stir him up a bit, and prepares itself. As you
rush toward, darts out of the way and dodge-rolls
beyond your attack. No effect.
SAM: It's a wraith! It's a grave-walker! They can
disappear at will!
MATT: All right, so, that ends Eden's turn. Skak,
you're up first.
TRAVIS: The last one that remains un-asleep:
crossbow.
MATT: Go for it.
TRAVIS: Nice. Is he now within melee of him?
MATT: He is, yes.
TRAVIS: 17, so I'll use my sneak attack. 12,
that's an eight. 12, 16, 20!
MATT: Yeah, between the damage he already took--
This one, the arrow strikes right in the abdomen.
It clutches it, gets the axe up to its side, and
you see it, with its final bit of strength, trying
to strike a blow toward your olog friend over
there, but crumples to the ground and bleeds out
from its abdomen.
SAM: Thanks, Skak!
TRAVIS: Yeah. Now, quiet-- I'm looking at you--
quietly kill the other, and leave one for
questioning!
SAM: Kill the other? There's two asleep.
LAURA: I walk over and use my maul and smash down
on one of the ones that's sleeping.
MATT: Okay, make an attack with advantage. It's an
auto-crit because it is incapacitated.
LAURA: Ooh, 16 plus eight, so that's definitely
going to hit, and it's not a crit.
MATT: No, it is a crit. It's an auto-crit because
it's right there. Actually, you wouldn't even have
to roll because, when it's incapacitated. No,
attack rolls have advantage, you're right. And
within five feet, it's a critical hit. So yeah,
you did hit and you have a crit.
TRAVIS: Re-roll that. That'll do.
LAURA: Yeah! 20 plus five, 25!
MATT: (snoring) (impact) Scattered. Gallagher
performance. All of you are like (splatter).
SAM: A good kill.
MATT: The one sleeping now has this section of
hand that slopped onto its head. Pulls it in,
cuddles with the disembodied orc arm.
TRAVIS: Sucks the thumb.
SAM: Sucking somebody else's thumb! That's so
gross!
TRAVIS: How do I get down? I'm tiny!
LAURA: Here! I'll catch you!
SAM: We'll catch you, just come down. Oh, wait! I
have a blanket. Let's spread it out and we'll hold
it, and you can jump down on the blanket.
TRAVIS: Don't let me fall!
LAURA: No, of course not! Right as he jumps, I let
go and start picking my nose.
MATT: Make an acrobatics check.
TRAVIS: Oh no. Oh, hey! 17! Trickster rogues, man,
okay!
MATT: All right, so, as you leap off and watch one
of three taut points on it vanish, you flap your
arms really fast to try and maneuver through the
air. You manage to hit some tension on their side
and roll off. You only suffer three points of
bludgeoning damage as you roll on the ground. As
you land, I want you to roll a constitution saving
throw.
SAM: What's that all about? Oh, I know what it
is.
TRAVIS: Oh, that's not good. That's a six.
MATT: All right, so, as you roll and land, the
sleeping powder seems to have worn off. The one
that's on the ground, clutching and sucking on the
thumb of the disembodied uruk arm goes,
(sniffing and grunting) (confused noises) (cry of alarm).
TRAVIS: Grab him!
SAM: We're not to kill him?
TRAVIS: No! Question him!
DARIN: We will question him, and we will question
him in the patented way we always question
individuals, when we all speak as one!
SAM, LAURA, and TRAVIS: As one!
SAM, DARIN, and LAURA: Don't bite his throat.
DARIN: Right.
TRAVIS: You, strong people, grapple him!
SAM: I will grapple him!
MATT: Make an athletics check.
SAM: Not good. Nine.
MATT: Natural 19. As you go to grab, he goes
(yelling), pulls away. You can attempt to make
another, if you want. You get two attacks. You can
make one per attack.
SAM: That's right. This one is, it's an athletics
check? 13.
MATT: 13. Yeah, no, he's like, (grunting), pushes
away from you twice. This slimy little orc is now
freaked out.
LAURA: I start grabbing at him like it's a piece
of paper blowing in the wind.
MATT: Make an athletics check. It's like (slurping
sounds).
LAURA: Oh no! Athletics, or what? Athletics is
ten.
MATT: Ten. Nope! It's like grabbing the soap.
Boop, boop, boop! It keeps slipping out of your
grasp and it's crawling on the ground.
LAURA: 25!
MATT: 25. Okay, yeah, that'll do it. It slips past
each one, crawling on the ground,
(heavy breathing) (clunk) "Ugh!" You get the ankle and
you pull it back in. Slides onto his back and is
like, (panicked yelling) underneath this giant
olog body, covered in armor, that's towering over
it. Looking up at you, Arby, like--
LAURA: We're going to ask you some questions.
TRAVIS: All together, right? One, two--
ALL: --Three. Who do you serve? We are the Forcs!
Who do you serve? Not meaning food! Because we are
the Forcs!
MATT: Somebody make an intimidation check.
TRAVIS: Not me.
SAM: I will intimidate. Natural one.
LAURA: Seven.
TRAVIS: Nine.
DARIN: (softly) Two.
TRAVIS: Oh my god. Are you serious?
MATT: After this display, the uruk on the ground
goes, (bursts into laughter). "What is this? What,
"the Forcs? Really? (giggling) Just kill me."
SAM: I guess we have to kill him.
TRAVIS: Give him pain.
SAM: Pain?
TRAVIS: Pain.
LAURA: I lift him up, hanging by his ankle. Do we
want to use him as a piñata?
SAM: It's multicultural. Sure! I'll take out my
length of chain and sort of start whipping him.
MATT: (shrieking)
LAURA: Who do you serve? Who do you work for?
MATT: "My! Name's! Borg! Please, stop it! I'm
Borg!"
LAURA &amp; DARIN: Borg. Borg? Borg borg.
LAURA: Who sent you? Where are you from? Who do
you work for?
SAM: We're looking for Ur-Gram.
MATT: "I know Ur-Gram!"
SAM: You do! Where's Ur-Gram?
MATT: (stuttering) "I could tell you. I could show
you!"
LAURA: All right! I drop him.
MATT: "Oh! (groaning) Okay. I could show you. So.
Just know, Ur-Gram is strange. He's a fanatic. Bit
"of a creepy individual."
LAURA: Should we take a short rest while we talk
about him? Can I sit down? I'm going to sit down
and listen to what he's saying.
MATT: This uruk, which at a close glance is small,
it's borderline goblin in how thin and tiny it is,
sits up on his feet. (wheezing) "A fanatic,
Ur-Gram is. Near death once, he was! Now works for
"some tark who walks like the wraiths do. The
Bright Lord, he is. Marks all his gobs with his
"hand, he does. I don't question, though. Ur-Gram
can break any of us. I've seen it, I have."
LAURA: He can't break me. I'm unbreakable.
MATT: "That's good."
TRAVIS: You said he works for the Bright Lord?
MATT: "The Bright Lord, aye. I've seen him around.
He's just some stupid man-filth."
TRAVIS: Pig-skin!
SAM: Soft-skin!
LAURA: Man-swine!
SAM: Sure, sure, those are all good ones.
DARIN: What other ones can we use?
SAM: Man-filth! Man-beast!
MATT: "I already said man-filth."
DARIN: Now, what other insults could we use, all
together, in one voice? In our traditional way?
MATT: "Please, don't. Borg is asking you."
DARIN: You see, we're tougher than your master.
You said creepy? Who's creepier than the Forcs?
You can answer.
MATT: "No one?"
SAM: Correct answer.
DARIN: There's two things I know. We are the
creepiest, and that's it.
MATT: (whimpering)
TRAVIS: So Ur-Gram works for the Bright Lord and
can bend anyone to his will?
MATT: "Well, didn't bend me. Didn't ask."
SAM: Where is he?
MATT: "I'll show you."
LAURA: Can you show us in 30 minutes? Because I
want to take a short break.
MATT: "Sure, take your rest."
SAM: If we rest, what if they send a patrol up
here?
LAURA: We'll pretend that we're the guards that we
just killed.
TRAVIS: You lead us to Ur-Gram, we'll rest for a
minute, and then when you lead us we'll let you leave!
MATT: "Okay."
LAURA: I'm going to use him as a pillow as I take
a short rest.
TRAVIS: I'm going to bind his hands first, and
then I'm going to stick some dirty garments
hanging off of Eden in his mouth, to gag him up.
DARIN: You have a choice, mate. You could join us.
Every Forc, as has been proven by science, has
five forky things. We are but four! If you join
us, we will be five.
LAURA: No, but then we'd be--
SAM: --the Fircs.
LAURA: Doesn't work as well. If you join us, you
could be my pillow as long as you want.
MATT: (muffled whimpering)
TRAVIS: Hold on. I take out the--
LAURA: I fluff him up and lay down.
MATT: (yelps of pain) You break a few bones in the
process.
TRAVIS: I should gag him back up. I walk back over
to Eden and I tear off a bit of cloth near the
groin area. Yeah, I put it back in. Okay, should
we take a short rest?
SAM: I guess.
MATT: All right, so you guys all take a short
rest. You can use any hit dice that are currently
unspent.
SAM: Got to use them all.
TRAVIS: Because you have those hit dice once per
day.
SAM: Back up at full.
MATT: You get your ki back. You get your action
surge back.
DARIN: Almost full.
LAURA: Almost full, not quite.
MATT: All right. At the end of this rest, as
you're laying back, you hear this silent
whimpering as Borg's like (whimpering).
LAURA: It's okay, Borg-borg.
TRAVIS: Oh man, pet names.
LAURA: Well, he said his name twice!
TRAVIS: Pet names for our captive.
SAM: Lead us to Ur-Gram.
MATT: "I need to get up first."
TRAVIS: You've got a gag in your mouth.
MATT: (muffled)
TRAVIS: Now hold on!
MATT: "Blah! I need to get up first!"
SAM: Let him up.
LAURA: All right, I sit up.
MATT: (gasping and heavy breathing)
LAURA: You're very comfy. I start taking his ropes
off him as I pat his little head.
TRAVIS: Oh, why are you untying his hands?
LAURA: Well, because I thought he needs to walk?
TRAVIS: They're on his hands!
LAURA: I don't understand what the problem is.
TRAVIS: Now, I've made him a nice bit of jewelry
for his wrists. Let's leave it on so he feels like
he's part of the group.
LAURA: All right.
TRAVIS: Okay. I tie his hands back together. In
front!
LAURA: Should I undo his feet then?
TRAVIS: Those were never tied.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: As you guys continue eastward under the
cover of night, having crossed over the apex of
this mountain range, you descend down the
treacherous paths and cliffs below. A few hours
downward, continuing with the pushing of Borg
ahead of you, he begins to continuously glance out
in the darkness ahead of you until eventually, you
come around one bend through this small valley
path that's been carved through years and years of
heavy rains and wind that have burrowed this small
walkway through these big cliff-sides. You turn
around the corner and you can see, immediately,
about a dozen or so dotted lights in the distance,
the dark. Maybe a quarter-mile away. There, Borg
goes, "That there! That's where he is! That's
where Ur-Gram and the tark have been preparing!"
LAURA: Is the Bright Lord down there?
MATT: "Maybe!"
SAM: How do we get inside?
MATT: "I don't know! I've only had to go outside
of it!"
DARIN: You've never been inside?
MATT: "Oh, well I've been inside, but they let me
in! Don't think they're going to do that for you."
SAM: Is there a password or something?
LAURA: Do all of you wear special hats or
something?
MATT: "I mean--" He looks down at himself and
looks around. "They gave us these." He tugs at the
tunic that he has under his ramshackle, piecemeal
armor. There's this soft grey material that has a
dull grey handprint that's pulled across the
front. He goes, "Maybe this?"
LAURA: That's pretty. I could wear that.
SAM: You're big.
DARIN: You said the other uruk were marked by this
Bright Lord?
MATT: "Well, he gives them like, a--"
DARIN: Does it leave a print on their face?
MATT: "Don't think so."
LAURA: You want me to give it a try?
TRAVIS: Do it.
LAURA: All right, I walk over to Mozuu and slap
him as hard as I can across the face.
DARIN: How many hit points do I lose?
MATT: What's your strength modifier?
LAURA: Five.
MATT: Your strength modifier is five? You take six
points of bludgeoning damage to the face, as your
jaw actually disconnects from one side and
(cracking sound).
TRAVIS: You are huge. Oh my gosh.
DARIN: (indistinct)
LAURA: I can't understand you.
TRAVIS: Is that what the mark looks like?
MATT: "Yeah."
TRAVIS: Can I make an insight check to see if he's
lying? Natural 20.
MATT: Yeah, he's totally lying. He has no idea. He
watched you slap the shit out of your friend and
is amused by it.
TRAVIS: I've got an idea. What if we untie him
and he brings us in as new recruits to Ur-Gram?
LAURA: And then what?
TRAVIS: We'll get an audience with him and we cut
his head off! And then we bring it back.
MATT: "I can hear you!"
SAM: No, we're not going to cut your head off!
MATT: "Oh, oh!"
LAURA: No, no, the Man-eater. The Face-eater.
MATT: "I could do that! I could help you in."
TRAVIS: And we'll cut you in on the spoils.
LAURA: Good idea!
SAM: We're going to get a lot of money for this
mission, and we'll give you one half.
MATT: Make a deception check.
TRAVIS: That's me, man! I actually have deception
for once!
SAM: 15!
MATT: He's like, "That's very generous. So then,
to Ur-Gram? Come on."
DARIN: To Ur-Gram! May I fix my jaw?
SAM: Oh, I can fix it! I'm a medic.
DARIN: Thank you.
MATT: Make a medicine check.
SAM: That's cocked. 11 plus medicine? 14.
MATT: 14? It takes a minute, but eventually
(cracking). It's sore. It's swollen. Your face
looks disproportionate.
DARIN: I feel alive.
LAURA: I start yanking his robes off of his hands.
His robes off? His ropes off of his hands. I'll
take his robes off too, just in case.
TRAVIS: Make him naked!
SAM: He needs to have a costume on, for the ruse.
LAURA: All right, I give him his robes back.
Sorry.
SAM: Remember, you're bringing us in because we're
new recruits. You're here to see Ur-Gram. No
questions.
TRAVIS: Ferocious warriors, we are.
SAM: The moment you betray us, we will kill you.
MATT: "Right."
TRAVIS: Painfully.
SAM: And that's it.
MATT: "Okay, good to know. Follow me!" Begins to
carefully dart around. You guys progress for about
20 or so minutes before you reach the very base of
this mountain. It's now evened out and you're in
this valley, where this small fortress is. The
closer you get, I want you to make a perception check.
SAM: All of us?
MATT: All of you guys.
TRAVIS: 17.
SAM: 17 here as well.
LAURA: Ooh, 22.
MATT: All right. Darin?
DARIN: Plus what?
MATT: Perception.
LAURA: It's toward the bottom.
DARIN: Oh, 14.
MATT: All right, some decent rolls all around.
Okay, you guys can see, on the other side of this
wide valley, where the torchlights encircle a
fenced, walled encampment, a single ramshackle
watchtower marks the center of the interior of
this large, sharpened pike-like wall. The back
half of the wall is buttressed against the
mountain base, across the valley from you,
vanishing into a large cavern. So it's not a full
encirclement. You see the wall encircles around
the base of the mountain and each side ends at the
mountain. There's an actual natural cavern that
the base of it hides in shadow.
LAURA: That's a nice camp. They've got a real nice
camp.
TRAVIS: Location, location, location.
SAM: But do they have grog?
TRAVIS: I hope.
MATT: You had the 22? You also hear, faintly, off
in the distance, this (snuffling and growling).
You've heard this sound before. It's kept you up
at night, whenever the caragors in their cages
were particularly rambunctious. It sounds like a
caragor. As soon as you hear it, you also hear a
(alert yelp). A second one, not far from it, goes
(snuffling).
LAURA: There's caragors!
MATT: Yeah, but like, near you. Maybe 40 feet from
you, at the moment.
TRAVIS: Are there trees around us?
MATT: No trees. You're in Mordor right now.
TRAVIS: Yep, just thought I'd ask. You know, some
ashen trees?
MATT: I mean, there are jagged rocks. Part of the
terrain itself is a series of broken shale and
large rock faces that jut out of the ground from
seismic activity.
LAURA: Should we hide behind rocks? It's
caragors.
TRAVIS: You hear caragors?
LAURA: Yeah, like real big-sounding ones.
TRAVIS: Prepare to fight! And I hide.
MATT: Okay, make a stealth check.
SAM: Hide? No, we should sneak past them!
TRAVIS: That's true, we should. 16.
MATT: Okay. So you watch as Skak disappears behind
a rock. What are you guys doing?
LAURA: I also try to duck behind a rock.
SAM: Are we going to sit here?
LAURA: I'm going to duck behind a rock and wait
for one to show its face around a rock, and then
I'm going to hit it with my maul.
MATT: Okay, make a stealth check with
disadvantage.
SAM: Why don't we try to go past them?!
LAURA: Seven.
MATT: Okay. You watch as Arby nods, follows suit,
right behind where Skak is. The rock's almost the
size of Arby, so you see this outline of Arby
clutching this rock and trying to act quiet as the
armor (clanking).
TRAVIS: Look and see if we can make it past them!
You, stick your head out.
SAM: All right, I will stealthily see if I can see
any caragors. Move out, look around.
MATT: Make a stealth check.
SAM: Ooh! 25!
LAURA: Sneaky sneaky!
MATT: As you climb a little bit of the rock face
on one side of this pathway that's carved into the
mountain base here, you glance up. You can see the
faint bit of moonlight that breaks through one of
the nearby clouds. You can see the outer rim of
two fully-grown caragors that are currently
walking, maybe 15 feet from each other, a dual
hunting scenario. They're both like (sniffing and
grunting) on the ground, and they're smelling for
any sort of possible prey that might be in the
vicinity.
SAM: Hi! We need to distract them somehow. Does
anyone have any meat on them?
LAURA: No, but I have a bell!
SAM: A bell?
LAURA: Yeah.
SAM: That would distract?
LAURA: Well, it's a bell! It makes noise.
MATT: (bell clanging) The bell is now ringing in
her hand.
SAM: Throw the bell!
LAURA: I throw the bell as far away as I can!
MATT: The caragors at this point (snarling). They
both go jumping and leaping in toward where the
source of the bell sound was.
LAURA: I throw the bell!
MATT: Make a strength check.
TRAVIS: Oh my god. Please throw it a mile.
LAURA: 18!
MATT: The bell arcs behind where you guys were.
LAURA: Oh wait, no, 15. Because it's not a saving
throw.
MATT: Right. It arcs off behind you and you watch
as one large caragor, nearly 15 feet from end to
end, leaps from the top of the cliff, down into
the ravine behind you, the rock ravine where you
were, and pounces on right where the bell landed.
You hear it ping (crushing). With an impact, you
see rocks get thrown, as it scrapes across the
ground and it tears where the sound source was, it
sits there, tearing at it. The other one comes
right up to the edge to inspect inside. Right over
where you are, it hasn't quite noticed you right
now as you guys are all standing still, the bell
is quickly being noticed to not be anything
fleshy.
LAURA: I look up. Is it like right above the
head?
MATT: It's about, maybe, five feet above you right
now.
LAURA: So I could take my maul and go like
this!
MATT: Sure.
TRAVIS: I could use Mage Hand to create a better
distraction.
LAURA: Too late.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: Go ahead and roll an attack. You have
advantage on this strike since it's unaware of
your position.
LAURA: 26.
MATT: 26 hits, yeah.
LAURA: (laughing) Aw. 11.
MATT: 11 points of damage, nice. So, as the one
that-- its snout kind of creeped over the edge,
you can see its teeth are this thick underbite of
its jaw pulling open as it's trying to take in
the air both through its nose and its mouth.
(snarling) At which point, out of the darkness,
this giant maul head slams right into its snout
and it backs up briefly, and as that happens and
you pull the maul back, it glances down with this
look of absolute hatred and death in its eyes.
(roars)
LAURA: I think it saw us.
MATT: You do get a second attack because you did
take the action on this one. And at this point,
the other one spins around from where the bell
was, hearing the pained sound of its ally.
LAURA: 17?
MATT: 17 hits.
LAURA: Yes! 12.
MATT: 12 points of damage, all righty. So, as it's
gearing up over the side, you take the maul and
slam it again. This time it moves its head to the
side and it hits the side of its neck. It's a
heavy hit, and it takes the brunt of it, but it's
so big. I mean, you're pretty big as an
olog-hai. It's probably at least two or more times
the mass of your body.
LAURA: Oh, it's so much bigger than I thought it
was.
TRAVIS: I think you were thinking it was like a
dog.
SAM: Oh, because you didn't play an orc in the
game, so you don't know that these things are
really powerful.
LAURA: No!
TRAVIS: Really terrible.
DARIN: But they can be defeated by a bell.
TRAVIS: It's like a giant liger.
MATT: And on that note, I would like everybody to
roll initiative, please, as these two caragor are
now bearing down on you in this ravine. Oh, okay.
LAURA: We got more of them than they have. It's
okay.
DARIN: 17.
MATT: Oh, nice.
SAM: I think we should try to run.
MATT: (laughs) Yeah, these guys don't seem very
fast.
SAM: Six.
LAURA: Oh no.
TRAVIS: Yeah, only four-legged.
LAURA: Nine.
TRAVIS: Greyhounds of death. 15.
MATT: All right, Mozuu, you're up first. There's
the one that's up behind you on the path, maybe
about 15, 20 feet from you, and there's the one
that's right above the edge right now that she
slammed twice in the face. What are you going to
do?
DARIN: Thunderous Smite.
MATT: All right, so you pull forth your war pick,
and you're going to go ahead and strike which one?
DARIN: The one that was closest to Arby.
MATT: Okay.
DARIN: Or I should go for the other one?
MATT: It's a little high for you right now.
Because of her size, she can barely reach it.
You'd have to try and make your way up either
Arby, or climb part of the cliff side. Up to you.
DARIN: Do you mind if I climb you?
LAURA: Not a bit.
DARIN: I'm going to climb.
MATT: Make an athletics check.
DARIN: Okay.
SAM: That's either a one or a 20.
DARIN: I don't know what that is.
SAM: It's a 20!
DARIN: Oh, it's a 20!
MATT: Oh, snap, okay. So, using Arby's body as a
ramp, you begin to leap up from shoulder to back
to shoulder, the top of her head, and jump in the
air, warpick in the sky as you scream to bring it
bearing down on the first caragor before you.
DARIN: (yelling) I speak for Sauron!
MATT: (laughs) All righty, so, make an attack roll
against it.
DARIN: 16.
MATT: 16 hits! Go ahead and roll for this.
DARIN: I think it's a 1d8 plus three.
MATT: So yes, 1d8 plus three, and then you add an
additional 2d6 thunder damage to the target.
DARIN: That's eight, and the six, that is three,
and that is a one. 12.
MATT: 12 points of damage?
DARIN: Yeah.
MATT: All right, so. As you slam the war pick
right into the front of its snout, it jams into
one nostril and tears through across the side of
its face, releasing this gout of dark purplish-red
blood, and as the impact hits, there's a burst of
energy. The sheer force of your anger as you
scream in its face scares it back, and it blows
about ten feet behind you and is knocked prone. It
rolled a natural four plus four, that's eight. And
I believe your spell DC is 11, right?
DARIN: Yes it is. Oh yeah!
MATT: This caragor now gets thrown back ten feet
and is knocked prone on the ground on its side.
It's trying to snap around and get its feet any
sort of purchase to get back up on to the ground,
but currently it's open.
DARIN: The Forcs are a powerful team.
TRAVIS: We don't forc around.
MATT: That ends your turn. Okay, so, Skak, you're
up.
TRAVIS: Skak. Because it's laying prone, I
probably can't see it from below, right?
MATT: No, you'd have get up.
TRAVIS: I'll aim to the other one that turned at
the sound of pain, and I will use my crossbow to
shoot at it.
MATT: All right, go for it. It just turned around.
(growls)
TRAVIS: That's terrible. 12.
MATT: 12. Okay. That does not hit. You turn around
and you fire and it--
TRAVIS: (whimpers) Bonus action! Hide!
MATT: I'll let you move around the rock where you
are and try and hide.
TRAVIS: Okay, fair enough. 18. On stealth.
MATT: Okay. Good to know. All right. That ends
your turn, it's now their turn. So the one that
was knocked prone gets up off the ground. Ten feet
away, it still has enough movement as you're
standing now on the shoulders of Arby. It's going
to go ahead and-- Let's see.
DARIN: And we put on a big coat and pretend we're
one person. And we sneak into a movie theatre.
MATT: It takes a five-foot step back and goes into
a 15-foot leap right towards you. It's a deadly
leap. (snarls) It lunges towards you.
DARIN: Mm-hmm. This was a wonderful game. Thank you
for letting me play.
MATT: Yeah, I need both Mozuu and Arby to make
strength or dexterity saving throw, your choice.
TRAVIS: Get its attention, you can do it.
DARIN: That's a 13.
LAURA: 25.
MATT: You succeed, you do not. All right, so. Here
we go.
TRAVIS: All the dice come out. Just all the dice.
MATT: 14 points of bludgeoning and slashing damage
to you, Mozuu, and you are knocked prone as it
lands on top of you, knocking you off of Arby's
shoulders. You are now on the ground with it on
top of you going (snarls). And it's tearing and
biting at you as you are currently pinned to the floor.
DARIN: He's trying to rip out my throat? Sure is
poetic.
MATT: Turnabout's fair play. You take seven points
of damage, Arby, and you are not knocked prone or
thrown off, you manage to keep your weight there.
However, it's partially standing on you now, its
hind legs are up on your back and it's using you
to hold itself as it's currently putting all of
its weight on Mozuu. The other one that was shot
at by Skak is going to go ahead and rush forward
and it's going to go ahead and make a deadly leap
as well. Let's see, all that going on with that
space it's going to have to go after Eden. I need
you to go ahead and make a strength or dexterity
saving throw, your choice.
SAM: I'll choose dexterity, and that's a 21.
MATT: 21, all right. Okay, you take six points of
bludgeoning and slashing damage together, and you
are not knocked prone. It doesn't pin you in the
space. You just manage to pull out of the way, but
it's right up in your face now and your back's
against the rock that he's hiding behind. There's
your friends and the other caragor right behind
you over your shoulders, and this one is right in
front of you right now, slashing and snarling at
you. That's going to end their turn. Arby, you're up.
LAURA: I'm going to spin around and try to hit the
one that's standing on me.
MATT: Okay, that's the one you've hit before, so
go for it.
LAURA: Yeah. Ooh, 26.
MATT: 26 hits!
LAURA: Aw. Dang. Plus seven plus five is 12.
MATT: All righty, so that first hit slams into its
side. You hit it again, you hear the crunch. One
shoulder blade seems to almost buckle a little
bit. It's looking pretty hurt but it's still
standing there.
LAURA: I'm going to try to hit it again. That's a
19.
MATT: That hits.
LAURA: 14.
MATT: 14, all righty. And with that, you slam up
your maul a second time. It actually catches it
right underneath the jaw and forces its head to
snap up so fast that its spine seems to break into
place, and with a (whines) it falls limp, the
entirety of its weight sliding off of your
shoulders and onto Mozuu, who is now prone and
pinned underneath it.
DARIN: I've gotten the most damage of this entire
game.
LAURA: Eden! Do you want me to try to hit that one
too?
SAM: Yes!
LAURA: I'm going to action surge and try to run up
to the other one and attack it too.
TRAVIS: Action surge.
MATT: Okay. So. Taking a little bit there, shoving
it off to the side, you rush up to the one that's
right in the face of Eden. It's a quick jaunt.
LAURA: That's a 24.
MATT: That hits!
SAM: You're so powerful.
TRAVIS: Wow.
LAURA: Are you kidding me?!
TRAVIS: Double ones both times!
MATT: What?!
LAURA: Sorry, that's seven points of damage.
MATT: All right, seven points of damage. You rush
up and swing at it. This time, it brings its head
back and manages to deflect some of the blow with
the side of its face; not quite doing as much
damage as you'd like.
LAURA: Ooh, natural 20 on the next hit!
MATT: Make up for that! There you go!
LAURA: 25 points of damage.
MATT: 25 points of damage! So, while it deflects
the first blow, as it turns its head back to
strike at you, you put your foot up and hold it
right in its jaw to keep it from getting away. You
use that to aim it up and whack right up the side
of its temple. It rings its bell and you watch as
it pulls away, the slobber and blood dripping from
its jaws, shaking its head back and forth from the
pain you just inflicted. I believe that ends your
turn.
LAURA: Yes, it does.
MATT: End of Arby's turn brings it to you, Eden.
SAM: (growling) I will attack relentlessly! 23 to
hit.
MATT: 23 hits!
SAM: That is five points of damage.
TRAVIS: Relentless damage!
SAM: I will use my Flurry of Blows.
MATT: You get two attacks and then you can use
your Flurry.
SAM: Got it. So, second attack doesn't hit. It's
12. So I can't use my Flurry of Blows?
MATT: You can!
SAM: Okay! Flurry of Blows!
MATT: So you get two more attacks.
SAM: That's worse. And 15.
MATT: 15 just barely hits.
SAM: Eight! Plus four is 12 points of damage. Plus
I will choose a condition for it. Strength saving
throw? If it fails, no, it probably is strong.
It's probably dextrous, too. I'm going to choose
that it can't take reactions until the end of my
next turn.
MATT: So it can't take attacks of opportunity.
There you go. Perfect. That ends your turn, Eden.
Mozuu, you're up. Currently prone and pinned under
the dead body of a caragor.
DARIN: May I call for help?
MATT: Yes, you may.
DARIN: I would like to do that. You thought I was
going to say something else, but I would like to
call: Hello? Might I have a bit of aid, please?
MATT: Are you going to attempt to pull your way
out, or are you just waiting for someone to help you?
DARIN: I'm waiting for someone to help me.
MATT: You're holding your action for someone to
aid.
DARIN: I've been beaten up a lot.
TRAVIS: Do we see him under this giant caragor?
MATT: You hear and see, out of the corner of your
eye. You especially see it because you're right
behind the rock and you see his head and shoulders
are right there like, "Help!"
DARIN: Excellent. The person who isn't the
strongest! This'll be fun!
TRAVIS: I'm on my way!
MATT: Holding your action for someone to help you.
That brings us to Skak's turn.
TRAVIS: (panicked noises) Can I not help him at
all? I pop back up out of hiding. Can I take aim
with the crossbow again? As a bonus, can I smash a
poison vial on one of my arrows to make it a
poisoned arrow?
MATT: It's an action to poison a weapon. It's more
of a preparation thing.
TRAVIS: I'll keep that in mind. Crossbow! Natural
20!
MATT: Oh shit! Roll your dice and then add the
modifiers after you double it.
TRAVIS: Six.
LAURA: Plus your sneak attack.
TRAVIS: Is it sneak attack? Is he within melee of
the other ones?
MATT: Yeah, they've both been bashing it.
TRAVIS: Excellent. Oh god. 16. 24.
LAURA: You're supposed to double your dice, all of
your dice.
TRAVIS: 26. That one's supposed to be doubled too,
right?
LAURA: Yep.
TRAVIS: Okay. 26.
MATT: 26 points of damage. All right. Yeah. As you
peek out of hiding, you see it snapping and
snarling at both of your friends over on the side.
You take a moment and slow your breathing. (heartbeats)
And release the crossbow bolt. You watch
behind as it streaks forward between your friends.
The caragor turns, opening its jaw to snap over
Arby and it goes right in the back of the throat,
up into the brain and it collapses to the ground,
no longer moving.
TRAVIS: Oh, are you okay, Mozuu?
DARIN: Yes.
LAURA and SAM: Mozuu?
DARIN: I am a talking caragor!
LAURA: I walk over and try to push the caragor.
MATT: Since you're not in immediate danger, it
takes you a minute or so. You all manage to push
this giant caragor corpse off of Mozuu's body.
You're sore, you're crushed, you're sweaty and
covered in blood, but you're now standing.
LAURA: See! That wasn't so bad!
SAM: Is our prisoner still around, or did he run
away?
MATT: Make a perception check.
LAURA: Oh, I forgot we even had him!
SAM: Oh, perception! 21!
MATT: 21. He is quite a ways down the walkway
sprinting away.
SAM: I could catch him!
TRAVIS: Can you?
SAM: I can!
LAURA: Let's take off after him.
SAM: I'm going to sprint after him using Step of
the Wind.
MATT: You're going to use another ki point. With
your speed and double dash, as he's sprinting.
(heavy panting) About a minute later or so, you
catch up right behind him and he's within grasp of
you. He hasn't noticed you, he's just eyes on the
prize right towards the fortress.
SAM: I grab the top of his skull.
MATT: Make an athletics check to grapple him.
SAM: Athletics? 17.
MATT: 17. You grab him by the back of the head and
he gets yanked out from under his feet and slams
into the ground. You're still clutching him. You
pick him up. He's dangling now from your giant
olog mitts.
SAM: Can't run from the Forcs!
MATT: "I was running from the caragors!
Self-preservation, mate!"
SAM: That makes sense. All right, we'll wait here
for the others and then we follow this plan.
MATT: "Yes!"
SAM: You're on our side.
MATT: "Of course!"
SAM: I trust you implicitly.
MATT: "Don't worry!"
SAM: I don't worry about anything.
TRAVIS: Can we see if he's killing him or having a
chat?
MATT: Make a perception check.
TRAVIS: Nope! Two!
MATT: You see him grabbing him by the head and
pulling him in and you see a bit of a struggle.
LAURA: You should probably shoot him.
TRAVIS: He's killing him.
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: I nock an arrow.
MATT: Roll an attack.
TRAVIS: Oh shit. 25.
MATT: Roll damage with sneak attack.
(laughter)
LAURA: We're so terrible!
TRAVIS: That's terrible! Eight. Nine. 13.
MATT: As you're holding him.
SAM: I trust you implicitly. We are in this
together 100%.
MATT: "Don't worry, we've got this! All right, we're
going to make our way inside."
SAM: Friends. Oh no!
TRAVIS: Heal him!
SAM: I can! I will use my medical kit to stabilize
him! I pull out the arrow! No, don't do this to
me! Come on, fight! You can come back! I spit into
the wound, I close it with my hand.
MATT: I'm going to ask you right now to make an
initiative roll to see how fast you are at healing
him versus how fast he's bleeding out from the
wound.
SAM: Nine.
MATT: You finish applying the bandages, you've
pulled out the bolt, and you have the body there.
(cough) He rolled a three.
SAM: Bock! Bock-Bock! What's his name?
LAURA: Borg-Borg!
SAM: Borg-Borg?
MATT: "Just Borg."
SAM: Borg, I thought I had lost you. I don't know
what happened. All I can say is: I'm sorry and it
will never happen again.
MATT: You guys approach as Eden is cradling this
freshly bandaged goblin.
LAURA: Did we kill him?
TRAVIS: Oh, you fixed him up?
SAM: Why did you do that?! He's our ticket in!
LAURA and TRAVIS: Oh!
SAM: I think you can still trust us, all right?
MATT: "Okay."
TRAVIS: Or you can take that as a sign of things
to come if you do it again!
MATT: Make an intimidation check.
TRAVIS: Prepare to feel the-- oh, not terrible!
20!
MATT: He goes, "Right. Point making. I'm good. All
right."
TRAVIS: Boy, don't you call me point making! All
right. Inside. Wait. Should we make him look a
little better? You almost killed him.
LAURA: Does anybody have any lipstick? And some
rouge?
TRAVIS: What?
LAURA: I thought we were going to make him
pretty.
SAM: I have a robe.
DARIN: I have oil. In certain cases, I'm just
saying.
LAURA: I have some bagpipes.
TRAVIS: I have a crowbar.
SAM: You have a bagpipe?
LAURA: I like to play music sometimes, that's
all.
SAM: I think we're good, let's just get on with
it.
MATT: All right. So as you guys slowly begin to
encroach upon the outer elements of this fortress,
the points of torchlight burning in these braziers
along the top side of it, you can see guards
walking back and forth along the edges, shortbows
at the side, nocked and ready in case any sign of
danger happens. You can see a front-- actually,
for you guys that are closest, go ahead and make a
perception check.
TRAVIS: Yeah! 17.
MATT: All righty.
SAM: Nothing.
LAURA: Five.
DARIN: Nine.
MATT: Okay. So as you all stare off and it's about
as much as you can make out. You, however, Skak,
looking ahead, you can see: one, there's a main
entrance. There's two large, eight-foot-wide doors
that are currently closed on the north side of the
wall. You also see what happens to be a
muck-covered mud hole that's towards the south
side, where the wall meets the mountain, where you
can see it's a little swampy and it looks like
some of this thick muck and mud meets up to the
side of the wall there.
TRAVIS: So the doors lie ahead but I see off to
the side a little quagmire.
LAURA: What's that?
TRAVIS: It's like mucky, muddier earth and
liquid--
LAURA: Oh, we could take a bath!
TRAVIS: We could, yes, or we could see if perhaps
there's a way under the wall.
DARIN: Do you know what that is? Have you been
through there before?
MATT: "Well, I've seen it, aye."
DARIN: Have you ever seen anyone go in or out of
there?
MATT: "Not intentionally. It's the shrak
hole."
(groaning)
LAURA: What's that?
MATT: "I could show you." (coughs) Its wrapping is
all around the face and one eye-- it was already
swollen from earlier and is now-- he's a
wrecked-looking goblin.
LAURA: What happened to your neck?
MATT: "I don't know."
TRAVIS: So we either go in through the front
door--
SAM: Or the back door.
TRAVIS: (laughs) Oh yes, literally! Oh jeez! Oh
gosh.
SAM: I think we should go through the back door.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: (laughs) Okay.
SAM: Hey, shrak happens.
TRAVIS: Yeah, it does. Shrak yeah! Okay, do we
send him first? No, because if he gets in, he
runs away. I'm just saying.
SAM: Yeah, we'll go first. Right?
TRAVIS: Which one of us?
DARIN: Who's the most beaten up? Who's been through
absolute hell?
SAM: You.
DARIN: There's two things I know. I'm going
first--
ALL: And that's it.
DARIN: I'm going first.
SAM: Go through that shrak hole!
MATT: All right. So I want you guys to all make
stealth checks to make your way around that hole
without being seen.
SAM: We're stealthing?
MATT: Yes, and that's disadvantage for you, Arby,
unfortunately. Because you have heavy armor on.
LAURA: (high-pitched) Oh man! But I rolled so well
on that first one!
MATT: (high-pitched) Well, roll a second time!
DARIN: So the roll plus dexterity?
MATT: No, it's a stealth check.
DARIN: Oh, five.
TRAVIS: Five total?
SAM: Nine.
DARIN: It was a one.
TRAVIS: 21.
LAURA: Ten.
MATT: Okay! As you guys quietly make your way over
to the shrak hole, you approach the base of the
gate there and you hear a voice above you go,
"Hey! What are you doing?"
SAM: Bonk! Say something!
MATT: You look up and there's three archers that
all have their bows notched on you, going, "What
"the hell are you--"
SAM: Brick, say something!
MATT: "Oh. We're gathering for the alchemist. Getting
some more prime shrak for his boomy balls!
"Yeah!" He's going to attempt to make a deception--
oh, not bad, actually. Let's see if they-- rolling
against myself here. "All right. Who are them?"
LAURA: We're the Forcs!
MATT: "What's the Forcs?"
LAURA: It's what you eat with!
SAM: We work for Ur-Gram!
MATT: Make a deception check.
SAM: Oh no. Five.
MATT: One of them starts whispering to the other
one and the one that he's whispering to nods and
goes and grabs one of the torches and starts going
over towards one of the unlit braziers. You've
seen these before; they're used usually as a
beacon, a warning, a signal for any sort of undue--
SAM: Let's go through the shrak hole right away!
Fast, charging in!
LAURA: You kill him.
TRAVIS: The guy walking towards the brazier? Yeah,
but there are three longbows above us and we have
the low ground.
SAM: That's why we have to go through the shrak
hole, as fast as we can!
LAURA: Kill him so he doesn't light it, then we go
into the poop.
TRAVIS: Okay. I eye the guy walking with the torch
towards the brazier. Does he look like he intends
to light said brazier?
MATT: He looks like he intends to light it.
TRAVIS: I will draw very quickly the crossbow and
try and put one in while he's not looking.
MATT: Go ahead and roll for an attack.
TRAVIS: Rolling with sneak attack.
SAM: How high is the wall, Matt?
LAURA: Is it a surprise attack?
MATT: No, it is not a surprise attack. It's
probably about 15 feet high.
TRAVIS: But is it a sneak attack?
MATT: You weren't-- oh, you were pretty stealthed,
the rest weren't. So yeah, it is now a sneak
attack.
TRAVIS: 16 to hit.
MATT: 16 to hit. Yeah, that hits! The archer.
TRAVIS: Okay. Ten, 15, 16, 17.
MATT: All right, so the one that's walking towards
the brazier falls off the wall on the side and
slams into the mud there. And the other two
archers immediately go--
TRAVIS: (shouting) Go!
MATT: And they both pull and they're going to both
fire arrows down. One of them is going to fire at
you-- actually they're both going to fire at you
because you killed their friend. You revealed
yourself. They suck though-- that's an 11.
TRAVIS: That will miss!
MATT: Yeah. And a ten.
TRAVIS: That misses as well!
MATT: So you duck out on both sides and they both
go for secondary arrows and begin running towards
the brazier themselves now. What are you guys
doing?
LAURA: Oh no! You should hit them too because
they're going to light it.
SAM: I'm going to jump up onto the wall.
LAURA: Can you do that?
SAM: I'm going to use my step of the wind which
doubles my jump distance. Distance, does that mean
height?
MATT: Well, yeah. But horizontal distance-- we'll
say height for this. What's your strength
modifier?
SAM: Four-- one. My strength modifier is one.
MATT: Right. It doubles it, so you get (grunts).
I'll say you barely-- because of your height.
Because you are an olog, you barely get your
fingers up on the top. Go ahead and make a
strength saving throw to try and pull yourself up.
SAM: Okay. (scoffs) Nine.
MATT: You drop back down. It's just too high.
LAURA: Are there any rocks around?
MATT: Make an investigation check if you want to.
DARIN: We did take a rest. Did we regain any spells
we use?
MATT: No. It's a long rest.
LAURA: 12.
MATT: A 12? You find a small rock. In your hand,
it's really small.
LAURA: I'm going to try to throw this little rock
at one of them.
MATT: Make an attack roll. (laughs)
LAURA: 11!
MATT: It arcs over the wall.
LAURA: I'm used to bigger-sized rocks, is all. Just
because they were so--
SAM: To the shrak hole!
LAURA: Wait, you have it. Try to hit it.
TRAVIS: I'm going to try and hit him, one of the
last two.
MATT: All right, go for it and they're going to go
again.
TRAVIS: Okay. 15.
MATT: 15 just barely hits!
LAURA: We've got to get them before they light the
brazier!
SAM: It'll be okay.
MATT: It's technically not sneak attack because
you've already hit them.
TRAVIS: Oh, thank you. Then that is only-- it's
only ten.
MATT: Ten damage. Okay, so one of them gets hit
and he's still standing and he's going to whip
around and try to fire back at you. The other one
that's running past is going to go ahead and pull
out a torch and try to light it. All right, so
that ends your turn. They're going to go. One is
going to take another shot at you. There we go!
That is a 24 to hit.
DARIN: Do we all get-- I did not make an action.
MATT: Oh shit! That's right, you didn't. So you
go.
DARIN: Shrak hole.
SAM: Shrak hole.
LAURA: You go in?
DARIN: Yes, I'm going in.
MATT: Okay. So you go ahead and make a-- as you
dive into it, make an investigation check to try
and feel your way through.
LAURA: Eww!
DARIN: Seven.
MATT: You disappear into it and writhe around a
bunch to try and reach out for something. It's
very taut. Even your uruk form is having a hard
time pulling underneath.
DARIN: Again I feel alive.
MATT: Indeed. (laughs) All right, so you--
TRAVIS: Uncanny dodge, please.
MATT: Yes. That would be seven points of piercing
damage, reduced to three and the other guy manages
to light the brazier. The light goes bright. The
signal has been lit. What are you guys doing?
TRAVIS: We should run to the front door and act
like we saw attackers running off in a different
direction.
LAURA: That's really smart.
SAM: Split the party? He's in shrak right now. I'm
going to go in the shrak hole.
LAURA: I'm going to pick up the body of the guy
that fell and try to throw him at the other guy.
MATT: Make an attack roll!
LAURA: Yeah? I'm big.
MATT: This is just your strength modifier. You're
not proficient in bodies.
TRAVIS: (laughs) Body chucking's not a thing?
LAURA: Eight.
MATT: Eight? (laughs) You slam it against the
wall. It slides down and hits the ground. You hear
this horrible crunching sound as a number of
previously unbroken bones are now freshly broken
in the dead body. You have another attack if you
want to walk up and try it again.
LAURA: I want to try it again but this time, since
I didn't throw him high enough, I'm going to spin
around and try to lob him up. Yeah.
MATT: Okay. Make another attack roll with a
crumpled body.
LAURA: (laughs) That's terrible! Seven!
MATT: You release a little too early and it (heavy
impact) hits the wall right next to you. One of
the arms tears and flies off against the mud. You
liquefied his insides at this point.
LAURA: He's not feeling very good.
TRAVIS: Are we going into the shrak hole?
SAM: I'm going into the shrak hole!
LAURA: How big is the shrak hole? Can all of us
fit in there?
MATT: Well, as you dive in, it pushes you out the
other side. You get shoved out, plopped out,
covered in shrak. And you look around, immediately
you can see, as you wipe your eyes off the
shrak, everybody is now starting to look around at
the signal and begin to grab their weapons and
start preparing for an incursion. You dive into
it. You get halfway in-- this is a very small
space underneath and you're a very large olog. I'm
going to need you to make either an athletics
check or an acrobatics check to try and push
through. Your choice.
SAM: Acrobatics. 19.
MATT: 19. You push through and watch as the bottom
of the wall splinters and breaks, but you manage
to make your way through and now, you stand up
behind Mozuu, a good number of feet taller than
him, also covered in shrak and you both now look
around at this chaos happening. What are you
doing?
LAURA: Well, go in, Skak.
TRAVIS: No. Yes, and I jump in. I jump in after
him, in the shrak hole.
MATT: All right. You dive in. The space has been
opened, thankfully. You follow through. They paved
the path.
TRAVIS: Oh, I could barely make it through! So
big.
MATT: You glide through and now it's just you and
your friend, Borg, who's looking at the archers.
Well, the archers, the one that's with the torch
is going to go ahead and try and take another
shot. They're both taking a shot. One's going to
be at you and one's going to be at you, now that
you guys are on that side. Against you, that is a
21.
TRAVIS: Hits.
MATT: You take-- ooh, nine points of piercing
damage.
TRAVIS: Uncanny dodge. No, I already used my
reaction.
MATT: Well, you used it from last time, so it
returns. So you have it back again. You can use
it-- yeah. okay, it's reduced to four points of
piercing damage. And then one against you is a
14.
LAURA: Doesn't hit me.
MATT: It breaks off the armor. They're both firing
arrows down at you. All right, so what are you
guys doing? You glide underneath as they fire at
you. You slip under. You're back there with Borg.
LAURA: I'm telling Borg to go through before me.
Go on.
MATT: Dives in, like slowly wades into it (groans)
and goes under and pushes his way through without
an issue.
LAURA: All right. I'm going to gingerly lower
myself into the shrak and then go under slowly.
MATT: Okay. As you guys get up on the other side,
you can now see about 40 to 50 various uruk have
now gathered at the base of the wall where you're
standing. They're all armored and ready, their
weapons are drawn and you are completely
surrounded on the interior of this wall. Nothing
but liquid shrak at your back, as you all stand
there but they're all keeping at bay. You watch as
a hand comes up behind the crowd and goes,
"Hold!" Everyone was like-- they are ready to tear
at you but they begin to part at the center and
you watch with heavy steps as an olog-hai
approaches with a giant, mutated underbite with
tusks that reach up past the nostril. The eyes
peek through from heavily scarred muscle tissue
where a face once existed, but has since been torn
and not healed very well over. You see, clutching
a giant greataxe in its grasp, what you assume to
be Ur-Gram the Face-Eater, who's approached and goes,
"Who? Who enters my home?"
DARIN: The Bright Lord called to us.
MATT: Make a deception check.
DARIN: 15.
MATT: "The Bright Lord, you say?"
DARIN: Yes.
MATT: "Then stand at me! Walk up and prove you
bear the mark!"
DARIN: I bear no mark yet. I desire to.
I've literally gone through shrak for this moment.
The Bright Lord spoke to me in my head. He told
me, the strong take what they want. And I want to
be part of the Bright Lord's army.
MATT: At this point, you see Ur-Gram is taken
aback by this response and glances over his
shoulders. He steps back and you hear a voice from
behind him go, "Let me see this orc. Bring him
"before me." And as Ur-Gram steps aside, you see a
human male standing with long, somewhat-tattered
dark hair, beard towards the base of the chin,
wearing leather and hide armor and bits of
chainmail beneath a dark cloak with a single long
blade extended to one side. All the rest of the
various uruks around the area separate and back
away. As they do, you see a familiar flash in
their eyes, that strange gray-white light that you
saw when you first had your fortress attacked. The
human man walks forward. "You say you came this
far for the Bright Lord. Then come. Stand before
"me. Be marked as you say your request."
LAURA: (whispering) Mozuu! Mozuu!
SAM: (whispering) He's been chosen.
DARIN: I walk towards the Bright Lord. I kneel
before the Bright Lord. I am Mozuu the Chosen.
Choose me, Bright Lord.
MATT: As he looks down upon this snivelling uruk,
his hand protrudes forward and you see for a
second, the outer image of his form begin to
shimmer and for a moment, you see a familiar sight
you've only seen towards the outskirts of the dead
waste and swamps on the western side of Mordor.
You see spiritual energy pull out of him and you
see for a brief instant, a wraith-like form of
some long-dead elf that marks the exterior of his
body. As the hand reaches forward, this voice
echoes around. "Come. May you join the rest of
this army." Takes the hand and places it against
the side of Mozuu's face.
LAURA: I scream out, No! And run forward and try
to tackle him. Manswine!
(laughter)
MATT: I need you all to roll initiative right
now.
TRAVIS: Oh crap, oh crap, oh crap!
DARIN: That's really something!
LAURA: Oh shrak, oh shrak, oh shrak!
DARIN: So much for that idea.
MATT: Okay. You rolled a 12 initiative?
DARIN: Yeah.
MATT: All right. So we have--
SAM: Nine here.
MATT: All righty.
LAURA: 18.
MATT: Oh wow. You are dead even with the tark.
TRAVIS: 16 for me.
MATT: Okay. All right, so top of the round. Arby.
As you go charging forward right as the hand
reaches to grab the side of Mozuu's face, what are
you going to do?
LAURA: I'm going to--
MATT: Make a shove attack or try and push him out
of the way?
LAURA: I was trying to push him off of Mozuu.
MATT: Okay then. Making a shove attack for your
first strike. I believe I need you to make an
athletics check. I'm checking here. It doesn't
happen too often.
LAURA: 20!
MATT: 20. Okay. Yep, contested against athletics
or acrobatics. All righty. Weirdly enough, you
manage to get in fast enough. Your large olog-hai
form (heavy footsteps) and slam with your shoulder
into this tark. He goes flying off, spinning in the
air and landing, barely catching himself as he
skids back about ten feet or so. Looks up at you
and still the wraith form is on the outside. The
eyes flash with this vibrant scary white light and
the wraith form fits back into the body. As the
tark stands to his feet, the blade at his side and
goes, "Very well. So you've chosen death."
LAURA: (shouting) Death!
(laughter)
MATT: All right. So you still have another attack
if you want to take it.
LAURA: Okay! I want to keep attacking him! I don't
know which dice to use though. Okay! 26!
MATT: 26 hits!
LAURA: (shouting) Man-filth! 14!
MATT: (laughs) 14 points of damage. Nice! All
right. So as you hit him, you hear a ringing out
behind him, the voice of the Face-Eater himself,
Ur-Gram says, "Gravewalker! Smash the invaders!"
TRAVIS: Oh jeez.
LAURA: We're all going to die!
(laughter)
TRAVIS: There's only 40 of them. 40 or 50.
MATT: All right. So at this point, the gravewalker,
who's now up in front of you, takes the hit and
glares back at you with the burning white eyes.
He's going to go ahead and make two strikes on you
with Urfael, his sword. That is a 21.
LAURA: That hits me.
MATT: And that is seven points of slashing damage.
And 19.
LAURA: Ugh. That also hits.
MATT: That is six points of slashing damage and
then he is going to go ahead and attempt a shadow
strike attack. As it strikes you twice with the
sword, sidesteps to the side and looks around at
you and that is a 16. What's your armor class?
TRAVIS: 16!
MATT: 16! It hits you! As you watch the
gravewalker suddenly vanishes from his place, a
streak of vibrant white light shoots between the
two of you and appears right in front of you,
before striking down. That's an 18 to hit?
TRAVIS: (laughs) Yeah, it hits!
MATT: All right. You suffer five points of-- I'm
sorry, nine points of slashing damage and four
points of radiant damage.
TRAVIS: Whoa, so can I use uncanny dodge on the
slashing but not the radiant?
MATT: Well, it's against the whole attack.
TRAVIS: So 13 points down to seven?
MATT: Correct. Down to six, it would be. All
right. And that's going to end the gravewalker's
turn. All right. Ending that, Skak, you're up.
TRAVIS: (shrieks) Please! Let us live! Let us
live! I want to be with you! And I will aim my
crossbow over at Eden.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: And I'll pull the trigger.
MATT: (laughs) Okay! Roll. Go for it.
TRAVIS: Is he within melee of one of my 40 or 50
of my new allies?
MATT: No. What was once an ally is now no
longer--
TRAVIS: 23.
SAM: That hits, but I'll use deflect missiles.
MATT: Roll for damage.
TRAVIS: (laughs) Ah, shit! Seven.
SAM: I reduce that by more than seven points.
MATT: So as you fire the crossbow bolt, you watch
as Eden--
SAM: (catches bolt) (bolt whooshes)
TRAVIS: Oh!
(laughter)
MATT: So you spend a ki point and go ahead and
roll an attack with it. It's considered
proficient.
LAURA: Oh my god. You get to attack him?
MATT: Yeah. If you reduce the damage past what it
did, you get to throw it back at him.
LAURA: That's awesome!
SAM: 16. I rolled a 16 plus I don't
know.
MATT: Yeah, that hits! So go and roll damage. So
it's a d8 plus your dexterity.
SAM: Oh. My dexterity is plus four.
MATT: Yeah. So d8 plus four.
TRAVIS: (scared voice) Play along! Tell a joke!
SAM: Eight plus four.
MATT: 12 points of piercing damage.
TRAVIS: I can't use uncanny dodge--
MATT: No, you already used it! (laughs)
LAURA: What are you at right now?
TRAVIS: Eight.
MATT: Good to know. All right, at the end of your
turn-- you still have a bonus action if you want
to try something.
TRAVIS: I want to hide behind the gravewalker's
legs!
(laughter)
MATT: Okay! So you move behind the gravewalker?
All right, at the end of your turn, he's going to
use two of his legendary actions to try a dominate
on you.
TRAVIS: Me?
MATT: Yes. So as you reach behind--
SAM: You've shown yourself to be weak.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: I was born this way.
MATT: It's an 18. So he reaches behind and as he's
still staring forward, grasps the side of your
face and you feel this burning, singeing
sensation. Make a wisdom saving throw.
TRAVIS: 13.
MATT: 13. The mark, the brand of the gravewalker
now burned into your face. You see the majesty of
the Bright Lord before you and you understand.
This is the one to follow.
TRAVIS: This is the one to follow.
MATT: So whereas you may have decided to change
allegiance before, it's solidified now. You are
working for the gravewalker.
TRAVIS: Yes! Bright Lord!
MATT: All right. That ends that turn. Mozuu,
you're up. The rest of the uruks are stepping back
and watching this. They're just enjoying the
fray.
DARIN: I stand ready to be chosen.
MATT: (laughs) So you stay there and still
kneeling, 20 feet away? All righty. That's your
whole--
DARIN: There's two things I know. The Bright Lord
is my new master and I am merely Mozuu unless you
choose me.
MATT: (evil laughter) Perfect. All right, that
ends Mozuu's turn. Eden, you're up, having just
thrown the bolt back at Skak.
SAM: I look over at Arby, trying to get a sense of
what-- is she on my side?
(laughter)
LAURA: I got a lot of shrak falling off me right
now.
SAM: (sighs) This is not going to end well. Our
leader, Barfta, told us if we found where they
were, that would be a reward. I'm going to leave.
(laughter)
SAM: I can't win this fight!
MATT: All right. So--
TRAVIS: Not with that attitude!
SAM: Everyone's turning into bad guys!
TRAVIS: Well, technically, we are bad guys.
SAM: That's right. Oh, I don't know what to do! I
can't beat that guy. He's a wraith! I'm going to--
MATT: You're going to run?
SAM: --spend my last ki point and run as fast as I
can through the shrak.
MATT: You're like-- dive back into the shrak hole
underneath. It's easy enough for you to push past
now, since you made way earlier. You pop out on
the other side and start bolting away. All right.
At the end of your turn, the gravewalker's going
to go ahead and use his last legendary action--
seeing you dart away, he's going to turn back
towards you. He's going to go ahead and the blade
goes away for a second and pulls his bow, Azkar,
out and pulls back an arrow, releases it.
Actually, that's a 12! Rolled really low.
LAURA: I dodge it. It's all the shrak on me, it
slips off.
MATT: It slips off and you're unmoving.
Unbreakable, even.
LAURA: Unbreakable!
MATT: All right. Back to the top. It's now Arby
and the gravewalker's turn.
LAURA: I run over and I try to hit him!
MATT: All right, you rush, maul swinging in the
air. Go for it.
LAURA: Oh no! That's 11!
MATT: 11? You go and swing and you watch as the
form shimmies by and he dodges right out of the
way, preternaturally fast.
LAURA: You're tricky, you! I try to hit him
again!
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Oh no! That's only 11, again!
MATT: (laughs) The second swing goes wide and for
a second, you're sure you made contact but in the
space where the hammer goes, you watch as the
gravewalker stands back into place. "You sow chaos
"and invite it."
LAURA: I don't even know what you mean.
MATT: "Bow or crumple before your Bright Lord. The
choice matters not, for death has already found me
"once and lost." And he's going to go ahead and
attempt a wraith stun attack against you. That is
23 to hit?
LAURA: Oh no!
MATT: All right. You take ten points of radiant
damage.
LAURA: I'm going to use my troll's endurance! And
I'm going to take that down by ten.
MATT: By ten? So it hits you and you resist the
damage but I still need you to make a constitution
saving throw.
LAURA: Oh no. 21!
MATT: Okay. You feel the impact, the wraith
energies, but your physical form, being a tough
olog-hai, you resist the stunning effect of the
strike and push through it. No stun on you
whatsoever. And then he's going to go ahead and
follow up with two more attacks with Urfael, as
the bow's been put by the side. He's going to
swing twice with the blade against you. That is a
15? It just slides off your armor. Second strike,
that's cocked. Natural one.
ALL: Yeah!
MATT: So he swings a second time and you actually
catch the blade in your hand. You feel it like
cutting into your grip a little bit, but you
tighten as you stare down at the gravewalker.
Unmoved at this threatening presence that's
looking up at you, like it's only an
inevitability.
LAURA: I'm a boss fight, pig-skin!
(laughter)
MATT: All right. So that's going to go ahead and
end their turn. Skak, you're up.
TRAVIS: I serve the Bright Master! Can I hold my
attack and ask for one of the large uruks or
uruk-hais to pick me up and throw me above the
wall so I can take a crossbow shot at fleeing
Eden?
MATT: Sure, you glance off to the side and one of
the ologs who's off to the side there, has chains
around the chest, you can see maybe it was more
of the physical-handy ologs as opposed to warrior.
Looks at you with a nod. Make a persuasion check.
TRAVIS: We all must serve, answer the call! Yeah,
that's going to be a 19.
MATT: 19! The olog picks you up and gives
you an alley-oop into the air. Yeah, easily
enough, you arc up. Make an acrobatics check to
try and land your feet on the wall.
TRAVIS: 21.
MATT: You land on the edge of the wall and you
glance up, just passing, you can see Eden darting
away.
TRAVIS: We cannot flee!
MATT: Make an attack!
TRAVIS: Does he know what's coming? Any chance of
sneak attack? He's on the other side of the wall.
MATT: I will say, he's not aware of your presence.
Sure, I'll allow it.
TRAVIS: Yeah! 15, 17, 18.
MATT: 18 points of piercing damage.
SAM: I will use my troll's endurance to reduce
that by 11 points.
LAURA: Seven points.
MATT: So crossbow bolt catches you in the back of
the shoulder blades, right where the spine meets
them. Your body tenses for a second.
SAM: I touch the arrow and I say, ugh! He's right.
Forcs don't run. They stick in meat and they stay
there forever. And I turn around and I run back
into the shrak hole!
(laughing)
MATT: All right, so when you get to your turn,
you're bolting back. All right. So Mozuu, it's
back up to your turn.
DARIN: Can I hold it until the actions are done?
MATT: I mean, pretty much everyone else is gone.
DARIN: Can I speak to the Bright Lord? I said I
heard the voice of Sauron. I lied. I never heard
anything, but I will hear your voice if you would
speak to me.
MATT: Okay. You use that as your action? All
right, at the top. It is Arby and Talion's turn.
So, what are you doing?
LAURA: Do I still have a hold of his blade?
MATT: Currently, yeah.
LAURA: Oh, yeah. Can I try to smack it with
himself and say stop hitting yourself! Stop
hitting yourself!
MATT: Sure. All right. Go ahead and make-- this
would be an athletics versus athletics.
LAURA: A 14.
MATT: 23. As you attempt to do it, he pulls the
blade from your grasp. Cuts your hand a little bit
but nothing too major.
LAURA: All right, then I'm going to try to attack
him then.
MATT: So you have one more attack.
LAURA: That is a 20!
MATT: 20 hits!
LAURA: Seven plus five is 12.
MATT: All right. 12 points of damage. This time,
the gravewalker gets taken off his feet a little
bit. He rolls a little bit, just around the side
and gets back up to his feet, maybe five feet,
almost ten feet from you. Blade's still out, looks
at you, looks at the surrounding scenarios. Seems
to become somewhat impressed by the fact that
you're still fighting in the midst of such
immeasurable danger.
LAURA: And as my bonus action, I'm going to take
my second wind. I'm going to take 1d10 and add five to it.
So 14 points of damage added back!
MATT: There you go. At which point, the
gravewalker turns his back on you and steps
towards Mozuu and says, "Then prove to me. Prove
to me you have what it takes." And reaches down
and grabs your face, this time finally making
contact. Go ahead and make a wisdom saving throw.
You can opt to not resist it if you'd like to.
DARIN: That is 16.
MATT: Do you want to resist it or you want to let
it happen?
DARIN: I'm on board.
MATT: Then you don't need to make a saving throw.
Then that being the case, the brand burns in the
side of your face. You watch as Mozuu's eyes flare
with a vibrant energy. And as it fades, you now
see that indeed, this prophecy you spoke earlier
seems to be true.
DARIN: I'm truly chosen.
MATT: You are now. As the brand is there, you
glance back and see the pittance that is the
existence of your previous allies. And the Bright
Lord, as you stand up, goes, "Kill for me." And
looks back towards Arby.
TRAVIS: Not me, we're on the same team!
DARIN: Right, buddy!
TRAVIS: Betrayers unite!
MATT: And with that, he's going to go ahead and
pull back Azkar and take two arrow shots at you.
That is a 23.
LAURA: Oh, that hits me!
MATT: And a 19.
LAURA: Oh no!
MATT: All right. That is 11 points of piercing
damage and seven points of piercing damage. Both
arrows slam into your armor; you can feel the
plates break and crumble. These are not normal
arrows, not with the strength that they're being
tossed at you. That's going to end the
gravewalker's turn. Skak, you're up. You can see
Eden running back.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Crossbow.
MATT: You want to try and hide first?
TRAVIS: Oh! Does it up my-- if I'm from a hidden
position?
MATT: Well, if you can manage to hide and move and
he's not aware of where you are? I'll allow it.
TRAVIS: I will use my bonus action to try and
hide.
MATT: Okay. So make a stealth check.
TRAVIS: 27.
MATT: Make a perception check if you like, Eden.
SAM: Natural 20.
TRAVIS: Oh my god!
MATT: So right as he's running, he glances up and
catches you. Skak, make your attack. No sneak
attack on this one, unfortunately.
TRAVIS: Damn! Oh, that's pretty good. 25.
SAM: That hits, but I will catch that shit. I
mean, catch that shrak and throw it back.
MATT: Do you have any ki left?
SAM: It doesn't say I need ki!
MATT: To throw it back, you need to spend a ki.
SAM: Oh, I see. I can catch it.
TRAVIS: 12 points of damage, and I will use fury of
the small to add five extra damage to it, so 17.
SAM: I rolled 17.
MATT: What?!
SAM: It's 1d10 plus nine. So I rolled an
eight.
TRAVIS: What happens?
MATT: So as he's running, and just catches it.
TRAVIS: It's not fair. It's not fair!
I can only do that once a day!
MATT: All right. Ending Skak's turn. Mozuu, you're
up.
DARIN: Sorry.
LAURA: Yeah, you're real sorry. Chosen.
DARIN: I leap at Arb-Uruk and attempt to rip her
throat out.
MATT: All right. Make an athletics check against
Arb-Uruk. You make an athletics check as well, as
it's opposed.
DARIN: 20.
LAURA: Oh, no. Athletics. Oh no, he gets me. 12.
MATT: So you leap onto the front of her. Which, by
the way, you're small in comparison. You're like
this spider climbing up the body up to the throat.
Go ahead and make an attack.
DARIN: Okay. 16 plus three. 19.
MATT: 19. Armor class is 18. Roll a d4 plus your
strength modifier.
DARIN: That is a five.
MATT: So you take five points of piercing damage
as Mozuu begins biting chunks out of your throat.
DARIN: Do I get another attack or is leaping the
attack?
MATT: I'll consider leaping as part of it.
DARIN: That's a good thing. Sorry.
TRAVIS: Sorry!
MATT: All right. Eden, you're up.
SAM: Do I have enough movement to get under the
shrak hole?
MATT: As you ran and then came right back, you
come up from underneath and you're out of the
shrak hole and you see now Mozuu latched onto
Arb-Uruk, biting into the throat.
SAM: I'm going to attack Mozuu.
MATT: Go for it.
SAM: Or is the Bright--
MATT: The Bright Lord is not that far from you.
You can get to the Bright Lord. You're pretty fast.
LAURA: Attack Mozuu!
SAM: I'll attack Mozuu. I choose Mozuu the
Chosen.
MATT: Go for it.
SAM: Mozuu!
DARIN: Mozuu!
SAM: 20 to hit.
MATT: 20 to hit? That hits Mozuu, I think.
DARIN: Oh yes, I'm at 18. Otherwise known as, ow.
SAM: Eight plus four. 12.
MATT: So 12 points of bludgeoning damage as out of
nowhere, Eden rushes forward and slams you in the
side of the body. Almost knocking you off of
Arb-Uruk but not quite strong enough to do so.
SAM: A second attack. 11 plus seven. 18 to hit!
MATT: That hits. Roll damage again!
SAM: Two plus four. So that's six more points of
damage.
MATT: Six more points of bludgeoning damage. And
you have your bonus action still, if you want to.
SAM: Oh! One more hit. This is an open-handed hit,
right?
MATT: I believe so, yeah.
SAM: No good. That's a 13 to hit.
MATT: 13. The third and final hit, you manage to
deflect it with your with your arm. It makes no
impact there. Ending Eden's turn. Up to you and
the gravewalker.
LAURA: Can I grab a hold of Mozuu and rip him off
me and then hit the gravewalker with him?
MATT: Sure! Go for it!
MATT: So make an athletics check and you make an
athletics check as well.
LAURA: 13.
DARIN: Ten.
MATT: Yeah, you tear him off. Go ahead and make an
attack roll. You don't get the proficiency bonus
on this but you still get your strength bonus.
LAURA: Just my strength modifier? 18.
MATT: 18 hits the gravewalker! His AC is 17! I'll
say for this one, roll a d6 and add your strength
modifier.
SAM: Kill the tark! For the glory of the uruk!
MATT: You don't get to reroll your damage roll
because he's not considered--
LAURA: He's not a two-handed weapon?
MATT: Sure! You know what, sure! I'll let him be a
two-handed weapon. Yeah, I'll allow it.
LAURA: So that's ten.
MATT: So ten points of bludgeoning damage to both
you and the gravewalker.
DARIN: Guess what?
MATT and TRAVIS: What?
LAURA: You're unconscious?
MATT: After the hit, Mozuu goes limp in your hand
and you're flailing him around in the grasp.
The gravewalker takes the hit, looks up at
you. He's going to go ahead and make
one strike with Urfael. That is 20.
LAURA: Oh no! It hits me.
MATT: All right, you take eight points of slashing
damage. And that is a 22 to hit.
LAURA: Oh god. It gets me.
MATT: You take 12 points of slashing damage.
LAURA: Oh no! I'm unconscious!
MATT: You're unconscious? All right, as you fall
unconscious and collapse to the ground, he reaches
down and grasps the side of your face and you feel
this urge of energy come up from underneath and as
your eyes flare open, you see the burning, vibrant
eyes of the wraith within the gravewalker say,
"Stand and join me." Do you want to resist or not?
Make a will save to resist, if you want.
LAURA: I'm going to try and resist it.
MATT: Make a wisdom saving throw.
LAURA: Oh shit! 19.
MATT: And you do. Brought back to the brink, there
the gravewalker stands ahead of you. As you
resist, he goes, "Fine. I gave you a choice."
Spins the blade around and takes you out from that point.
SAM: Is she dead?
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: Dead dead?
TRAVIS: Yep. Dead.
LAURA: I didn't get turnt! And it was worth it!
MATT: Skak, your turn, up on the edge of the
wall.
TRAVIS: Can I try and resist the domination? That
I'm under the hold?
MATT: No.
TRAVIS: No. Then I will gladly take a-- can I jump
down from the wall? No, crossbow. Is he within
melee of anybody for sneak attack?
MATT: Actually, yeah. He would have been in melee
with her, which means he's right next to Talion.
So, yeah.
TRAVIS: All right. Crossbow right at him.
SAM: I don't think I have another resistance to
this this time, I mean, is it cycled through
again?
MATT: It would be because you've gone since last
time.
TRAVIS: With my bonus, can I try and hide?
MATT: You may.
TRAVIS: That's 26.
MATT: Make a perception check.
SAM: It's not good. It's like eight.
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: How do I get advantage on the rolls? Sneak
attack?
MATT: Well, you do now that he doesn't see you.
TRAVIS: Okay great, come on. Damn it! Okay, that's
fine. 18.
MATT: 18 hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: Aw. 12, 15, 20.
SAM: I resist 18 points of damage.
TRAVIS: Damn it!
But the tip goes into your chin.
MATT: Oh my god. That's so great. I love it. I
love it so much.
TRAVIS: Dang it, Eden! Just take it! Take the
arrow!
SAM: I'm making a nice collection of your arrows.
TRAVIS: Throw it at the Bright Lord!
MATT: All right, that ends your turn, Skak.
TRAVIS: Yes.
MATT: Mozuu's unconscious.
DARIN: Mozuu's dead.
MATT: Mozuu's pretty gone. Eden, you're up.
SAM: Yes. All right, Bright Lord, let's see what
you got! Hi-ya!
LAURA: Shrak is flinging everywhere.
MATT: Yeah. All across.
SAM: 13! Ugh! Nine!
Bonus action! Oh! 18 plus seven, that's 25!
MATT: That hits. Go ahead and roll a d6 plus
damage.
SAM: Oh, you've got a mark on your face from my
hand! Oh, it's a poo mark!
That's the mark of the shrak! The shrak lord!
One!
MATT: Plus?
SAM: Plus four, I guess?
MATT: All right, so five damage. He's going to use
a legendary action at the end of your turn to do
dominate on you. He goes, "One mark for another,
uruk brother." Reaches forward to grasp at you.
Natural 20. Make a wisdom saving throw.
SAM: I mean, you got a 20!
MATT: I'll say disadvantage on the wisdom saving
throw, because of the natural 20.
SAM: Yeah. So seven?
MATT: As the brand of the gravewalker burns into
your face, suddenly you see now the vision of
glory, the possible downfall of the Dark Lord and
a new beginning under the Bright Lord here in
Mordor. And as he pulls the hand away, now the
fray has come to a calm. The villains and the
current scenario from there and now, your
perspective now ended. The rest of the uruk begin
to gather around. Face-eater Ur-Gram comes up
behind and the gravewalker looks about to invite
those that survived the fray now under his grasp.
"Come. We must salvage the shreds. I mean to carve
"my way northwest." You watch now as a red-orange
flare off in the distance up in the clouds
signifies the volcanic explosion within Mount Doom
far, far away. "Stand at my side, orcs. For we
"march on Barad-dűr. The time of the Dark Lord
wanes in the wake of the Bright Lord's wrath."
And that's where we're going to end it tonight.
(cheering)
LAURA: That was awesome!
MATT: Well done, guys!
TRAVIS: That was fun!
LAURA: I died!
TRAVIS: I want you to know that after that ended,
I went up and shot Eden in his sleep. To rise
through the ranks.
MATT: And there you have it.
TRAVIS: My warchief ambitions.
DARIN: Well, we tried to hit every angle of the
orcs in the game.
LAURA: That was so fun!
MATT: That was great. Guys, well done. That was a
blast.
SAM: But not as fun as the game that's coming out
on October 10. It's called "Mordor, Mordor, Mordor."
DARIN: No it is not!
MATT: Shadow of War, coming out October 10. Also
out on iOS and for Android. WB Games, thank you so
much for making this happen. We had a blast. Hope
you guys had a good time.
TRAVIS: That shadow strike is real in the game,
too. It's legit.
MATT: All right. Well, have a wonderful day. And
is it Thursday yet? Bye.
[music]